Wired

August 27, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Florida’s Covid Surge Is Screwing With the Water Supply (Hint: Oxygen) More people in the hospital means more people need oxygen. But treatment plants also need the gas to purify water. https://www.wired.com/story/why-floridas-covid-surge-is-screwing-with-the-water-supply/

August 27, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider New Vaccine Decisions, an Influx of Mandates, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-approval-boosters-mandates-coronavirus-news/

August 27, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Would the Free Guy  Inflatable Bubble Protect a Real Person? In the movie’s video game world, a whole-body airbag protects Ryan Reynolds as he falls off of a building and onto a car. Would that … work? https://www.wired.com/story/would-the-free-guy-inflatable-bubble-protect-a-real-person/

August 27, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Titan’s Strange Chemical World Gets Simulated in Tiny Tubes A research chemist mixed nitrogen, methane, and other molecules to re-create the conditions that might harbor life on one of Saturn’s moons. https://www.wired.com/story/titans-strange-chemical-world-gets-simulated-in-tiny-tubes/

August 26, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Vaccine Mandates Work—but Only If They’re Done Right Requiring people to get their shots can stop Covid-19, but those rules have to be doable and equitable. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-mandates-work-but-only-if-theyre-done-right/

August 25, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Afghanistan Almost Beat Polio. Now the Future Is Uncertain It’s a heart-stopping moment for health officials, who reported only a single case this year—and whose campaigns may end up paused. https://www.wired.com/story/afghanistan-almost-beat-polio-now-the-future-is-uncertain/

August 24, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Barnacle-Inspired Glue Seals Bleeding Organs in Seconds The paste sticks onto wet tissue firmly by repelling blood. Surgeons hope it can save time—and lives. https://www.wired.com/story/this-barnacle-inspired-glue-seals-bleeding-organs-in-seconds/

August 23, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Would It Be Fair to Treat Vaccinated Covid Patients First? Last week, Texas health care policymakers discussed taking vaccination status into account for Covid triage. It’s a larger conversation ethicists are bracing for. https://www.wired.com/story/would-it-be-fair-to-treat-vaccinated-covid-patients-first/

August 23, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon So Hey Here’s a Tortoise Hunting and Eating a Baby Bird How does one of the slowest animals on Earth manage to chase down a bird? Have a look for yourself. https://www.wired.com/story/so-hey-heres-a-tortoise-hunting-and-eating-a-baby-bird/

August 23, 2021 | Author: Jess CraigJess Craig Can This Sun-Reflecting Fabric Help Fight Climate Change? An experimental textile called metafabric is designed to cool down the wearer and reduce the need for air-conditioning. https://www.wired.com/story/can-this-sun-reflecting-fabric-help-fight-climate-change/

August 22, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica How the Cuttlefish’s Robust Memory System Defies Old Age This cephalopod is the only known animal that doesn’t exhibit age-related deterioration when recalling specific events. https://www.wired.com/story/how-cuttlefishs-robust-memory-system-defies-old-age/

August 22, 2021 | Author: Stephen OrnesStephen Ornes How Big Data Carried Graph Theory Into New Dimensions Researchers are turning to the mathematics of higher-order interactions to better model the complex connections within their data. https://www.wired.com/story/how-big-data-carried-graph-theory-into-new-dimensions/

August 21, 2021 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester A Plan to Slow the Creep of the Sahara—by Planting Gardens People along the desert’s border are building a kind of circular plot called a tolou keur to keep the soil fertile and to slow desertification. https://www.wired.com/story/a-plan-to-slow-the-creep-of-the-sahara-by-planting-gardens/

August 20, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The US Is Getting Covid Booster Shots. The World Is Furious The White House’s plan to roll out third shots for any American adult is raising profound questions about global equity. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-is-getting-covid-booster-shots-the-world-is-furious/

August 20, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Biden Pushes Boosters, Schools Mandate Shots, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/biden-boosters-school-mandates-coronavirus-news/

August 20, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Ace Physics Class (Even if You Don’t Ace Physics) It’s back-to-school season, so here are some tips on getting the most out of college science courses. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-ace-physics-class-even-if-you-dont-ace-physics/

August 19, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Next Big Challenge for Lunar Astronauts? Moon Dust NASA is trying out sonic waves, electrostatic devices, and extra-slick coatings as ways to repel pesky space dirt. https://www.wired.com/story/the-next-big-challenge-for-lunar-astronauts-moon-dust/

August 18, 2021 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell The Push for Ad Agencies to Ditch Big Oil Clients An activist coalition is pressuring firms to stop promoting fossil fuel companies—some of which have advertised oil and gas as “climate friendly.” https://www.wired.com/story/push-ad-agencies-ditch-big-oil-clients/

August 18, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wildfires Used to Be Helpful. How Did They Get So Hellish? Fires are supposed to reset ecosystems, paving the way for new growth. But human meddling and climate change have turned them into monsters. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfires-used-to-be-helpful-how-did-they-get-so-hellish/

August 17, 2021 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles NASA’s Lucy Mission Gets Ready to Fly by the Trojan Asteroids The spacecraft will provide the first up-close look at these building blocks of the early solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-lucy-mission-gets-ready-to-fly-by-the-trojan-asteroids/

August 16, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller Is the Robot-Filled Future of Farming a Nightmare or Utopia? A new paper argues that the rise of artificial intelligence in agriculture could be the best—or worst—innovation for our environment. https://www.wired.com/story/is-the-robot-filled-future-of-farming-a-nightmare-or-utopia/

August 16, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Clare BallJennifer Clare Ball This AI Helps Detect Wildlife Health Issues in Real Time A system that scans animal rehabilitation center data could provide early alerts when a disease is spreading. https://www.wired.com/story/this-ai-helps-detect-wildlife-health-issues-in-real-time/

August 15, 2021 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz Animals Count and Use Zero. How Far Does Their Number Sense Go? Crows recently demonstrated an understanding of the concept of zero. It’s only the latest evidence of animals’ talents for numerical abstraction. https://www.wired.com/story/animals-count-and-use-zero-how-far-does-their-number-sense-go/

August 14, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Want to Slash Carbon Emissions? Start With These Power Plants The worst 5 percent of energy producers account for almost 75 percent of the sector’s emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/to-slash-carbon-emissions-start-with-these-power-plants/

August 14, 2021 | Author: Zoya TeirsteinZoya Teirstein Eastern Hemlocks Face Extinction. A Tiny Fly Could Save Them An invasive insect called the woolly adelgid is eating the Northeast’s forests alive. So some researchers are calling in hungry silver flies. https://www.wired.com/story/eastern-hemlocks-face-extinction-a-tiny-fly-could-save-them/

August 13, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The FDA OKs an Extra Covid Vaccine Dose for Immune-Impaired People The federal agency will allow people living with organ transplants, undergoing cancer treatments, and taking some medications to get a third shot. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-oks-an-extra-covid-vaccine-dose-for-immunosuppressed-people/

August 13, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Cases Among Kids, New Mandates, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/cases-kids-new-mandates-coronavirus-news/

August 13, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Johnny Knoxville, Human Cannonball Jackass Forever is back with more dumb stunts. Please: Only try the physics at home. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-johnny-knoxville-human-cannonball/

August 12, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Perseverance’s First Mars Drilling Attempt Came Up Empty Far from a failure, the sampling might actually offer tantalizing clues about the geology—and potential past life—of the Red Planet. https://www.wired.com/story/why-perseverances-first-mars-drilling-attempt-came-up-empty/

August 12, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A Mammoth Tusk Reveals a Woolly (and Unprecedented) Tale Scientists used something called isotopic mapping to get a first look at how the creatures lived more than 17,000 years ago. https://www.wired.com/story/a-mammoth-tusk-reveals-a-woolly-and-unprecedented-tale/

August 12, 2021 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Without Code for DeepMind’s Protein AI, This Lab Wrote Its Own The Google subsidiary solved a fundamental problem in biology but didn’t promptly share its solution. So a University of Washington team tried to re-create it. https://www.wired.com/story/without-code-for-deepminds-protein-ai-this-lab-wrote-its-own/

August 11, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon If You Want to Tackle Climate Change, Start With Methane The landmark assessment was dire. But it shows that by slashing methane emissions, humanity can make rapid progress in fighting climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/the-ipcc-reports-silver-lining-we-can-tackle-methane-now/

August 11, 2021 | Author: Maia SzalavitzMaia Szalavitz The Pain Was Unbearable. So Why Did Doctors Turn Her Away? A sweeping drug addiction risk algorithm has become central to how the US handles the opioid crisis. It may only be making the crisis worse. https://www.wired.com/story/opioid-drug-addiction-algorithm-chronic-pain/

August 10, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Gymnasts Make the Wolf Turn Look Easy. Physics Shows It’s Not The spin seems simple if you’re just watching it on TV. But it’s a complex move that requires understanding your center of mass. https://www.wired.com/story/gymnasts-make-the-wolf-turn-look-easy-physics-shows-its-not/

August 10, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Smart Cities, Bad Metaphors, and a Better Urban Future Shannon Mattern’s new book, A City Is Not a Computer, digs into the data, dashboards, and language that keep people from building better, safer communities. https://www.wired.com/story/smart-cities-bad-metaphors-and-a-better-urban-future/

August 9, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Squishy, Far-Out New Experiments Headed to the ISS Muscle cells, 3D-printed lunar regolith, and le Blob will soon orbit 250 miles above Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/the-squishy-far-out-new-experiments-headed-to-the-iss/

August 9, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The UN Climate Report: All Is Not Well—but All Is Not Lost A major new report from the IPCC paints a devastating portrait of climate change. But it also shows that it’s not too late for drastic action. https://www.wired.com/story/the-un-climate-report-all-is-not-well-but-all-is-not-lost/

August 8, 2021 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK Watch Out, Beyond Burgers—the Fungi Renaissance Is Here While the popular plant-based meats grab all the headlines, a much more humble foodstuff is poised to lead the next wave of alternative proteins. https://www.wired.com/story/fungi-renaissance-is-here/

August 8, 2021 | Author: Jonathan O’CallaghanJonathan O’Callaghan A Failed Star Called ‘The Accident’ Puzzles Astronomers The brown dwarf isn’t a star and it’s not a planet. But it’s illuminating the murky borderlands that separate the two. https://www.wired.com/story/a-failed-star-called-the-accident-puzzles-astronomers/

August 7, 2021 | Author: Maddie StoneMaddie Stone Can You Recycle a Hard Drive? Google Is Trying to Find Out Rare-earth magnet recycling could reduce the need to mine for more resources, leading to more sustainable data centers. https://www.wired.com/story/can-you-recycle-a-hard-drive-google-is-trying-to-find-out/

August 6, 2021 | Author: Matt JancerMatt Jancer Where to Get a Covid-19 Vaccine, and What to Expect Vaccines are rolling out across the US. These tips will help you figure out where to find an appointment in your area, and how to prepare. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-us-vaccination-guide/

August 6, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Even Small Volcanic Eruptions Could Create Global Chaos Relatively minor meltdowns might destroy underwater cables and disrupt vital industries, scientists say, creating a cascade of economic misery. https://www.wired.com/story/even-smaller-volcanic-eruptions-could-create-global-chaos/

August 5, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy What Rat Empathy May Reveal About Human Compassion Rats may feel concern when cage mates are trapped. But, like people, they don’t always care enough to help. https://www.wired.com/story/what-rat-empathy-may-reveal-about-human-compassion/

August 4, 2021 | Author: Grace Browne, WIRED UKGrace Browne, WIRED UK Exactly How Many People Have Long Covid? Pinning down the number of “long-haulers” suffering from the mysterious condition is an important task. It’s also proving impossible. https://www.wired.com/story/exactly-how-many-people-long-covid/

August 4, 2021 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright Scientists Could One Day Float an Aerial Robot Above Venus Researchers recently tested whether a balloon-borne sensor could listen for venusquakes to learn about the planet’s makeup. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-could-one-day-float-an-aerial-robot-above-venus/

August 3, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Did People Find the Fundamental Charge With Drops of Oil? Back in 1909, figuring out the charge of a single electron was a Nobel-worthy pursuit. Today, it’s a good lesson in understanding four key forces. https://www.wired.com/story/how-did-people-find-the-fundamental-charge-with-drops-of-oil/

August 3, 2021 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica Russia’s Latest Space Station Incident Points to Larger Issues Nauka’s errant firings were likely the result of human error—and they raise concerns about the future of the country’s space program and its partnership with NASA. https://www.wired.com/story/russia-space-station-nauka-issues/

August 3, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller Why Even the Fastest Human Can’t Outrun Your House Cat A new model explains the forces and body design features that limit maximum sprinting speed. https://www.wired.com/story/why-even-the-fastest-human-cant-outrun-your-house-cat/

August 2, 2021 | Author: Jim MorrisonJim Morrison Sunny-Day Flooding Is About to Become More Than a Nuisance Sea level rise will soon combine with a host of other environmental factors to produce dozens of floods each fall in US coastal cities. https://www.wired.com/story/sunny-day-flooding-is-about-to-become-more-than-a-nuisance/

August 2, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Weird, Sustainable Booze of the Future Tastes … Good? Small distilleries like Empirical Spirits are working on uncategorizable drinks made of stuff like plum pits, for the resilient quaff of tomorrow. https://www.wired.com/story/the-weird-sustainable-booze-of-the-future-tastes-good/

August 1, 2021 | Author: Thomas LewtonThomas Lewton Fractons, the Weirdest Matter, Could Yield Quantum Clues Theorists are in a frenzy over these bizarre, but potentially useful, hypothetical particles that can only move in combination with one another. https://www.wired.com/story/fractons-the-weirdest-matter-could-yield-quantum-clues/

July 31, 2021 | Author: Emiliano RuprahEmiliano Ruprah How the Jaguar, King of the Forest, Might Save Its Ecosystem With a new train line threatening its habitat, the big cat may be the key to protecting this Mexican reserve—and everything else in it. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-jaguar-king-of-the-forest-might-save-its-ecosystem/

July 30, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica 3D Imaging Shows How Shark Guts Work Like a Tesla Valve Using CT scans and 3D modeling, researchers found the fish’s spiral digestive system is analogous to Nikola Tesla’s ingenious check valve design. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-imaging-shows-shark-guts-work-like-nikola-tesla-water-valve/

July 30, 2021 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Dogs, Unlike Wolves, Are Born to Communicate With People Wolf puppies can’t understand human gestures as well as their dog cousins. The difference could help explain what makes dogs so special. https://www.wired.com/story/dogs-unlike-wolves-are-born-to-communicate-with-people/

July 29, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Dam Is Breaking on Vaccine Mandates Hopes for a “normal” fall have been dashed by variants and low vaccine uptake. Businesses and the White House think requiring shots can turn things around. https://www.wired.com/story/the-dam-is-breaking-on-vaccine-mandates/

July 29, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler How Much Will It Cost to Prevent Deaths by Climate-Driven Heat? A new formula measures the “mortality cost of carbon” and how much would have to be removed from the atmosphere to save a single life. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-will-it-cost-to-prevent-deaths-by-climate-driven-heat/

July 28, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Extreme Heat Could Also Mean Power and Water Shortages An extraordinary drought in the West, plus dry lakes and reservoirs, mean there will be less water for farms, hydroelectric energy, and home users. https://www.wired.com/story/extreme-heat-could-also-mean-power-and-water-shortages/

July 27, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Oh Good, Now There’s an Outbreak of Wildfire Thunderclouds Huge pyrocumulonimbus clouds just formed over fires in the West. Here’s why they could become more common on a warmer planet. https://www.wired.com/story/oh-good-now-theres-an-outbreak-of-wildfire-thunderclouds/

July 26, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Incredible Physics of Simone Biles’ Yurchenko Double Pike Calculating angular velocity and the moment of inertia isn’t quite as hard as competing in the Olympic gymnastics tournament—but it’s pretty darn tough. https://www.wired.com/story/the-incredible-physics-of-simone-biles-yurchenko-double-pike/

July 25, 2021 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz DNA Has Four Bases. Some Viruses Swap in a Fifth Dozens of viruses don’t use the same four nucleotide bases found in all other life. New work shows how this is possible—and perhaps more common than we think. https://www.wired.com/story/dna-has-four-bases-some-viruses-swap-in-a-fifth/

July 24, 2021 | Author: Janet MarinelliJanet Marinelli Cities Aren’t the Wildlife ‘Deserts’ Scientists Once Feared As more animals are spotted in urban areas, researchers recognize how cities can play a significant role in fostering biodiversity. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-arent-the-wildlife-deserts-scientists-once-feared/

July 23, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The Pandemic Olympics, Vaccine Misinformation, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-olympics-vaccine-misinformation-coronavirus-news/

July 23, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica How Mockingbirds Compose Songs Just Like Beethoven The birds aren’t producing sounds at random. Some of their strategies are surprisingly similar to ones used by humans. https://www.wired.com/story/how-mockingbirds-compose-songs-like-beethoven/

July 22, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Olympics Could Be a Covid-19 ‘Super-Evolutionary Event’ In a warped version of international cooperation, the Games could provide a place for variants of the virus to spread and then return home with athletes. https://www.wired.com/story/tokyo-olympics-covid-delta-variant/

July 22, 2021 | Author: Katrina Miller, Matt SimonKatrina Miller and Matt Simon Scientists Just ‘Looked’ Inside Mars. Here’s What They Found InSight and Perseverance have sent back unprecedented data on everything from marsquakes to the Red Planet’s inner layers. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-just-looked-inside-mars-heres-what-they-found/

July 21, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Jeff Bezos Goes to Space. Day Three: Reentry For the Amazon and Blue Origin founder, suborbital space tourism is just the first step toward something much bigger. https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-goes-to-space-day-three-reentry/

July 21, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber These Bendy Plastic Chips Fit in Unusual Places Researchers think these flexible semiconductors will be able to monitor your heartbeat or tell you whether your milk has spoiled. https://www.wired.com/story/bendy-plastic-chips-fit-unusual-places/

July 20, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Jeff Bezos Goes to Space. Day Two: Blastoff The day was a career highlight for the Amazon and Blue Origin founder. But the real star of the show was Wally Funk. https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-goes-to-space-day-two-blastoff/

July 20, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Everything You Need to Know About the Coronavirus Here’s all the WIRED coverage in one place, from how to keep your children entertained to how this outbreak is affecting the economy.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-guide-faq-advice/

July 20, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Jeff Bezos Touches Space Aboard Blue Origin Rocket The Amazon founder, his brother, aviation pioneer Wally Funk, and a paying passenger were the first to test out the New Shepard suborbital rocket system. https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-touches-space-aboard-the-blue-origin-rocket/

July 19, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Hungry Wild Pigs Are Worsening Climate Change When the invasive swine root through soils around the world, they release as much carbon dioxide as a million cars. Good luck getting rid of them. https://www.wired.com/story/hungry-wild-pigs-are-worsening-climate-change/

July 19, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Jeff Bezos Goes to Space. Day One: Countdown WIRED is reporting daily from Van Horn, Texas, where the Amazon founder will be among the first passengers aboard Blue Origin’s New Shepard rocket system. https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-is-going-to-space-day-one-countdown/

July 18, 2021 | Author: Boone AshworthBoone Ashworth Watch Jeff Bezos Go to Space on a Blue Origin Rocket Whether you’re here for the history or you’re watching passive-aggressively as the world’s wealthiest man plays with toys, here’s how to tune in. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-jeff-bezos-go-to-space/

July 18, 2021 | Author: Jonathan O’CallaghanJonathan O’Callaghan What Causes Gamma-Ray Bursts? Their Ultrabright Flashes Hold Clues These high-energy explosions, brighter than billions and billions of suns, have recently been tracked for days, upending ideas about the cataclysms that create them. https://www.wired.com/story/what-causes-gamma-ray-bursts-their-ultrabright-flashes-hold-clues/

July 17, 2021 | Author: Sarah SaxSarah Sax Can Swimmers and Sharks Coexist? Smarter Maps Might Help Great whites have returned to Cape Cod, a conservation success story and a hazard. Can new, predictive tools help keep beachgoers safe? https://www.wired.com/story/can-swimmers-and-sharks-coexist-smarter-maps-might-help/

July 16, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Vaccines for Kids, a Global Surge in Cases, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccines-kids-delta-surge-coronavirus-news/

July 16, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Device Could Tune Your Heart—Then Dissolve Away The latest in “electronic medicine” offers an alternative to temporary pacemakers and could help reduce tissue scarring. https://www.wired.com/story/this-device-could-tune-your-heart-then-dissolve-away/

July 15, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Next Covid-19 Battle Will Be About Vaccinating Kids Pfizer and Moderna are midway through clinical trials, and the public health system is well versed in delivering childhood shots. The challenge? Politics. https://www.wired.com/story/the-next-covid-19-battle-will-be-about-vaccinating-kids/

July 14, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller The Latest Twist in the Life-on-Venus Debate? Volcanoes Last fall, researchers said the presence of phosphine in the planet’s atmosphere could indicate life. But a new study says there could be a geological explanation. https://www.wired.com/story/life-on-venus-debate-phosphine-volcanoes/

July 14, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Why Humans See Faces in Everyday Objects The ability to spot Jesus’ mug in a piece of burnt toast might be a product of evolution. https://www.wired.com/story/why-humans-see-faces-everyday-objects/

July 14, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Be Very Careful Where You Build That Seawall Walls are meant to keep out rising seas—but that water still has to go somewhere. New modeling shows it could well end up flooding your neighbors. https://www.wired.com/story/be-very-careful-about-where-you-build-that-seawall/

July 13, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller This Is How Aliens Might Search for Human Life If habitable worlds exist around certain stars, they’d have just the right vantage point to spy on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/this-is-how-aliens-might-search-for-human-life/

July 13, 2021 | Author: Evan LubofskyEvan Lubofsky A Son Is Rescued at Sea. But What Happened to His Mother? Nathan Carman went fishing with his mom. A week later, he was found on a life raft—alone. Tragic accident or murder? Ocean sensors may point to the truth. https://www.wired.com/story/a-son-is-rescued-at-sea-but-what-happened-to-his-mother/

July 12, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Prepare for the Robot Apocalypse (If You’re a Robot) In the Netflix show The Mitchells vs. the Machines, robots are planning to blast all of humanity into outer space. How much time and energy will that take? https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-prepare-for-the-robot-apocalypse-if-youre-a-robot/

July 12, 2021 | Author: Karmela Padavic-CallaghanKarmela Padavic-Callaghan A Graphene ‘Camera’ Images the Activity of Living Heart Cells Using a novel device made from carbon atoms and a laser, researchers captured real-time electrical signals from muscle tissue. https://www.wired.com/story/a-graphene-camera-images-the-activity-of-living-heart-cells/

July 11, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Richard Branson Reaches Space on Virgin Galactic’s VSS Unity The historic flight is the first time the rocket plane has carried a full crew. https://www.wired.com/story/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-vss-unity-space-flight/

July 11, 2021 | Author: Allison WhittenAllison Whitten Mathematicians Prove Symmetry of Phase Transitions At critical moments, rotational invariance is a universal property across many physical systems. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-prove-symmetry-of-phase-transitions/

July 10, 2021 | Author: Adam PopescuAdam Popescu Iconic Yellowstone Park Faces Startling Climate Threats A new report details global warming’s effect on the national park and its surroundings, including everything from its forests to the Old Faithful geyser. https://www.wired.com/story/iconic-yellowstone-park-faces-startling-climate-threats/

July 9, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The Olympics Bars Fans, Pfizer Eyes Boosters, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/olympics-bars-fans-pfizer-boosters-coronavirus-news/

July 9, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Scientists Love Making Robots Build Ikea Furniture This robot can help a human assemble a bookcase by predicting what part they’ll want next and handing it over. https://www.wired.com/story/why-scientists-love-making-robots-build-ikea-furniture/

July 8, 2021 | Author: Kasra ZareiKasra Zarei Access to Birth Control Lets More Girls Finish High School A new study finds that making contraceptives and reproductive care accessible through a state-funded program in Colorado reduced the dropout rate for young women. https://www.wired.com/story/access-to-birth-control-let-more-girls-graduate-high-school/

July 8, 2021 | Author: Aviva StahlAviva Stahl Prisoners, Doctors, and the Battle Over Trans Medical Care Those who are incarcerated are suing for their right to gender confirmation surgery—if deemed necessary. Meet the psychiatrist who almost always says it’s not. https://www.wired.com/story/inmates-doctors-battle-over-transgender-medical-care/

July 8, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller Mystery Solved: How Plant Cells Know When to Stop Growing The discovery could have a profound effect on cell research for many species of plants and animals, as well as the future of crops. https://www.wired.com/story/mystery-solved-how-plant-cells-know-when-to-stop-growing/

July 7, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Massive Water Recycling Proposal Could Help Ease Drought Members of Congress from Western states are pushing for $750 million to turn wastewater into pure water. Here’s how that works. https://www.wired.com/story/a-massive-water-recycling-proposal-could-help-ease-drought/

July 6, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid Protections Kept Other Viruses at Bay. Now They’re Back When we masked and stayed home, we were shielded from winter viruses. As we get back to normal, some will resurge—and our immune systems may not be prepared. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-protections-kept-other-viruses-at-bay-now-theyre-back/

July 6, 2021 | Author: Geoff Manaugh, Nicola TwilleyGeoff Manaugh and Nicola Twilley When the Next Animal Plague Hits, Can This Lab Stop It? A new federal facility in Kansas will house the deadliest agricultural pathogens in the world—and researchers working tirelessly to contain them. https://www.wired.com/story/when-next-animal-plague-hits-can-this-lab-stop-it/

July 5, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The Pandemic Changed Sleep Habits. Maybe That’s a Good Thing A growing body of research shows that to optimize health and productivity, workers should adjust their workdays to their sleep schedules. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-changed-sleep-habits-maybe-thats-a-good-thing/

July 4, 2021 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Mathematicians Prove a 2D Version of Quantum Gravity Works In three towering papers, a team of mathematicians has worked out the details of Liouville quantum field theory, forging a bridge between math and physics. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-prove-a-2d-version-of-quantum-gravity-works/

July 3, 2021 | Author: Gemma TarlachGemma Tarlach The Quest to Tally Alaska’s Wild ‘Warm-Blooded’ Bumblebees Extreme environments offer them an unexpected paradise. Now researchers and conservationists want to get a head count. https://www.wired.com/story/the-quest-to-tally-alaskas-wild-warm-blooded-bumblebees/

July 2, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The Delta Variant’s Rise, New Vaccine Tactics, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/delta-variant-vaccines-coronavirus-news/

July 2, 2021 | Author: Keith GilloglyKeith Gillogly Which Crops Can Survive Drought? Nanosensors May Offer Clues The technique can be used to track how water flows through plants—which could be key to breeding more resilient crops in an increasingly hot, dry climate. https://www.wired.com/story/which-crops-can-survive-drought-nanosensors-may-offer-clues/

July 1, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Miami Building Collapse and Humanity’s Tragic Fight for the Future From the fallen Champlain Tower to climate change, humans haven’t yet learned to avoid catastrophes they know are coming. https://www.wired.com/story/the-miami-building-collapse-and-humanitys-tragic-fight-for-the-future/

July 1, 2021 | Author: Lindsay GellmanLindsay Gellman How Fringe Stem Cell Treatments Won Allies on the Far Right Advocates for dubious therapies (fight Covid with your own fat!) have latched on to conservative grievances—and formed an unholy alliance. https://www.wired.com/story/stem-cell-treatment-far-right/

July 1, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Biologists Mask Up to Protect Bats (Yes, Bats) From Covid-19 New federal guidelines ask scientists to wear protective gear to keep the virus from jumping back into animal species. https://www.wired.com/story/biologists-mask-up-to-protect-bats-yes-bats-from-covid-19/

June 30, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Experimental African Houses That Outsmart Malaria A field test of custom-designed homes proves that when carbon dioxide can flow out, mosquitoes stay out too. https://www.wired.com/story/the-experimental-african-houses-that-outsmart-malaria/

June 30, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller Black Scientists Find Community—and Plan for the Road Ahead The Black in X network mobilized last summer to bring attention to racism in STEM. This week, they’re holding their first conference to talk about what’s next. https://www.wired.com/story/black-scientists-find-community-and-plan-for-the-road-ahead/

June 29, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Space Laser Shows How Catastrophic Sea Level Rise Will Be Scientists calculate that by 2100, over 400 million people could live in low-lying, at-risk areas—and that’s a conservative estimate.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-space-laser-shows-how-catastrophic-sea-level-rise-will-be/

June 29, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica A New Type of Supernova Unlocks Thousand-Year-Old Stellar Mysteries The discovery of a rare “electron-capture” supernova provides crucial insight for understanding the Crab Nebula. https://www.wired.com/story/new-type-of-supernova-unlocks-thousand-year-old-stellar-mysteries/

June 29, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Clare BallJennifer Clare Ball Lakes Are Losing Oxygen—and Their Inhabitants Are in Danger Hundreds of temperate lakes around the world are showing trends toward anoxia, becoming warmer, murkier, and less hospitable to cold-water species. https://www.wired.com/story/lakes-are-losing-oxygen-and-their-inhabitants-are-in-danger/

June 28, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Underground Fiber Optics Spy on Humans Moving Above Vibrations from cars and pedestrians create unique signals in cables. Now scientists have used the trick to show how Covid-19 brought life to a halt. https://www.wired.com/story/how-underground-fiber-optics-spy-on-humans-moving-above/

June 28, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Race to Put Silk in Nearly Everything The fiber has been considered a “miracle material” for anything from body parts to food. Has the revolution finally arrived? https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-put-silk-in-nearly-everything/

June 27, 2021 | Author: K.E.D. Coan, Ars TechnicaK.E.D. Coan, Ars Technica 24,000 Years in Permafrost Still Didn’t Kill These Ancient Critters The hardy rotifer can live through all manner of conditions, but this is a historic feat even for this tiny creature. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-find-24000-years-in-siberian-permafrost-still-didnt-kill-the-ancient-rotifer/

June 27, 2021 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz The Secret Workings of Smell Receptors, Revealed At Last Researchers have finally seen how some of them bind to odor molecules—yielding new insights into one of the most mysterious and versatile senses. https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-workings-of-smell-receptors-revealed-at-last/

June 26, 2021 | Author: Eric BenderEric Bender A $26 Billion Plan to Save the Houston Area From Rising Seas Lawmakers are poised to decide the fate of a massive project to protect the Texas coast from surging seawater. https://www.wired.com/story/a-dollar26-billion-plan-to-save-the-houston-area-from-rising-seas/

June 25, 2021 | Author: Adam MannAdam Mann What the Pentagon’s New UFO Report Reveals About Humankind The document says less about the search for life in the universe, and more about our current cultural climate and distrust of expertise. https://www.wired.com/story/what-the-pentagons-new-ufo-report-tells-us-about-ourselves/

June 25, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider US Vaccinations Slow, Americans Travel Again, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccinations-slow-americans-travel-coronavirus-news/

June 25, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Break Into the Hex From WandaVision—With Physics! Want to safely pass through the radiation field surrounding the town of Westview? You’re going to need some lead—and some handy equations. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-break-into-the-hex-from-wandavision-with-physics/

June 25, 2021 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst Tiny Satellites Could Help Warn of the Next Big Hurricane A constellation of nanosats could improve our understanding of the world’s most dangerous storms. https://www.wired.com/story/tiny-satellites-could-help-warn-of-the-next-big-hurricane/

June 24, 2021 | Author: Beth Mole, Ars TechnicaBeth Mole, Ars Technica The Delta and Gamma Covid-19 Variants Are Taking Over the US The two variants are threatening Alpha’s reign—and the country’s path out of the pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/delta-gamma-alpha-covid-19-variants-taking-over-the-united-states/

June 24, 2021 | Author: Grant CurrinGrant Currin Citizen Scientists Digitized Centuries of Handwritten Rain Data As the UK went into lockdown, 16,000 volunteers put their spare time to good use, transcribing 350 years of archival records for use by modern climate scientists. https://www.wired.com/story/citizen-scientists-digitized-centuries-of-handwritten-rain-data/

June 23, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Coelacanth May Live for a Century. That’s Not Great News Scale markings reveal that this weird fish’s lifespan is double what scientists first estimated. That also means they’re closer to extinction than we thought. https://www.wired.com/story/the-coelacanth-may-live-for-a-century-thats-not-great-news/

June 22, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Utilities Want to Control Your Smart Thermostat Sometimes Don’t mess with Texans’ air conditioning. Here’s why some customers in the state had their thermostats remotely controlled. https://www.wired.com/story/why-utilities-want-to-sometimes-control-your-smart-thermostat/

June 22, 2021 | Author: Katrina MillerKatrina Miller An Observatory Spied on LA’s Carbon Emissions—From Space The instrument reads sunlight intensity to determine carbon dioxide in Earth’s atmosphere. Its findings could help reduce our carbon footprint. https://www.wired.com/story/an-observatory-spied-on-las-carbon-emissions-from-space/

June 22, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Ranked Choice Voting Reveals the Weird Math of Elections The New York City mayoral race could show whether a new way of measuring voter desires can actually be an alternate timeline for democracy.  https://www.wired.com/story/ranked-choice-voting-reveals-the-weird-math-of-elections/

June 21, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Northern Farms Are Releasing Massive Amounts of Carbon Humans have been draining peatlands to grow crops for centuries. It’s a huge, underestimated source of greenhouse gas, scientists say.  https://www.wired.com/story/northern-farms-are-releasing-massive-amounts-of-carbon/

June 21, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain No, Covid-19 Vaccines Won’t Make You Magnetic. Here’s Why No matter how many videos you’ve seen of people sticking spoons to their faces, that’s just not how magnets work. https://www.wired.com/story/no-covid-19-vaccines-wont-make-you-magnetic-heres-why/

June 20, 2021 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett The Mystery at the Heart of Physics—That Only Math Can Solve The full picture of quantum field theory has long eluded physicists. Calling in mathematicians will have profound consequences for both fields. https://www.wired.com/story/the-mystery-at-the-heart-of-physics-that-only-math-can-solve/

June 19, 2021 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester What’s With All This Ooey, Gooey Sea Snot? A phlegmy film is coating the coast around Istanbul—and warmer water could be to blame. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-with-all-this-ooey-gooey-sea-snot/

June 18, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica The Mystery of Betelgeuse’s Dimming Has Finally Been Solved Astronomers say a cold patch and a stellar burp are behind the star’s strange dip in brightness. https://www.wired.com/story/mystery-of-betelgeuse-dimming-finally-solved/

June 17, 2021 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles GPS III’s Long Journey Is Picking Up Speed With the launch of a fifth new-generation satellite, the US finally has a constellation able to globally beam M-Code signals that are tough to spoof or jam. https://www.wired.com/story/gps-iiis-long-journey-is-picking-up-speed/

June 17, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Lithium Mine Versus the Wildflower The deposit could power millions of clean-energy car batteries. There’s just one roadblock: a rare, fragile species of buckwheat, for which a mine might mean extinction. https://www.wired.com/story/lithium-mine-for-batteries-versus-the-wildflower/

June 16, 2021 | Author: Beth Mole, Ars TechnicaBeth Mole, Ars Technica The Delta Variant and Low Vaccine Rates Could Spell Trouble Vaccines are effective against the variant, but experts worry about states where fewer people are inoculated. https://www.wired.com/story/delta-coronavirus-variant-low-vaccine-rates-could-spike-cases/

June 16, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Clever Robot Spies on Creatures in the Ocean’s ‘Twilight Zone’ Mesobot looks like a giant AirPods case, but it’s in fact a sophisticated machine that tracks animals making the most epic migration on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/a-clever-robot-spies-on-creatures-in-the-oceans-twilight-zone/

June 16, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Challenge of Covid-19 Vaccines for the Immunosuppressed Recent studies find transplant patients and immune-suppressed people who get the shot don’t make many antibodies. But that research is just beginning. https://www.wired.com/story/the-challenge-of-covid-19-vaccines-for-the-immunosuppressed/

June 15, 2021 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright NASA Might Put a Huge Telescope on the Far Side of the Moon Observing the secrets of the universe’s “Dark Ages” will require capturing ultra-long radio wavelengths—and we can’t do that on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-might-put-a-huge-telescope-on-the-far-side-of-the-moon/

June 15, 2021 | Author: Neil SinghNeil Singh What If Doctors Are Always Watching but Never There? Remote technology could save lives by monitoring health from home or outside the hospital. It could also push patients and health care providers further apart. https://www.wired.com/story/can-remote-tech-save-lives/

June 15, 2021 | Author: Annie Murphy Paul Annie Murphy Paul How Humans Think When They Think As Part of a Group The fancy word for it is “entitativity,” and it’s produced when people act and feel together in close proximity. We need it more, but we’re getting it less. https://www.wired.com/story/how-humans-think-when-they-think-group/

June 14, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Do You Make a Robot Walk on Mars? It’s a Steep Challenge Meet SpaceBok, a little, four-legged machine that’s taking the first steps toward walking on the Red Planet’s brutal terrain. https://www.wired.com/story/how-do-you-make-a-robot-walk-on-mars-its-a-steep-challenge/

June 13, 2021 | Author: Scott AaronsonScott Aaronson What Makes Quantum Computing So Hard to Explain? Before we can even begin to talk about these computers’ potential applications, we need to understand the fundamental physics behind them. https://www.wired.com/story/what-makes-quantum-computing-so-hard-to-explain/

June 12, 2021 | Author: Louise Johns Louise Johns When the Bison Come Back, Will the Ecosystem Follow? An effort to bring wild buffalo to the Great Plains aims to restore one of the world’s most endangered landscapes and increase climate resilience. https://www.wired.com/story/when-the-bison-come-back-will-the-ecosystem-follow/

June 11, 2021 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins A New Way to Understand the Brain’s Intricate Rhythm Researchers have found evidence in humans that individual neurons time their firing to a deeper beat. But there’s a mystery: What does it mean? https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-way-to-understand-the-brains-intricate-rhythm/

June 10, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler How Risky Is It to Send Jeff Bezos to the Edge of Space? Today’s commercial spacecraft have a safety advantage, thanks to simpler designs and suborbital missions. But with rockets, nothing is certain. https://www.wired.com/story/how-risky-is-it-to-send-jeff-bezos-to-the-edge-of-space/

June 10, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Protect Species and Save the Planet—at Once A major new report calls on humanity to tackle the biodiversity and climate crises simultaneously. Here’s what that might look like. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-protect-species-and-save-the-planet-at-once/

June 9, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Watch a Drone Swarm Fly Through a Fake Forest Without Crashing Each copter doesn’t just track where the others are. It constantly predicts where they’ll go. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-a-drone-swarm-fly-through-a-fake-forest-without-crashing/

June 8, 2021 | Author: Amit Katwala, WIRED UKAmit Katwala, WIRED UK Could Brain Training Help Address Police Brutality? New neuroscience-based technologies aim to improve decisionmaking under pressure. But solving systemic problems will take a lot more than that. https://www.wired.com/story/brain-training-police-brutality/

June 8, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Clothes Spew Microfibers Before They’re Even Clothes The clothing supply chain releases some 265 million pounds of microfibers that wash into the environment each year. https://www.wired.com/story/your-clothes-spew-microfibers-before-theyre-even-clothes/

June 7, 2021 | Author: Karmela Padavic-CallaghanKarmela Padavic-Callaghan A New Way to Shape Metal Nanoparticles—With a Magnetic Field Making the tiny nanoparticles used in everything from electronics to paint isn’t easy. But a new experiment creates order out of chaos. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-way-to-shape-metal-nanoparticles-with-a-magnetic-field/

June 6, 2021 | Author: Robin George AndrewsRobin George Andrews Will a Volcanic Eruption Be a Burp or a Blast? Scientists have begun to decipher the seismic signals that reveal how explosive a volcanic eruption is going to be. https://www.wired.com/story/will-a-volcanic-eruption-be-a-burp-or-a-blast/

June 5, 2021 | Author: Anna V. SmithAnna V. Smith The Drought Is Making the Klamath River’s Baby Salmon Sick Dry conditions are worsening a warm-water disease that’s sweeping through juvenile fish. Their deaths will create a future crisis for both fish and human populations. https://www.wired.com/story/the-drought-is-making-the-klamath-rivers-baby-salmon-sick/

June 4, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider New Vaccine Incentives, Surplus Dose Shipments, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-incentives-surplus-doses-coronavirus-news/

June 4, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Need to Weigh Some Water. All You’ve Got Is a Paper Clip OK, so you might need a couple other supplies, but your best option is to do what MacGyver would do: Turn it into a scale. https://www.wired.com/story/you-need-to-weigh-some-water-all-youve-got-is-a-paper-clip/

June 3, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Sneaky, Lying Flower That Pretends to Be a Rotting Beetle Aristolochia microstoma finds love by smelling like death. Coffin flies can’t resist. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sneaky-lying-flower-that-pretends-to-be-a-rotting-beetle/

June 3, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Wait, Vaccine Lotteries Actually Work? Ooh, the behavioral economists are going to be so smug about this. https://www.wired.com/story/wait-vaccine-lotteries-actually-work/

June 2, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The UK Has a Plan for a New ‘Pandemic Radar’ System Disease surveillance schemes to catch the next rising virus already exist—they’re just not communicating with each other. https://www.wired.com/story/the-uk-has-a-plan-for-a-new-pandemic-radar-system/

June 1, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Peanut the Waiter Robot Is Proof That Your Job Is Safe Restaurants are struggling to hire people, so one Jersey Shore grill employed a machine. It confirms that humans remain indispensable. https://www.wired.com/story/peanut-the-waiter-robot-is-proof-that-your-job-is-safe/

May 31, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Dam Acts Like a Water Cannon. Let’s Do Some Physics! Like a giant bucket with a hole, the Funil Hydropower Plant sprays out an enormous jet of water. We can use its speed to calculate the depth of the reservoir. https://www.wired.com/story/this-dam-acts-like-a-water-cannon-lets-do-some-physics/

May 30, 2021 | Author: Veronique GreenwoodVeronique Greenwood Sleep Evolved Before Brains. Hydras Are Living Proof Some of nature’s simplest animals suggest that sleep evolved long before centralized nervous systems. https://www.wired.com/story/sleep-evolved-before-brains-hydras-are-living-proof/

May 29, 2021 | Author: Eric BoodmanEric Boodman There’s a Great Whip Spider Boom. What Gives? The discovery of exotic arachnids reveals as much about the structure of science as it does about the creatures. https://www.wired.com/story/theres-a-great-whip-spider-boom-what-gives/

May 28, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Covid-19 Lab Leak Theory Is a Tale of Weaponized Uncertainty Scientists almost never say they’re sure, and it could take years to pin down the pandemic’s origins. Until then: People are trying to scare you. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-lab-leak-theory-weaponized-uncertainty/

May 28, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A New Vaccine Milestone in the US, Shots for India, and More Coronavirus News  Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/us-vaccine-milestone-india-shots-coronavirus-news/

May 28, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA’s MOXIE Experiment Is Making Oxygen on Mars Future crews on the Red Planet will need it to make propellant for the trip home. Scientists are also testing whether oxygen can be extracted from lunar soil. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-moxie-experiment-is-making-oxygen-on-mars/

May 28, 2021 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Space and Air Forces Launch an LGBTQ Task Force Ten years after “Don’t ask, don’t tell,” a major general from the Space Force is leading a new inclusion initiative. https://www.wired.com/story/the-space-and-air-forces-launch-an-lgbtq-task-force/

May 27, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy How Many People Die When Polluters Exceed Their Limits? A new report tallies the death toll from excess emissions by looking at air pollution and spikes in local ozone levels. https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-people-die-when-polluters-exceed-their-limits/

May 27, 2021 | Author: Brendan I. KoernerBrendan I. Koerner One Man’s Amazing Journey to the Center of the Bowling Ball Mo Pinel spent a career reshaping the ball’s inner core to harness the power of physics. He revolutionized the sport—and spared no critics along the way. https://www.wired.com/story/one-mans-amazing-journey-to-the-center-of-the-bowling-ball/

May 25, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Nature Can Save Humanity From Climate Doom—but Not On Its Own By restoring ecosystems, conservationists can help the land sequester carbon. But it’s still no substitute for drastically cutting emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/nature-can-save-humanity-from-climate-doom-but-not-on-its-own/

May 25, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna As the US Unmasks, the Pressure Is on for Vaccine Passports Now that the CDC has relaxed mask requirements, a verification system might help identify who’s vaccinated—but it’ll be a technical and political mess. https://www.wired.com/story/as-the-us-unmasks-the-pressure-is-on-for-vaccine-passports/

May 24, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison This Evolutionary Gift May Protect Coral From Climate Change Coral in the Red Sea is unusually heat tolerant. The secret to its success may lie in the lucky confluence of geography and genetics. https://www.wired.com/story/this-evolutionary-gift-may-protect-coral-from-climate-change/

May 24, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Drug Trial That Could Actually Produce Covid Treatments Some studies are too small. Some are too pharma. But a bigger, bolder approach could (finally!) figure out which drugs work against the virus—and which don’t. https://www.wired.com/story/the-drug-trial-that-could-actually-produce-covid-treatments/

May 24, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy The Long, Strange Life of the World’s Oldest Naked Mole Rat These death-defying rodents do not age normally. Will their weird biology help extend human life spans, or are those ambitions a dead end? https://www.wired.com/story/long-strange-life-worlds-oldest-naked-mole-rat/

May 23, 2021 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Climate Change Is Erasing Humanity’s Oldest Art Extreme weather is rapidly eroding the limestone caves where people first drew images 40,000 years ago. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-erasing-humanitys-oldest-art/

May 23, 2021 | Author: Steve NadisSteve Nadis A New Math Shortcut Helps Describe Black Hole Collisions The calculations work even in cases where it shouldn’t, like when the black holes are close in size. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-math-shortcut-helps-describe-black-hole-collisions/

May 22, 2021 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester Walden Pond Is Now Teeming With Jellyfish—but Don’t Panic The tiny jellies, which arrived sometime after Henry David Thoreau, are an example of how a non-native species can coexist peacefully with its new environment. https://www.wired.com/story/walden-pond-is-now-teeming-with-jellyfish-but-dont-panic/

May 21, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Vaccine Deals for Countries in Need, a Surge in Japan, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccines-countries-in-need-surge-in-japan-coronavirus-news/

May 21, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler We Hiked Along With Cicada Biologists So You Don’t Have To Researchers only get a chance to study Brood X every 17 years. WIRED came for the ride—and got up close to thousands of hatching cicadas. https://www.wired.com/story/we-hiked-along-with-cicada-biologists-so-you-dont-have-to/

May 20, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Brain-Controlled Robotic Arm Can Twist, Grasp—and Feel Nathan Copeland learned to move a robotic arm with his mind, but it was kind of slow. Then researchers gave him touch feedback. https://www.wired.com/story/this-brain-controlled-robotic-arm-can-twist-grasp-and-feel/

May 19, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Zombie-Fire Outbreak May Be Growing in the North “Overwintering” fires smolder under the snow, reigniting vegetation in the spring. New research shows the zombies may proliferate in a warmer world. https://www.wired.com/story/a-zombie-fire-outbreak-may-be-growing-in-the-north/

May 19, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Do People Actually Catch Baseballs? There’s the physics textbook way, and there’s the human way. https://www.wired.com/story/how-do-people-actually-catch-baseballs/

May 18, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Hurricane ‘Price Tags’ Could Reveal the Cost of Global Warming A new study shows that climate-driven sea level rise made the damage from Superstorm Sandy $8 billion worse around New York City. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-price-tags-could-reveal-the-cost-of-global-warming/

May 18, 2021 | Author: Marcel AgüerosMarcel Agüeros The Arecibo Observatory Was Like Family. I Couldn’t Save It I grew up in awe of the iconic telescope. It raised me, and I helped control its fate. Could I have done more to protect it before its sudden collapse? https://www.wired.com/story/arecibo-observatory-family-collapse/

May 17, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Mexico City Could Sink Up to 65 Feet Due to a phenomenon called subsidence, the metropolis’s landscape is compacting—and parts of the city are now dropping a foot and a half each year. https://www.wired.com/story/mexico-city-could-sink-up-to-65-feet/

May 16, 2021 | Author: Viviane CallierViviane Callier The Secret Role Histones Played in Complex Cell Evolution New work shows that the proteins, long treated as boring spools for DNA, are key to the origin story for eukaryotes and still play important roles in disease. https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-role-histones-played-in-complex-cell-evolution/

May 15, 2021 | Author: Robin George AndrewsRobin George Andrews Geology Students Did Video Game Fieldwork During Covid. It Rocked With travel and real-life fieldwork shut down, a couple of enterprising professors started with simulations of Italy and Scotland, then took to the stars. https://www.wired.com/story/geology-students-did-video-game-fieldwork-during-covid-it-rocked/

May 14, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider New Mask Guidance, Shots for Teens, and More Coronavirus News  Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/new-mask-guidance-shots-for-teens-coronavirus-news/

May 14, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica A New Brain Implant Translates Thoughts of Writing Into Text In early experiments, a paralyzed man with implants in his premotor cortex typed 90 characters per minute—by envisioning he was writing by hand. https://www.wired.com/story/new-brain-implant-translates-thoughts-of-writing-into-text/

May 14, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Could You Really Climb the Spinning Ship’s Cable in Stowaway? Anna Kendrick’s rotating spacecraft cleverly uses cables and a counterweight to make artificial gravity. But scaling them would be harder than it looks. https://www.wired.com/story/stowaway-anna-kendrick-spinning-ship-artificial-gravity-physics/

May 13, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Yankees Covid Outbreak May Be Bad News for Ditching Masks The spate of cases is a bad bounce—and it might show that lifting mask mandates for the vaxxed won’t be a grand slam. https://www.wired.com/story/the-yankees-covid-outbreak-may-be-bad-news-for-ditching-masks/

May 13, 2021 | Author: Ashley StimpsonAshley Stimpson Firefly Tourism Can Put Insects in Peril A new study shines light on how bug spray, flashlights, and foot traffic can spell disaster for the fragile creatures behind brilliant synchronous displays. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-shed-light-on-the-perils-of-firefly-tourism/

May 13, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The 60-Year-Old Scientific Screwup That Helped Covid Kill All pandemic long, scientists brawled over how the virus spreads. Droplets! No, aerosols! At the heart of the fight was a teensy error with huge consequences. https://www.wired.com/story/the-teeny-tiny-scientific-screwup-that-helped-covid-kill/

May 12, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Snake Robot Go for a Swim The Hardened Underwater Modular Robot Snake has thrusters for muscles and a camera for a face. Your move, evolution. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-a-snake-robot-go-for-a-swim/

May 11, 2021 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst Awesome, Hypnotic Photos of Swirling, Crystal Chemistry A new book goes micro to show the wonderful world of close-up chemical reactions. https://www.wired.com/story/awesome-hypnotic-photos-swirling-crystal-chemistry/

May 11, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Is Your Brain Under Anesthesia For the first time, researchers were able to observe, in extra-fine detail, how neurons behave as consciousness shuts down. https://www.wired.com/story/this-is-your-brain-under-anesthesia/

May 10, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber US Teens Can Get Their Covid Shot. What’s Next for Schools? Kids as young as 12 are now authorized for Pfizer’s vaccine. That could make it easier for campuses to reopen this fall—but it introduces a whole new set of decisions. https://www.wired.com/story/us-teens-can-get-their-covid-shot-whats-next-for-schools/

May 10, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain 2 Baseballs Collided at an MLB Game. How Did That Even Happen? During a pregame warmup, Phillies right fielder Bryce Harper batted a line drive right into a ball zooming in from the outfield. It’s not impossible, but it’s a long shot.  https://www.wired.com/story/2-baseballs-collided-at-an-mlb-game-how-did-that-even-happen/

May 10, 2021 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK Faulty Weather Forecasts Are a Climate Crisis Disaster Predicting the output of solar panels is tricky—but getting it right could slash carbon emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/bad-weather-forecasts-climate-crisis-disaster/

May 9, 2021 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood What If Gravity Is Actually a Double Copy of Other Forces? An enigmatic connection between the forces of nature is allowing physicists to explore the quantum side of gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/what-if-gravity-is-actually-a-double-copy-of-other-forces/

May 8, 2021 | Author: Damian CarringtonDamian Carrington What’s the Point of Wasps, Anyway? A new study says the reviled stinging insects play a critical ecological role—and their venom might even be useful to people. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-the-point-of-wasps-anyway/

May 7, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Pfizer’s FDA Request, Vaccine Diplomacy, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/pfizer-fda-request-vaccine-diplomacy-coronavirus-news/

May 7, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Bats Raised in Helium-Rich Air Reveal a Key to Echolocation To test bats’ sense of the speed of sound, researchers put them in an atmosphere that alters it. No word on whether the helium made the bats sound funny. https://www.wired.com/story/bats-raised-in-helium-rich-air-reveal-key-to-echolocation/

May 6, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Sharks Use the Earth’s Magnetic Field Like a Compass Biologists have long believed that these animals rely on magnetic sensing to migrate across oceans. Someone finally figured out how to prove it. https://www.wired.com/story/sharks-use-the-earths-magnetic-field-like-a-compass/

May 6, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Statistical Secrets of Covid-19 Vaccines They’re really very good, and they’re the only way out of the pandemic. But a tour through the numbers could bring the vaccine-hesitant into the tent. https://www.wired.com/story/the-statistical-secrets-of-covid-19-vaccines/

May 6, 2021 | Author: Yashraj SharmaYashraj Sharma Twitter Groups Offer India a Covid-19 Lifeline Hashtags have provided a kind of emergency hotline—but the need for mutual aid on social media is also a rebuke to the government. https://www.wired.com/story/twitter-groups-offer-india-a-covid-19-lifeline/

May 5, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Weird, Bouncy Cell Signals Can Help Track Wildfire Smoke A hazy atmosphere makes data ricochet all over the place. Now scientists think they can use that signal to better predict severe smoke events. https://www.wired.com/story/how-cell-signals-can-help-track-wildfire-smoke/

May 5, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna It’s Already Time to Stop the Next Pandemic. Can a Prize Help? Covid-19 is still raging, but so are efforts to nip its successor in the bud—thanks to data sharing, political cooperation, or a multimillion-dollar challenge. https://www.wired.com/story/its-already-time-to-stop-the-next-pandemic-can-a-prize-help/

May 4, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain When You Jump to Hyperspace, Make Sure You Wear a Seatbelt May the 4th be with you! If you’re hitching a ride on the Millennium Falcon today, you should know a little bit about the bumpy physics of acceleration. https://www.wired.com/story/when-you-jump-to-hyperspace-make-sure-you-wear-a-seatbelt/

May 3, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Where’s the Dark Matter? Look for Suspiciously Warm Planets Physicists calculated that these mysterious particles will betray their location with heat. To prove it, they’ll need the most powerful telescopes in the cosmos. https://www.wired.com/story/wheres-the-dark-matter-look-for-suspiciously-warm-planets/

May 3, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Not Turn Airports Into Giant Solar Farms? Airports have vast swaths of empty land and rooftops. But it’s not so easy as just covering everything with solar panels.  https://www.wired.com/story/why-not-turn-airports-into-giant-solar-farms/

May 2, 2021 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover High-Energy Cosmic Ray Sources Get Mapped Out for the First Time They twist and turn on their way to Earth, which has made it nearly impossible to identify the colossal monsters that create them. https://www.wired.com/story/high-energy-cosmic-ray-sources-get-mapped-out-for-the-first-time/

May 1, 2021 | Author: Rebecca Ann HughesRebecca Ann Hughes The Race to Save St. Mark’s Basilica From Salty Floodwaters As Venice faces a 4-foot sea level rise, the historic cathedral—and its marble—could succumb to damaging tides. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-save-st-marks-basilica-from-salty-floodwaters/

April 30, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider New Guidance for Vaccinated Americans, a Worsening Crisis in India, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/new-guidance-vaccinated-crisis-in-india-coronavirus-news/

April 30, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How One Naughty Bird Cheats With Fancy Feather Structures For male tanager birds, carotenoid feather pigments just aren’t flashy enough. They have another way to make their colors really pop. https://www.wired.com/story/how-one-naughty-bird-cheats-with-fancy-feather-structures/

April 29, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Win a Hot Wheels Derby on a Moving Treadmill Sure, you could just crank up the speed and let chance have its way. But there’s also a reason why some cars go fast and others flip over the sidewall. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-win-a-hot-wheels-derby-on-a-moving-treadmill/

April 28, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Melting Mountain Glaciers May Not Survive the Century Scientists crunched 20 years’ worth of satellite data to estimate the melt rate across the planet, and the news isn’t good. https://www.wired.com/story/melting-mountain-glaciers-may-not-survive-the-century/

April 27, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Human-Sized Origami Reimagines Emergency Shelters When flat, the structure is about the size of a twin mattress. But when it’s inflated, walls widen and a roof snaps into place. https://www.wired.com/story/this-human-sized-origami-reimagines-emergency-shelters/

April 26, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison 35 Years Later, Studies Show a Silver Lining From Chernobyl One new study found that radiation exposure didn’t genetically harm future generations, while another offers insights into how radiation causes thyroid cancer. https://www.wired.com/story/35-years-later-studies-show-a-silver-lining-from-chernobyl/

April 26, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid Lockdowns Prevented Other Infections. Is That Good? The “hygiene hypothesis” says early contact with microbes trains our immune systems. But what happens after a year of distancing? https://www.wired.com/story/covid-lockdowns-prevented-other-infections-is-that-good/

April 25, 2021 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz The Brain ‘Rotates’ Memories to Save Them From New Sensations Some groups of neurons process sensory data and memories at the same time. New work shows how the brain pivots those representations to prevent interference. https://www.wired.com/story/the-brain-rotates-memories-to-save-them-from-new-sensations/

April 24, 2021 | Author: Nicola JonesNicola Jones ‘Blue Carbon’ Credits Could Help Restore Ecosystems Seagrasses, mangrove forests, and wetlands store tons of carbon. But can a market based on regrowing them avoid the pitfalls that plague land-based programs? https://www.wired.com/story/blue-carbon-credits-could-help-restore-ecosystems/

April 23, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The CDC Reviews J&J, India Battles an Outbreak, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/cdc-reviews-jandj-india-battles-outbreak-coronavirus-news/

April 23, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Vaccine Can Be Bad for a Person but Awesome for All People The safety pause in giving the Johnson & Johnson Covid-19 vaccine is up for debate again—a battle in a Secret War of Denominators and risk-benefit philosophies. https://www.wired.com/story/a-vaccine-can-be-bad-for-a-person-but-awesome-for-all-people/

April 23, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA Launches Astronauts to the ISS on a Reused SpaceX Rocket The six-month mission is another step toward a moonshot, as SpaceX’s Elon Musk says he will land Starship on the lunar surface by 2024. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-launches-astronauts-to-the-iss-on-a-reused-spacex-rocket/

April 22, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 5 Surprising Ways to Help Save the Planet What do an electronic turtle egg, an Arctic seed bank, and carbon-eating machines have in common? They’re helping us be optimistic this Earth Day. https://www.wired.com/story/5-surprising-ways-to-help-save-the-planet/

April 22, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How the US Might Reach Biden’s New Climate Goal The president wants the country to halve its greenhouse gas emissions by 2030. Here’s what it will take to actually succeed. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-us-might-reach-bidens-new-climate-goal/

April 22, 2021 | Author: Lauryn HillLauryn Hill After Us the Deluge Captures Images of a Sinking World Kadir van Lohuizen photographed nations affected by climate change. His book documents the present, but offers a glimpse of the future. https://www.wired.com/story/after-us-the-deluge-captures-images-of-a-sinking-world/

April 21, 2021 | Author: Kasra ZareiKasra Zarei Can an App Help Change Your Personality? Want to be more sociable or less of a doormat? There’s an (experimental) app for that. https://www.wired.com/story/can-an-app-help-change-your-personality/

April 20, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Could Bad Guys Actually Escape Falcon in a Wingsuit for Two? In The Falcon and the Winter Soldier, a villain straps a hostage to his wingsuit and leaps off a plane. Cue the action—and the fun physics. https://www.wired.com/story/could-bad-guys-actually-escape-falcon-in-a-wingsuit-for-two/

April 20, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Hungry, Hungry Microbes in Tree Bark Gobble Up Methane Bad news: Trees emit methane, a greenhouse gas. Good news: Some are home to bacteria that can’t get enough of it. https://www.wired.com/story/hungry-hungry-microbes-in-tree-bark-gobble-up-methane/

April 19, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy NASA Lands Ingenuity, the First-Ever Mars Helicopter The copter safely whirled its way up and back down, demonstrating the first powered, controlled flight on another planet. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-lands-ingenuity-the-first-ever-mars-helicopter/

April 19, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Get Along With Robots? Pretend They’re Animals Robotics ethicist Kate Darling surveys our history with animals—in work, war, and companionship—to show how we might develop similar relationships with robots. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-get-along-with-robots-pretend-theyre-animals/

April 18, 2021 | Author: Kelsey Houston-EdwardsKelsey Houston-Edwards Mathematicians Settle the Erdős Coloring Conjecture Fifty years ago, three mathematicians came up with a graph theory problem that they thought they might solve on the spot. A team has finally settled it. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-settle-the-erdos-coloring-conjecture/

April 17, 2021 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester We’re Starting to See How Covid PPE Litter Affects Wildlife More than a year into the pandemic, scientists and environmentalists have the first data on where disposable gloves and masks are turning up in ecosystems. https://www.wired.com/story/were-starting-to-see-how-covid-ppe-litter-affects-wildlife/

April 16, 2021 | Author: Elena LaceyElena Lacey A Pause on J&J, Preparations for Booster Shots, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/pause-jandj-preparations-booster-shots-coronavirus-news/

April 16, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Archaeologists Unearth a ‘Lost Golden City’ in Egypt The Luxor finding has been called “the second most important archaeological discovery” since King Tut’s tomb. https://www.wired.com/story/archaeologists-unearth-lost-golden-city-in-egypt/

April 16, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison What Octopus Dreams Tell Us About the Evolution of Sleep Understanding how other animals dream could help us figure out why it’s so important to the human brain, and why it may have been preserved throughout history. https://www.wired.com/story/what-octopus-dreams-tell-us-about-the-evolution-of-sleep/

April 15, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Pausing the J&J Vaccine Was Easy. Unpausing Will Be Hard Johnson & Johnson’s Covid-19 vaccine was supposed to be the uncomplicated one. But even with new data, getting people to trust it again will be tricky. https://www.wired.com/story/pausing-the-jandj-vaccine-was-easy-unpausing-will-be-hard/

April 15, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Humble Shrub That’s Predicting a Terrible Fire Season Chamise may not look (or smell) like much, but it’s actually a kind of crystal ball for understanding how badly California might burn. https://www.wired.com/story/the-humble-shrub-thats-predicting-a-terrible-fire-season/

April 14, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Will Future Electric Vehicles Be Powered by Deep-Sea Metals? Mining companies and marine scientists want to know whether harvesting blobs of useful materials from the seafloor harms ocean life. https://www.wired.com/story/will-future-electric-vehicles-be-powered-by-deep-sea-metals/

April 14, 2021 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst Did This Scorching-Hot Planet Lose—and Regain—an Atmosphere? A veritable hellscape of an exoplanet is challenging researchers’ assumptions about what types of worlds host atmospheres. https://www.wired.com/story/did-this-scorching-hot-planet-lose-and-regain-an-atmosphere/

April 13, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Many Homes Could You Power With Free Doughnuts? Krispy Kreme is offering a year of treats to anyone who gets the Covid-19 vaccine. What if they worked off the energy on pedal-powered bike generators? https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-homes-could-you-power-with-free-doughnuts/

April 13, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Plastic Is Falling From the Sky. But Where’s It Coming From? At any given time, 1,100 tons of microplastic are floating over the western US. New modeling shows the surprising sources of the nefarious pollutant. https://www.wired.com/story/plastic-is-falling-from-the-sky/

April 12, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison This AI Could Help Wipe Out Colon Cancer Medtronic’s GI Genius, recently cleared by the FDA, will help doctors identify precancerous polyps.  https://www.wired.com/story/ai-help-wipe-out-colon-cancer/

April 12, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Clare BallJennifer Clare Ball Pandemic Lockdowns Did Cut Air Pollution—but With a Catch Studies from all over the globe show short-term improvements in urban air quality, but experts are skeptical about how long they’ll last. https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-lockdowns-did-cut-air-pollution-but-with-a-catch/

April 11, 2021 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover A ‘Last Hope’ Experiment Finds Evidence for Unknown Particles Long-awaited news from Fermilab’s Muon g-2 team may resolve a tantalizing conflict between nature and theory. But a separate calculation clouds the picture. https://www.wired.com/story/a-last-hope-experiment-finds-evidence-for-unknown-particles/

April 10, 2021 | Author: Beth GardinerBeth Gardiner In Europe, Backlash Heats Up Over Garbage Incinerators Trash-burning facilities once seemed like a useful way to minimize pollution and generate power. But the EU is withdrawing support over emissions concerns. https://www.wired.com/story/in-europe-backlash-heats-up-over-garbage-incinerators/

April 9, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Tracking Variants, New Hot Spots, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/tracking-variants-new-hot-spots-coronavirus-news/

April 9, 2021 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica The High-Powered Thrusters Behind NASA’s Mission to Psyche Hall thrusters have been used in satellites for years. Now, they’ll play a crucial role in reaching a metallic asteroid called Psyche. https://www.wired.com/story/high-powered-thrusters-behind-nasas-mission-psyche/

April 9, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Variant Hunters Race to Find New Strains Where Testing Lags In countries without much sequencing, new versions of the Covid virus can go unnoticed. Scientists across Africa are collaborating to track them down. https://www.wired.com/story/variant-hunters-race-to-find-new-strains-where-testing-lags/

April 8, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy This Sticker Absorbs Sweat—and Might Diagnose Cystic Fibrosis The device may make it easier to quickly test newborns and could open the door to at-home monitoring. https://www.wired.com/story/this-sticker-absorbs-sweat-and-might-diagnose-cystic-fibrosis/

April 7, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Strong Is King Kong? And Could He Even Stand Up? In physics, big things are not like small things. Here’s what that means for a giant gorilla. https://www.wired.com/story/how-strong-is-king-kong-could-he-stand-up/

April 7, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon More Lightning in the Arctic Is Bad News for the Planet Lightning strikes in the far north could double by 2100. That means more wildfires, which could release massive amounts of planet-warming gas. https://www.wired.com/story/more-lightning-in-the-arctic-is-bad-news-for-the-planet/

April 6, 2021 | Author: Jesse KleinJesse Klein Reforestation Is Great! But We’re Running Out of Seeds Planting trees is a popular solution to carbon emissions. But where will all those seedlings come from? https://www.wired.com/story/reforestation-is-great-but-were-running-out-of-seeds/

April 5, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Sneaky New Bacteria on the ISS Could Build a Future on Mars NASA tracks the microbes that live on the space station, and sometimes it discovers new ones. Those hardy bugs may offer clues about surviving long missions. https://www.wired.com/story/sneaky-new-bacteria-on-the-iss-could-build-a-future-on-mars/

April 4, 2021 | Author: Doug Johnson, Ars TechnicaDoug Johnson, Ars Technica The Dinosaur-Killing Asteroid Birthed Today’s Rainforests Plant fossils from Colombia reveal the forests of the Cretaceous period were sparser and less humid than their modern-day counterparts. https://www.wired.com/story/the-dino-killing-asteroid-birthed-todays-rainforests/

April 4, 2021 | Author: Philip BallPhilip Ball Cells Form Into Living ‘Xenobots’ on Their Own Embryonic cells can self-assemble into new forms that don’t resemble the bodies they usually generate, challenging old ideas of what defines an organism. https://www.wired.com/story/cells-form-into-living-xenobots-on-their-own/

April 3, 2021 | Author: Ysabelle KempeYsabelle Kempe The US Is Finally Trying to Unlock the Power of Wave Energy After decades of false starts, the federal approval of a new testing site off the coast of Oregon could give the technology a much-needed jolt. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-is-finally-trying-to-unlock-the-power-of-wave-energy/

April 2, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider New Travel Guidelines, Real-World Vaccine Efficacy, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/new-travel-guidelines-real-world-vaccine-efficacy-coronavirus-news/

April 2, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain So Can Flash Actually Run Faster Than the Speed of Light? In Justice League he runs so fast that he goes back in time. But it wouldn’t be quite so easy in real life (unless he was a tachyon). https://www.wired.com/story/can-flash-actually-run-faster-than-speed-of-light/

April 2, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid-19 Vaccine Passports Are Coming. What Will That Mean? Scores of plans to verify immunity are in the works. But there are even more questions about how they’ll use data, protect privacy—and who gets certified first. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-vaccine-passports-are-coming-what-will-that-mean/

April 1, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Biden Wants $10 Billion for a Climate Army. It’s Not Enough The Civilian Climate Corps would put people to work preparing the nation for hotter heat waves and fiercer storms. They’ll need a lot more money to succeed. https://www.wired.com/story/biden-wants-a-civilian-climate-corps/

April 1, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Narwhal Tusks Tell a Troubling Tale An analysis of the 10-foot-long teeth shows that as the Arctic warms, narwhal diets are changing, and their bodies are accumulating more mercury. https://www.wired.com/story/narwhal-tusks-tell-a-troubling-tale/

April 1, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Larry Brilliant Has a Plan to Speed Up the Pandemic’s End We’ll never get herd immunity, but with speedy, deft combat against new infections, the epidemiologist says we could get back to normalish life. https://www.wired.com/story/larry-brilliant-herd-immunity-end-of-pandemic/

March 31, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Physicists Learn to Superfreeze Antimatter (Hint: Pew Pew!) Antimatter, the mysterious mirror-stuff of the universe, is hard to make and harder to study. A laser that literally chills it out could change all that. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-learn-to-superfreeze-antimatter-hint-pew-pew/

March 31, 2021 | Author: Keith GilloglyKeith Gillogly How Cargo Ships Could Help Detect Tsunamis By using GPS data to monitor slight changes in elevation, the world’s fleet of commercial vessels could aid in forecasting incoming waves. https://www.wired.com/story/how-cargo-ships-could-help-detect-tsunamis/

March 30, 2021 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK The Weird Science of Loneliness and Our Brains Social isolation has been linked to poorer physical and mental health, but scientists are finally starting to understand its neurological impact.  https://www.wired.com/story/weird-science-of-loneliness-brains/

March 30, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Robot Could Help Fulfill Your Online Shopping Sprees Ambi Robotics is using years of research in robot manipulation to teach machines how to get a grip. The secret? Giving them suction cups for fingers. https://www.wired.com/story/this-robot-could-help-fulfill-your-online-shopping-sprees/

March 29, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler It’s Finally Time to Take Out the Space Trash Junk satellites can pose risks to other objects in Earth’s orbit. Startups are testing out ways to tidy up, from magnets to robotic tentacles. https://www.wired.com/story/its-finally-time-to-take-out-the-space-trash/

March 29, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Boston Dynamics’ New Robot Doesn’t Dance. It Has a Warehouse Job Called Stretch, the machine may look wildly different than its famous cousins Spot and Atlas, but it shares a ton of their DNA. https://www.wired.com/story/boston-dynamics-new-robot-has-a-warehouse-job/

March 28, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of That Spinning Hug in Dua Lipa’s Music Video The dance move seems to defy gravity—but it actually involves Newton’s second law, equilibrium, and a fake force. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-spinning-hug-dua-lipas-music-video/

March 28, 2021 | Author: Howard LeeHoward Lee Ancient Rocks Reveal When Earth’s Plate Tectonics Began New data indicating that the planet’s surface broke up about 3.2 billion years ago helps clarify how shifting plates drove the evolution of complex life. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-rocks-reveal-when-earths-plate-tectonics-began/

March 27, 2021 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester The Feds Want You to Destroy This Sneaky Mussel’s Hiding Spot Moss balls sold for aquariums can hide Zebra mussels, invasive mollusks that quickly overtake waterways. The US government would like you to kill them, please. https://www.wired.com/story/the-feds-want-you-to-destroy-this-sneaky-mussels-hiding-spot/

March 26, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A New Vaccination Goal, a Hasty Return to ‘Normal,’ and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/new-vaccination-goal-hasty-return-to-normal-coronavirus-news/

March 26, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica A New Snapshot of a Black Hole Reveals Its Mysterious Physics The Event Horizon Telescope’s groundbreaking image provides clues into how the cosmic phenomena gobble up matter. https://www.wired.com/story/new-snapshot-of-black-hole-reveals-its-mysterious-physics/

March 26, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Free the Ever Given—Using Buoyancy Force! Sure, you could dig the massive ship out from the Suez Canal. Or you could calculate how many containers you’d have to remove to make it light enough to float again. https://www.wired.com/story/how-free-ever-given-using-buoyancy-force/

March 26, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Ionizer in Your School May Not Do Much to Fight Covid Manufacturers say the devices remove 99 percent of viruses. Researchers say such claims are unproven, and cheaper air filters are more effective. https://www.wired.com/story/ionizer-school-not-fight-covid/

March 25, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Scientists Finally Identify a Deadly Toxin That’s Been Killing Birds Thousands of eagles and other fowl have died from a mysterious condition that attacks their nervous systems. Now, after decades of investigation, we know why. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-finally-identify-a-deadly-toxin-thats-been-killing-birds/

March 25, 2021 | Author: Seema YasminSeema Yasmin A Boy, His Brain, and a Decades-Long Medical Controversy No one could deny that Timothy was sick. But when doctors can’t agree on the cause of an illness, what happens to the patients trapped in limbo? https://www.wired.com/story/a-boy-his-brain-and-a-decades-long-medical-controversy/

March 24, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Kill a Zombie Fire Underground peat fires refuse to die, even when flooded with water. So scientists developed a new weapon to put them down for good. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-kill-a-zombie-fire/

March 23, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Even Mild Brain Injuries Raise the Risk of Dementia A new study shows that concussions and other head traumas can have long-lasting effects on our health. https://www.wired.com/story/even-mild-brain-injuries-raise-the-risk-of-dementia/

March 22, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid Spilled From Animals to Humans. Now It’s Spilling Back Bats likely gave it to a mystery animal that then gave it to people. We passed it on to minks. Where does it go from there—and could it come back to us? https://www.wired.com/story/covid-spilled-from-animals-to-humans-now-its-spilling-back/

March 21, 2021 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Quantum Mischief Rewrites the Laws of Cause and Effect Spurred on by experiments that scramble the ordering of causes and their effects, some physicists are figuring out how to abandon causality altogether. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-mischief-rewrites-the-laws-of-cause-and-effect/

March 20, 2021 | Author: Gemma TarlachGemma Tarlach Fossils in a Forgotten Ice Core Rewrite Greenland’s Icy Past A secret Cold War project led to signs of ancient life—and a new warning about the future of the climate. https://www.wired.com/story/fossils-in-a-forgotten-ice-core-rewrite-greenlands-icy-past/

March 19, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider 100 Million Vaccines, New School Guidelines, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/100-million-vaccines-new-school-guidelines-coronavirus-news/

March 19, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica How Food Waste Could Be Turned Into Climate-Friendly Jet Fuel Humans dump an estimated 10 billion gallons of potential biofuel into landfills every year. Researchers found a way to capitalize on it. https://www.wired.com/story/could-food-waste-be-a-climate-friendly-source-of-jet-fuel/

March 19, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Covering Canals With Solar Panels Is a Power Move Covering waterways would, in a sense, make solar panels water-cooled, boosting their efficiency. https://www.wired.com/story/why-covering-canals-with-solar-panels-is-a-power-move/

March 18, 2021 | Author: Scott K. Johnson, Ars TechnicaScott K. Johnson, Ars Technica Satellites Can Help Detect When a Volcano’s About to Blow Researchers used thermal radiation data to find patterns in recent eruptions—providing another metric to help get ahead of a potentially deadly blast. https://www.wired.com/story/satellites-can-help-detect-when-volcanos-about-to-blow/

March 18, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Bill Gates Is Upbeat on Climate, Capitalism, and Even Politics The technologist and philanthropist goes beyond his recent book to talk about climate denial, vaccines, and David Foster Wallace. https://www.wired.com/story/bill-gates-is-upbeat-on-climate-capitalism-and-even-politics/

March 17, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon People Who Text While Walking Actually Do Ruin Everything Clever experiments demonstrate how having your face in your phone disrupts the flow of pedestrian traffic and makes life difficult for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/people-who-text-while-walking-actually-do-ruin-everything/

March 17, 2021 | Author: Karmela Padavic-CallaghanKarmela Padavic-Callaghan An Ultracold Plasma Models the Universe’s Most Extreme Places The super cool, dense particle swarm gives physicists a way to study the insides of stars—without ever leaving the lab. https://www.wired.com/story/an-ultracold-plasma-models-the-universes-most-extreme-places/

March 17, 2021 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis The Struggle to Vaccinate People in Jails and Prisons One year later, Covid-19 is still hitting incarcerated people at a disproportionate rate. But efforts are under way to prioritize them for vaccines. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-prisons-vaccines/

March 16, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Covid-19 Meant a Year Without the Flu. That’s Not All Good News The 2020–2021 flu season basically didn’t happen. Same for a couple other respiratory viruses. But that could make future seasons worse. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-meant-a-year-without-the-flu-thats-not-all-good-news/

March 15, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Shape-Shifting Robot Prowl the Big, Bad World Meet DyRET, a doglike machine that can lengthen its four legs on the fly. That’s not to creep out humans, but to help ramblin’ robots of all stripes. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-a-shape-shifting-robot-prowl-the-big-bad-world/

March 15, 2021 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright NASA Gets a Quick Peek at a Mysterious Layer of the Sun A new map of the chromosphere’s magnetic field could help us predict solar weather patterns—and anticipate flares that wreak havoc on the power grid. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-gets-a-quick-peek-at-a-mysterious-layer-of-the-sun/

March 14, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Pi Keeps Train Wheels on Track Happy 3/14! Here’s how this mathematical constant keeps train cars from flying off their tracks during turns. https://www.wired.com/story/how-pi-keeps-train-wheels-on-track/

March 14, 2021 | Author: Jonathan O’CallaghanJonathan O’Callaghan New Kind of Space Explosion Reveals the Birth of a Black Hole A supernova-like explosion dubbed the Camel appears to be the result of a newborn black hole eating a star from the inside out. https://www.wired.com/story/new-kind-of-space-explosion-reveals-the-birth-of-a-black-hole/

March 13, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Indoor-Grown Weed Is Spewing Carbon Into the Atmosphere Most legal marijuana is grown in a controlled environment. A study just quantified how much damage that’s doing to the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/cannabis-enormous-carbon-emissions/

March 13, 2021 | Author: Elizabeth KolbertElizabeth Kolbert How Far Should Humans Go to Help Species Adapt? A project to teach threatened marsupials to avoid feral cats is among a host of “assisted evolution” efforts to help animals in the face of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/how-far-should-humans-go-to-help-species-adapt/

March 12, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The Pandemic Turns One, Vaccine Trials Adapt, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-turns-one-vaccine-trials-adapt-coronavirus-news/

March 12, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Ocean Acidification Could Make Tiny Fish Lose Their Hearing Their inner ears turn wonky when they grow up in carbon-rich water, which could keep juveniles from finding their way to the reefs. That could mean trouble. https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-acidification-could-make-tiny-fish-lose-their-hearing/

March 12, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Perplexing Psychology of Returning to ‘Normal’ For a year now, we’ve been living in constant fear of Covid-19. But when you get that vaccine in your arm, it’s not like your stress will magically melt away. https://www.wired.com/story/the-perplexing-psychology-of-returning-to-normal/

March 11, 2021 | Author: Stephen S. HallStephen S. Hall A Genetic Curse, a Scared Mom, and the Quest to ‘Fix’ Embryos Danielle Messer carried a mitochondrial mutation that left her son severely disabled. Before even daring another pregnancy, she tracked down an “egg specialist.” https://www.wired.com/story/genetic-disease-quest-fix-embryo-dna/

March 11, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Offshore Energy Gets a Second Wind Under Biden New turbines proposed for a development off Cape Cod could provide green energy, but the science of how they might affect the environment is a bit murky. https://www.wired.com/story/offshore-energy-gets-a-second-wind-under-biden/

March 11, 2021 | Author: Jared WhitlockJared Whitlock The US Has 3 Covid Vaccines—Testing New Ones Is Complicated Now that authorized versions are available, it’s tough to recruit volunteers for trials that might give them a placebo. But there are other options. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-has-3-covid-vaccines-testing-new-ones-is-complicated/

March 10, 2021 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica SpaceX Is Going All In on Its South Texas Starport New documents show the company has grand plans for its Boca Chica launch site, providing more evidence that Elon Musk is bullish on SpaceX’s future there. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-reveals-texas-starport-plans/

March 10, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Fingertip for Robots Uses Magnets to ‘Feel’ Things By sensing the subtle changes in the finger’s own magnetic field, this new technology could one day make for ultra-sensitive prosthetic hands. https://www.wired.com/story/this-fingertip-for-robots-uses-magnets-to-feel-things/

March 9, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Code Breaker Is the Crispr Chronicle You Need to Read Walter Isaacson’s account, out Tuesday, is a thrilling tale of scientific discovery. He talks about gene-editing tech—and the future of the human race. https://www.wired.com/story/the-code-breaker-is-the-crispr-chronicle-you-need-to-read/

March 9, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Pandemic Can’t End While Wealthy Nations Hoard Shots Eliminating Covid globally means navigating a minefield of competition, limited supply, and suspicion that some vaccines aren’t as good. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-cant-end-while-wealthy-nations-hoard-shots/

March 8, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Hey, So These Sea Slugs Decapitate Themselves and Grow New Bodies Showing off their best impressions of Deadpool, the animals survived for weeks without organs, only to regrow everything and go about their business. https://www.wired.com/story/sea-slugs-decapitate-themselves-and-grow-new-bodies/

March 8, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Figure Out the Mass of Earth—With Balls and String It involves calculating some very, very tiny numbers in order to find some super huge big ones. https://www.wired.com/story/how-figure-out-mass-earth-balls-string/

March 8, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Tide Is High—and Getting Higher A trove of historic records show that dredging and sea level rise are making nuisance high tides worse along the US coasts. https://www.wired.com/story/the-tide-is-high-and-getting-higher/

March 7, 2021 | Author: Victoria Turk, WIRED UKVictoria Turk, WIRED UK Microdosing’s Feel-Good Benefits Might Just Be Placebo Effect A study found no significant difference in the well-being of participants who thought they were taking mini hits of psychedelics and those who actually were. https://www.wired.com/story/microdosing-might-be-a-placebo/

March 7, 2021 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Imaginary Numbers May Be Essential for Describing Reality A new thought experiment indicates that quantum mechanics doesn’t work without strange numbers that turn negative when squared. https://www.wired.com/story/imaginary-numbers-may-be-essential-for-describing-reality/

March 6, 2021 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica The ‘Lamborghini’ of Chariots Was Just Unearthed Near Pompeii Most of the vehicles uncovered so far have been akin to modern-day station wagons. This one’s a straight-up sports car. https://www.wired.com/story/archaeologists-discover-lamborghini-chariots-near-pompeii/

March 6, 2021 | Author: Ramin SkibbaRamin Skibba The Biden Administration Weighs the Social Cost of Carbon A new White House policy tries to put a dollar value on the future harm of greenhouse gas emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/the-biden-administration-weighs-the-social-cost-of-carbon/

March 5, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The US Has a Covid ‘Scariants’ Problem. Here’s How to Fix It Researchers are racing to understand new versions of the coronavirus. But without scientific standards, too many mutants are getting the monster treatment. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-has-a-covid-scariants-problem-heres-how-to-fix-it/

March 5, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Johnson & Johnson Shots Administered, States Reopen Prematurely, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/johnson-and-johnson-shots-states-reopen-coronavirus-news/

March 5, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers ‘We’re Vaccinated. Everyone Wants to Visit. Now What?’ My mom and stepdad got their two doses. They want to know why their New Normal isn’t normal at all. https://www.wired.com/story/were-vaccinated-everyone-wants-to-visit-now-what/

March 4, 2021 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst Can Alien Smog Lead Us to Extraterrestrial Civilizations? A new study modeled whether we could find intelligent life on another planet—by looking for its pollution. https://www.wired.com/story/can-alien-smog-lead-us-to-extraterrestrial-civilizations/

March 4, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Secret Behind North Dakota’s Speedy Vaccine Rollout The state’s independent rural drugstores are showing the power of small. https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-behind-north-dakotas-speedy-vaccine-rollout/

March 3, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Far Away From Perseverance Did the Descent Stage Land? The rocket lowered the rover onto the surface of Mars before it shot away from the landing site. So where did it end up? https://www.wired.com/story/how-far-away-from-perseverance-did-descent-stage-land/

March 3, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy If You Transplant a Human Head, Does Its Consciousness Follow? In her new book, Brandy Schillace recalls the unbelievable legacy of a Cold War era neurosurgeon’s mission to preserve the soul. https://www.wired.com/story/if-you-transplant-human-head-does-consciousness-follow/

March 3, 2021 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Anthony Fauci Pleads: Don’t Declare Victory The Covidologist-in-chief says we can’t relax on masks and social distancing yet. Hear that, Texas? https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-fauci-pleads-dont-declare-victory/

March 2, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Sleuths Read Old Booby-Trapped Letters Without Opening Them People once folded their correspondence in intricate ways, known as “letterlocking,” to keep out snoops. A fancy new imaging technique sees right through it. https://www.wired.com/story/sleuths-read-old-booby-trapped-letters-without-opening-them/

March 2, 2021 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica How Elon Musk Convinced Gwynne Shotwell to Join SpaceX Ultimately, their management styles were similar: Don’t talk about doing things, just do things.  https://www.wired.com/story/how-elon-musk-gwynne-shotwell-join-spacex/

March 2, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can Technology Open Spaceflight to Disabled Astronauts? The European Space Agency wants to make sure its new astronaut class is more diverse. But it will take redesigned gear to make space accessible to everybody. https://www.wired.com/story/can-technology-open-spaceflight-to-disabled-astronauts/

March 1, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Raging Evolutionary War Between Humans and Covid-19 Fighting the pandemic isn’t only about vaccines and drugs. It’s about understanding how viruses mutate and change inside us, and among us. https://www.wired.com/story/the-raging-evolutionary-war-between-humans-and-covid-19/

February 28, 2021 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover A Decades-Long Quest Reveals New Details of Antimatter Twenty years ago, physicists began investigating a mysterious asymmetry inside the proton. Their results show how antimatter helps stabilize every atom’s core. https://www.wired.com/story/a-decades-long-quest-reveals-new-details-of-antimatter/

February 27, 2021 | Author: Lou Del BelloLou Del Bello Border Disputes Threaten Climate Science in the Himalayas Cross-border teams of scientists need to collaborate on climate models, even as their countries’ militaries clash. https://www.wired.com/story/border-disputes-threaten-climate-science-in-the-himalayas/

February 26, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The Johnson & Johnson Shot Nears Approval, Experts Study Transmission, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/shot-approval-transmission-coronavirus-news/

February 26, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison This Is What It’s Like to Live Without Smell Losing any sense can be devastating, even if you never appreciated it before it was gone. https://www.wired.com/story/this-is-what-its-like-to-live-without-smell/

February 26, 2021 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Could Fruit Flies Help Match Patients With Cancer Treatments? A British company is seeding genetically modified flies with human tumors, giving patients their own personal drug trials. https://www.wired.com/story/could-fruit-flies-help-match-patients-with-cancer-treatments/

February 25, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni We Still Don’t Know How Well Covid Vaccines Stop Transmission Two new studies are being hailed as proof that vaccinated people can doff masks and pod-hop worry-free. But not so fast. https://www.wired.com/story/we-still-dont-know-how-well-covid-vaccines-stop-transmission/

February 25, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Texas’ Icy Disaster Makes the Case for Uniting the US Grid The national grid is split into sections that can’t share much power. Connecting them won’t be cheap or easy, but it will help usher in the future of energy. https://www.wired.com/story/texas-disaster-makes-the-case-for-uniting-the-grid/

February 24, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Twinkling Black Holes Reveal an Invisible Cloud in Our Galaxy Cosmic radio backlights are helping scientists size up “missing” forms of matter and might offer clues about what makes up the universe. https://www.wired.com/story/twinkling-black-holes-reveal-an-invisible-cloud-in-our-galaxy/

February 24, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber When the Grid Goes Down, Can a Fleet of Batteries Replace It? In a power crisis, maybe the solution is a network of smaller energy sources distributed across multiple places—like your garage. https://www.wired.com/story/when-the-grid-goes-down-can-a-fleet-of-batteries-replace-it/

February 23, 2021 | Author: Jim MorrisonJim Morrison What a 1900s Wildlife Survey Reveals About Climate Change A century ago, a biologist counted California’s desert animals. Now researchers are retracing his steps—and the results are surprising. https://www.wired.com/story/what-a-1900s-wildlife-survey-reveals-about-climate-change/

February 23, 2021 | Author: Erika HayasakiErika Hayasaki How to Remember a Disaster Without Being Shattered by It Margaret McKinnon survived a midair catastrophe, then became a major researcher of memory and trauma. Now she’s studying how the pandemic will haunt us. https://www.wired.com/story/remember-disaster-without-being-shattered-ptsd-covid/

February 23, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Perseverance’s Eyes See a Different Mars The Red Planet’s red looks different to an Earthling than it would to a Martian—or to a robot with hyperspectral cameras for eyes. https://www.wired.com/story/perseverances-eyes-see-a-different-mars/

February 22, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Mantis Shrimp Inspires a New Material—Made by Bacteria By 3D-printing scaffolds and dipping them in microbe juice, scientists make robust structures that could one day lead to self-growing roads.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-mantis-shrimp-inspires-a-new-material-made-by-bacteria/

February 22, 2021 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman Great News, America: Cheese Isn’t Bad for You Don’t feel sheepish reaching for that manchego. Cheese doesn’t deserve its unhealthy reputation. https://www.wired.com/story/cheese-actually-isnt-bad-for-you/

February 22, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Pandemic Will End—but Covid-19 May Be Here to Stay Some viruses became endemic over time, circulating constantly, perhaps in a less lethal form. We’ll need a new game plan if this one sticks around. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-will-end-but-covid-19-may-be-here-to-stay/

February 21, 2021 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Million-Year-Old DNA Rewrites Mammoths’ Evolutionary Tree  The oldest DNA ever sequenced shows how the genus split off into new species. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-dna-mammoth-evolutionary-tree/

February 21, 2021 | Author: Elizabeth LandauElizabeth Landau The Brain’s ‘Background Noise’ May Be Meaningful After All By digging out signals hidden within the brain’s electrical chatter, scientists are getting new insights into sleep, aging, and more. https://www.wired.com/story/the-brains-background-noise-may-be-meaningful-after-all/

February 20, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Can Hamburger Buns Save Your Pipes from Freezing? Water expands when it freezes, and that’s bad for plumbing. Insulation—any insulation—is better than nothing. https://www.wired.com/story/can-hamburger-buns-save-your-pipes-from-freezing/

February 20, 2021 | Author: Maddie StoneMaddie Stone Why France’s New Tech ‘Repairability Index’ Is a Big Deal Liberté, égalité, reparabilité. https://www.wired.com/story/frances-new-tech-repairability-index-is-a-big-deal/

February 19, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Storm Delays for Vaccines, Expanded Virus Sequencing, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/storm-delays-vaccines-virus-sequencing-coronavirus-news/

February 19, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni As Coronavirus Variants Spread, the US Struggles to Keep Up The nation is a sequencing superpower. But without a federal strategy or enough funding, scientists can’t coordinate to track an evolving threat fast enough. https://www.wired.com/story/as-coronavirus-variants-spread-the-us-struggles-to-keep-up/

February 19, 2021 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight The AI Research Paper Was Real. The ‘Coauthor’ Wasn’t An IBM researcher found his name on two papers with which he had no connection. A different paper listed a fictitious author by the name of “Bill Franks.” https://www.wired.com/story/ai-research-paper-real-coauthor-not/

February 18, 2021 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles NASA Lands the Perseverance Rover on Mars The science mission will launch the first drone to fly on another planet, attempt making oxygen in space, and search for signs of ancient life. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-lands-the-perseverance-rover-on-mars/

February 18, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy How to Watch NASA’s Perseverance Mars Rover Landing NASA’s biggest and boldest rover attempts a momentous landing on February 18. Here’s how to watch—and why you should. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-nasas-perseverance-mars-rover-landing/

February 18, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Birders’ Tweets Are Causing an Online Flap Sharing photos and location details of rare bird sightings is boosting the birdwatching community. But some worry that the exposure threatens the animals. https://www.wired.com/story/birders-tweets-are-causing-an-online-flap/

February 17, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Researchers Are Studying These Worm Blobs to Build Robots These crawlers form clumps to protect the collective. Understanding their movement gives engineers a model for shape-shifting robot swarms. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-are-studying-these-worm-blobs-to-build-robots/

February 17, 2021 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The LA Musician Who Helped Design a Microphone for Mars How an obsession with space led to a partnership on the Perseverance rover—and the chance we could finally hear what our planetary neighbor sounds like. https://www.wired.com/story/musician-who-designed-microphone-mars/

February 16, 2021 | Author: Keith GilloglyKeith Gillogly Nature Makes Wood. Could a Lab Make It Better? For millennia, humans have been chopping down trees and harvesting plants. Lab-grown plant material might change that. https://www.wired.com/story/nature-makes-wood-could-a-lab-make-it-better/

February 15, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Calculate the String Angle of a Kite vs. a Balloon It’s a beautiful day to go outside with a kite or a balloon, and compute how wind speed alters their flight. https://www.wired.com/story/how-calculate-string-angle-kite-vs-balloon/

February 15, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Scientists Accidentally Discover Strange Creatures Under a Half Mile of Ice Researchers only drilled through an Antarctic ice shelf to sample sediment. Instead, they found animals that weren’t supposed to be there. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-discover-strange-creatures-under-a-half-mile-of-ice/

February 14, 2021 | Author: Timothy B. Lee, Ars TechnicaTimothy B. Lee, Ars Technica What Happens When You Swap a Human Gene With a Neanderthal’s? Now that we’ve gotten a look at the genomes of archaic humans, researchers are trying to determine whether our differences are due to genetics.  https://www.wired.com/story/replace-human-genes-neanderthals/

February 14, 2021 | Author: Jonathan O’CallaghanJonathan O’Callaghan Don’t Tell Einstein, but Black Holes Might Have ‘Hair’ The general theory of relativity states that black holes have only three observable properties; additional ones, or “hair,” do not exist. Or do they? https://www.wired.com/story/dont-tell-einstein-but-black-holes-might-have-hair/

February 13, 2021 | Author: Hannah Thomasy Hannah Thomasy Scientists Can Literally Become Allergic to Their Research Researchers spend long periods of time around the organisms they study. Sometimes, that exposure has unintended—and potentially deadly—effects. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-can-literally-become-allergic-to-their-research/

February 13, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni We Need a Global Outbreak Investigation Team—Now The WHO’s fact-finding mission into the origins of Covid-19 was limited and late. But there are models to help prepare for the next crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-a-global-outbreak-investigation-team-now/

February 12, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Researchers Levitated a Small Tray Using Nothing but Light One day a “magic carpet” based on this light-induced flow technology could carry climate sensors high in the atmosphere—wind permitting. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-levitated-a-small-tray-using-nothing-but-light/

February 12, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Vaccine Progress, New Mask Guidelines, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-progress-new-mask-guidelines-coronavirus-news/

February 11, 2021 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins As More Women Enter Science, It’s Time to Redefine Mentorship In STEM fields, female students often can’t find an adviser who looks like them. It’s important to talk about what they need from a mentor. https://www.wired.com/story/as-more-women-enter-science-its-time-to-redefine-mentorship/

February 11, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA Wants to Set a New Radiation Limit for Astronauts As the agency considers sending people to the moon and Mars, it’s taking a fresh look at the research on cancer risk and recalculating acceptable thresholds. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-wants-to-set-a-new-radiation-limit-for-astronauts/

February 11, 2021 | Author: Eva HollandEva Holland Premature Babies and the Lonely Terror of a Pandemic NICU Baby Olivia weighed 1 pound, 10 ounces. Her doctors faced a stressful paradox: giving her the healing power of a parent’s touch, while keeping the virus out. https://www.wired.com/story/preterm-babies-lonely-terror-of-a-pandemic-nicu/

February 10, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Listen to an 18,000-Year-Old Instrument Sing Once More Long, long ago, a human modified a conch shell to belt out a tune. Here’s how scientists resurrected its triumphant sound. https://www.wired.com/story/listen-to-an-18000-year-old-instrument-sing-once-more/

February 9, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How This Teeny-Tiny Sea Critter Punches Like Mike Tyson Using a camera shooting 300,000 frames per second, researchers catch the amphipod snapping its extraordinarily powerful claw. https://www.wired.com/story/teeny-tiny-sea-critter-punches-like-mike-tyson/

February 8, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Did They Find the Secret Space Lab in Captain Marvel? They talk about something called state vectors. What the heck are those, and would it really work? https://www.wired.com/story/how-find-secret-space-lab-captain-marvel/

February 8, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy Forget Blood—Your Skin Might Know If You’re Sick This glowing microneedle test could catalyze a transition from blood-based diagnostics to a stick-on patch. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-blood-your-skin-might-know-if-youre-sick/

February 8, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers All These Mutant Virus Strains Need New Code Names As potentially more dangerous variants of Covid-19 spread, scientists are taking a crack at giving them clearer names that’ll help in the fight. https://www.wired.com/story/all-these-mutant-virus-strains-need-new-code-names/

February 7, 2021 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover What Dust From Space Tells Us About Ourselves Micrometeorites fill every corner of our planet. Matthew Genge is using these shards of interplanetary space to understand Earth and its place in the solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/what-dust-from-space-tells-us-about-ourselves/

February 6, 2021 | Author: Maria GallucciMaria Gallucci How Steel Might Finally Kick Its Coal Habit In order to curb the industry’s prolific carbon emissions, the sector will have to transform how the material is traditionally made. https://www.wired.com/story/how-steel-might-finally-kick-its-coal-habit/

February 5, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A New Vaccine, Protection Against Strains, and More Coronavirus News  Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/new-vaccine-protection-against-strains-coronavirus-news/

February 5, 2021 | Author: Lauryn HillLauryn Hill Stunning Images of Starlings in Flight For this Danish photographer, documenting the birds’ migration through the autumn dusk takes patience—and a fast shutter speed. https://www.wired.com/story/stunning-images-of-starlings-in-flight/

February 5, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber More Covid Vaccine Choices Mean New Equity Challenges Johnson & Johnson’s vaccine can be delivered in a single dose, but it’s also slightly less effective. Who should get it? https://www.wired.com/story/more-covid-vaccine-choices-mean-new-equity-challenges/

February 4, 2021 | Author: Tom VanderbiltTom Vanderbilt Here’s What Learning to Juggle Does to Your Brain First of all, you have to stop thinking and kind of become a robot. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-what-learning-juggle-does-your-brain/

February 4, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison How to Make a Fitbit for an Elephant The accelerometers give scientists information about whether animals are swimming, walking, running, or even sprinting up a hill. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-make-a-fitbit-for-an-elephant/

February 4, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon So, Jeff Bezos, You Really Want to Fix the Planet? Amazon’s founder is stepping down to focus on other projects, like the Bezos Earth Fund. Here’s what he can do to help fix the mess humans have made of the world. https://www.wired.com/story/so-jeff-bezos-you-really-want-to-fix-the-planet/

February 3, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Will it Take to Make Covid-19 Vaccines Variant-Proof? As emerging mutations threaten the progress made against the pandemic, scientists and regulators are racing to figure out a process for updating shots. https://www.wired.com/story/what-will-it-take-to-make-covid-19-vaccines-variant-proof/

February 3, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers It’s Time for a National Pandemic Prediction Agency A federal office that collects outbreak data, models epidemics, and spreads the word to the public could keep the next Covid from being another Covid. https://www.wired.com/story/its-time-for-a-national-pandemic-prediction-agency/

February 2, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon American Cities Are Way Underreporting Their Carbon Footprints A modeling system called Vulcan shows that on average, cities across the country pollute 18.3 percent more than they’ve estimated.  https://www.wired.com/story/american-cities-underreporting-their-carbon-footprints/

February 2, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Use Your Speedometer to Figure Out Where Your Car Is You should never drive in a car with no windows. But if you ever do find yourself in one, you can use physics to get your bearings. https://www.wired.com/story/use-speedometer-figure-out-where-car-is/

February 2, 2021 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser The Lion, the Polygamist, and the Biofuel Scam How a member of a breakaway Mormon sect teamed up with a Lambo-driving, hard-partying tycoon to bilk the government for hundreds of millions of dollars. https://www.wired.com/story/lion-polygamist-and-biofuel-scam/

February 2, 2021 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell Those Most Likely to Get Covid Are Last in Line for Vaccines Distribution plans that favor people with time and internet access hurt Black and Latinx people disproportionately. https://www.wired.com/story/most-likely-covid-last-vaccines/

February 1, 2021 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus February’s Gonna Be a Big Month for Mars On the 9th, the first of three spacecraft will arrive at the Red Planet and inaugurate a new era of Martian exploration. https://www.wired.com/story/februarys-gonna-be-a-big-month-for-mars/

January 31, 2021 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood How Universes Might Bubble Up and Collide To understand how universes might inflate and bump into each other in the hypothetical multiverse, physicists are studying digital and physical analogs of the process. https://www.wired.com/story/how-universes-might-bubble-up-and-collide/

January 30, 2021 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Dozens of Egyptian Tombs Will Be Unearthed at Saqqara Necropolis Archaeologists found the entrance to the unexplored burial shaft earlier this week. https://www.wired.com/story/egyptian-tombs-unearthed-saqqara-necropolis/

January 30, 2021 | Author: Patrick BarkhamPatrick Barkham A Quarter of Known Bee Species Haven’t Been Seen Since 1990 A global study finds that species numbers reported in the wild fell sharply between 1990 and 2015. https://www.wired.com/story/a-quarter-of-known-bee-species-havent-been-seen-since-1990/

January 29, 2021 | Author: Max G. LevyMax G. Levy A New Way to Restore Hand Mobility—With an Electrified Patch In a clinical trial, wearing a small stimulator on their necks helped people with quadriplegia build back movement they had lost years ago. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-way-to-restore-hand-mobility-with-an-electrified-patch/

January 29, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Why Kids Matter in the Quest to Stamp Out Covid-19 Testing a vaccine on children takes longer and comes with more challenges. But inoculating kids can protect an entire population. https://www.wired.com/story/why-kids-matter-in-the-quest-to-stamp-out-covid-19/

January 28, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 9 Russian Adventurers Mysteriously Froze to Death. A New Theory Explains Why More than 60 years after the incident, scientists say they have new evidence pointing to a peculiar kind of avalanche as the culprit. https://www.wired.com/story/dyatlov-pass-incident-slab-avalanche/

January 28, 2021 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica The Trump Administration Left Biden With a Rocket Dilemma Mike Pence promised to land on the moon in 2024, but that’s fallen out of reach. So what now?  https://www.wired.com/story/trump-biden-rocket-dilemma/

January 28, 2021 | Author: Roxanne KhamsiRoxanne Khamsi May I Borrow Your Covid Immunity? Whenever a new virus emerges—be it HIV or SARS-CoV-2—a few lucky people put up a potent natural defense. Monoclonal antibody drugs let them share the health. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-immunity-antibodies/

January 27, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Worrisome New Coronavirus Strains Are Emerging. Why Now? Across the globe, SARS-CoV-2 is evolving ways to evade the immune system and become more infectious. Blown pandemic response plans are to blame. https://www.wired.com/story/worrisome-new-coronavirus-strains-are-emerging-why-now/

January 26, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Is It Time for an Emergency Rollout of Carbon-Eating Machines? Facilities that suck carbon dioxide out of the air could be powerful weapons for fighting climate change. But their deployment requires a huge wartime-style investment. https://www.wired.com/story/is-it-time-for-an-emergency-rollout-of-carbon-eating-machines/

January 26, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Are Mass Clinics the Solution for Covid-19 Vaccination? Mega-sites need a lot of personnel and pose problems of access and equity. But other vaccination campaigns might point us in the right direction. https://www.wired.com/story/are-mass-clinics-the-solution-for-covid-19-vaccination/

January 25, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Could Bobbie Really Hold 2 Spaceships Together in The Expanse? This scenario is very similar to a classic physics problem—but with more Martian armor. https://www.wired.com/story/could-bobbie-hold-two-spaceships-together-expanse/

January 25, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Sun-Loving Bacteria May Be Accelerating Glacial Melting Scientists find that cyanobacteria cause sediments on glaciers to clump, thus absorbing more sunlight. It’s not great news for fans of lower sea levels. https://www.wired.com/story/sun-loving-bacteria-may-be-accelerating-glacial-melting/

January 24, 2021 | Author: Thomas LewtonThomas Lewton The Secret Ingredient That Powers Supernovas Three-dimensional computer simulations have solved the mystery of why doomed stars explode at all. https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-ingredient-that-powers-supernovas/

January 23, 2021 | Author: Rochelle BakerRochelle Baker A New Project Maps the Pacific Coast’s Critical Kelp Forests Using sea charts and satellites, the effort will trace how the kelp beds are changing in response to global warming and commercial harvesting.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-project-maps-the-pacific-coasts-critical-kelp-forests/

January 23, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Do You Define Electric Field, Voltage, and Current? These three big ideas are all connected—and a demonstration with water and an LED can show how. https://www.wired.com/story/how-you-define-electric-field-voltage-and-current/

January 22, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Biden Gets to Work, Vaccine Guidelines Change, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/biden-gets-to-work-vaccine-guidelines-change-coronavirus-news/

January 22, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Year Ago I Asked: How Bad Could Covid Get? Now We Know No one was calling it a pandemic yet, at least publicly. Then came more troubling evidence about transmission, as the US ignored warning signs. https://www.wired.com/story/a-year-ago-i-asked-how-bad-could-covid-get-now-we-know/

January 21, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Is This a Fossilized Lair of the Dreaded Bobbit Worm? Scientists say they’ve got 20-million-year-old evidence of giant worms that hunted in pretty much the most nightmarish way possible. https://www.wired.com/story/is-this-a-fossilized-lair-of-the-dreaded-bobbit-worm/

January 21, 2021 | Author: LaVonne RobertsLaVonne Roberts These Recharge Rooms Are Helping Health Care Workers Cope Using voice-activation tech and nature-inspired soundscapes, these space are designed to give medical workers some respite from the Covid-19 front lines. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-recharge-rooms-health-care-front-line/

January 21, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Biden Returns the US to the Paris Climate Accord. Will It Matter? Biden’s first-day actions signal that he’s serious about global warming. But he’s got to make up for four years of lost time. https://www.wired.com/story/biden-returns-the-us-to-the-paris-climate-accord-will-it-matter/

January 20, 2021 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Vaping Doesn’t Keep Young People From Smoking Cigarettes Later It won’t prevent teens from later becoming smokers. But some health experts say that focusing on the risk of addicting new smokers cuts off a chance to help adults quit. https://www.wired.com/story/vaping-doesnt-keep-young-people-from-smoking-cigarettes-later/

January 20, 2021 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Biden’s Covid Plan Will Define His Presidency It’s not just about the pandemic. How the new administration handles Covid-19 will be a test of every one of its policies—and its values. https://www.wired.com/story/bidens-covid-plan-will-define-his-presidency/

January 19, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Ongoing Collapse of the World’s Aquifers When humans over-exploit underground water supplies, the ground collapses like a huge empty water bottle. It’s called subsidence, and it could affect 1.6 billion people by 2040. https://www.wired.com/story/the-ongoing-collapse-of-the-worlds-aquifers/

January 19, 2021 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Is Training an AI to Detect Fresh Craters on Mars An algorithm discovered dozens of Martian craters. It’s a promising remote method for exploring our solar system and understanding planetary history. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-is-training-an-ai-to-detect-fresh-craters-on-mars/

January 18, 2021 | Author: Eric RavenscraftEric Ravenscraft It’s Not Just You: Everyone’s Mental Health Is Suffering If you’re thinking, “Oh, I just need to suck it up,” stop. What you’re feeling is real. Here’s how to cope. https://www.wired.com/story/mental-health-coronavirus-pandemic-tips/

January 18, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Autonomous Saildrone Surveyor Preps for Its Sea Voyage The robo-vessel will map the ocean floor, and its solar-powered sensors will sample fish DNA and collect climate data. https://www.wired.com/story/the-autonomous-saildrone-surveyor-preps-for-its-sea-voyage/

January 18, 2021 | Author: Sandra UpsonSandra Upson Covid, Schools, and the High-Stakes Experiment No One Wanted Reopening in the fall was a massive gamble. At one high-poverty elementary school, navigating the risks paid off. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-schools-experiment-orlando/

January 17, 2021 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Virgin Orbit Just Launched a Rocket From a 747 Launching rockets from planes is a decades-old concept that never really took off. Billionaire Richard Branson thinks its time has come. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-orbit-just-launched-a-rocket-from-a-747/

January 17, 2021 | Author: Patrick HonnerPatrick Honner The Crooked, Complex Geometry of Round Trips Imagine if we lived on a cube-shaped Earth. How would you find the shortest path around the world? https://www.wired.com/story/the-crooked-complex-geometry-of-round-trips/

January 16, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Reddit’s Spinning Solar System Icon If the dots on the loading screen were planets, is their motion realistic? And can we actually model it? https://www.wired.com/story/physics-reddits-spinning-solar-system-icon/

January 16, 2021 | Author: Doug JohnsonDoug Johnson Can This Group Revive the Finicky Corpse Flower? In botanic gardens around the world, the reproductive future of the famously smelly plant is threatened. A new collaborative program wants to save it. https://www.wired.com/story/can-this-group-revive-the-finicky-corpse-flower/

January 15, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Faster Vaccinations, New Mutations, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/faster-vaccinations-more-mutations-coronavirus-news/

January 15, 2021 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler 2020 Was the One of the Hottest Years on Record Officials from NASA and NOAA say the warming of both the planet’s air and water are driving weather disasters. https://www.wired.com/story/2020-was-the-one-of-the-hottest-years-on-record/

January 15, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Everything We Know Now About Schools, Kids, and Covid-19 Researchers are finally getting good data on how severely SARS-CoV-2 affects children and how they transmit it. What does it mean for reopening classrooms? https://www.wired.com/story/everything-we-know-now-about-schools-kids-and-covid-19/

January 14, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Can an AI Predict the Language of Viral Mutation? Computational biologists used an algorithm meant to model human language to instead predict how viruses could evolve to evade the immune system. https://www.wired.com/story/can-an-ai-predict-the-language-of-viral-mutation/

January 13, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Adorable Fish Bots Get Schooled in How to Swarm Meet Bluebot, a friendly swimming robot with big camera eyes. Put a few in a tank together and they’ll collaborate to complete surprisingly complex tasks. https://www.wired.com/story/these-adorable-fish-robots-form-schools-like-the-real-thing/

January 13, 2021 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Covid-19 Vaccine Rollout Faces a Two-Shot Problem Millions of follow-up doses have been languishing in freezers, causing a massive logjam—and not everyone likes the ideas for a fix. https://www.wired.com/story/the-covid-19-vaccine-rollout-faces-a-two-shot-problem/

January 12, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Arctic Ocean Is Teeming With Microfibers From Clothes Scientists find an average of 40 microplastic particles per cubic meter of the northern water. The likely source? The synthetic clothing in our washing machines. https://www.wired.com/story/the-arctic-ocean-is-teeming-with-microfibers-from-clothes/

January 12, 2021 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber How Many Microcovids Would You Spend on a Burrito? Six nerdy roommates used public health data to create an online Covid-risk points system for every activity—and protect their pandemic pod. https://www.wired.com/story/group-house-covid-risk-points/

January 11, 2021 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Plan to Build a Global Network of Floating Power Stations A lot of thermal energy is trapped in the ocean. An ex-NASA researcher has figured out how it might generate unlimited clean power for aquatic robots. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-build-a-global-network-of-floating-power-stations/

January 11, 2021 | Author: John HudsonJohn Hudson If You Are Going to Survive, You Must Prepare to Fail Whether you are ejecting from a fighter jet or psyching yourself up for a meeting, plan for the worst—over and over and over again. And don’t forget to breathe.  https://www.wired.com/story/if-you-are-going-survive-you-must-prepare-fail/

January 10, 2021 | Author: Viviane CallierViviane Callier A Newfound Source of Cellular Order in the Chemistry of Life Inside cells, droplets called condensates merge, divide, and dissolve. Their dance may regulate vital processes. https://www.wired.com/story/a-newfound-source-of-cellular-order-in-the-chemistry-of-life/

January 9, 2021 | Author: Shannon OsakaShannon Osaka What Would It Take to Run a City on 100 Percent Clean Energy? Most claims of running on “clean” electricity come with caveats, and many technologies required for round-the-clock renewable energy aren’t quite ready yet. https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-it-take-to-run-a-city-on-100-percent-clean-energy/

January 9, 2021 | Author: Victoria Turk, WIRED UKVictoria Turk, WIRED UK The Mystery of the World’s Loneliest Penguins A small group of king penguins have appeared on Martillo Island in Argentina. How they got there, and whether they will stay, is unknown. https://www.wired.com/story/mystery-worlds-loneliest-penguins/

January 9, 2021 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Long Would It Take for a 747 to Stop, Like in Tenet? The airplane in the movie is stripped down and doesn’t have all of its brakes installed, making the calculations even more fun. https://www.wired.com/story/how-long-would-it-take-747-stop-like-tenet/

January 8, 2021 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A Variant Spreads, Vaccine Efforts Accelerate, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/variant-spreads-vaccine-accelerates-coronavirus-news/

January 8, 2021 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Fast Can Scientists Find the New Coronavirus Strains? The discovery of more contagious variants of SARS-CoV-2 in the US sparks a push for a long-overdue national genomic surveillance network. https://www.wired.com/story/how-fast-can-scientists-find-the-new-coronavirus-strains/

January 7, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Change Is Turning Cities Into Ovens A new model estimates that by 2100, cities across the world could warm as much as 4.4 degrees Celsius. It’s a deadly consequence of the heat-island effect. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-turning-cities-into-ovens/

January 6, 2021 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins For Marginalized Groups, Being Studied Can Be a Burden Academics often research minority communities in the hope of helping them. But too much time under the microscope can cause its own harms. https://www.wired.com/story/for-marginalized-groups-being-studied-can-be-a-burden/

January 5, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Robot Dog Learn How to Deftly Fend Off a Human Kick over this robot and it’ll quickly right itself—not because someone told it how, but because it taught itself to overcome the embarrassment. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-a-robot-dog-learn-how-to-deftly-fend-off-a-human/

January 4, 2021 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Drone Sniffs Out Odors With a Real Moth Antenna Researchers slap a living antenna on a drone to give the machine an insanely keen sense of smell. Ladies and gentlemen, meet the “Smellicopter.” https://www.wired.com/story/this-drone-sniffs-out-odors-with-a-real-moth-antenna/

January 3, 2021 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood The Milky Way Gets a New Origin Story Over the past two years, astronomers have rewritten the history of our galaxy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-milky-way-gets-a-new-origin-story/

January 2, 2021 | Author: Yvette CabreraYvette Cabrera What a Victorian Disease Detective Proved About Urban Health John Snow showed that London’s cholera outbreak arose from bad water, not the moral failings of the poor. His legacy can help tackle new problems like Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/what-a-victorian-disease-detective-proved-about-urban-health/

December 31, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Yes to Masks. No to Parties. 2021 Will Be a Lot Like 2020 Sorry, folks: Thanks to Covid, next year won’t be much more fun than this one, at least until enough vaccines arrive. https://www.wired.com/story/yes-to-masks-no-to-parties-2021-will-be-a-lot-like-2020/

December 30, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 30 Years Since the Human Genome Project Began, What’s Next? Eric Green, head of the nation’s top genomics research institute, looks back on how far the field has come and shares his bold vision for the future. https://www.wired.com/story/30-years-since-the-human-genome-project-began-whats-next/

December 29, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison In a Pandemic, Medical Illustrators Made Science Accessible With lots of research, arrows, and an inviting color palette, artists helped transform complex research into useful information. https://www.wired.com/story/in-a-pandemic-medical-illustrators-made-science-accessible/

December 28, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 2020 Was a Breakout Year for Crispr Between glimpses of a medical cure and winning science’s shiniest prize, this proved to the gene-editing technology’s biggest year yet. https://www.wired.com/story/2020-was-a-breakout-year-for-crispr/

December 28, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Error of Fighting a Public Health War With Medical Weapons It was a mistake that cost 300,000 lives. https://www.wired.com/story/the-error-of-fighting-a-public-health-war-with-medical-weapons/

December 27, 2020 | Author: Steve NadisSteve Nadis After Centuries, a Simple Math Problem Gets an Exact Solution Mathematicians have long pondered a deceptively easy puzzle about the reach of a goat tied to a fence. Until now, they’ve only found approximate answers. https://www.wired.com/story/after-centuries-a-simple-math-problem-gets-an-exact-solution/

December 26, 2020 | Author: Fiona HarveyFiona Harvey Can the Paris Agreement Still Avert Climate Chaos? As the Trump era wanes, there is a sense of optimism about what the accord could achieve, five years in—but only if countries meet their targets. https://www.wired.com/story/can-the-paris-agreement-still-avert-climate-chaos/

December 24, 2020 | Author: Jim MorrisonJim Morrison A Bold Plan to Save the Last Whitebark Pines The high-altitude tree is vital to its ecosystem, but it’s being decimated by a fungus. Its admirers are fusing old and new methods to bring it back. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bold-plan-to-save-the-last-whitebark-pines/

December 23, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Would Deadpool Jump Into a Moving Vehicle? Our sardonic superhero needs to get the timing just right to crash through the sunroof and beat up the bad guys. https://www.wired.com/story/how-would-deadpool-jump-into-a-moving-vehicle/

December 23, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A Unique Alliance Could Help Warn Us of Toxic Algae In Washington state, scientists, coastal communities, and state agencies are banding together to manage the growing threat of harmful algal blooms. https://www.wired.com/story/a-unique-alliance-could-help-warn-us-of-toxic-algae/

December 22, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Could Carbon Dioxide Be Turned Into Jet Fuel? A team at Oxford University has reverse engineered fuel from the greenhouse gas—but so far just in the lab. https://www.wired.com/story/could-carbon-dioxide-be-turned-into-jet-fuel/

December 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Oldest Crewed Deep Sea Submarine Just Got a Big Makeover The 60-year-old sub is preparing to take its deepest plunge yet. But in the age of autonomous machines, why are humans exploring the ocean floor at all? https://www.wired.com/story/the-oldest-crewed-deep-sea-submarine-just-got-a-big-makeover/

December 20, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover The Universe Is Expanding Faster Than Expected Astronomers get their wish—new ultra-precise distance measurements between Earth and the stars—but that only intensifies a cosmic crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/the-universe-is-expanding-faster-than-expected/

December 20, 2020 | Author: Josh Clark, Chuck BryantJosh Clark and Chuck Bryant Facial Hair Is Biologically Useless. So Why Do Humans Have It? Pubes protect you; head hair keeps you warm. But beards and mustaches seem to exist for mainly ornamental reasons. https://www.wired.com/story/facial-hair-is-biologically-useless-so-why-do-humans-have-it/

December 19, 2020 | Author: Natasha GilbertNatasha Gilbert Will Rising Temperatures Make Superweeds Even Stronger? Widely used herbicides are struggling to kill some weeds. Some experts think heat could be part of the problem. https://www.wired.com/story/will-rising-temperatures-make-superweeds-even-stronger/

December 18, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Check Out These Awesome Objects in the Night Sky Get your binoculars (or not) and let’s explore the reaches of our galaxy and the craters of the moon. https://www.wired.com/story/check-out-cool-stuff-in-the-night-sky/

December 18, 2020 | Author: Monique BrouilletteMonique Brouillette A New Field Guide for Earth’s Wild Microbes The most massive database of microbial gene sequences so far shows that the tree of life is much larger than we knew. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-field-guide-for-earths-wild-microbes/

December 17, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wildfire Smoke Is Loaded With Microbes. Is That Dangerous? Researchers are putting out a call to study the potential effects of bacteria- and fungi-filled haze on human health. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-smoke-is-loaded-with-microbes-is-that-dangerous/

December 17, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Vaccines Are Here. We Have to Talk About Side Effects Disinformation could thwart distribution before government messages have a chance to push back. Debunking might turn out to be everyone’s job. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccines-are-here-we-have-to-talk-about-side-effects/

December 16, 2020 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright How NASA Scrambled to Save OSIRIS-REx From Leaky Disaster The $800 million craft successfully collected precious asteroid material from a near-Earth asteroid. Then it started spilling regolith into space. https://www.wired.com/story/how-nasa-scrambled-to-save-osiris-rex-from-leaky-disaster/

December 16, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Cops Are Getting a New Tool For Family-Tree Sleuthing Verogen’s push into public crime labs with genetic genealogy may help solve more cold cases, but it raises concerns about DNA data collection. https://www.wired.com/story/cops-are-getting-a-new-tool-for-family-tree-sleuthing/

December 16, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The First Americans Are Being Vaccinated. Now, the Hard Part State and local officials are scrambling to figure out how to inoculate millions—after health care workers and the elderly—against the novel coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/first-americans-vaccinated-now-hard-part/

December 15, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon All the Stuff Humans Make Now Outweighs Earth’s Organisms Anthropogenic mass—concrete, metal, and other human creations—has grown to be heavier than plants, animals, and microbes combined. Planet Earth is not happy. https://www.wired.com/story/all-the-stuff-humans-make-now-outweighs-earths-organisms/

December 15, 2020 | Author: Adam MannAdam Mann The Steampunk Rover Concept That Could Help Explore Venus 50 years after the first spacecraft touched down on our super hot neighbor (and promptly died), NASA has a plan for a tougher mechanical lander. https://www.wired.com/story/the-steampunk-rover-concept-that-could-help-explore-venus/

December 14, 2020 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff A Letter to My Pandemic Baby On this week’s Get WIRED podcast, an editor captures the bizarre world of 2020 for his unborn daughter. https://www.wired.com/story/letter-to-my-pandemic-baby/

December 14, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins An AI Used Facebook Data to Predict Mental Illness Volunteers let an AI scan their messages from more than a year before they received a psychiatric diagnosis. It was able to flag signs of their conditions. https://www.wired.com/story/an-ai-used-facebook-data-to-predict-mental-illness/

December 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler A Bolivian ‘Cloud Forest’ Reveals a Bonanza of New Species An expedition into a steep, remote mountain area unveils discoveries of strange frogs, snakes, and plants—and the return of species thought to be extinct. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bolivian-cloud-forest-reveals-a-bonanza-of-new-species/

December 13, 2020 | Author: John PavlusJohn Pavlus Super Slow Computer Programs Reveal Math’s Fundamental Limits The goal of the “busy beaver” game is to find the longest-running computer program. Its pursuit has surprising connections to profound questions in math. https://www.wired.com/story/super-slow-computer-programs-reveal-maths-fundamental-limits/

December 12, 2020 | Author: Phoebe WestonPhoebe Weston An Atlas Reveals Climate Change Is Pushing Birds Further North Data from 120,000 birdwatchers in 48 countries shows forest birds have expanded their range while area occupied by farmland birds has shrunk. https://www.wired.com/story/an-atlas-reveals-climate-change-is-pushing-birds-further-north/

December 11, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider The First Shots, Grim Milestones, and More Coronavirus News  Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/the-first-shots-grim-milestones-coronavirus-news/

December 11, 2020 | Author: Jesse KleinJesse Klein Severe Wildfires Are Devastating the California Condor This year’s aggressive fire season wiped out a record number of the endangered birds, as well as a facility wildlife biologists use to track and care for them. https://www.wired.com/story/severe-wildfires-are-devastating-the-california-condor/

December 11, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight I Tested Positive for Covid-19. What Does That Really Mean? We reduce test results to “positive” or “negative.” Some experts think patients, and the community, would be better served by a more nuanced approach. https://www.wired.com/story/i-tested-positive-covid-19-what-that-mean/

December 11, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The FDA’s Green Light for a Vaccine Might Tank Ongoing Trials The agency is close to authorizing Pfizer’s Covid-19 shot. That raises questions about the fate of study volunteers and lost opportunities to collect their data. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fdas-green-light-for-a-vaccine-might-tank-ongoing-trials/

December 10, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica A Rocket From 1966 Has Found Its Way Back to Earth’s Orbit More than 50 years after its course correction failure, Surveyor 2’s rocket booster seems to have reappeared.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-rocket-from-1966-has-found-its-way-back-to-earths-orbit/

December 10, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles There Are No Real Rules for Repairing Satellites in Space—Yet Fixing, refueling, and upgrading satellites in orbit is about to become more common. A group is pushing for international standards to keep these missions safe. https://www.wired.com/story/there-are-no-real-rules-for-repairing-satellites-in-space-yet/

December 9, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Launches—and Crashes—Its Starship Mars Rocket The test flight didn’t come close to the edge of space, but the prototype was a big step toward the rocket’s first orbital mission. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launches-and-crashes-its-starship-mars-rocket/

December 9, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Bees Paint Animal Poo on Their Homes to Repel Giant Hornets What at first seems like terrible housekeeping turns out to be a clever ploy to fend off huge predators, which can otherwise easily destroy a hive. https://www.wired.com/story/bees-paint-animal-poo-on-their-homes-to-repel-giant-hornets/

December 8, 2020 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 8 Science Books to Read (or Gift) This Winter Here are the best new books to pick up—for yourself, or someone else—according to WIRED staff. https://www.wired.com/gallery/8-science-books-read-gift-winter-2020/

December 8, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Perfect Strategy to Fight Covid-19 Is … Everything? It’d be great to know which public health interventions against the coronavirus have the biggest bang for the buck. But nobody does. https://www.wired.com/story/the-perfect-strategy-to-fight-covid-19-is-everything/

December 8, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Did QuantumScape Just Solve a 40-Year-Old Battery Problem? Earlier this year, the startup claimed to have a revolutionary solid-state lithium-ion cell that could change EVs forever. Now it has data to prove it. https://www.wired.com/story/quantumscape-solid-state-battery/

December 7, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Let’s Unpack the Pendulum Rocket Fallacy And explore how it relates to Iron Man’s flight strategy. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-unpack-the-pendulum-rocket-fallacy/

December 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Who Will We Be When This Is All Over? The Covid-19 pandemic has brought incalculable suffering and trauma. But it also offers ways for people—and even societies—to change for the better. https://www.wired.com/story/who-will-we-be-when-the-pandemic-is-over/

December 6, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica High-Energy X-Rays Reveal the Secrets of Ancient Egyptian Ink Analysis of 12 papyrus fragments from the Tebtunis Temple suggests that certain paint techniques were developed and used well before the 15th Century. https://www.wired.com/story/high-energy-x-rays-reveal-the-secrets-of-ancient-egyptian-ink/

December 6, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood The Search for Dark Matter Is Dramatically Expanding Physicists are checking whether dark matter tickles different types of detectors, nudges starlight, warms planetary cores, or even lodges in rocks. https://www.wired.com/story/the-search-for-dark-matter-is-dramatically-expanding/

December 5, 2020 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Physicists Are Closer to Knowing the Size of a Proton … Sort of A new and potentially improved measurement of a proton’s charge radius brings scientists closer to an answer. But the issue is still unresolved.  https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-are-closer-to-knowing-the-size-of-a-proton-sort-of/

December 5, 2020 | Author: Kate YoderKate Yoder Another Victim of Global Warming: The Great British Bake Off Increasing summer temperatures are proving a menace to butter, chocolates, and baked Alaska. https://www.wired.com/story/another-victim-of-global-warming-the-great-british-bake-off/

December 4, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Trust in Vaccines Grows, Distribution Faces Challenges, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/trust-in-vaccines-distribution-challenges-coronavirus-news/

December 4, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus For the Second Time Ever, an Asteroid Sample Returns to Earth The Japanese Hayabusa2 mission to asteroid Ryugu marks a major milestone this weekend with the return of pristine space rock. https://www.wired.com/story/for-the-second-time-ever-an-asteroid-sample-returns-to-earth/

December 3, 2020 | Author: Scott K. Johnson, Ars TechnicaScott K. Johnson, Ars Technica Underground Brine Could Be a Source of Oxygen on Mars A new study tests a device that can efficiently split the resource’s water into pure oxygen and hydrogen in Martian conditions. https://www.wired.com/story/underground-brine-could-be-a-source-of-oxygen-on-mars/

December 3, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The NIH’s Top Vaccine Maker Wants Warp Speed to Be the New Normal John Mascola, who worked on the research that led to the Moderna shot, thinks Covid-19 proves we have to prep for the next virus, too. https://www.wired.com/story/the-nihs-top-vaccine-maker-wants-warp-speed-to-be-the-new-normal/

December 2, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Incredible Journey of the Electronic Plastic Bottle Researchers loaded containers with trackers and released them in the Ganges and the Bay of Bengal, giving new insight into how plastic pollution travels. https://www.wired.com/story/the-incredible-journey-of-the-electronic-plastic-bottle/

December 2, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler New AI-Based Navigation Helps Loon’s Balloons Hover in Place Reinforcement learning might be the next step in keeping broadband-carrying balloons afloat above remote areas. Could Venus be next? https://www.wired.com/story/new-ai-based-navigation-helps-loons-balloons-hover-in-place/

December 2, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Two Global Efforts Try to Trace the Origin of the Covid Virus Both teams want to know when—or how often—the virus passed from animals to people. But the trail may have gone cold, and the search has gotten political. https://www.wired.com/story/two-global-efforts-try-to-trace-the-origin-of-the-covid-virus/

December 1, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill How a Vibrating Smartwatch Could Be Used to Stop Nightmares The FDA has given NightWare clearance to market a “digital therapeutic” device that uses an Apple Watch to interrupt PTSD-related nightmares. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-vibrating-smartwatch-could-be-used-to-stop-nightmares/

November 30, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Beautiful Yet Unnerving Photos of the Arctic Getting Greener Using tricked-out drones, scientists are watching vegetation boom in the far north. Their findings could have big implications for the whole planet. https://www.wired.com/story/beautiful-yet-unnerving-photos-of-the-arctic-getting-greener/

November 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Race To Crack Battery Recycling—Before It’s Too Late Millions of EVs will soon hit the road, but the world isn’t ready for their old batteries. A crop of startups wants to crack this billion-dollar problem. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-crack-battery-recycling-before-its-too-late/

November 29, 2020 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Geometry Reveals How the World Is Made of Cubes An exercise in pure mathematics has led to a wide-ranging theory that unites Plato with geophysics. https://www.wired.com/story/geometry-reveals-how-the-world-is-made-of-cubes/

November 28, 2020 | Author: Rochelle BakerRochelle Baker Endangered Vancouver Island Marmots Are Making a Comeback Canada’s most endangered mammal is back from the brink of extinction—and offers hope as an “ambassador” for the conservation of less adorable species. https://www.wired.com/story/endangered-vancouver-island-marmots-are-making-a-comeback/

November 27, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What’s a Semi-Log Plot and How Can You Use It for Covid Data? It is very useful for showing data that spans different orders of magnitude—like case numbers in South Korea compared to the numbers in the United States. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-a-semi-log-plot-and-when-would-you-use-one/

November 25, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Does the AstraZeneca Vaccine Also Stop Covid Transmission? Vaccines can prevent symptoms, but some can also keep people from spreading infection. That’s critical, and no one knows if the new vaccines do it. https://www.wired.com/story/does-the-astrazeneca-vaccine-also-stop-covid-transmission/

November 25, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet the Microbes Living on Da Vinci’s Iconic Sketches Think you’ve got an interesting microbiome? Your body ain’t got nothing on what’s accumulated on Leonardo’s drawings over 500 years. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-microbes-living-on-da-vincis-iconic-sketches/

November 24, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A New Study About Color Tries to Decode ‘The Brain’s Pantone’ How do humans perceive color? An NIH experiment finds a way to measure what happens after light hits the eye—using brain scans. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-study-about-color-tries-to-decode-the-brains-pantone/

November 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Squishy 3D-Printed Human Heart Feels Like the Real Thing A clever technique allows scientists to scan a heart and reconstruct it in a soup of gelatin. It’s like making jello, only way more useful for surgeons. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-printed-human-heart-feels-like-the-real-thing/

November 23, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Last, ‘Ultra-Cold’ Mile for Covid-19 Vaccines Two vaccines are nearly here—but their unusual storage requirements could deprive the rural areas that need them most. A tech fix might be coming. https://www.wired.com/story/the-last-ultra-cold-mile-for-covid-19-vaccines/

November 22, 2020 | Author: Thomas LewtonThomas Lewton Physicists Pin Down the Nuclear Reaction Just After the Big Bang The newly measured rate of a key nuclear fusion process that forged the first atomic nuclei matches the picture of the universe 380,000 years later. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-pin-down-the-nuclear-reaction-just-after-the-big-bang/

November 21, 2020 | Author: Victoria PetersenVictoria Petersen Climate Change Is Intensifying the Tsunami Threat in Alaska As glaciers retreat and permafrost thaws, massive landslides threaten coastal communities. Those, in turn, could trigger giant sea waves. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-intensifying-the-tsunami-threat-in-alaska/

November 20, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Pfizer Seeks Vaccine Approval, the CDC Urges Restraint, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/pfizer-seeks-vaccine-approval-the-cdc-urges-restraint-and-more-coronavirus-news/

November 20, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Solar-Powered Rocket Might Be Our Ticket to Interstellar Space The idea for solar thermal propulsion has been around for decades, but researchers tapped by NASA just conducted a first test. https://www.wired.com/story/a-solar-powered-rocket-might-be-our-ticket-to-interstellar-space/

November 20, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Iowa’s Covid Wave and the Limits of Personal Responsibility Until Monday, the governor urged Iowans to “do the right thing” but kept businesses open and masks optional. Now cases are surging and hospitals are filling up. https://www.wired.com/story/iowas-covid-wave-and-the-limits-of-personal-responsibility/

November 19, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Materials at Minus 80 Degrees Celsius Pfizer’s new vaccine has to be stored at extremely low temperatures. Here’s how things work when it gets that cold.  https://www.wired.com/story/physics-of-materials-minus-80-degrees-celsius/

November 19, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler An Enormous Iceberg Is Headed for South Georgia Island—Again If they collide, it could cause big problems for breeding penguins and seals by cutting off their access to the open sea. https://www.wired.com/story/an-enormous-iceberg-is-headed-for-south-georgia-island-again/

November 19, 2020 | Author: Esther LandhuisEsther Landhuis How a Medication for OCD Ended Up in a Covid-19 Trial In a small study, the drug kept patients with mild symptoms from worsening. If it holds up in a larger test, it could help keep more people out of hospitals. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-medication-for-ocd-ended-up-in-a-covid-19-trial/

November 18, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Can You Get Covid-19 on an Airplane? Yeah, Probably As usual, a lack of good data makes evaluating the risk of getting the virus on a flight hard to calculate. It’s probably low. It’s definitely not zero. https://www.wired.com/story/can-you-get-covid-19-on-an-airplane-yeah-probably/

November 18, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Larry Brilliant Says We’ll Beat Covid—After We Go Through Hell The epidemiologist calls it “the best of times and the worst of times,” as good news on vaccines and testing coincides with a terrifying rise in cases. https://www.wired.com/story/larry-brilliant-says-we-will-beat-covid-after-we-go-through-hell/

November 17, 2020 | Author: Chelsea CirruzzoChelsea Cirruzzo How to Reduce (but Not Eliminate) Covid Risk at Holiday Gatherings With a surge in cases, there is no safe way to travel or gather for Thanksgiving or Christmas. But if you must, here are some ways to lower your risk. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-risk-holiday-travel-family-gatherings/

November 17, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Rare Seeds Escaped Syria’s War—to Help Feed the World Conflict forced scientists to abandon a gene bank, but not before duplicating their last remnants of essential crops in the Svalbard vault on a remote Arctic island. https://www.wired.com/story/these-rare-seeds-escaped-syrias-war-to-help-feed-the-world/

November 16, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How NASA Finds the Mass of the Dirt Grabbed From an Asteroid Just how much material did OSIRIS-REx collect from Bennu? The method relies on something called the moment of inertia, and you can replicate it with a fan and a penny. https://www.wired.com/story/osiris-rex-bennu-dirt-mass/

November 16, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Ancient Dog DNA Reveals Their Enduring Connection With People Genetic material from prehistoric dogs shows how early humans may have migrated with, bred, and cared for their canine companions. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-dog-dna-reveals-their-enduring-connection-with-people/

November 15, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich Computer Scientists Achieve the ‘Crown Jewel’ of Cryptography For years, a master tool called indistinguishability obfuscation seemed too good to be true. Three researchers have figured out that it can work. https://www.wired.com/story/computer-scientists-achieve-the-crown-jewel-of-cryptography/

November 14, 2020 | Author: Jane C. HuJane C. Hu Wilderness Rescuers Brace for a Rough Covid-19 Winter The popularity of outdoor recreation has skyrocketed during the pandemic. But now snow is on the way—and recovery missions are on the rise. https://www.wired.com/story/wilderness-rescuers-brace-for-a-rough-covid-19-winter/

November 13, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A Vaccine Nears, Biden Gets to Work, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/a-vaccine-nears-biden-gets-to-work-and-more-coronavirus-news/

November 13, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Is Ready to Launch Its First Official Crewed Mission Saturday’s SpaceX launch will mark the return of regular crewed launches in the US after nearly a decade hiatus. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launches-first-official-crewed-mission/

November 13, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers We’ll Need More Than One Vaccine to Beat the Pandemic All the Covid vaccine candidates work in different ways, and none will be perfect for everyone. It’ll take a slate of options to help cover us all. https://www.wired.com/story/well-need-more-than-one-vaccine-to-beat-the-pandemic/

November 12, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Fireball Is Werner Herzog’s Ode to Space Rocks A new documentary from the German auteur examines the influence of meteorites on cultures around the world. https://www.wired.com/story/fireball-herzog-meteorite-documentary/

November 12, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can Biden Make Climate Progress With a Divided Congress? Actually, Yeah Environmental experts say the administration may fare better by working with green governors and clean tech businesses, and by signing executive orders. https://www.wired.com/story/can-biden-make-climate-progress-with-a-divided-congress-actually-yeah/

November 12, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Covid Winter Is Coming. Could Humidifiers Help? As the air gets drier, and people stay indoors with the heater on, humidity will likely play a role in how easily the respiratory virus spreads. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-winter-is-coming-could-humidifiers-help/

November 11, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Plan to Turn Scrapped Rockets Into Space Stations Spent rockets are dangerous space trash, but they could be the future of living and working in orbit. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-turn-scrapped-rockets-into-space-stations/

November 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Thinking About a Holiday Gathering? Look at This Troubling Map First An alarming visualization shows the odds that at least one Covid-positive person attends a given event. It should give us all pause about family plans. https://www.wired.com/story/thinking-about-a-holiday-gathering-look-at-this-map/

November 11, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Strange and Twisted Tale of Hydroxychloroquine The much-hyped drug sparked a battle between power and knowledge. Let’s not repeat it. https://www.wired.com/story/hydroxychloroquine-covid-19-strange-twisted-tale/

November 10, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why It’s a Big Deal If the First Covid Vaccine Is ‘Genetic’ If approved by the FDA, Pfizer and BioNTech’s mRNA vaccine would be the first of its kind, setting a record for speed—but raising questions about distribution. https://www.wired.com/story/why-its-a-big-deal-if-the-first-covid-vaccine-is-genetic/

November 10, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Everything You Need to Know About Energy  We’ll talk about the different types—kinetic energy, electrical potential energy, etc.—and different sources, from fossil fuels to solar.  https://www.wired.com/story/everything-you-need-to-know-about-energy/

November 10, 2020 | Author: Christopher CoxChristopher Cox The Vulnerable Can Wait. Vaccinate the Super-Spreaders First Who gets priority when Covid-19 shots are in short supply? Network theorists have a counterintuitive answer: Start with the social butterflies. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-vaccine-super-spreaders/

November 9, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon ‘Godzilla’ Wasp Swims—So Its Young Can Burst Out of Caterpillars In non-election news, Microgaster godzilla dives to find a caterpillar, forces it to the surface, and injects it with a baby that eats the host from the inside out. https://www.wired.com/story/godzilla-wasp-swims-so-its-young-can-burst-out-of-caterpillars/

November 9, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Next Covid Dilemma: How to Make Buildings Breathe Better Better indoor ventilation systems could make people safer and healthier—and not just because they’d slow down the coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/the-next-covid-dilemma-how-to-make-buildings-breathe-better/

November 8, 2020 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica The Genome of Your Pet Fish Is Extremely Weird Unlike most domestic animals, the goldfish is purely decorative. https://www.wired.com/story/the-genome-of-your-pet-fish-is-extremely-weird/

November 8, 2020 | Author: George MusserGeorge Musser The Most Famous Paradox in Physics Nears Its End In a landmark series of calculations, physicists have proved that black holes can shed information, which seems impossible by definition.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-black-hole-information-paradox-comes-to-an-end/

November 7, 2020 | Author: Emily CataneoEmily Cataneo A Plan to Save Appalachia’s Wild Ginseng American ginseng is imperiled by overharvesting. Locals are racing to preserve the plant—and its economic potential, through “forest farming.” https://www.wired.com/story/a-plan-to-save-appalachias-wild-ginseng/

November 6, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider An Election Week Case Surge, Vaccine Progress, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/election-week-case-surge-vaccine-progress-coronavirus-news/

November 6, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Confused About Covid Brain Fog? Doctors Have Questions, Too Physicians have seen this recovery symptom before, but they still don’t know why so many coronavirus survivors are being affected. https://www.wired.com/story/confused-about-covid-brain-fog-doctors-have-questions-too/

November 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Batteries of the Future Are Weightless and Invisible There’s a renaissance underway in structural battery research, which aims to build energy storage into the very devices and vehicles they power. https://www.wired.com/story/the-batteries-of-the-future-are-weightless-and-invisible/

November 5, 2020 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Astronomers Finally Know What Causes Fast Radio Bursts After more than a decade, researchers have confirmed their suspicions about the source of the phenomena. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-finally-know-what-causes-fast-radio-bursts/

November 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Fight the Zombie Fire Apocalypse? Weaponize Math Peat fires smolder in the ground for months, suddenly emerging as surface wildfires. New simulations reveal their strange life, death, and reanimation. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-fight-the-zombie-fire-apocalypse-weaponize-math/

November 4, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler What Is a Super Typhoon, and Why Are They So Dangerous? Massive storms like Goni, which hit the Philippine islands on Sunday, could be a glimpse of our future. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-a-super-typhoon-and-why-are-they-so-dangerous/

November 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Happens When You Fly a Science Plane Through Wildfire Smoke Aboard a decked-out C-130, researchers measure how smoke transforms from “fresh” to “stale” and begin to parse what that means for humans downwind. https://www.wired.com/story/what-happens-when-you-fly-a-science-plane-through-wildfire-smoke/

November 2, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Formulas or Code? It’s All Numbers When It Comes to Physics People say that computational methods are a separate branch of science, but that’s not really true.  https://www.wired.com/story/formulas-or-code-its-all-numbers-when-it-comes-to-physics/

November 2, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Winning Trust for a Vaccine Means Confronting Medical Racism The US has a long history of abusing minorities for pharmaceutical profit. Messaging for a Covid-19 inoculation will have to overcome that past. https://www.wired.com/story/winning-trust-for-a-vaccine-means-confronting-medical-racism/

November 1, 2020 | Author: Anil AnanthaswamyAnil Ananthaswamy Deep Neural Networks Are Helping Decipher How Brains Work Neuroscientists are finding that deep-learning networks, often criticized as “black boxes,” can be good models for the organization of living brains. https://www.wired.com/story/deep-neural-networks-are-helping-decipher-how-brains-work/

October 31, 2020 | Author: Fred PearceFred Pearce Is It Better to Plant Trees or Let Forests Regrow Naturally? Nations are pledging to plant billions of trees. But a new study shows that we’ve underestimated the power of natural forest regrowth to fight climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/is-it-better-to-plant-trees-or-let-forests-regrow-naturally/

October 30, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A Holiday Season Surge, Outbreaks in Swing States, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/holiday-season-surge-outbreaks-in-swing-states-and-more-coronavirus-news/

October 30, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Why Are Lines at Polling Places So Long? Math It’s a resource allocation problem, a tough challenge in “queueing theory.” It’s also racism. https://www.wired.com/story/why-are-lines-at-polling-places-so-long-math/

October 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How Humanity Spent Its First 20 Years in Orbit Aboard the ISS Two decades ago, three explorers arrived at the International Space Station and marked the beginning of a permanent human presence beyond Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/how-humanity-spent-its-first-20-years-in-orbit-aboard-the-iss/

October 29, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni In Embryos, Crispr Can Cut Out Whole Chromosomes—That’s Bad The DNA-cutting tool has been hailed as a way to fix genetic glitches. But a new study suggests it can remove more than scientists bargained for. https://www.wired.com/story/in-embryos-crispr-can-cut-out-whole-chromosomes-thats-bad/

October 29, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison How Octopuses Use Their Suction Cups to Taste Through Touch A new study reveals that the invertebrates use a novel kind of receptor embedded in their suckers to explore their ocean habitats. https://www.wired.com/story/how-octopuses-use-their-suction-cups-to-taste-through-touch/

October 29, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A New Way to Plug a Human Brain Into a Computer: via Veins Electrodes threaded through the blood vessels that feed the brain let people control gadgets with their minds. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-way-to-plug-a-human-brain-into-a-computer-via-veins/

October 28, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What to Wear When You’re Battling Giant, Venomous Hornets The suits worn by Washington state entomologists aren’t “official” hornet-fighting armor. But they were affordable—and came up in an Amazon search. https://www.wired.com/story/what-to-wear-when-youre-battling-giant-venomous-hornets/

October 28, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Did Pterosaurs Eat? Look Very Closely at Their Teeth An “infinite focus microscope” reveals characteristic patterns on the flying reptiles’ chompers, showing in new detail how they lived—and evolved. https://www.wired.com/story/what-did-pterosaurs-eat-look-closely-at-their-teeth/

October 28, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Should You Do About Holiday Gatherings and Covid-19? Amid the Covid-19 pandemic, there’s no perfectly safe way to socialize. But here are some tips on how to talk to your relatives about risk—or opting out. https://www.wired.com/story/what-should-you-do-about-holiday-gatherings-and-covid-19/

October 27, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler These Oceanographers Want to Turn Marine Slime Into Drugs A California team will use a robotic vehicle to study tiny seafloor creatures, hoping they might yield new compounds to fight viruses and cancer. https://www.wired.com/story/these-oceanographers-want-to-turn-marine-slime-into-drugs/

October 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus What Comes After the International Space Station? Funding for the world’s premiere orbital laboratory won’t last forever. Its end could usher in a new era of commercial space stations. https://www.wired.com/story/what-comes-after-the-international-space-station/

October 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus There May Be Far More Water on the Moon Than NASA Thought A new pair of studies reveals that the resource isn’t limited to large shadowy craters. That’s good news for the upcoming crewed missions. https://www.wired.com/story/there-may-be-far-more-water-on-the-moon-than-nasa-thought/

October 26, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode Boston Dynamics’ Robots Won’t Take Our Jobs … Yet On this week’s Get WIRED podcast, writer Matt Simon talks about Spot the dog and SpaceX with Marc Raibert. https://www.wired.com/story/get-wired-podcast-14-boston-dynamics/

October 26, 2020 | Author: Ronan O’ConnellRonan O’Connell Pandemic Quiet Is Helping Humans Eavesdrop on Rare Dolphins Researchers are hoping to use the opportunity to get a better handle on the language of Australia’s endangered Burrunan dolphins. https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-quiet-is-helping-humans-eavesdrop-on-rare-dolphins/

October 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Mark Kelly’s Been To Space. Can He Make it to Capitol Hill? Mark Kelly isn’t the first former NASA astronaut to run for office, but if he’s elected he’ll be the first astronaut in Congress in nearly 40 years. https://www.wired.com/story/mark-kellys-been-to-space-can-he-make-it-to-capitol-hill/

October 25, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Scientists Discover the First Room-Temperature Superconductor Physicists finally achieved the long-sought goal, but there’s a catch: Their compound requires crushing pressures to keep from falling apart. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-discover-the-first-room-temperature-superconductor/

October 24, 2020 | Author: Jonathan WattsJonathan Watts Uh-Oh. Russia’s Laptev Sea Should Have Started to Freeze by Now Normally, the ‘birthplace of ice’ freezes by late October. For the first time in recorded history, it hasn’t. That could have knock-on effects across the Arctic. https://www.wired.com/story/russias-laptev-sea-should-have-started-to-freeze-by-now/

October 23, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Another Surge, Vaccine and Treatment Progress, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/another-surge-vaccine-and-treatment-progress-and-more-coronavirus-news/

October 23, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica How the Venus Flytrap ‘Remembers’ When It Captures Prey The carnivorous plant is believed to have something akin to a short-term “memory.” A team of scientists has uncovered new details on how it works. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-venus-flytrap-remembers-when-it-captures-prey/

October 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Case for Reviving the Civilian Conservation Corps If the US brought back the Great Depression’s massive worker program, it could put millions of Americans back to work—and help stave off disasters like wildfires. https://www.wired.com/story/the-case-for-reviving-the-civilian-conservation-corps/

October 22, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Your Brain Prefers Happy Endings. That’s Not Always Smart People tend to focus on whether an experience ends on an up note or a sour one, even if it leads us to make bad decisions. A new study examines why. https://www.wired.com/story/your-brain-prefers-happy-endings-thats-not-always-smart/

October 21, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How the ‘Diabolical’ Beetle Survives Being Run Over by a Car The puny insect can withstand forces 39,000 times its body weight. Scientists just discovered its super-strength secret—which could inspire new materials. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-diabolical-beetle-survives-being-run-over-by-a-car/

October 21, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Even Is Friction, Anyway? You might think of it as the force that slows things down, but you literally couldn’t get anywhere without it. https://www.wired.com/story/what-even-is-friction-anyway/

October 20, 2020 | Author: Claudia Lopez LloredaClaudia Lopez Lloreda Can Placebos Work—Even When Patients Know They’re Fake? Researchers showed that a saline spray “treatment” reduced people’s emotional distress, even though the study subjects knew the spray wouldn’t do anything. https://www.wired.com/story/can-placebos-work-even-when-patients-know-theyre-fake/

October 20, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber It’s Time to Talk About Covid-19 and Surfaces Again In the early days, we furiously scrubbed, afraid we could get sick from the virus lingering on objects and surfaces. What do we know now? https://www.wired.com/story/its-time-to-talk-about-covid-19-and-surfaces-again/

October 19, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Babies May Be Drinking Millions of Microplastic Particles a Day Scientists discover that baby bottles shed up to 16 million bits of plastic per liter of fluid. What that means for infants’ health, no one can yet say. https://www.wired.com/story/babies-may-be-drinking-millions-of-microplastic-particles-a-day/

October 19, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s OSIRIS-REx Is About to Touch an Asteroid After years of studying Bennu, the spacecraft will make its first attempt at a sample collection on Tuesday. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-osiris-rex-is-about-to-touch-an-asteroid/

October 19, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode The New Science of Wildfire Prediction  On this week’s Get WIRED podcast, writer Dan Duane dives into the inevitability of fires in the west and how better models would help combat them.  https://www.wired.com/story/get-wired-podcast-13-fire-science/

October 18, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich Computer Scientists Break the ‘Traveling Salesperson’ Record Finally, there’s a better way to find approximate solutions to the notorious optimization problem, often used to test the limits of efficient computation. https://www.wired.com/story/computer-scientists-break-the-traveling-salesperson-record/

October 17, 2020 | Author: Kate YoderKate Yoder Want Some Eco-Friendly Tips? A New Study Says No, You Don’t Nagging, giving unsolicited advice, and “ecopiety” are out. But there are better ways to get people to adopt green habits. https://www.wired.com/story/want-some-eco-friendly-tips-a-new-study-says-no-you-dont/

October 16, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Treatment and Vaccine Trials Are Halted, US Cases Rise, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/treatment-and-vaccine-trials-are-halted-us-cases-rise-and-more/

October 16, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Preexisting Conditions of the Coronavirus Pandemic An enormous new data set peers into the health of the world’s population before 2020—and how the coronavirus turned that into a global disaster. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pre-existing-conditions-of-the-coronavirus-pandemic/

October 16, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna In the US, 50 States Could Mean 50 Vaccine Rollout Strategies The CDC put out a central playbook for how to distribute the shots. But how states will address these guidelines is anything but uniform. https://www.wired.com/story/in-the-us-50-states-could-mean-50-vaccine-rollout-strategies/

October 15, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to Build a Spacecraft to Save the World WIRED paid a visit to NASA’s first probe designed to protect Earth from killer asteroids. It launches next year. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-build-a-spacecraft-to-save-the-world/

October 15, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Forest Floor Playgrounds Teach Us About Kids and Germs Finnish researchers just published the first big test of the “biodiversity hypothesis”—that exposure to the microbes in dirt is good for young immune systems. https://www.wired.com/story/what-forest-floor-playgrounds-teach-us-about-kids-and-germs/

October 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Wild Predators Are Relying More on Our Food—and Pets A new study shows that some big carnivores are getting up to half their diet from sources like trash, crops, or small mammals that live near people. https://www.wired.com/story/wild-predators-are-relying-more-on-our-food-and-pets/

October 14, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon See Earth Transform Like You’re a Time-Traveling Astronaut The new photo book Overview Timelapse shows the startling ways humanity is changing the planet, from lithium mines to the ravages of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/see-earth-transform-like-youre-a-time-traveling-astronaut/

October 14, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus This Is My Brain on Salvia I loaned my head to the world’s first fMRI study on the effects of salvinorin A, a potent psychedelic. Here’s what it revealed. https://www.wired.com/story/this-is-my-brain-on-salvia/

October 13, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Would Happen If All the Antarctic Ice Melted? It … let’s just say it would not be good. Here, let’s do the math.  https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-happen-antarctic-ice-melted/

October 13, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Meteorite Is a Love Letter to Space Rocks For centuries, scientists thought meteorites were too fantastical to exist. A new book reveals that they hold even more mysteries. https://www.wired.com/story/meteorite-is-a-love-letter-to-space-rocks/

October 12, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus AI Is Throwing Battery Development Into Overdrive Improving batteries has always been hampered by slow experimentation and discovery processes. Machine learning is speeding it up by orders of magnitude. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-is-throwing-battery-development-into-overdrive/

October 12, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber New York Is Trying Targeted Lockdowns. Will It Stop a Second Wave? Instead of shutting down all of New York City, this time officials are taking a block-by-block approach to home in on areas with increasing case numbers. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-is-trying-targeted-lockdowns-will-it-stop-a-second-wave/

October 11, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett The Effort to Build the Mathematical Library of the Future A community of mathematicians is using software called Lean to build a new digital repository. They hope it represents where their field is headed next. https://www.wired.com/story/the-effort-to-build-the-mathematical-library-of-the-future/

October 10, 2020 | Author: Kalen GoodluckKalen Goodluck Covid Is Strengthening the Push for Indigenous Data Control Due to data control concerns, tribal nations are not part of the “All of Us” DNA collection program. But that means missing out on its Covid-19 antibody testing. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-is-strengthening-the-push-for-indigenous-data-control/

October 10, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Testing Alone Won’t Stop Covid. Just Look at the White House Some employers are relying on rapid tests to reopen. The outbreak around President Trump shows the shortcomings of that approach.  https://www.wired.com/story/testing-alone-wont-stop-covid-white-house/

October 9, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider A Super-Spreading Presidency, Experimental Treatments, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/a-superspreading-presidency-experimental-treatments-and-more-coronavirus-news/

October 9, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Most Sway-Prone Buildings in LA Aren’t Where You Expect Using a network of sensors, researchers found that the Los Angeles high-rises most likely to rock in a future quake aren’t downtown. https://www.wired.com/story/the-most-sway-prone-buildings-in-la-arent-where-you-expect/

October 9, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why These Cursed Debates Made You Feel So Upset Here’s the psychology and political science behind why the embarrassing presidential and vice presidential debates were so anxiety-inducing. https://www.wired.com/story/why-these-cursed-debates-made-you-feel-so-upset/

October 8, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why Doesn’t the Earth Have a Bunch of Mini Moons? To answer this question (and try to predict how an object called 2020 SO might behave), let’s take a look at something called the Three-Body Problem.  https://www.wired.com/story/why-doesnt-the-earth-have-bunch-mini-moons/

October 8, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Could Biden Rebuild the Economy by Funding Green Energy? When he was VP, Biden helped turn the 2008 financial crisis into an era of environmental funding. Here’s what he could do if he gets another shot. https://www.wired.com/story/could-biden-rebuild-the-economy-by-funding-green-energy/

October 7, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Superspreading Presidency of Donald Trump Covid-19 infects people in “bursts” like the one at the White House, and this administration hasn’t just made that easier—it made it inevitable. https://www.wired.com/story/the-superspreading-presidency-of-donald-trump/

October 7, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Global Data Effort Probes Whether Covid Causes Diabetes Dozens of case reports have hinted that the coronavirus might trigger the onset of diabetes in people with no history of the disease. https://www.wired.com/story/a-global-data-effort-probes-whether-covid-causes-diabetes/

October 6, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Neutrino Detectors Could Be Used to Spot Nuclear Rogues In theory, the particles could reveal whether a reactor is building up plutonium for weapons. US energy experts are starting to take the idea seriously. https://www.wired.com/story/neutrino-detectors-could-be-used-to-spot-nuclear-rogues/

October 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Wire Inspired a Fake Turtle Egg That Spies on Poachers Scientists 3D-printed sea turtle eggs and stuffed transmitters inside. When poachers pulled them out of nests, the devices tracked their every move. https://www.wired.com/story/the-wire-inspired-a-fake-turtle-egg-that-spies-on-poachers/

October 5, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Common Plant Virus Is an Unlikely Ally in the War on Cancer Researchers have seen promising results by injecting dog and mouse tumors with the cowpea mosaic virus. Now they’re aiming for a human trial. https://www.wired.com/story/a-common-plant-virus-is-an-unlikely-ally-in-the-war-on-cancer/

October 4, 2020 | Author: Philip BallPhilip Ball At Last, Alchemy Arrives in a Burst of Light—From Lasers Researchers have shown how to effectively transform one material into another using a finely shaped laser pulse. https://www.wired.com/story/at-last-alchemy-arrives-in-a-burst-of-light-from-lasers/

October 3, 2020 | Author: Lisa CoxLisa Cox Australia’s Koalas Are ‘Sliding Towards Extinction’  The species is among 28 animals being assessed for potential upgrade of their threat status as their numbers plummet following sweeping bushfires. https://www.wired.com/story/australias-koalas-are-sliding-towards-extinction/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Adam RogersMegan Molteni and Adam Rogers How the Coronavirus Got to Donald Trump Covid-19’s path through the president’s world is an epidemiological mystery. We know why it spread, but not if it spread via a single infectious event. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-coronavirus-got-to-donald-trump/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Trump Tests Positive, Schools Navigate Reopening, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-tests-positive-schools-navigate-reopening-and-more-coronavirus-news/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight Who Did Trump Infect? Tracing His Contacts Is a Big Task The president, who tested positive for coronavirus on Thursday, has been at campaign rallies and fundraisers, potentially exposing hundreds of people. https://www.wired.com/story/who-trump-infect-tracing-contacts-big-task/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Clare BallJennifer Clare Ball Why Some Ecologists Worry About Rooftop Honey Bee Programs Urban beekeeping has given some scientists pause. They wonder if these efforts are really helping to save the bees—especially native species. https://www.wired.com/story/why-some-ecologists-worry-about-rooftop-honey-bee-programs/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers President Donald Trump Tests Positive for Covid-19 Some people get no symptoms or mild ones, and there are treatments for the severest cases. But the disease is risky for people who are older and overweight. https://www.wired.com/story/donald-trump-positive-coronavirus-covid-19/

October 2, 2020 | Author: Caitlin HarringtonCaitlin Harrington Your ‘Ethnicity Estimate’ Doesn’t Mean What You Think It Does DNA testing companies are rolling out algorithm updates, spotlighting the fickleness of ethnicity results, and perhaps reinforcing some troubling beliefs. https://www.wired.com/story/your-ethnicity-estimate-doesnt-mean-what-you-think-it-does/

October 1, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Power Does It Take to Do the Red Bull 400 Hill Run? 400 meters. A 37-degree incline. Turns out humans are capable of superhuman power outputs—if only for a short time. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-energy-to-do-the-red-bull-400-hill-run/

October 1, 2020 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman This Congressperson Wants to Rev Up Covid Testing Mikie Sherrill’s new bill would tie federal reimbursement to testing result times—and reward labs for extra quick turnarounds. https://www.wired.com/story/speedy-act-covid-19-faster-testing-results/

October 1, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What Does It Mean If a Vaccine Is ‘Successful’? The pharma companies are all using different playbooks to test their Covid-19 shots, so the first team to claim victory may not have the best formula. https://www.wired.com/story/what-does-it-mean-if-a-vaccine-is-successful/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins WIRED25 Day 3: Look at Problems in a New Way Guests like Anthony Fauci, Lisa Piccirillo, Patrice Peck, and Audrey Tang discussed how to puzzle through seemingly intractable situations. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-day3-summary/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Taiwan’s Digital Minister Knows How to Crush Covid-19: Trust On day three of WIRED25, Audrey Tang explains how the Asian nation used open data and transparent governance to empower its citizens to code their own way out of a pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-day3-audrey-tang-taiwan/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Debate Was a Disaster. But Hey, Climate Change Came Up The good news: The presidential debate addressed global warming. The bad news: Trump dodged it, especially when it came to wildfires. https://www.wired.com/story/the-debate-was-a-disaster-but-hey-climate-change-came-up/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Anthony Fauci Has Some Very Good Reasons to Be Optimistic On day three of WIRED25, the public-health rock star emphasized the importance of masks, distancing, handwashing … and a positive outlook. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-day3-anthony-fauci/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Coronavirus Dashboard Creator Has a New Target: Elections On day three of WIRED25, coder Avi Schiffmann talks about his plans for a site that aggregates candidates’ positions—in a way users can understand. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-day3-avi-shiffmann-coronavirus-dashboard/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler In an Odd Twist, Cleaner Air in China May Mean a Warmer Earth Coal plant upgrades led to a dramatic reduction in sulfur dioxide emissions. But those particles also help reflect solar heat away from the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/in-an-odd-twist-cleaner-air-in-china-may-mean-a-warmer-earth/

September 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel DuaneDaniel Duane The West’s Infernos Are Melting Our Sense of How Fire Works 42,000-foot plumes of ash. 143-mph firenadoes. 1,500-degree heat. These wildfires are a new kind of hell on earth, and scientists are racing to learn its rules. https://www.wired.com/story/west-coast-california-wildfire-infernos/

September 29, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Fish Form Social Networks—and They’re Actually Good New models of coral reefs show how fish species communicate with one another. The findings may well help save these threatened ecosystems. https://www.wired.com/story/fish-form-social-networks-and-theyre-actually-good/

September 29, 2020 | Author: Michelle KonstantinovskyMichelle Konstantinovsky During Covid, Eating Disorder Patients Turn to Apps Anorexia, bulimia, and binge eating patients are facing novel challenges as in-person care is on hold. Can tech tools fill in the treatment gaps? https://www.wired.com/story/during-covid-eating-disorder-patients-turn-to-apps/

September 28, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Could the National HIV Strategy Help Guide the Covid Fight? The Trump administration hasn’t created a comprehensive plan for battling the pandemic. Some researchers propose borrowing one from the past. https://www.wired.com/story/could-the-national-hiv-strategy-help-guide-the-covid-fight/

September 28, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber A School Ran a Simulation of the Pandemic—Before the Pandemic A Florida middle school has staged mock outbreaks for years to teach science and civics. Last December’s lesson was an uncanny harbinger of Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/a-school-ran-a-simulation-of-the-pandemic-before-the-pandemic/

September 27, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Scientists May Have Found a Material for Building on Mars Using simple chemistry, the organic polymer chitin can be transformed into a viable substance for creating tools and habitats on the Red Planet. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-may-have-found-a-material-for-building-on-mars/

September 27, 2020 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Is Dark Matter Just Black Holes Made During the Big Bang? Stephen Hawking once proposed that unseen “primordial” black holes might be the hidden dark matter. A series of new studies shows how it can work. https://www.wired.com/story/is-dark-matter-just-black-holes-made-during-the-big-bang/

September 26, 2020 | Author: Oliver MilmanOliver Milman Some Cities Are Plotting a ‘Green Recovery’ After Covid-19 Cities like Los Angeles, Seattle, and New Orleans are aiming to tackle another, longer-term emergency: the climate crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/some-cities-are-plotting-a-green-recovery-after-covid-19/

September 26, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Here’s How You Can ‘See’ Molecules—on a Whole ’Nother Planet Scientists picked up signs of phosphene on Venus by using a technique called rotational spectroscopy. It works like this.  https://www.wired.com/story/heres-how-you-can-see-molecules-on-a-whole-nother-planet/

September 25, 2020 | Author: Eve SneiderEve Sneider Covid Vaccines in Phase III, New Risk Calculators, and More Coronavirus News Catch up on the most important updates from this week. https://www.wired.com/story/more-covid-vaccines-in-phase-iii-new-risk-calculators-and-more/

September 25, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Why Is It So Hard to Study Covid-Related Smell Loss? Patients have long reported the sudden inability to smell. But restrictions on in-person exams are complicating efforts to figure out what’s going on. https://www.wired.com/story/why-is-it-so-hard-to-study-covid-related-smell-loss/

September 24, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How the Pandemic Transformed This Songbird’s Call When the San Francisco Bay Area locked down, urban noise levels plummeted. In response, the white-crowned sparrow changed its tune. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-pandemic-transformed-this-songbirds-call/

September 24, 2020 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman There Are No Excuses Left for Leaving Climate Change Out of the Debates The West is on fire, the Gulf Coast is under water, and voters want candidates to talk about the environment. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-biden-debate-without-climate-change-inexcusable/

September 24, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can a Genetically Modified Bug Combat a Global Farm Plague? Biotech company Oxitec has created a caterpillar with self-destructing eggs in an attempt to curb agricultural damage. But will other pests simply move in? https://www.wired.com/story/can-a-genetically-modified-bug-combat-a-global-farm-plague/

September 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet Curly, the Curling Robot That Beats the Pros Curling is one of the world’s most precise sports. An ice-going, stone-throwing robot just mastered it.  https://www.wired.com/story/meet-curly-the-curling-robot-that-beats-the-pros/

September 23, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Cool Physics of a Supersonic Baseball For one thing, let’s build a model of air drag and how it affects the ball differently when it’s traveling faster and slower than the speed of sound. https://www.wired.com/story/cool-physics-supersonic-baseball/

September 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Where Was the Battery at Tesla’s Battery Day? Elon Musk made big promises at Tesla’s highly anticipated event. But a prototype never appeared, and it was unclear what the company had actually achieved. https://www.wired.com/story/where-was-the-battery-at-teslas-battery-day/

September 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to Watch Tesla’s Battery Day Event—and What to Expect After months of delays, Tesla’s much-hyped Battery Day is finally upon us. Here’s what the company might reveal. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-teslas-battery-day-event-and-what-to-expect/

September 22, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen To Make Fairer AI, Physicists Peer Inside Its Black Box After repurposing facial recognition and deepfake tech to study galaxies and the Higgs boson, physicists think they can help shape the responsible use of AI. https://www.wired.com/story/to-make-fairer-ai-physicists-peer-inside-its-black-box/

September 22, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Instagram’s Founders Explain Their Covid-Charting Obsession In their first post-Facebook project, Kevin Systrom and Mike Krieger built rt.live, which state officials can use to plan their reopening. https://www.wired.com/story/instagrams-founders-explain-their-covid-charting-obsession/

September 22, 2020 | Author: Emily WillinghamEmily Willingham Does a Millipede Have a Penis? Well … Define ‘Penis’ From gonopods to pedipalps, nature has a lot of ways to get gametes where they need to go. https://www.wired.com/story/does-spider-have-penis-well-define-penis/

September 21, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica A New Tool Detects Counterfeit Whiskey—Without Wasting a Drop Bogus booze has been infiltrating the market, so physicists found a way to test for authenticity while keeping the precious bottles sealed. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-tool-detects-counterfeit-whisky-without-wasting-a-drop/

September 21, 2020 | Author: Gayathri VaidyanathanGayathri Vaidyanathan Could a Century-Old TB Shot Protect Against Other Respiratory Diseases? A trial in Greece shows a long-used tuberculosis vaccine may cut respiratory infections, raising hopes for similar protection against Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/could-a-century-old-tb-shot-protect-against-other-respiratory-diseases/

September 21, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Colds Nearly Vanished Under Lockdown. Now They’re Coming Back The return of non-Covid respiratory illnesses is putting a new strain on testing supplies around the world—and is a preview of what’s in store for the US. https://www.wired.com/story/colds-nearly-vanished-under-lockdown-now-theyre-coming-back/

September 20, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Mathematical ‘Hocus-Pocus’ Saved Particle Physics Renormalization, a technique that helps bridge the big and the small, has become perhaps the single most important advance in theoretical physics in 50 years. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematical-hocus-pocus-saved-particle-physics/

September 19, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Mathematicians May Have Figured Out How ‘Stone Forests’ Form An NYU team thinks it’s finally unlocked the secret to how these mysterious landforms get their interesting shape. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-may-have-figured-out-how-stone-forests-form/

September 19, 2020 | Author: Phoebe WestonPhoebe Weston What’s Causing the Mass Bird Die-Off in the Southwest? Thousands of migrating birds have died, perhaps starved by drier conditions related to climate change or by having to fly inland to avoid wildfire smoke. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-causing-the-mass-bird-die-off-in-the-southwest/

September 19, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The 943-Dimensional Chess of a Trustworthy Covid-19 Vaccine Scientists want public confidence. The White House wants an October Surprise. The FDA wants to avoid looking political. Big Pharma wants a win. You’re in the middle. https://www.wired.com/story/the-943-dimensional-chess-of-a-trustworthy-covid-19-vaccine/

September 18, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What’s in Wildfire Smoke, and How Dangerous Is It? Blazes on the West Coast are spewing a haze clear across the country. Along the way, the complex chemistry of what we inhale gets even more complex. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-in-wildfire-smoke-and-how-dangerous-is-it/

September 18, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Rocket Lab Could Beat NASA Back to Venus in the Search for ET After years of neglect, Earth’s other neighbor is back in the spotlight following a major discovery. A private rocket company may be the first to visit. https://www.wired.com/story/rocket-lab-could-beat-nasa-back-to-venus-in-the-search-for-et/

September 17, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The NIH Launches a Global Hunt for Animal-to-Human Diseases It’s a reversal for an administration that’s been loath to prepare for pandemics or cooperate with China, where Covid-19 jumped from wildlife to people. https://www.wired.com/story/the-nih-launches-a-global-hunt-for-animal-to-human-diseases/

September 17, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Save the Whales? Eavesdrop on Their Calls A clever new system called Whale Safe listens for the cetacean chorus to alert vessels to slow down, potentially preventing deadly ship strikes. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-save-the-whales-eavesdrop-on-their-calls/

September 17, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Hey Students! Here’s How to Deal With School in a Pandemic Obviously this situation sucks for everyone, but I have a few tips to help you make the most of a bad situation. (Also, don’t cheat.)  https://www.wired.com/story/hey-students-heres-how-deal-with-school-pandemic/

September 16, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Netflix’s Challenger Is a Gripping Look at NASA in Crisis A new four-part documentary about the ill-fated Challenger mission highlights the risk of putting bureaucracy before science in human spaceflight https://www.wired.com/story/netflixs-challenger-is-a-gripping-look-at-nasa-in-crisis/

September 16, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber A Utah Company Claims It Invented Contact Tracing Tech Blyncsy wants states using Apple and Google technology to pay it $1 per resident. It may not win, but the patent tussle could deter others from adopting apps. https://www.wired.com/story/utah-company-claims-invented-contact-tracing-tech/

September 16, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers America’s Top Science Journal Has Had It With Trump The editor of Science has abandoned staid academic-speak to take on falsehoods in the White House—decorum be damned. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-top-science-journal-has-had-it-with-trump/

September 15, 2020 | Author: Terry Virts Terry Virts How to Leave Space and (Safely) Crash Back Down to Earth A former astronaut explains what it’s like to pilot the Space Shuttle onto the runway … and boink back down to the ground on the Soyuz. https://www.wired.com/story/how-leave-space-safely-crash-back-down-earth/

September 15, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni If You’ve Just Had Covid, Exercise Might Not Be Good for You A growing number of studies are raising concerns about the coronavirus’ long-term effects on the heart. Athletes especially need to heed the warnings. https://www.wired.com/story/if-youve-just-had-covid-exercise-might-not-be-good-for-you/

September 15, 2020 | Author: Keith GilloglyKeith Gillogly Could Breathalyzers Make Covid Testing Quicker and Easier? A breath test would offer advantages over throat and nose swabs, but the technology is novel, and early trials with volunteers are still ongoing. https://www.wired.com/story/could-breathalyzers-make-covid-testing-quicker-and-easier/

September 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Antarctic Glaciers Are Growing Unstable Above and Below Water New studies show fractures on surface ice and warm seawater melting the ice from underneath. That’s a harbinger of a coming collapse—and sea level rise. https://www.wired.com/story/antarctic-glaciers-are-growing-unstable-above-and-below-water/

September 14, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Happens If You Smash a Boat Into a Whale? On the show The Boys, a speedboat smashes into a cetacean and the humans emerge unscathed. Could this happen in real life? https://www.wired.com/story/what-happens-if-you-collide-boat-with-whale/

September 14, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Grief Is Burning Across the American West Climate change is making wildfires bigger, fiercer, and deadlier, fueling a new kind of despair on the West Coast—and beyond. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-grief-is-burning-across-the-american-west/

September 13, 2020 | Author: Steve NadisSteve Nadis Mathematicians Open a New Front on an Ancient Number Problem For millennia, many have wondered whether odd perfect numbers exist. Insight could come from studying the next best things. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-open-a-new-front-on-an-ancient-number-problem/

September 12, 2020 | Author: Sofia Quaglia Sofia Quaglia Asbestos Removal Is a Hard Job, but Covid-19 Makes It Harder Getting rid of asbestos is good for public health, but it’s risky for abatement workers, whose occupational risks make them vulnerable to Covid-19 complications. https://www.wired.com/story/asbestos-removal-is-a-hard-job-but-covid-19-makes-it-harder/

September 11, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Does a Sturgis-Sized Crowd Affect Covid? It’s Complicated That paper on the South Dakota motorcycle rally had flaws, but it’s not useless. And it shows the US needs better data collection. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-do-crowds-contribute-to-covid-its-complicated/

September 11, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Blood Centers Are Barely Meeting Convalescent Plasma Demand Despite a lack of scientific studies on its efficacy for Covid-19, interest in the treatment has surged alongside case numbers. https://www.wired.com/story/blood-centers-are-barely-meeting-convalescent-plasma-demand/

September 10, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Those Orange Western Skies and the Science of Light Sure, it was wildfire smoke that made parts of California and Oregon change hue. But inside that smoke was alchemy—the chemistry and physics of molecules and wavelengths. https://www.wired.com/story/those-orange-western-skies-and-the-science-of-light/

September 9, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Bay Area Just Turned Orange. All Eyes Are on PurpleAir Catastrophic wildfires are spewing smoke all over the West Coast. This website lets you track the respiratory crisis in real time—with a few caveats. https://www.wired.com/story/bay-area-just-turned-orange-all-eyes-on-purpleair/

September 9, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Let’s Calculate How Many Balloons David Blaine Needed to Float I’m not saying you should lift yourself up into the air with helium, but if you did, you’d need to take pressure, density, and a few other things into account. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-calculate-how-many-balloons-david-blaine-needs-float/

September 9, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Is Lightning-Fast Plasma the Key to a Cleaner Car Engine? Researchers have long experimented with “lean burn” engines, which boost efficiency and reduce the emissions from combustion. But getting them to ignite is tricky. https://www.wired.com/story/is-lightning-fast-plasma-the-key-to-a-cleaner-car-engine/

September 8, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Mental Health in the US is Suffering—Will It Go Back to Normal? Covid-19 has left lots of people feeling anxious and depressed. But it’s hard to untangle whether this is a normal response to a difficult situation or actual pathology. https://www.wired.com/story/mental-health-in-the-us-is-suffering-will-it-go-back-to-normal/

September 8, 2020 | Author: Gregory Barber, Will KnightGregory Barber and Will Knight Why Contact-Tracing Apps Haven’t Slowed Covid-19 in the US Lack of coordination, test shortages, and mistrust of technology have hobbled what looked like a promising innovation.  https://www.wired.com/story/why-contact-tracing-apps-not-slowed-covid-us/

September 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Smartphone Can Tell If You’re Drunk-Walking In a recent study, scientists could tell if people were intoxicated just by looking at their phones’ motion data. https://www.wired.com/story/your-smartphone-can-tell-if-youre-drunk-walking/

September 6, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich Mathematicians Report New Discovery About the Dodecahedron Starting at a corner, could you walk around the surface of this Platonic solid without crossing other corners? To get the answer, you need an 81-holed doughnut. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-report-new-discovery-about-the-dodecahedron/

September 6, 2020 | Author: Helen SantoroHelen Santoro Doctors and Nurses Take to TikTok to Fight Covid Myths “We can treat only one patient at a time, but if we can get a message out there that can hit thousands or hundreds of thousands, then we can change their thoughts.” https://www.wired.com/story/doctors-nurses-tiktok-fight-covid-myths/

September 5, 2020 | Author: Nicola DavisNicola Davis Climate Change Drove the American Mastodon to Extinction They migrated north to escape the heat but lost their genetic diversity, making them vulnerable to extinction. Today, some species face the same problem. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-drove-the-american-mastodon-to-extinction/

September 4, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Neuralink Is Impressive Tech, Wrapped in Musk Hype Cool research tool? Definitely. A way to remotely control a computer or a prosthetic? Sure. But reading minds and storing memories? Not so fast. https://www.wired.com/story/neuralink-is-impressive-tech-wrapped-in-musk-hype/

September 3, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Human Embryo Gene Editing Gets a Road Map—Not a Green Light After the 2018 “Crispr baby” scandal, a global commission assessed the technology and set strict criteria for moving it toward clinical trials. https://www.wired.com/story/human-embryo-gene-editing-gets-a-road-map-not-a-green-light/

September 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Could a Tree Help Find a Decaying Corpse Nearby? On a “body farm,” researchers are exploring whether the nutrients from human cadavers can change the look of plants, which authorities might use to locate missing persons. https://www.wired.com/story/could-a-tree-signal-if-a-corpse-is-decaying/

September 3, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite Big Tech Companies Want to Help Get You Back in the Office Alphabet, Microsoft, and Salesforce are offering services to track employees, arrange tests, and record results—all while most of their staffers are remote. https://www.wired.com/story/big-tech-help-get-you-back-office/

September 2, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Beloved Blue Jeans Are Polluting the Ocean—Big Time When you wash denim, tiny fibers shed and flow into the environment. Scientists just found that Arctic waters are now loaded with little bits of jeans. https://www.wired.com/story/your-blue-jeans-are-polluting-the-ocean/

September 2, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Flu Season and Covid-19 Are About to Collide. Now What? Hospitals in the US are already stressed. Now, they must brace for a wave of flu patients needing more beds, lab tests, and ventilators. https://www.wired.com/story/flu-season-and-covid-19-are-about-to-collide-now-what/

September 1, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Google and Apple Change Tactics on Contact Tracing Tech The companies will handle more of the technology for notifying people who may have been exposed to the coronavirus. Privacy won’t be affected, they say.  https://www.wired.com/story/google-apple-change-tactics-contact-tracing-tech/

September 1, 2020 | Author: Louise MatsakisLouise Matsakis A Grim Reality of Reopening: More Mold Unoccupied buildings, abandoned during the coronavirus shutdowns, give fungi a great opportunity to move in. https://www.wired.com/story/grim-reality-reopening-more-mold-offices-schools-houses/

September 1, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can a Bubble Net Stop a Hurricane? Some Norwegians Think So An idea to use underwater bubbles to cool oceans and deflate oncoming storms is the latest in a series of far-out schemes for controlling the weather. https://www.wired.com/story/can-a-bubble-net-stop-a-hurricane-some-norwegians-think-so/

August 31, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Beautiful Yet Grim Map Shows How Wildfire Smoke Spreads California’s blazes have sent a haze across the United States. An experimental model shows where that cloud ends up. https://www.wired.com/story/map-shows-how-wildfire-smoke-spreads/

August 31, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Are Radioactive Diamond Batteries a Cure for Nuclear Waste? Researchers are developing a new battery powered by lab-grown gems made from reformed nuclear waste. If it works, it will last thousands of years. https://www.wired.com/story/are-radioactive-diamond-batteries-a-cure-for-nuclear-waste/

August 30, 2020 | Author: Marcus WooMarcus Woo These New Shape-Shifting Materials Get Super Cool, Super Fast Shape memory alloys and a kind of plastic crystal chill quickly under force or pressure. They could lead to eco-friendly fridges and air conditioners. https://www.wired.com/story/these-new-shape-shifting-materials-get-super-cool-super-fast/

August 29, 2020 | Author: Tom PhilpottTom Philpott The Biblical Flood That Will Drown California The Great Flood of 1861–1862 was a preview of what scientists expect to see again, and soon. https://www.wired.com/story/the-biblical-flood-that-will-drown-california/

August 28, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Can People Without Symptoms Get Tested for Covid? Who Knows Top health officials have issued contradictory statements, and the CDC’s newest guidance limiting testing comes just as the Trump Administration invests in rapid tests. https://www.wired.com/story/can-people-without-symptoms-get-tested-for-covid-who-knows/

August 28, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins What Virtual Reality for Flies Teaches Us About Human Vision Optical illusions can be a useful tool for studying how we see stuff, but it’s hard to uncover just how they work. Unless, that is, you show them to flies. https://www.wired.com/story/what-virtual-reality-for-flies-teaches-us-about-human-vision/

August 28, 2020 | Author: Arielle PardesArielle Pardes Elon Musk Is About to Show Off His Neuralink Brain Implant Musk tweeted that his “V2” update will blow our minds. But how close is he to putting computer chips in them? https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-neuralink-brain-implant-v2-demo/

August 27, 2020 | Author: Sandy Ong, WIRED UKSandy Ong, WIRED UK Scientists Want to Ditch Formula for Lab-Grown Breast Milk Formula has come a long way, but it still lacks many nutrients and takes a toll on the environment. A few companies are hoping to provide an alternative. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-want-to-ditch-formula-for-lab-grown-breast-milk/

August 27, 2020 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright The Pandemic Could Derail a Generation of Young Scientists Lost funding, lab access, and publishing opportunities mean PhD students and postdocs are uniquely vulnerable. It doesn’t bode well for the field’s future. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-could-derail-a-generation-of-young-scientists/

August 26, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Hurricane Laura’s Storm Surge Could Be ‘Unsurvivable’ The deadliest aspect of a hurricane is the storm surge. And Louisiana and Texas are about to get hit with a massive wall of water. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-laura-storm-surge-could-be-unsurvivable/

August 26, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A California Wildfire Nearly Destroyed the Historic Lick Observatory The state’s apocalyptic blazes have burned 2,000 square miles in 10 days. Here’s how they almost claimed a 130-year-old astronomical icon. https://www.wired.com/story/california-wildfire-historic-lick-observatory/

August 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Ball of Bacteria Survived for 3 Years … in Space! New research from the Japanese Tanpopo mission adds to scientists’ understanding of how living organisms can endure the hostile environment. https://www.wired.com/story/a-ball-of-bacteria-survived-for-3-years-in-space/

August 25, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Gregory BarberMegan Molteni and Gregory Barber The First Repeat Covid-19 Infection Case Isn’t All Bad News A report from Hong Kong provides the first credible evidence that it’s possible to catch the virus twice. Some immunologists are breathing a sigh of relief. https://www.wired.com/story/the-first-repeat-covid-19-infection-case-isnt-all-bad-news/

August 25, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler A Huge Covid-19 Natural Experiment Is Underway—in Classrooms As K-12 students head back to school, epidemiologists are watching for clues about how kids spread the virus, and what can stop it. https://www.wired.com/story/a-huge-covid-19-natural-experiment-is-underway-in-classrooms/

August 24, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Inside the Sprint to Map the Murder Hornet Genome The arrival of the insect in the US sent scientists racing to unravel its DNA, looking for clues to where it came from and how to stop it from sticking around. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-sprint-to-map-the-murder-hornet-genome/

August 24, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode How Animal Activists Exposed a Pig Farm’s Brutal Covid-19 Culling In the second part of a Get WIRED series, we go inside one man’s mission to bring to light one of factory farming’s most notorious practices. https://www.wired.com/story/get-wired-podcast-6-ventilation-shutdown-factory-farms/

August 24, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite Covid Hits Minorities Hardest, but Data Often Doesn’t Show It Many states are not collecting the race or ethnicity of coronavirus patients, which can make it harder to know the true impact on low-income communities. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-hits-minorities-hardest-data-doesnt-show/

August 24, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A Postal Slowdown Is Scary for Those Who Get Meds By Mail Many seniors, veterans, and chronically ill people rely on the USPS for prescriptions and medical supplies. During Covid-19, they can’t just go to a drugstore. https://www.wired.com/story/a-postal-slowdown-is-scary-for-those-who-get-meds-by-mail/

August 23, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The FDA Just OK’d Emergency Use of Plasma for Covid-19 Sick people can already get the treatment, and the data is inconclusive. But the president is super into it. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-just-okd-emergency-use-of-plasma-for-covid-19/

August 23, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Fleet of Computers Helps Settle a 90-Year-Old Math Problem By translating Ott-Heinrich Keller’s conjecture into a computer-friendly search, researchers confirmed a conjecture about seven-dimensional space. https://www.wired.com/story/a-fleet-of-computers-helps-settle-a-90-year-old-math-problem/

August 22, 2020 | Author: Maddie StoneMaddie Stone Solar Panels Are Starting to Die, Leaving Behind Toxic Trash Photovoltaic panels are a boon for clean energy but are tricky to recycle. As the oldest ones expire, get ready for a solar e-waste glut. https://www.wired.com/story/solar-panels-are-starting-to-die-leaving-behind-toxic-trash/

August 21, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon California Wildfires Can Create Their Own Terrifying Weather Sparked by freak thunderstorms, the blazes changed wind patterns and could potentially lead to fire tornadoes and pyrocumulonimbus clouds. https://www.wired.com/story/california-wildfires-can-create-terrifying-weather/

August 21, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers 97,000 People Got Convalescent Plasma. Who Knows if It Works? A treatment made from the blood of recovered Covid-19 patients seemed promising in March. Today … well, it’s still just promising. https://www.wired.com/story/97000-people-got-convalescent-plasma-who-knows-if-it-works/

August 21, 2020 | Author: Erin SchulteErin Schulte This Team Made a $500 Ventilator—but How Will It Be Used? Fears of a ventilator shortage inspired doctors and engineers to improvise new designs. Inside the race to build a cheap, reliable machine. https://www.wired.com/story/team-made-dollar500-ventilator-may-never-used/

August 20, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Ever Seen Inside a Mummified Cat? Well Now You Have Here’s how scientists used a fancy microCT scanner to peer inside the remains of a cat, bird, and snake from ancient Egypt.  https://www.wired.com/story/see-inside-a-mummified-ancient-egyptian-cat/

August 20, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon California’s Wildfire and Covid-19 Disasters Just Collided Rare thunderstorms have peppered the California landscape with conflagrations, pouring smoke into the Bay Area—all as the state struggles with the pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-wildfire-and-covid-19-disasters-just-collided/

August 19, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna New Data on How Many Kids Got That Covid Mystery Illness A few young patients also develop strange inflammatory symptoms. A CDC report sheds light on how widespread this syndrome is, and what it could mean for vaccines. https://www.wired.com/story/new-data-on-how-many-kids-got-that-covid-mystery-illness/

August 19, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A New Study Suggests a Possible Disease Vector: Germy Dust Since the pandemic’s beginning, scientists have argued over how respiratory viruses can spread. Now an experiment with guinea pigs and influenza is adding a new wrinkle. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-study-suggests-a-possible-disease-vector-germy-dust/

August 18, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wait, How Much Microplastic Is Swirling in the Atlantic? Scientists calculate that the top 200 meters of ocean alone contains up to 21 million metric tons of plastic. And that wasn’t even counting microfibers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-microplastic-is-swirling-in-the-atlantic/

August 17, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus This Cobalt-Free Battery Is Good for the Planet—and It Actually Works Reducing the cobalt content in lithium-ion batteries is good for the environment, human rights, and maybe even the performance of the battery itself. https://www.wired.com/story/this-cobalt-free-battery-is-good-for-the-planet-and-it-actually-works/

August 17, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins A Radical New Model of the Brain Illuminates Its Wiring Network neuroscience could revolutionize how we understand the brain—and  change our approach to neurological and psychiatric disorders. https://www.wired.com/story/a-radical-new-model-of-the-brain-illuminates-its-wiring/

August 17, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode VR Puts Viewers Inside the Grisly Reality of Factory Farms In the first of a two-part Get WIRED podcast series, we look at the radical, virtual-reality-based tactics of animal-rights group Direct Action Everywhere. https://www.wired.com/story/get-wired-podcast-5-wayne-hsiung-direct-action-everywhere/

August 16, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich A Landmark Math Proof Clears a Hurdle in the Top Erdős Conjecture Two mathematicians have proved the first leg of the Hungarian scholar’s all-time favorite problem about number patterns. https://www.wired.com/story/a-landmark-math-proof-clears-a-hurdle-in-the-top-erdos-conjecture/

August 15, 2020 | Author: Shannon OsakaShannon Osaka Want to Save Lives? Name Heat Waves Like Hurricanes As temperatures soar into the the triple digits, the Extreme Heat Resilience Alliance says such names will spark public awareness and encourage safety measures. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-save-lives-name-heat-waves-like-hurricanes/

August 14, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Derechos Are So Devilishly Difficult to Predict The destructive storms, with winds over 75 mph, are often compared to inland hurricanes. But unlike a hurricane, a derecho can come out of nowhere. https://www.wired.com/story/why-derechos-are-so-devilishly-difficult-to-predict/

August 14, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Making a Covid-19 Vaccine Is Hard. Making One for Kids Is Harder As researchers deepen their understanding of children’s role in the pandemic, some argue they are being overlooked in the race to a vaccine. https://www.wired.com/story/making-a-covid-19-vaccine-is-hard-making-one-for-kids-is-harder/

August 13, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Should We Conserve Parasites? Apparently, Yes A group of ecologists and biologists say the world’s ticks, leeches, and tapeworms need love and conservation, too. Now they’ve got a 12-point plan. https://www.wired.com/story/should-we-conserve-parasites-apparently-yes/

August 12, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Iconic Arecibo Telescope Goes Quiet After Major Damage A cable cut a large gash into the radio telescope this week and it’s uncertain when it will be back in working order. https://www.wired.com/story/the-iconic-arecibo-telescope-goes-quiet-after-major-damage/

August 12, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon AI Magic Makes Century-Old Films Look New Denis Shiryaev uses algorithms to colorize and sharpen old movies, bumping them up to a smooth 60 frames per second. The result is a stunning glimpse at the past. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-magic-makes-century-old-films-look-new/

August 12, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientists Put Masks to the Test—With a Cell Phone and a Laser Not all face coverings—like masks, bandanas, and neck gaiters—are equally good at blocking germs. A new, low-cost testing device literally illuminates the difference. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-put-masks-to-the-test-with-an-iphone-and-a-laser/

August 11, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A New Survey Links Vaping to Higher Covid-19 Risk A Stanford University report shows that teens and young adults who use e-cigarettes are five to seven times more likely to test positive for the virus. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-survey-links-vaping-to-higher-covid-19-risk/

August 11, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Solve the Covid-19 Testing Crunch, Win $5 Million For decades, governments and private organizations like Xprize have put up prizes to spur scientific innovation. But how much can contests help in a crisis? https://www.wired.com/story/solve-the-covid-19-testing-crunch-win-dollar5-million/

August 11, 2020 | Author: Daniel DuaneDaniel Duane San Francisco Was Uniquely Prepared for Covid-19  Why did an American city beset by inequality and dysfunction face the onset of the pandemic so well? Because history left it ready for this moment. https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-uniquely-prepared-covid-19/

August 10, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Why Do Solar Farms Kill Birds? Call in the AI Bird Watcher Solar facilities kill tens of thousands of birds every year, and no one is quite sure why. An artificial-intelligence-powered birder is on the case. https://www.wired.com/story/why-do-solar-farms-kill-birds-call-in-the-ai-bird-watcher/

August 10, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode Bill Gates Is Still Optimistic On the Get WIRED podcast, the philanthropist and Microsoft cofounder tackles everything from Covid-19 vaccine development to TikTok. https://www.wired.com/story/get-wired-podcast-4-bill-gates/

August 10, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Covid-19 Drug Research Is a Big Huge Mess Scientists have been studying treatments for the disease for half a year. Lack of coordination and a broken system mean they still don’t know very much. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-drug-research-is-a-big-huge-mess/

August 9, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood What If the Big Bang Was Actually a Big Bounce? New computer simulations model an alternate way of thinking about the cosmos: as a cyclic universe that has no beginning or end. https://www.wired.com/story/what-if-the-big-bang-was-actually-a-big-bounce/

August 8, 2020 | Author: Damian CarringtonDamian Carrington A Satellite Spots 11 New Emperor Penguin Colonies Good news! An orbiter saw signs of almost a dozen previously uncounted colonies in Antarctica, boosting known numbers for a threatened species. https://www.wired.com/story/a-satellite-spots-11-new-emperor-penguin-colonies/

August 7, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The End Is Nearer for ‘Forever Chemicals’ in Food Wrappers Your takeout may come with a dose of chemicals known as PFAS—but the FDA’s push to get rid of some of them will take five years. https://www.wired.com/story/the-end-is-nearer-for-forever-chemicals-in-food-wrappers/

August 7, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Bill Gates on Covid: Most US Tests Are ‘Completely Garbage’ The techie-turned-philanthropist on vaccines, Trump, and why social media is “a poisoned chalice.” https://www.wired.com/story/bill-gates-on-covid-most-us-tests-are-completely-garbage/

August 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Yes, Emissions Have Fallen. That Won’t Fix Climate Change The drop in carbon pollution will cool the planet only a tiny bit. So how about this: Revive the economy and the Earth by pouring money into green tech. https://www.wired.com/story/emissions-have-fallen-that-wont-fix-climate-change/

August 6, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Why Do Razor Blades Get Dull So Quickly?  An MIT team tackled the mystery of why something as soft as hair can erode a steel blade, hoping to figure out how to make shaving tools last longer. https://www.wired.com/story/why-do-razor-blades-dull-so-quickly/

August 6, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The US Is Disastrously Behind in Covid-19 Testing. Again With infections rampant in parts of the nation, backlogs are preventing people from getting timely test results, hampering efforts to contain the virus. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-is-disastrously-behind-in-covid-19-testing-again/

August 6, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Feds Want These Teams to Hack a Satellite—From Home Meet the hackers who, this weekend, will try to commandeer an actual orbiter as part of a Defcon contest hosted by the Air Force and the Defense Digital Service. https://www.wired.com/story/the-feds-want-these-teams-to-hack-a-satellite-from-home/

August 6, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Could a Janky, Jury-Rigged Air Purifier Help Fight Covid-19? Indoor-air experts think: Sure, maybe. Why the hell not? We convinced the CEO of an air filter company to give it a try. https://www.wired.com/story/could-a-janky-jury-rigged-air-purifier-help-fight-covid-19/

August 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Income Predicts How Well You Can Socially Distance America’s rich used to move around more than the poor. When Covid landed, that flipped: The wealthy now work remotely, while essential workers toil. https://www.wired.com/story/your-income-predicts-how-well-you-can-socially-distance/

August 4, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Summer Camp Covid-19 Outbreak Offers Back-to-School Lessons A CDC report from a Georgia hot spot illuminates just how easily kids can spread coronavirus, adding to our understanding of kids’ role in transmission. https://www.wired.com/story/a-summer-camp-covid-19-outbreak-offers-back-to-school-lessons/

August 4, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Should Governments Slap a Tax on Plastic? More than a billion tons of it could enter the environment in the next 20 years. It’s time, advocates say, to put a sin tax on single-use plastic. https://www.wired.com/story/should-governments-slap-a-tax-on-plastic/

August 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Frog Eats Beetle. Beetle Crawls Through Guts to Escape Regimbartia attenuata doesn’t take too kindly to being eaten. Once locked inside a frog’s maw, it turns around and starts heading for the exit. https://www.wired.com/story/frog-eats-beetle-beetle-crawls-through-guts/

August 3, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison What Poetry Means for Doctors and Patients During a Pandemic The poetry editor of The Journal of the American Medical Association talks about medicine, metaphor, and how literature can even improve patient outcomes. https://www.wired.com/story/what-poetry-means-for-doctors-and-patients-during-a-pandemic/

August 2, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Brings Astronauts Home Safely in a Historic First That’s a wrap on SpaceX’s crewed demo mission, which clears the way for the company to regularly launch astronauts for NASA. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-brings-astronauts-home-safely-in-a-historic-first/

August 2, 2020 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Archaeologists Have Found the Source of Stonehenge’s Boulders Modern scholars have only been able to speculate about where the huge stones came from—until now. https://www.wired.com/story/archaeologists-have-found-the-source-of-stonehenges-boulders/

August 2, 2020 | Author: Rodrigo Pérez OrtegaRodrigo Pérez Ortega Why Are Plants Green? The Answer Might Work on Any Planet A new model of photosynthesis points to an evolutionary principle governing light-harvesting organisms that might apply throughout the universe. https://www.wired.com/story/why-are-plants-green-the-answer-might-work-on-any-planet/

August 1, 2020 | Author: Michael SchulsonMichael Schulson What Can Ants and Bees Teach Us About Containing Disease? Social insects cooperate to curb the spread of pathogens. Maybe their systems of behavior can help human societies battling pandemics of our own. https://www.wired.com/story/what-can-ants-and-bees-teach-us-about-containing-disease/

August 1, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Grace HuckinsMegan Molteni and Grace Huckins The WIRED Guide to Crispr Everything you need to know about how scientists can repurpose a bacterial immune system to alter DNA, making everything from cheap insulin to extra starchy corn. https://www.wired.com/story/wired-guide-to-crispr/

July 31, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Anglerfish Deleted Its Immune System to Fuse With Its Mate Underwater “sexual parasitism” between male and female allows two bodies to become one. Now we know the reason why. https://www.wired.com/story/the-anglerfish-deleted-its-immune-system-to-fuse-with-its-mate/

July 31, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What the Science of Animal Networks Reveals About Protests The movement of demonstrators echoes the fluid collective responses of the animal world, as groups respond to threats and signal across large spaces. https://www.wired.com/story/what-the-science-of-animal-networks-reveals-about-protests/

July 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Just Launched Its New Perseverance Rover to Mars The new rover is its biggest, most autonomous yet and may lead us to the first signs of ancient life on the Red Planet. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-nasa-launch-its-new-perseverance-mars-rover/

July 30, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid-19 Data in the US Is an ‘Information Catastrophe’ The order to reroute CDC hospitalization figures raised accuracy concerns. But that’s just one of the problems with how the country collects health data. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-data-in-the-us-is-an-information-catastrophe/

July 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s Mars Rover Will Be Powered by US-Made Plutonium In 2015, Oak Ridge National Laboratory produced the first plutonium fuel in the US in nearly 30 years. Now it’s headed to another planet. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-mars-rover-will-be-powered-by-us-made-plutonium/

July 29, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Anthony Fauci Explains Why the US Still Hasn’t Beaten Covid The director of NIAID talks about vaccines, school reopenings, hostility toward science, and the lessons we’ll learn when (yes, when) we recover. https://www.wired.com/story/anthony-fauci-explains-why-the-us-still-hasnt-beaten-covid/

July 28, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Mad Scientists Revive 100-Million-Year-Old Microbes Researchers collected sediment thousands of feet deep, filtered out bacteria, and revived the cells. But fear not—the destruction of humanity by ancient microbes is not nigh. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-revive-100-million-year-old-microbes/

July 28, 2020 | Author: Victoria Turk, WIRED UKVictoria Turk, WIRED UK These 4 Covid-19 Vaccines Are Closest to Becoming Reality There are hundreds of trials currently in the works. Here’s everything you need to know about the ones edging ahead in the global race. https://www.wired.com/story/these-4-covid-19-vaccines-are-closest-to-becoming-reality/

July 27, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins A Study Finds Sex Differences in the Brain. Does It Matter? The NIH research connecting anatomy and sex chromosomes could shed light on mental disorders. But the topic is sensitive, and such findings are easy to misuse. https://www.wired.com/story/a-study-finds-sex-differences-in-the-brain-does-it-matter/

July 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Helicopter Ride Over Mars? NASA’s About to Give It a Shot “I see it as kind of a Wright brothers moment on another planet,” says the project’s chief engineer at JPL. https://www.wired.com/story/a-helicopter-ride-over-mars-nasas-about-to-give-it-a-shot/

July 27, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Some Countries Reopened Schools. What Did They Learn About Kids and Covid? Studies from around the world suggest that success depends on class size, distancing, the age of the students, and how prevalent the virus is locally. https://www.wired.com/story/some-countries-reopened-schools-what-did-they-learn-about-kids-and-covid/

July 26, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica The Sly Psychology Behind Magicians’ Card Tricks Is this your card? A recent study found that participants will select the suit or number they were primed to choose. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sly-psychology-behind-magicians-card-tricks/

July 26, 2020 | Author: Thomas LewtonThomas Lewton Looking for Gravitons? Check for the ‘Buzz’ The hypothetical particles are a cornerstone of quantum gravity theories, but they’re famously hard to observe. Yet maybe they create detectable ‘noise.’ https://www.wired.com/story/looking-for-gravitons-check-for-the-buzz/

July 25, 2020 | Author: Shreya DasguptaShreya Dasgupta In India, Modern Construction Threatens Prehistoric Sites The plots of land are key to the story of early human migration. But they’re rapidly disappearing as infrastructure and agriculture encroach. https://www.wired.com/story/in-india-modern-construction-threatens-prehistoric-sites/

July 24, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Rehab Centers Struggle as Covid-19 Drives Up Costs Drug and alcohol use has risen, but the pandemic could force some treatment centers out of business. https://www.wired.com/story/rehab-centers-struggle-as-covid-19-drives-up-costs/

July 24, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Crispr Calf Is Born. It’s Definitely a Boy UC Davis scientists spent years editing a sex-determining gene into bovine embryos. In April, Cosmo arrived—and his DNA reveals how far the field has to go. https://www.wired.com/story/a-crispr-calf-is-born-its-definitely-a-boy/

July 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon During Lockdowns, the Earth (Sort of) Stood Still Seismometers pick up human activity, like driving. When Covid arrived, scientists watched that global seismic noise plummet by 50 percent. https://www.wired.com/story/during-lockdowns-the-earth-sort-of-stood-still/

July 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Billion More Tons of Plastic Could Blanket Earth by 2040 Even with immediate action, 710 million metric tons of plastic will enter the environment in the next two decades, scientists show. Welcome to Plastic Planet. https://www.wired.com/story/billion-more-tons-of-plastic-could-blanket-earth/

July 23, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber A Wisconsin City Experiments With a Faster, DIY Covid-19 Test In a former boxing gym in Racine, firefighters are trying out a spit test that’s simpler and cheaper than PCR. Could it change how we screen for the virus? https://www.wired.com/story/a-wisconsin-city-experiments-with-a-faster-diy-covid-19-test/

July 23, 2020 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell Neuroscience Could Be the Key to Getting People to Wear Masks In a study, people responded to messages that resonated with them personally—up to a certain extent. The results could help shape responses to future pandemics. https://www.wired.com/story/neuroscience-key-people-wear-masks/

July 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to See Comet Neowise Before It’s Gone The comet will make its closest approach to Earth on Thursday before it fades into black. Here’s how you can catch a glimpse. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-see-comet-neowise-before-its-gone/

July 22, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen How Quickly Can Atoms Slip, Ghostlike, Through Barriers? A new experiment on how rapidly atoms can tunnel through a barricade revives a physics debate about how time passes on the quantum scale. https://www.wired.com/story/how-quickly-can-atoms-slip-ghost-like-through-barriers/

July 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus China’s First Mars Rover Launch Could Make History If the mission succeeds, China will become only the second country ever to deploy a rover on the surface of the Red Planet. https://www.wired.com/story/chinas-first-mars-rover-launch-could-make-history/

July 22, 2020 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK Everything You Need to Know About the Oxford Covid-19 Vaccine  Early results from the UK team show that its approach is safe and provokes an immune response. But that doesn’t mean it works. https://www.wired.com/story/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-oxford-covid-19-vaccine/

July 21, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How NASA Built a Self-Driving Car for Its Next Mars Mission It’s hard enough to get an autonomous vehicle to work on Earth. It’s even harder on another planet. https://www.wired.com/story/how-nasa-built-a-self-driving-car-for-its-next-mars-mission/

July 21, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna To Navigate Risk In a Pandemic, You Need a Color-Coded Chart Is going to the dentist more dangerous than grocery shopping? Public health groups want to help us weigh everyday risks with to easy-to-read guides. https://www.wired.com/story/to-navigate-risk-in-a-pandemic-you-need-a-color-coded-chart/

July 20, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Terrible Consequences of Australia’s Uber-Bushfires Scientists calculate that the unprecedented wildfires burned 37,500 square miles. For already endangered species, the conflagration may have spelled doom. https://www.wired.com/story/the-terrible-consequences-of-australias-uber-bushfires/

July 20, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What Does It Mean to Say a New Drug ‘Works’? Covid-19 is a new disease. Remdesivir is an experimental drug. How can scientists tell if it’s successful while the world shifts around them? https://www.wired.com/story/what-does-it-mean-to-say-a-new-drug-works/

July 19, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover How Gödel’s Proof Works His incompleteness theorems destroyed the search for a mathematical theory of everything. Nearly a century later, we’re still coming to grips with the consequences. https://www.wired.com/story/how-godels-proof-works/

July 18, 2020 | Author: Jenny MorberJenny Morber The World Is Noisy. These Groups Want to Restore the Quiet Silence is increasingly scarce, even in national parks. Now, scientists and environmentalists are working to calm the noise for the good of nature—and for us. https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-is-noisy-these-groups-want-to-restore-the-quiet/

July 17, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Universities Need Covid-19 Tests to Reopen. Few Have Them As campuses reopen, the logistics of preventing an outbreak are posing thorny questions: Who to test? How often? And will students buy in? https://www.wired.com/story/colleges-prepare-to-test-thousands-of-students-for-covid-19/

July 16, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Hydroxychloroquine Still Doesn’t Do Anything, New Data Shows Two more studies prove that the much-hyped antimalarial doesn’t treat Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/hydroxychloroquine-still-doesnt-do-anything-new-data-shows/

July 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Vantablack? Meh. Meet the Ultra-Black Vantafish Scientists have found that some fishes absorb up to 99.956 percent of the light that hits them. The deep-sea menagerie just got a whole lot weirder. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-ultra-black-vantafish/

July 16, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Nuclear Tests Have Changed, but They Never Really Stopped 75 years after the first explosive nuclear tests, now outlawed, sophisticated virtual testing allows American physicists to understand these weapons better than ever. https://www.wired.com/story/nuclear-tests-have-changed-but-they-never-really-stopped/

July 15, 2020 | Author: Will Bedingfield, WIRED UKWill Bedingfield, WIRED UK Don’t Talk About Covid-19’s ‘Waves’—This Isn’t the Spanish Flu It’s not useful to think about coronavirus coming in synchronized surges. This is a long, lingering epidemic that is only just getting started. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-talk-about-covid-19s-waves-this-isnt-the-spanish-flu/

July 15, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Will the Hydrogen Revolution Start in a Garbage Dump? American companies are racing to commercialize technologies that can turn almost any kind of waste into clean hydrogen fuel. https://www.wired.com/story/will-the-hydrogen-revolution-start-in-a-garbage-dump/

July 15, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Llamas—Yes, Llamas—Could Help Us Fight Covid-19 These creatures have evolved special “nanobodies” that may have an edge over human antibodies when it comes to developing a new treatment. https://www.wired.com/story/llamas-yes-llamas-could-help-us-fight-covid-19/

July 14, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Car Is Spewing Microplastics That Blow Around the World When you drive, tiny bits of plastic fly off your tires and brakes. Now scientists have shown how all that road muck is blowing into “pristine” environments like the Arctic. https://www.wired.com/story/your-car-is-spewing-microplastics/

July 14, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen The Equity-Diversity-Inclusion Industrial Complex Gets a Makeover Companies and universities have long relied on seminars to reduce racism, despite lackluster results. Maybe institution leaders can salvage the format. https://www.wired.com/story/the-equity-diversity-inclusion-industrial-complex-gets-a-makeover/

July 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon You Don’t Need Single-Use Plastic Bags. You Need a Mask Honestly, you should just be disinfecting your reusable bags—the real issue is airborne virus, not infected shopping totes, experts say. https://www.wired.com/story/you-dont-need-single-use-plastic-bags/

July 12, 2020 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK How to Trick Your Brain into Remembering Almost Anything Four-time USA Memory Champion Nelson Dellis and psychological scientist Julia Shaw explain how to boost your memory skills. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-trick-your-brain-to-remember-almost-anything/

July 12, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett The Tricky Math of Herd Immunity for Covid-19 When will a disease stop spreading through a population? The formula is simple, but the variables are much more complicated.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-tricky-math-of-herd-immunity-for-covid-19/

July 11, 2020 | Author: Maddie StoneMaddie Stone What Happens After a ‘Million-Mile Battery’ Outlasts the Car? Electric-vehicle makers hope to roll out super-long-lasting batteries. That raises interesting questions about resources, performance—and a battery’s second act. https://www.wired.com/story/what-happens-after-a-million-mile-battery-outlasts-the-car/

July 10, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Covid-19 Immunity May Rely on a Microscopic Helper: T Cells Researchers have been looking beyond antibodies to understand how immunity to the new virus might work—and how to design a vaccine. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-immunity-may-rely-on-a-microscopic-helper-t-cells/

July 10, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How a ‘Heat Dome’ Forms—and Why This One Is So Perilous A massive, intense heat wave is settling over the continental US. The ravages of the Covid pandemic are going to make it all the more deadly. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-heat-dome-forms/

July 9, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Will We Recognize Life on Mars When We See It? If NASA’s Perseverance rover finds life on the Red Planet, there’s a good chance our first extraterrestrial encounter will be a little ambiguous. https://www.wired.com/story/will-we-recognize-life-on-mars-when-we-see-it/

July 9, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Covid Kills More Men Than Women. Experts Still Can’t Explain Why A new tracker from Harvard’s GenderSci Lab is the first to consolidate sex-separated data from across the US. It may help researchers solve the mystery. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-kills-more-men-than-women-experts-still-cant-explain-why/

July 9, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Larry Brilliant on How Well We Are Fighting Covid-19 Three months ago, the epidemiologist weighed in on what we must do to defeat this new threat. We went back to ask: How are we doing, and what comes next? https://www.wired.com/story/larry-brilliant-on-how-well-are-we-fighting-covid-19/

July 8, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison How to Read Covid-19 Research (and Actually Understand It) Confused? Surprised? Wondering where the good parts are? Here are a few tips on reading scientific papers to help those of us following along at home. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-read-covid-19-research-and-actually-understand-it/

July 8, 2020 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson Kai-Fu Lee Gives AI a B-Minus Grade in the Covid-19 Fight Robots and computer programs can help with social distancing and food delivery, but have been less helpful in developing a vaccine. https://www.wired.com/story/kai-fu-lee-ai-b-minus-grade-covid-19/

July 8, 2020 | Author: Lauren Goode, Adam RogersLauren Goode and Adam Rogers Global Warming. Inequality. Covid-19. And Al Gore Is … Optimistic? As vice president, he looked for big policy answers to hard global problems. Now he says all our crises are speeding us toward real solutions. https://www.wired.com/story/global-warming-inequality-covid-19-and-al-gore-is-optimistic/

July 7, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Company Wants to Rewrite the Future of Genetic Disease Tessera Therapeutics is developing a new class of gene editors capable of precisely plugging in long stretches of DNA—something that Crispr can’t do. https://www.wired.com/story/this-company-wants-to-rewrite-the-future-of-genetic-disease/

July 7, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Tech That Could Help Pro Sports Adapt to the Pandemic As pro leagues return to stadiums, here are a few novel technologies people are exploring as ways to keep fans and players safe. https://www.wired.com/story/tech-that-could-help-pro-sports-adapt-to-the-pandemic/

July 7, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber A Mathematician’s Guide to How Contagion Spreads Adam Kucharski wrote The Rules of Contagion before Covid-19. He talks about misinformation, bank failures, and coming up with hypotheses during a crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/a-mathematicians-guide-to-how-contagion-spreads/

July 6, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Epic Siberian Journey to Solve a Mass Extinction Mystery A quarter-billion years ago, huge volcanic eruptions burned coal, leading to the worst extinction in Earth’s history. Here’s how scientists hunted down the evidence. https://www.wired.com/story/the-epic-siberian-journey-to-solve-a-mass-extinction-mystery/

July 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The UAE’s First Mars Mission Is a Robo-Meteorologist The United Arab Emirates is preparing to launch its first Martian satellite, Hope, which will search for clues to the Red Planet’s atmospheric mysteries. https://www.wired.com/story/the-uaes-first-mars-mission-is-a-robo-meteorologist/

July 5, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Astronomers Are Uncovering the Magnetic Soul of the Universe Researchers are discovering that magnetic fields permeate much of the cosmos. If these fields date back to the Big Bang, they could solve a cosmological mystery. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-are-uncovering-the-magnetic-soul-of-the-universe/

July 4, 2020 | Author: Rebecca RatcliffeRebecca Ratcliffe A Bird’s Epic Migration Stuns Scientists and Wins Online Fans As researchers tracked his flight over 27 countries, a cuckoo became a celebrity and raised questions about how climate change could affect his species’ travel. https://www.wired.com/story/a-birds-epic-migration-stuns-scientists-and-wins-online-fans/

July 3, 2020 | Author: Scott K. Johnson, Ars TechnicaScott K. Johnson, Ars Technica Hummingbirds Can See Colors We Can’t Even Imagine When humans see purple, we’re really seeing a blend of red and blue light. Hummingbirds see purple plus ultraviolet—and lots of other nonspectral colors. https://www.wired.com/story/hummingbirds-can-see-colors-we-cant-even-imagine/

July 2, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Adam RogersMegan Molteni and Adam Rogers How Masks Went From Don’t-Wear to Must-Have Public health messaging and science have to work hard to stay in sync during a crisis. During the Covid-19 pandemic, they haven’t always succeeded. https://www.wired.com/story/how-masks-went-from-dont-wear-to-must-have/

July 2, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Firework Smoke Could Be Tainted With Lead It may be the most unpatriotic toxicology study ever, but so be it: Metals give fireworks their color, but some manufacturers are slipping in toxins. https://www.wired.com/story/your-firework-smoke-could-be-tainted-with-lead/

July 1, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Where Should Covid-19 Vaccines Be Tested? It’s a Moving Target Developers need to test in hotspots, but those keep changing. And they must avoid ethical problems, like testing in low-income areas but only selling in rich ones. https://www.wired.com/story/where-should-covid-19-vaccines-be-tested-its-a-moving-target/

June 30, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy The CEO of Novartis on Developing Drugs During a Pandemic Vas Narasimhan talks about drug prices, vaccine development, the rise and fall of hydroxychloroquine, and how Big Pharma might win back the trust of consumers. https://www.wired.com/story/the-ceo-of-novartis-on-developing-drugs-during-a-pandemic/

June 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Nuclear ‘Power Balls’ May Make Meltdowns a Thing of the Past Triso particles are an alien-looking fuel with built-in safety features that will power a new generation of high-temperature reactors. https://www.wired.com/story/nuclear-power-balls-triso-fuel/

June 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s New Moon-Bound Space Suits Will Get a Boost From AI Engineers are turning to generative design algorithms to build components for NASA’s next-generation space suit—the first major update in decades. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-new-moon-bound-space-suits-will-get-a-boost-from-ai/

June 29, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Anthropause: How the Pandemic Gives Scientists a New Way to Study Wildlife A group of scientists argue that the Covid lockdown, what they’re calling the “anthropause,” is an unprecedented opportunity to study how humans affect animal behavior. https://www.wired.com/story/the-anthropause-a-new-way-to-study-wildlife/

June 28, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett In Lockdown, Mathematicians Crack a Stubborn Geometry Riddle  The rectangular peg problem asks a seemingly simple question: Does a closed loop include the corners of every kind of rectangle? https://www.wired.com/story/in-lockdown-mathematicians-crack-a-stubborn-geometry-riddle/

June 27, 2020 | Author: Jane Braxton LittleJane Braxton Little The Debate Over Burning Dead Trees to Create Biomass Energy Critics worry about the risks of overcutting and wood smoke. But supporters say the practice will prevent megafires—which release even more carbon dioxide. https://www.wired.com/story/the-debate-over-burning-dead-trees-to-create-biomass-energy/

June 27, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Old Drugs Could Reveal a New Way to Attack the Coronavirus Researchers found that SARS-CoV-2 hijacks tendrils that grow from infected cells and may ride them to infect others. But existing compounds might slow their roll. https://www.wired.com/story/old-drugs-could-reveal-a-new-way-to-attack-the-coronavirus/

June 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Rocket Motor of the Future Breathes Air Like a Jet Engine This theoretical engine could drastically reduce the cost of getting to space. Now two companies are trying to make it real. https://www.wired.com/story/the-rocket-motor-of-the-future-breathes-air-like-a-jet-engine/

June 26, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Vaccine Makers Turn to Microchip Tech to Beat Glass Shortages We’ll need millions of vials to distribute the vaccine. The US government thinks manufacturing methods from the semiconductor industry can help. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-makers-turn-to-microchip-tech-to-beat-glass-shortages/

June 25, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins Scientists Taught Mice to Smell an Odor That Doesn’t Exist With direct brain stimulation, mice learned to recognize an imaginary scent—and helped researchers understand a key piece of the olfactory puzzle. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-taught-mice-to-smell-an-odor-that-doesnt-exist/

June 25, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Massive Saharan Dust Plumes Are Blowing Into the US Every summer, an atmospheric event propels desert dust thousands of miles across the Atlantic. This year is particularly bad, and timed terribly with Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/saharan-dust-plumes-are-blowing-into-the-us/

June 24, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Dexamethasone and the Recovery Trial’s High-Speed Science In just three months, one British research team identified the first life-saving drug of the pandemic (and helped cancel hydroxychloroquine). https://www.wired.com/story/dexamethasone-and-the-recovery-trials-high-speed-science/

June 24, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler ‘Carbon Farming’ Could Make US Agriculture Truly Green Today a Senate committee will hear about a bill that would help farmers adopt practices to release less carbon from the soil, reducing planetary warming. https://www.wired.com/story/carbon-farming-could-make-us-agriculture-truly-green/

June 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why the Arctic Is Warming So Fast, and Why That’s So Alarming When permafrost thaws, sea ice disappears, and wildfires rage in the north, the consequences extend to the rest of the world. https://www.wired.com/story/why-the-arctic-is-warming-so-fast/

June 23, 2020 | Author: Brian BarrettBrian Barrett My Friend Was Struck by ALS. To Fight Back, He Built a Movement At 37, Brian Wallach was diagnosed with the fatal disease. So he tapped a lifetime of connections to give help and hope to fellow sufferers—while grappling with his own mortality. https://www.wired.com/story/life-just-out-of-reach-als-brian-wallach/

June 23, 2020 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser 5 Weird Concepts to (Theoretically) Supercharge Mask Fabrics From diamonds to salt, researchers are exploring novel materials for face coverings. But don’t expect to see these far-out ideas in stores anytime soon. https://www.wired.com/story/weird-concepts-theoretically-supercharge-mask-fabrics/

June 22, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Who’s to Blame for Plastic Microfiber Pollution? Tiny bits of plastic are corrupting every corner of the planet. The major culprits: cheap synthetic clothing and washing machines. https://www.wired.com/story/whos-to-blame-for-plastic-microfiber-pollution/

June 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Why NASA Designed a New $23 Million Space Toilet Later this year, astronauts on the American module of the ISS will be able to test out the toilet before NASA puts it on crewed vehicles for deep-space missions. https://www.wired.com/story/why-nasa-designed-a-new-dollar23-million-space-toilet/

June 22, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Stuck at Home, Scientists Discover 9 New Insect Species Without a DNA sequencer, two Los Angeles entomologists relied on two of biology’s oldest tools: microscopes and lots of free time. https://www.wired.com/story/stuck-at-home-scientists-discover-9-new-insect-species/

June 21, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover A Super Sensitive Dark-Matter Search Yields Strange Results Researchers say there are three possible explanations for the anomalous data: One is mundane. Two would revolutionize physics. https://www.wired.com/story/a-super-sensitive-dark-matter-search-yields-strange-results/

June 20, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Ground-Penetrating Radar Mapped a Buried Ancient Roman City Archaeologists have found a monument, market, temple, bath complex, and water pipes from the walled town of Falerii Novi. https://www.wired.com/story/ground-penetrating-radar-mapped-a-buried-ancient-roman-city/

June 20, 2020 | Author: Doug JohnsonDoug Johnson Microtransit Gives City Agencies a Lift During the Pandemic Public transit ridership has dropped, so some cities are trying on-demand apps for more private van, bus, or shuttle rides—and possibly contact tracing. https://www.wired.com/story/microtransit-gives-city-agencies-a-lift-during-the-pandemic/

June 19, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Deep Dive With the Weirdest Fishes in the Sea Go behind the scenes at the California Academy of Sciences to see their greatest specimens, including fish from the “twilight zone” and a massive megalodon tooth. https://www.wired.com/story/a-deep-dive-with-the-weirdest-fishes-in-the-sea/

June 19, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Sheltering in Place Works—if You Can Afford to Stay Home In San Francisco’s Mission District, a study showed Covid-19 tests aren’t enough if people can’t take time off of work. They need financial and social support too. https://www.wired.com/story/shelter-in-place-works-if-you-can-afford-to-stay-home/

June 19, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers No, You Don’t Need to See President Trump’s Medical Records Throughout history, US presidents have fudged the truth about their health. But all the data voters need about Trump is already out for everyone to see. https://www.wired.com/story/no-you-dont-need-to-see-president-trumps-medical-records/

June 18, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Minnesota’s Protests Are Revealing About Covid-19 Spread After George Floyd’s killing, experts warned that demonstrations could set off new waves of infections. But early testing in Minneapolis tells another story. https://www.wired.com/story/what-minnesotas-protests-are-revealing-about-covid-19-spread/

June 18, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Trouble With Counting Aliens A new study estimates that there might only be 36 communicating extraterrestrial civilizations in our galaxy. But that number doesn’t tell the whole story. https://www.wired.com/story/the-trouble-with-counting-aliens/

June 18, 2020 | Author: Maimuna S. MajumderMaimuna S. Majumder Coronavirus Researchers Are Dismantling Science’s Ivory Tower—One Study at a Time Homebound scientists were looking for ways to help battle the pandemic. I put out a call on Twitter, and the Covid-19 Dispersed Volunteer Network was born. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-studies-dismantle-science-ivory-tower/

June 17, 2020 | Author: Grace HuckinsGrace Huckins The FDA Revokes Its Emergency Use Authorization for Hydroxychloroquine So far, no studies have shown that the antimalarial drug can fight Covid-19, and agency officials say its potential benefits do not outweigh its risks. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-revokes-its-emergency-use-authorization-for-hydroxychloroquine/

June 17, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid-19 Is Bad. But It May Not Be the ‘Big One’ Health experts want a 9/11 Commission-style report on the US pandemic response. They say we must forecast and prepare for outbreaks as we do for wars or weather. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-is-bad-but-it-may-not-be-the-big-one/

June 17, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Design and Science of Patio Dining During a Pandemic Public health experts think Covid-19 risk is lower outside, and restaurateurs want to fill tables. It’s an easy solution—except for all the hard parts. https://www.wired.com/story/the-design-and-science-of-patio-dining-during-a-pandemic/

June 16, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Universities Step Up the Fight for Open-Access Research Today’s deal between the University of California and publisher Springer Nature is a big milestone on the path to dismantling paywalls around academic journals. https://www.wired.com/story/universities-step-up-the-fight-for-open-access-research/

June 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon You Can Now Buy Spot the Robot Dog—If You’ve Got $74,500 Boston Dynamics is finally making its mechanical canine available for businesses and developers. But know that this puppy ain’t for everyone. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-now-buy-spot-the-robot-dog/

June 16, 2020 | Author: Evan RatliffEvan Ratliff We Can Protect the Economy From Pandemics. Why Didn’t We? A virologist helped crack an impossible problem: how to insure against the economic fallout from devastating viral outbreaks. The plan was ingenious. Yet we’re still in this mess. https://www.wired.com/story/nathan-wolfe-global-economic-fallout-pandemic-insurance/

June 15, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison When Doctors and Patients Talk About Death Over Zoom During the Covid-19 pandemic, palliative care specialists are discovering that technology can add a lot to these difficult discussions. https://www.wired.com/story/when-doctors-and-patients-talk-about-death-over-zoom/

June 15, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni An Army of Volunteers Is Taking On Vaccine Disinformation Online Anti-vaccine messages on social media have tripled since the pandemic began. One public health group wants to teach pro-vaccine Americans to fight fire with fire. https://www.wired.com/story/can-a-keyboard-crusade-stem-the-vaccine-infodemic/

June 14, 2020 | Author: Shannon HallShannon Hall Astronomers Track a Fast Radio Burst to Its Source—a Magnetar The origin of these explosions of radio waves has long been an astrophysics mystery. Now one has been traced to an ultra-dense spinning, magnetized stellar core. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-track-a-fast-radio-burst-to-its-source-a-magnetar/

June 13, 2020 | Author: Miranda WeissMiranda Weiss In Alaska, Summer’s Getting Too Hot for the Salmon Run Bristol Bay is heating up, killing fish as they try to swim upriver to spawn. It’s a harbinger of climate change and hard times for fisheries. https://www.wired.com/story/in-alaska-summers-getting-too-hot-for-the-salmon-run/

June 12, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Covid-19 Economic Slump Is Closing Down Coal Plants This year, coal usage has dropped in the US, and renewables now generate more electricity. To some experts, the financial crisis is a clean energy opportunity. https://www.wired.com/story/the-covid-19-economic-slump-is-closing-down-coal-plants/

June 12, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Hunt Is On for Elusive Ghost Particles in Antarctica Ultrahigh-energy neutrinos could help scientists unravel some of the biggest mysteries in astrophysics—and the best place to find them may be the South Pole. https://www.wired.com/story/the-hunt-is-on-for-elusive-ghost-particles-in-antarctica/

June 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Plastic Rain Is the New Acid Rain Researchers find that over 1,000 metric tons of microplastic fall on 11 protected areas in the US annually, equivalent to over 120 million plastic water bottles. https://www.wired.com/story/plastic-rain-is-the-new-acid-rain/

June 11, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber What’s Confusing About Calling Covid-19 Cases ‘Asymptomatic’ There’s a difference between people who never develop symptoms and people who just don’t have them yet. And that matters when calculating public health risk. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-confusing-about-calling-covid-19-cases-asymptomatic/

June 10, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The Dangers of Excluding Women From HIV Prevention Drug Tests PrEP, or pre-exposure prophylaxis, pills are highly effective in blocking HIV if taken daily. But their drug trials have a mixed track record for access. https://www.wired.com/story/the-dangers-of-excluding-women-from-hiv-prevention-drug-tests/

June 10, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Across the Globe, Scientists Are Striking for Black Lives On June 10, thousands of academics are stopping research activities to educate themselves about disparities and take action against systemic racism in science. https://www.wired.com/story/across-the-globe-scientists-are-striking-for-black-lives/

June 9, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Behind the Scenes With the Monterey Bay Aquarium’s Master of Jellyfish Aquarist Mac Bubel takes you into the rarely seen “jelly lab” to explore how she raises these sensitive, hypnotic creatures. https://www.wired.com/story/behind-the-scenes-monterey-bay-aquarium-jellyfish/

June 9, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen These Bacteria Ate Their Way Through a Really Tricky Maze Microbes are well known for working together in stressful environments. Scientists wanted to see how they would fare at a labyrinthine brain teaser. https://www.wired.com/story/these-bacteria-ate-their-way-through-a-really-tricky-maze/

June 8, 2020 | Author: Marion Renault Marion Renault When Health Care Moves Online, Many Patients Are Left Behind Amid the Covid-19 pandemic, more doctors are turning to telemedicine. That’s a problem for tens of millions on the wrong side of the digital divide. https://www.wired.com/story/health-care-online-patients-left-behind/

June 8, 2020 | Author: Chris WrightChris Wright The Remarkable Stuff Scientists Get Done as They Work From Home Researchers who usually rely on labs or command centers have been forced to work from laptops and closets—even as they control spacecraft millions of miles away. https://www.wired.com/story/the-remarkable-stuff-scientists-get-done-as-they-work-from-home/

June 8, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Science Behind Orchestras’ Careful Covid Comeback How readily can playing instruments transmit the virus? As researchers investigate, musical ensembles prepare for the show to go on. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-behind-orchestras-careful-covid-comeback/

June 7, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Black Hole Paradoxes Reveal a Link Between Energy and Entropy  What happens to a black hole as it decays? Investigating the possibilities has led researchers in recent years to major clues about quantum gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/black-hole-paradoxes-reveal-a-link-between-energy-and-entropy/

June 6, 2020 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Archaeologists Discover the Largest, Oldest Maya Monument Yet The structure, believed to have served as a ceremonial center 3,000 years ago, was discovered in Tabasco, Mexico. https://www.wired.com/story/archaeologists-discover-the-largest-oldest-maya-monument-yet/

June 6, 2020 | Author: Anuradha VaranasiAnuradha Varanasi India Is Using More Solar Energy—but It Carries a Lead Risk In rural areas, solar power is stored in lead batteries. If they aren’t properly recycled, contamination can cause health problems. https://www.wired.com/story/india-is-using-more-solar-energy-but-it-carries-a-lead-risk/

June 6, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Police Tactics Could Turn Protests Into Covid-19 Hot Spots Sure, large crowds already carry a risk of transmission. It’s just worse when you teargas people, make them cough on each other, and bus them to jail. https://www.wired.com/story/police-tactics-could-turn-protests-into-covid-19-hot-spots/

June 5, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Covid-19 Cases Were Already Rising Before the George Floyd Protests The easing of stay-at-home orders and Memorial Day travel have led to spikes in some parts of the country. That’s bad news for what comes next. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-cases-were-already-rising-before-the-george-floyd-protests/

June 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Triple Threat Imperils Millions of People Across Africa A “perfect storm” of ravenous locusts, flooding, and the Covid-19 pandemic threatens to create huge food shortages. https://www.wired.com/story/a-triple-threat-imperils-millions-of-people-across-africa/

June 4, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler A Drop in Commercial Flights Is Bad for Hurricane Forecasts Passenger jets and cruise ships normally gather key weather data. But full docks and empty skies make it hard to predict the details of incoming storms. https://www.wired.com/story/a-drop-in-commercial-flights-is-bad-for-hurricane-forecasts/

June 4, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon All This Chaos Might Be Giving You ‘Crisis Fatigue’ Your body is well adapted to handle temporary stresses, but it’s overwhelmed by the constant, unrelenting pressures of this horrible year. https://www.wired.com/story/crisis-fatigue/

June 3, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Major Hydroxychloroquine Trial Shows No Prevention Benefits A large, double-blind study examined 821 people who had been exposed to the virus. The drug was no better at stopping Covid-19 infection than a placebo. https://www.wired.com/story/major-hydroxychloroquine-trial-shows-no-prevention-benefits/

June 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 16 Health Workers Talk About Their Battles With the Pandemic WIRED’s video team reached out to doctors, physician assistants, and paramedics, and asked them about their experiences treating Covid-19 patients. https://www.wired.com/story/16-health-workers-talk-about-their-battles-with-the-pandemic/

June 2, 2020 | Author: Boone AshworthBoone Ashworth The WIRED Coronavirus Glossary Too many Covid-19 buzzwords? Here’s what they all mean. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-glossary/

June 2, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Rigorous Hand-Washing Will Be Part of Covid-19’s New Normal The simplest hygiene tasks are the toughest to maintain—take it from the health care experts who have advice about how to make the habit stick. https://www.wired.com/story/rigorous-hand-washing-will-be-part-of-covid-19s-new-normal/

June 1, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni In Minneapolis, Neighbors Are Mobilizing—Offline Worried about infiltration from extremist groups or police surveillance, residents are turning to pre-internet tactics to help protect homes and local stores. https://www.wired.com/story/in-minneapolis-neighbors-are-mobilizing-offline/

June 1, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Meet ACE2, the Enzyme at the Center of the Covid-19 Mystery Since January, scientists have published more than 700 studies to figure out the molecule’s link to risk for the disease—and to find possible treatments. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-ace2-the-enzyme-at-the-center-of-the-covid-19-mystery/

June 1, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon An Onslaught of Crises Has Created a Modern Paradox Never before have humans lived more comfortably. And yet today we’re overwhelmed by crises, be it inequality or economic collapse or Covid, all exacerbating one another. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-crisis-modern-paradox/

June 1, 2020 | Author: Flavie HalaisFlavie Halais Cities in Poorer Countries Are at Risk as Covid-19 Spreads Hot spots are emerging in urban areas across Africa,  Asia, and Latin America, where social distancing is challenging and missing work can mean not eating. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-poorer-countries-risk-covid-19-spreads/

May 31, 2020 | Author: Victoria Turk, WIRED UKVictoria Turk, WIRED UK Should We Purposely Infect Healthy Volunteers With Covid-19? Such studies could speed up the development of a vaccine—but would mean deliberately giving people a disease that could kill them. https://www.wired.com/story/should-we-purposely-infect-healthy-volunteers-with-covid-19/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Launched Two Astronauts—Changing Spaceflight Forever The test mission will clear the way for regular crewed launches from the United States for the first time in nearly a decade. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launched-two-astronauts-changing-spaceflight-forever/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Watch SpaceX and NASA Launch Two Astronauts to the ISS The occasion will mark the first time a private company blasts NASA astronauts into space. Here’s everything you need to know. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-spacex-launch-astronauts-to-the-iss/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Turns Out 4 ‘Blank’ Dead Sea Scrolls Actually Have Text A new analysis revealed what scientists believe is a passage from the book of Ezekiel. https://www.wired.com/story/turns-out-4-blank-dead-sea-scrolls-actually-have-text/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: An Eternal Voyage of Discovery As we sunset this weekly series, we take a farewell tour of the outer planets—and pay tribute to one of the most famous last looks at Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-an-eternal-voyage-of-discovery/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Mara Johnson-GrohMara Johnson-Groh The Quest to Purge New Zealand of Invasive Predators Rats, weasels, and other imported mammals have destroyed native bird populations. Local group Predator Free Wellington wants to turn the tables. https://www.wired.com/story/the-quest-to-purge-new-zealand-of-invasive-predators/

May 30, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood What Do the Quark Oddities at the Large Hadron Collider Mean? Measurements of particles called B mesons deviate from predictions. Alone, each anomaly looks like a fluke, but their collective drift is more suggestive. https://www.wired.com/story/what-do-the-quark-oddities-at-the-large-hadron-collider-mean/

May 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus What’s Next for SpaceX’s Crewed Mission to the ISS? On Saturday, the company will take a second run at launching astronauts to the International Space Station. But only if a lot of things go right. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-next-for-spacexs-crewed-mission-to-the-iss/

May 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus ‘Oumuamua Might Be a Giant Interstellar Hydrogen Iceberg  It isn’t an alien spaceship, but new research suggests the first known interstellar object to grace our solar system could be something even stranger. https://www.wired.com/story/oumuamua-might-be-a-giant-interstellar-hydrogen-iceberg/

May 29, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Covid-19 Testing Is Expensive. It Doesn’t Have to Be The diagnostics industry favors wealthy countries, but the rest of the world needs tests too. One Stanford bioengineer thinks “frugal science” can help. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-testing-is-expensive-it-doesnt-have-to-be/

May 29, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Some Nursing Homes Escaped Covid-19—Here’s What They Did Right As states start to reopen, senior care facilities must balance the needs of residents against the potential for more deadly Covid-19 outbreaks. https://www.wired.com/story/some-nursing-homes-escaped-covid-19-heres-what-they-did-right/

May 28, 2020 | Author: Monique BrouilletteMonique Brouillette Covid-19 Creates Long, Anxious Waits for Fertility Treatments As fertility clinics gradually reopen, patients and doctors must weigh the risks of seeking pregnancy during a pandemic—or waiting too long to try. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-creates-long-anxious-waits-for-fertility-treatments/

May 28, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers To Beat Covid-19, You Have to Know How A Virus Moves As public spaces reopen, scientists are racing to understand the mysterious and turbulent way the disease spreads through air—from person to person, and place to place. https://www.wired.com/story/to-beat-covid-19-you-have-to-know-how-a-virus-moves/

May 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Weather Delays the SpaceX Crew Dragon Launch The historic launch planned for Wednesday gets pushed back due to stormy conditions, but the launch window remains open. SpaceX and NASA will try again Saturday. https://www.wired.com/story/weather-delays-the-spacex-crew-dragon-launch/

May 27, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Whoooaaa Duuuuude: Why We Stretch Words in Tweets and Texts Notice you’ve been elongating your words lately? You’re actually loading them with a whooooole lot of meaning. https://www.wired.com/story/whoooaaa-duuuuude-stretch-words/

May 27, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill 3 Ways Scientists Think We Could De-Germ a Covid-19 World Researchers want to know if we can create an antiviral infrastructure that would protect humans from transmission. Here are a few ideas. https://www.wired.com/story/3-ways-scientists-think-we-could-de-germ-a-covid-19-world/

May 26, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Trump’s New Space Force Missile Might Be Too ‘Super-Duper’ To go that fast, it would need a ridiculous amount of fuel—and even then, it might never come back down. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-new-missile-is-too-super-duper/

May 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Virgin Orbit’s Air-Launched Rocket Fails Its First Test LauncherOne failed a few seconds into its first flight. But that’s OK—the only two US rocket startups that made it to orbit flubbed their first tries too. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-orbits-air-launched-rocket-failed-its-first-test/

May 26, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles This Citizen Science Gig Pays People to Match Space Photos Astronomers at the Hubble Image Similarity Project are employing their out-of-work neighbors to help them train a neural net to recognize celestial objects. https://www.wired.com/story/this-citizen-science-gig-pays-people-to-match-space-photos/

May 26, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How an Immunology Blog Became a Covid-19 Guide to Going Out With lockdowns ending, people have a lot of questions about how to calculate the risks of returning to everyday activities. Erin Bromage has answers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-an-immunology-blog-became-a-covid-19-guide-to-going-out/

May 26, 2020 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell Covid-19 Flares Up in America’s Polluted ‘Sacrifice Zones’ Researchers find that areas with high levels of airborne dust or toxic chemicals also have more deaths from the coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-flares-americas-polluted-sacrifice-zones/

May 25, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet This Museum’s All-Star Arachnids and Insects Camel spiders and giant hornets and shimmering butterflies, oh my. An arachnologist gives a behind-the-scenes tour at the California Academy of Sciences. https://www.wired.com/story/all-star-arachnids-and-insects/

May 25, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus What It’s Like to Be First to Fly a Brand New Spacecraft Robert Crippen is just one of two living NASA astronauts to have flown on a new spacecraft for the first time. The Crew Dragon flyers will join his elite club this week. https://www.wired.com/story/what-its-like-to-be-first-to-fly-a-brand-new-spacecraft/

May 25, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Covid-19 Makes the Case for More Meatpacking Robots The coronavirus has hit meat processing plants hard. But not in Denmark, where automation makes for safer slaughterhouses. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-makes-the-case-for-more-meatpacking-robots/

May 24, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich A Grad Student Solved the Epic Conway Knot Problem—in a Week Lisa Piccirillo encountered the more than 50-year-old question by chance at a conference. Her solution relies on a classical tool called the knot trace. https://www.wired.com/story/a-grad-student-solved-the-epic-conway-knot-problem-in-a-week/

May 23, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Keeping an Eye on Jupiter’s Storms NASA’s Juno orbiter, along with its Hubble and Gemini telescopes, will help scientists better understand the planet’s atmosphere. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-keeping-an-eye-on-jupiters-storms/

May 23, 2020 | Author: Kalen GoodluckKalen Goodluck Covid-19 Is Sweeping Through the Navajo Nation The pandemic has taken an acute toll on tribal nations that are also struggling with a lack of running water, sparse internet, and a high rates of chronic illness. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-is-sweeping-through-the-navajo-nation/

May 23, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What’s Up With the Funny-Looking Moons in Onward ? Yes, I know this is a fantasy movie. That shouldn’t stop us from thinking about the real causes of lunar phases. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-up-with-the-funny-moons-in-onward/

May 22, 2020 | Author: Kate KnibbsKate Knibbs The Promise of Antibody Treatments for Covid-19 As scientists race to create a vaccine, a parallel quest to engineer effective antibody treatments for the coronavirus is vital too—and may provide relief sooner. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-antibody-treatment/

May 22, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Will Wildfire Smoke Worsen the Pandemic? We’re About to Find Out When seasonal blazes descend on California, millions could be inhaling smoke, which is known to predispose people to lung diseases. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-smoke-pandemic/

May 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus On the Moon, Astronaut Pee Will Be a Hot Commodity Urine can be used for landing pads, gardens, and drinking water. But will there be enough to go around? https://www.wired.com/story/on-the-moon-astronaut-pee-will-be-a-hot-commodity/

May 21, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler A ‘Hyperactive’ Hurricane Season Is About to Strike Given the pandemic, how will emergency experts cope with evacuating people who might fear shared shelters, refuse to wear masks, and distrust authorities? https://www.wired.com/story/a-hyperactive-hurricane-season-is-about-to-strike/

May 21, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Polio Is Nearly Wiped Out. Covid-19 Could Halt That Progress The disease once paralyzed 350,000 children each year; vaccination campaigns brought it down to just a few hundred cases. Then, the pandemic struck. https://www.wired.com/story/polio-is-nearly-wiped-out-covid-19-could-halt-that-progress/

May 20, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Creating a Covid-19 Vaccine Is Taking So Long Developing a vaccine that’s both effective and safe is grueling, methodical work. And once we have one, we’ll need many, many doses too. https://www.wired.com/story/why-creating-a-covid-19-vaccine-is-taking-so-long/

May 20, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen This Lab ‘Cooks’ With AI to Make New Materials A Toronto lab recycles carbon dioxide into more useful chemicals, using materials it discovered with artificial intelligence and supercomputers. https://www.wired.com/story/this-lab-cooks-with-ai-to-make-new-materials/

May 20, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How Do Astronauts Escape When a Space Launch Goes Wrong? SpaceX is preparing for the first crewed launch of its Crew Dragon capsule. Engineers have spent years planning for what happens if things go awry. https://www.wired.com/story/how-do-astronauts-escape-when-a-space-launch-goes-wrong/

May 20, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How Does a Virus Spread in Cities? It’s a Problem of Scale Population density didn’t make Covid-19 worse in New York City. If you want to know what went wrong, you have to think a lot smaller. https://www.wired.com/story/how-does-a-virus-spread-in-cities-its-a-problem-of-scale/

May 19, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis Covid-19’s Toll on Prison Labor Doesn’t Just Hurt Inmates Work stoppages impact the incarcerated workforce as well. The financial losses extend beyond the walls. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-prison-labor/

May 19, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Carbon Dioxide Emissions Have Dropped 17 Percent During the Pandemic Some regions, like the US and the UK, have seen their outputs fall by a third, due in large part to people driving less.  https://www.wired.com/story/carbon-dioxide-emissions-pandemic/

May 19, 2020 | Author: Rachel RamirezRachel Ramirez The Drive to Replace Summer-Only ‘Peaker’ Power Plants These power plants run during the hottest months, when energy is in demand. But they are expensive, and they pollute nearby low-income neighborhoods. https://www.wired.com/story/the-drive-to-replace-summer-only-peaker-power-plants/

May 19, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Covid Is Accelerating the Rise of Faux Meat The supply chain for traditional meat is buckling, and plant-based alternatives from companies like Impossible Foods and Beyond Meat are filling the void. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-faux-meat/

May 18, 2020 | Author: Oliver Franklin-Wallis, Wired UKOliver Franklin-Wallis, Wired UK How School Shutdowns Have Long-Term Effects on Children Similar situations after natural disasters offer clues about the potential academic and mental-health impacts of lockdowns. https://www.wired.com/story/how-school-shutdowns-have-longterm-effects-on-children/

May 18, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Robot Can Guess How You’re Feeling by the Way You Walk Walk like you’re angry, and the emotionally intelligent machine will give you more room, leaving your personal bubble intact. https://www.wired.com/story/proxemo-robot-guesses-emotion-from-walking/

May 18, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis How Smart City Planning Could Slow Future Pandemics The Covid-19 crisis is an opportunity to rethink how cities are designed—and make them better equipped to stop disease from spreading.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-urban-planning-health/

May 17, 2020 | Author: Dana NajjarDana Najjar ‘Milestone’ Evidence for Anyons, a Third Kingdom of Particles Physicists have long known that the universe is made from two kinds of particles: fermions and bosons. Now there’s a third that behaves totally differently. https://www.wired.com/story/milestone-evidence-for-anyons-a-third-kingdom-of-particles/

May 17, 2020 | Author: Brian BarrettBrian Barrett How to Sleep When the World Is Falling Apart It’s not easy to relax in the middle of the Covid-19 pandemic. But there are some simple tips and techniques that can help you get some shut-eye. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-sleep-anxiety/

May 16, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Cassini’s Curtain Call Before it crashed onto Saturn, the spacecraft captured images of the most photogenic planet in our Solar System. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-cassinis-curtain-call/

May 16, 2020 | Author: Nina LakhaniNina Lakhani It’s Not Just the Extreme Heat. It’s the Extreme Humidity A new study shows rising humidity and temperatures are colliding in places like the US Gulf Coast, decades ahead of projections, and it’s likely to cause deaths. https://www.wired.com/story/its-not-just-the-extreme-heat-its-the-extreme-humidity/

May 15, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber What’s the Strange Ailment Affecting Kids With Covid-19? The spate of inflammatory symptoms has sparked anxiety in parents, but experts say the big picture hasn’t changed: The kids are still (mostly) alright. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-the-strange-ailment-affecting-kids-with-covid-19/

May 15, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Coming Soon: A Nuclear Reactor—With a 3D-Printed Core A nuclear reactor core is one of the most extreme human-made environments on the planet. These scientists just figured out how to print one. https://www.wired.com/story/coming-soon-a-nuclear-reactor-with-a-3d-printed-core/

May 15, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Will Empty Bleachers Change the Psychology of Sports? When German and US soccer kick off this summer, there will be no crowds. That might squelch the home-field advantage—and the emotion that drives players. https://www.wired.com/story/will-empty-bleachers-change-the-psychology-of-sports/

May 15, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni I Enrolled in a Coronavirus Contact Tracing Academy Health experts say we need up to 200,000 more people to track down the infected and anyone who crossed their path. I took the training to learn how it works. https://www.wired.com/story/i-enrolled-in-a-coronavirus-contact-tracing-academy/

May 14, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Science of Temperature Is Weirder Than You Think Getting warm is easy—like falling off a bike. So why is it so hard to be cool? https://www.wired.com/story/temperature-is-weirder-than-you-think/

May 14, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Secret Space Plane is Carrying a Solar Experiment to Orbit The idea of beaming solar energy to Earth with radio waves is decades old. But this weekend, the technology gets its first test in orbit. https://www.wired.com/story/a-secret-space-plane-is-carrying-a-solar-experiment-to-orbit/

May 14, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Why Has Covid-19 Hit Seniors So Hard? It’s not one thing, it’s everything. Older people are more likely to catch the disease, to suffer from it more severely, and to have a tougher recovery. https://www.wired.com/story/why-has-covid-19-hit-seniors-so-hard/

May 13, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How NASA Certifies New Spacecraft Safe Enough for Humans SpaceX’s Crew Dragon capsule will be only the fifth American craft to be rated for human spaceflight in history. Clearing NASA’s certification process takes years. https://www.wired.com/story/how-nasa-certifies-new-spacecraft-safe-enough-for-humans/

May 13, 2020 | Author: Brooke JarvisBrooke Jarvis The First Shot: Inside the Covid Vaccine Fast Track The very first vaccine candidate entered human trials—and Neal Browning’s arm—on March 16. Behind the scenes at Moderna and the beginning of an unprecedented global sprint. https://www.wired.com/story/moderna-covid-19-vaccine-trials/

May 12, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon That Fresh Sea Breeze You Breathe May Be Laced With Microplastic Researchers have discovered that the ocean is burping tiny plastic particles, which then blow onto land—and potentially into your lungs. https://www.wired.com/story/sea-breeze-microplastic/

May 12, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Hungry City Rats Are Looking for a New Lunch Spot Near You As restaurants have shuttered, the rats who depend on an eternal garbage buffet are becoming more bold and competitive—and looking for new homes. https://www.wired.com/story/hungry-city-rats-are-looking-for-a-new-lunch-spot-near-you/

May 12, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Let’s Say There’s a Covid-19 Vaccine—Who Gets It First? An immunization shot is still in development, but debate over who gets priority has already begun. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-say-theres-a-covid-19-vaccine-who-gets-it-first/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Simon WinchesterSimon Winchester How Albert Einstein’s Son Tamed the Mississippi River Multiple structures now keep the river from roaring into the Atchafalaya—but they may be inadequate against climate change.  https://www.wired.com/story/how-albert-einsteins-son-tamed-the-mississippi-river/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wildfires Already Threaten the West. Then Came Covid-19 What if you need to mobilize first responders while keeping them socially distanced—and also potentially evacuate whole communities to safety? https://www.wired.com/story/california-wildfires-covid-19/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite Infrared Cameras Can Spot a Fever, but May Not Slow Covid-19 Workplaces are deploying technology to screen employees who may be sick. But past experience suggests the sensors won’t find many infectious people. https://www.wired.com/story/infrared-cameras-spot-fever-not-slow-covid-19/

May 11, 2020 | Author: Mallory PickettMallory Pickett The Search for a Covid-19 Research Animal Model In a lab test, two monkeys died from the novel coronavirus. A species that reacts to the virus as humans do may help us find new treatments, but it’s a weighty task. https://www.wired.com/story/the-search-for-a-covid-19-research-animal-model/

May 10, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood What Goes On in a Proton? Quark Math Still Needs Answers The complex math that governs quark particles is still a mystery—even though a $1 million prize awaits anyone who can figure it out. https://www.wired.com/story/what-goes-on-in-a-proton-quark-math-still-needs-answers/

May 10, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Science Fairs Are Canceled. Maybe That’s Just as Well It’s time to reconsider these earnest events—and find ways for kids to experience the joyous, collaborative nature of real scientific discovery. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-wrong-with-science-fairs/

May 9, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Europa! Attempt No Landing There Despite a surface marked with so-called “chaos terrain,” we’re set to explore whether or not it’ll be possible to live on Jupiter’s moon. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-europa-attempt-no-landing-there/

May 9, 2020 | Author: Maddie StoneMaddie Stone Is Online Grocery Shopping Better for the Planet? During the Covid-19 pandemic, more people than ever are buying online to stock their pantries. What kind of carbon footprint is all that home delivery leaving behind? https://www.wired.com/story/is-online-grocery-shopping-better-for-the-planet/

May 8, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s EmDrive Leader Has a New Interstellar Project Harold White left NASA in December to join a new nonprofit focused on building the technologies to bring humans to the outer solar system and beyond. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-emdrive-leader-has-a-new-interstellar-project/

May 8, 2020 | Author: Fred Vogelstein, Will KnightFred Vogelstein and Will Knight Health Officials Say ‘No Thanks’ to Contact-Tracing Tech Silicon Valley companies have proposed automating the arduous task of identifying people potentially exposed to Covid-19. They’re finding few takers. https://www.wired.com/story/health-officials-no-thanks-contact-tracing-tech/

May 8, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Front-Runners Emerge in the Race for a Covid-19 Vaccine Two leading candidates are headed for mass clinical trials, and everything’s on the table—including deliberately infecting healthy vaccine volunteers. https://www.wired.com/story/frontrunners-emerge-in-the-race-for-a-covid-19-vaccine/

May 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Bizarre Insect Is Building Shelters Out of Microplastic Caddis fly larvae typically construct protective cases out of sand grains and silk. Now they’re also using microplastic particles. https://www.wired.com/story/caddisfly-microplastic/

May 7, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Meatpacking Plants Have Become Covid-19 Hot Spots Frigid temperatures, cramped conditions, and long hours put meat processing workers at higher risk for contracting the novel coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/why-meatpacking-plants-have-become-covid-19-hot-spots/

May 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus After 60 Years, Explosion-Powered Rockets Are Nearly Here Rotating detonation engines could make rockets lighter, faster, and simpler. First imagined in the 1950s, they’re now almost ready for their first flight. https://www.wired.com/story/after-60-years-explosion-powered-rockets-are-nearly-here/

May 6, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Covid-19 Forces Spring Science Field Work to Go Fallow Researchers and graduate students who depend on outdoor data collection find themselves stuck inside, just as expedition season normally gets going. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-forces-spring-science-field-work-to-go-fallow/

May 6, 2020 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica China Is One Launch Closer to Building Its Own Space Station The success of the Long March 5B rocket marked the country’s latest attempt to position itself as an equal to NASA in space. https://www.wired.com/story/china-is-one-launch-closer-to-building-its-own-space-station/

May 6, 2020 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell The H1N1 Crisis Predicted Covid-19’s Toll on Black Americans In 2009, nonwhite patients got sicker faster, recovered more slowly, and died at higher rates than white patients. Now history is repeating itself. https://www.wired.com/story/h1n1-crisis-predicted-covid-19-toll-black-americans/

May 5, 2020 | Author: Sirin Kale, Wired UKSirin Kale, Wired UK The Neuroscience of Why You Could Really Use a Hug Right Now For those quarantined alone, the lack of human touch can feel agonizing. A neurological phenomenon called “skin hunger” explains why. https://www.wired.com/story/the-neuroscience-of-why-you-could-really-use-a-hug-right-now/

May 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Pandemic Is Lonely. But Don’t Call Loneliness an ‘Epidemic’ Comparing isolation to infection disease isn’t helpful, says historian Fay Bound Alberti. But Covid-19 lends a unique opportunity to reframe the issue. https://www.wired.com/story/pandemic-loneliness/

May 5, 2020 | Author: Matt JancerMatt Jancer Everything We Know About Covid-19 Antibody Tests (So Far) Should you take a test, and what does it mean for immunity? You’ve got questions, but we’ve got … more questions. https://www.wired.com/story/everything-we-know-about-covid-19-antibody-tests-so-far/

May 4, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The FDA Tightens the Rules for Covid-19 Antibody Blood Tests In a reversal, agency officials raised the bar for validation and accuracy standards, citing concerns about flawed tests and fraudulent marketing. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-tightens-the-rules-for-covid-19-antibody-blood-tests/

May 4, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Energy Does It Take to Blow Up a Planet? From Alderaan to Kijimi, Sith lords sure do love to blast planets to smithereens. So how powerful are Star Wars’ doomsday weapons anyway? https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-energy-does-it-take-to-blow-up-a-planet/

May 4, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Mental Health App Is Tailor-Made for Your Pandemic Woes Covid Coach, from the National Center for PTSD, offers exercises and resources for dealing with uncertainty, isolation, and unemployment. https://www.wired.com/story/this-mental-health-app-is-tailor-made-for-your-pandemic-woes/

May 4, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna How Might the Change of Seasons Affect Covid-19? Researchers want to know if the disease is seasonal, like colds. But while heat and humidity harm the virus in the lab, that’s not the same as real life. https://www.wired.com/story/how-might-the-change-of-seasons-affect-covid-19/

May 3, 2020 | Author: Thomas LewtonThomas Lewton The Universe Is Expanding Faster Than It Should. Why? The Hubble constant predicts how rapidly space should grow—but astronomical observations don’t line up. Here are the top ideas about what might be going on. https://www.wired.com/story/the-universe-is-expanding-faster-than-it-should-why/

May 2, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Happy Birthday, Hubble! Every year on the telescope’s birthday, we’re the ones who get a gift: a brilliant and never-before-seen snapshot of the cosmos. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-happy-birthday-hubble-30/

May 2, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Build Your Own Pinhole Videocam! Explore the bouncy behavior of light beams by constructing a high-tech camera obscura. https://www.wired.com/story/build-your-own-pinhole-videocam/

May 2, 2020 | Author: Madeline OstranderMadeline Ostrander Want to Study Permafrost? Get It Before It’s Gone Alaska’s frozen earth is a cryo chamber for ancient bone and bacteria specimens, and it sequesters carbon too. But climate change is causing its collapse. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-study-permafrost-get-it-before-its-gone/

May 2, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis Covid-19 Is Killing Black People Unequally—Don’t Be Surprised The coronavirus pandemic is further exposing a gulf in the health statistics of white and black Americans that has existed for decades. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-coronavirus-racial-disparities/

May 1, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The World Is Still Producing More Oil Than It Needs. Why? Today, petroleum producers around the world will start shutting down wells after the Covid-19 pandemic caused demand to plummet. What took them so long? https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-is-still-producing-more-oil-than-it-needs-why/

May 1, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Info War Over Chloroquine Has Slowed Covid-19 Science There’s been a lot of heat but not much light on whether the antimalarial drug helps coronavirus patients. That’s because we still need a big clinical trial. https://www.wired.com/story/the-info-war-over-chloroquine-has-slowed-covid-19-science/

April 30, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon ‘Microplastic Hot Spots’ Are Tainting Deep-Sea Ecosystems Scientists found 2 million microplastic particles in a square meter of sediment, as currents drag debris into seafloor versions of the Great Pacific Garbage Patch. https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-hotspots/

April 30, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Early Remdesivir Data for Covid-19 Is Finally Here Preliminary findings from a major clinical trial of the antiviral drug indicate it speeds recovery time for some patients. But much more testing lies ahead. https://www.wired.com/story/early-remdesivir-data-for-covid-19-is-finally-here/

April 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Moxie Is the Robot Pal You Dreamed of as a Kid Four years ago, Paolo Pirjanian set out to “reinvent” companion robots. Now he’s ready for the world to meet his creation. https://www.wired.com/story/moxie-is-the-robot-pal-you-dreamed-of-as-a-kid/

April 30, 2020 | Author: Lauren SmileyLauren Smiley 27 Days in Tokyo Bay: What Happened on the Diamond Princess The cruise ship captivated the world as it docked in Yokohama, harboring Covid-19—and 3,711 people who became subjects in a life-and-death quarantine experiment. https://www.wired.com/story/diamond-princess-coronavirus-covid-19-tokyo-bay/

April 29, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Clear the Air With a Sweet Frickin’ Laser Beam Fast laser pulses produce a shock wave in air that pushes water vapor aside. That clears channels in clouds for transmitting optical data from satellites. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-clear-the-air-with-a-sweet-frickin-laser-beam/

April 29, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Stewart Brand Is 81—and He Doesn’t Want to Go on a Ventilator The legendary thinker and founder of the Whole Earth Catalog raises a public conversation about end-of-life care during the Covid-19 pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/stewart-brand-ventilator-end-of-life-care/

April 29, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Microbe Mappers Are Tracking Covid-19’s Invisible Traces Armies of microbiologists are swabbing subways, ATMs, and hospitals in search of the novel coronavirus. Their data could help cities reopen responsibly. https://www.wired.com/story/microbe-mappers-are-tracking-covid-19s-invisible-traces/

April 28, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Does It Matter That the DOD Released Those UFO Videos? The Department of Defense isn’t admitting that aliens exist. But apparently they don’t mind if you check out their sweet rides. https://www.wired.com/story/does-it-matter-that-the-dod-released-those-ufo-videos/

April 28, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 5 Big Mistakes We Can Make Fighting the Covid-19 Pandemic Staying at home is a big sacrifice. But lifting shelter-in-place orders too soon is one of the many mistakes that will make the crisis even more brutal. https://www.wired.com/story/5-big-mistakes-covid-19/

April 28, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Covid-19 Was Here Earlier Than Most Americans Thought. Now What? Epidemiologists aren’t surprised that virus was spreading in the US in early February. But those early days offer lessons for how to catch the next wave. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-was-here-earlier-than-most-americans-thought-now-what/

April 28, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Here’s What Disinfectants and UV Light Really Do to Your Body There’s a reason why cleaners for external surfaces are not meant for your innards. They’re indiscriminate killers, not medicine. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-what-disinfectants-and-uv-light-really-do-to-your-body/

April 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Brain Implant Restored This Man’s Motion and Sense of Touch After his accident, Ian Burkhart didn’t think he’d ever be able to move or feel his hand again. A small chip in his brain changed everything. https://www.wired.com/story/a-brain-implant-restored-this-mans-motion-and-sense-of-touch/

April 27, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The Race to Get Convalescent Plasma to Covid-19 Patients Blood centers across the nation are trying to get antibodies from coronavirus survivors to patients who want this experimental treatment. But it’s not easy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-get-convalescent-plasma-to-covid-19-patients/

April 26, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett The Legacy of Math Luminary John Conway, Lost to Covid-19 Conway, who passed away on April 11, was known for his rapid computation, his playful approach, and solving problems with “his own bare hands.” https://www.wired.com/story/the-legacy-of-math-luminary-john-conway-lost-to-covid-19/

April 25, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Wait a Second, That Table Has No Legs! How to build “magic,” gravity-defying structures—with Legos, kite string, and physics. https://www.wired.com/story/wait-that-table-has-no-legs/

April 25, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Wait a Second, That Table Has No Legs! How to build “magic,” gravity-defying structures—with Legos, kite string, and physics. https://www.wired.com/story/wait-that-table-has-no-legs/

April 25, 2020 | Author: Emily PontecorvoEmily Pontecorvo Covid-19 Is Pulling the Plug on Clean Energy Jobs A new analysis warns that up to 500,000 jobs in the renewable energy industry will be wiped out by June, including ones in solar power, biofuels, and electric cars. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-is-pulling-the-plug-on-clean-energy-jobs/

April 25, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight As Workers Spread Out to Halt the Virus, Robots Fill the Gaps Social distancing requires rethinking the layout of workplaces. A new breed of robots can help keep factories and warehouses running. https://www.wired.com/story/workers-spread-halt-virus-robots-fill-gaps/

April 24, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Want a New Covid-19 Drug Fast? Bring on the Battle Royale Scientists have no shortage of contenders to fight the new coronavirus. But to find the winners, they’re trying new approaches to testing. https://www.wired.com/story/want-a-new-covid-19-drug-fast-bring-on-the-battle-royale/

April 24, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Spot the Coronavirus Doctor Robot Dog Will See You Now Boston Dynamics’ famously deft robot gets a job screening patients at a hospital. But there’s still much that it and other medical robots can’t do. https://www.wired.com/story/spot-the-coronavirus-doctor-robot-dog/

April 23, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Argentina’s Strict Covid-19 Lockdown Saved Lives Being there in mid-March gave me a window into what it would have looked like had the US taken serious action from the start. It also nearly stranded me 5,000 miles from home. https://www.wired.com/story/how-argentinas-strict-covid-19-lockdown-saved-lives/

April 23, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison All the Ways to Kill a Coronavirus (So Far) Even a bug this ruthless has a few fatal weaknesses of its own. https://www.wired.com/story/all-the-ways-to-kill-a-coronavirus-so-far/

April 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Hungry Little Beetle Could Help Ease Seasonal Allergies Where the leaf beetle lives with the common ragweed, pollen counts crash 80 percent. Maybe the enemy of our enemy is our allergy-fighting friend. https://www.wired.com/story/this-hungry-little-beetle-could-help-ease-seasonal-allergies/

April 23, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Covid-19 May Worsen the Antibiotic Resistance Crisis The disease can’t be treated with these drugs, but antibiotic use is rising anyway, in ICUs and among the worried well. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-may-worsen-the-antibiotic-resistance-crisis/

April 22, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Absurd Planet: WIRED’s Absurd Creatures Evolves Into a New Netflix Series What began as the Absurd Creature of the Week column, and became the Absurd Creatures web video series, has now inspired Netflix’s new Absurd Planet docu-series. https://www.wired.com/story/absurd-planet-netflix/

April 22, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Deepwater Horizon Disaster Fueled a Gulf Science Bonanza A decade after the worst oil spill in US history, researchers have turned out a massive data set charting the health of the ecosystem. https://www.wired.com/story/the-deepwater-horizon-disaster-fueled-a-gulf-science-bonanza/

April 22, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s Plan to Turn the ISS Into a Quantum Laser Lab A national quantum internet would enable ultra-secure data transmission. But first, we’re going to need some space lasers. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-plan-to-turn-the-iss-into-a-quantum-laser-lab/

April 21, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber New Covid-19 Antibody Study Results Are In. Are They Right? Two preprints of California serosurveys offer surprising estimates about the infection rate, and have caused a Twitter “peer review” uproar. https://www.wired.com/story/new-covid-19-antibody-study-results-are-in-are-they-right/

April 21, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Is the Coronavirus Pandemic Affecting Climate Change? Sure, emissions have fallen. But a closer look at how the global crisis is influencing the environment reveals some surprising dynamics. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-pandemic-climate-change/

April 20, 2020 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman The Covid-19 Newsletter That’s by Doctors for Doctors A team of critical care specialists has a side project debunking questionable coronavirus theories for other medical professionals. https://www.wired.com/story/the-covid-19-newsletter-thats-by-doctors-for-doctors/

April 20, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna ‘Covid Near You’ Crowdsources Data to Predict New Hot Spots  The site relies on people to anonymously report their symptoms. That information could offer early warnings to where the disease is spreading. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-near-you-crowdsources-data-to-predict-new-hotspots/

April 19, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain ‘Common Sense’ Is No Substitute for Science in a Pandemic The scientific method isn’t perfect, but it’s better than the alternative when lives are at stake. https://www.wired.com/story/common-sense-is-no-substitute-for-science/

April 19, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover An Imbalance Among Tiny Particles Offers a Big Cosmology Clue If matter and antimatter cancel each other out, how can the universe exist? A discrepancy in the behavior of neutrinos and antineutrinos hints at an answer. https://www.wired.com/story/an-imbalance-among-tiny-particles-offers-a-big-cosmology-clue/

April 19, 2020 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst How Long Does the Coronavirus Live on Surfaces? How Do I Know If I’m Immune? Your Covid-19 Questions, Answered Everything you need to know about the coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-social-distancing-flattening-curve-covid-19-questions/

April 19, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Cold, Hard Work of Delivering Oxygen to Ventilators Oxygen is in the air. Getting it to a Covid-19 patient struggling to breathe can be trickier than it seems. https://www.wired.com/story/cold-hard-work-delivering-oxygen-ventilators/

April 18, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: 50 Years After Apollo 13 The ill-fated mission is a testament to NASA’s ability to overcome an unfortunate series of events, even while in space. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-50-years-after-apollo-13/

April 18, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Measure Pressure With a Phone and a Baggie Missing physics lab? Here are three experiments you can do at home, with a free app and some everyday stuff. https://www.wired.com/story/measure-pressure-with-a-phone-and-a-baggie/

April 18, 2020 | Author: Marion Renault Marion Renault Freshwater Mussels Are Dying—Which Is the Likeliest Culprit? The list of suspects is long: bacteria, viruses, pollution, invasive species. No matter the cause, the Unionid Mussel Strike Force aims to find out. https://www.wired.com/story/freshwater-mussels-are-dying-which-is-the-likeliest-culprit/

April 17, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Magical Thinking of the White House’s New Covid-19 Plan The White House has “phases” for ending coronavirus restrictions, but offers states no help in achieving them. https://www.wired.com/story/the-magical-thinking-of-the-white-houses-new-covid-19-plan/

April 17, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Here’s How Covid-19 Immunity Compares to Other Diseases To stop the pandemic, it is critical to know how our immune system’s antibodies fight the coronavirus. This is what science can tell us so far. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-immunity/

April 17, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus So You’ve Found a Comet With a Weird Orbit … A recently discovered space rock hurtling through the solar system has some of the characteristics of an interstellar object. Here’s how astronomers would know for sure. https://www.wired.com/story/so-youve-found-a-comet-with-a-weird-orbit/

April 17, 2020 | Author: Jared WhitlockJared Whitlock Covid-19 Stalls Clinical Trials for Everything but Covid-19 Tests for many experimental drugs are now on hold, but for patients with life-threatening diseases, that means putting hope on hold too. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-stalls-clinical-trials-for-everything-but-covid-19/

April 17, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite AI Uncovers a Potential Treatment for Covid-19 Patients Software suggested an arthritis drug might quell an out-of-control immune response that damages the lungs. Now it’s being tested in a clinical trial. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-uncovers-potential-treatment-covid-19-patients/

April 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Ferrofluid Sculptures Will Melt Your Mind Using powerful electromagnets, Eric Mesplé makes these substances behave in mesmerizing ways. Here’s how he works his gloopy, creepy magic. https://www.wired.com/story/ferrofluid-sculptures/

April 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The WIRED Guide to Robots Everything you wanted to know about soft, hard, and nonmurderous automatons. https://www.wired.com/story/wired-guide-to-robots/

April 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Africa’s Huge Locust Swarms Are Growing at the Worst Time As coronavirus takes hold and farmers plant crops, the continent faces a new wave of locusts 20 times larger than one earlier this year. https://www.wired.com/story/africas-huge-locust-swarms-are-growing-at-the-worst-time/

April 16, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers State Alliances Are Leading the US Fight Against Covid-19 The Western States Pact and a council of northeastern states have formed public health coalitions while the federal government does … whatever it’s doing. https://www.wired.com/story/state-alliances-are-leading-the-us-fight-against-covid-19/

April 16, 2020 | Author: Adam ElderAdam Elder How a Pudgy Porpoise May Save Other Animals From Extinction The vaquita, an icon of the Gulf of California, is swiftly dying out. But its strange DNA could hold valuable lessons for other threatened species. https://www.wired.com/story/vaquitas-can-save-other-animals-from-extinction/

April 15, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Hospitals Quickly Reshape to Treat Covid-19 Patients Health care facilities are hastily constructing new entrances and testing facilities, installing glass doors, and crafting face shields to protect workers. https://www.wired.com/story/hospitals-quickly-reshape-treat-covid-19-patients/

April 15, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Does Covid-19 Do to Your Brain? Scientists are racing to figure out why some patients also develop neurological ailments like confusion, stroke, seizure, or loss of smell. https://www.wired.com/story/what-does-covid-19-do-to-your-brain/

April 15, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Fast Nanoscale ‘Movies’ Shed Light on a Solar Cell Mystery Physicists found the locations of major defects in perovskite cells—a critical breakthrough on the path to cheap, flexible solar technology. https://www.wired.com/story/fast-nanoscale-movies-shed-light-on-a-solar-cell-mystery/

April 15, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber What if Covid-19 Returns Every Year, Like the Common Cold? A new Harvard study models how long we’d have to keep social distancing if the virus turns out to be seasonal, like its coronavirus cousins. It could be years. https://www.wired.com/story/what-if-covid-19-returns-every-year-like-the-common-cold/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Sidney Fussell, Will KnightSidney Fussell and Will Knight The Apple-Google Contact Tracing Plan Won’t Stop Covid Alone Putting the privacy of these smartphone apps aside, few Americans have been tested—and there’s a risk of false positives. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-google-contact-tracing-wont-stop-covid-alone/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Stephen Wolfram Invites You to Solve Physics His new initiative intends to crowdsource the pursuit of the discipline’s holy grail: a fundamental theory of everything. https://www.wired.com/story/stephen-wolfram-invites-you-to-solve-physics/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis How Health Care Workers Avoid Bringing Covid-19 Home What do frontline workers do when they finish their shifts? Some have to isolate from their families to keep them safe.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-health-care-workers-families/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Amos ZeebergAmos Zeeberg Coronavirus Testing Is Coming Closer to Your Doctor’s Office The FDA still hasn’t approved at-home tests. But faster, more distributed tech is on the way to clinics and ERs—and is just what the doctor ordered. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-testing-is-moving-closer-to-your-doctors-office/

April 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Are Running or Cycling Actually Risks for Spreading Covid-19? An unpublished study went viral after a research team warned that respiratory droplets may travel more than 6 feet during exercise. But that’s not the whole story. https://www.wired.com/story/are-running-or-cycling-actually-risks-for-spreading-covid-19/

April 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Big Cats of Tiger King Will Live and Die in a Cage Wantonly breeding a tiger in captivity and releasing it into the wild could be terrible for the native population. https://www.wired.com/story/tiger-king-captive-breeding/

April 13, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Wants to Photograph the Surface of an Exoplanet Our galaxy is potentially full of habitable planets. A team of scientists plans to take a picture of one by turning the sun into a giant camera lens. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-wants-to-photograph-the-surface-of-an-exoplanet/

April 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Yet Another Consequence of the Pandemic: More Plastic Waste This new normal means mountains of single-use plastic—and few places to put it but the dump. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-pandemic-recycling-crisis/

April 12, 2020 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich The New Math Bridge Beyond Fermat’s Last Theorem  Two papers, representing the work of more than a dozen mathematicians, have finally figured out how to connect two realms that were once seen as distant. https://www.wired.com/story/the-new-math-bridge-beyond-fermats-last-theorem/

April 12, 2020 | Author: Kate KnibbsKate Knibbs The Real Reason Veterinarians Gave a Tiger a Covid-19 Test It’s hard for humans in New York City to get a test for the coronavirus. So when a Bronx Zoo tiger tested positive for Covid-19, it invited some questions. https://www.wired.com/story/tiger-coronavirus-bronx-zoo/

April 11, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Whirl a Squirrel off of a Bird Feeder In a viral video, a backyard snack bandit gets his just desserts. Next time he’ll want to check the physics of circular motion. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-whirl-a-squirrel-off-a-bird-feeder/

April 11, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: The Super Pink Moon Our natural satellite has inspired great writers for centuries. So we’ve paired these images with verses from literary stargazers—can you guess them? https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-super-pink-moon/

April 11, 2020 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica A New, Plastic-Busting Enzyme Can Break Down Water Bottles The end result of the reaction is a raw material that can be reused in new products. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-plastic-busting-enzyme-can-break-down-water-bottles/

April 11, 2020 | Author: Yvette CabreraYvette Cabrera Farmworkers ‘Can’t Pick Strawberries Over Zoom’ Field workers face many risks trying to feed a nation during the pandemic: crowded conditions, a lack of safety protections, and hunger at home. https://www.wired.com/story/farmworkers-cant-pick-strawberries-over-zoom/

April 10, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Astronaut Mike Massimino on How to Make the Most of This Isolation We’re all feeling a little cooped up right now. So why not shelter in place like you’re in a space shuttle, orbiting above the Earth? https://www.wired.com/story/astronaut-mike-massimino-isolation-coronavirus/

April 10, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Modified Sleep Apnea Machines May Ease the Ventilator Crunch Preparing for surges of Covid-19 patients, health care workers are turning to retrofitted versions of devices that are plentiful and approved for use. https://www.wired.com/story/modified-sleep-apnea-machines-may-ease-the-ventilator-crunch/

April 10, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Does Vaping Raise Your Risk of Covid-19 Symptoms? There are no studies yet, but reports showing heightened dangers for tobacco smokers and lung damage from vaping are raising alarms for doctors and parents. https://www.wired.com/story/does-vaping-raise-your-risk-of-covid-19-symptoms/

April 9, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The FDA Asks Companies to Stop Selling Ranitidine The federal agency cites concerns that the widely-used antacid may contain a possibly cancer-causing contaminant called NDMA. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-asks-companies-to-stop-selling-ranitidine/

April 9, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Can You Use an Infrared Camera to Detect a Fever? These devices are fun to play around with, but they’re also really useful—if you know the science behind them. https://www.wired.com/story/can-an-infrared-camera-detect-a-fever/

April 9, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Satellite Data Reveals the Pandemic’s Effects From Above Images taken from space are providing details to governments and relief efforts about how humanity is handling the Covid-19 crisis. https://www.wired.com/story/satellite-data-reveals-the-pandemics-effects-from-above/

April 9, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Death Cuts the Degree of Separation Between You and Covid-19 If knowing someone who has died would make the pandemic concrete for someone in the US—real and actionable—how many have to die? Here’s the grim math. https://www.wired.com/story/death-cuts-the-degree-of-separation-between-you-and-covid-19/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The US Hitches Its Final Ride to Space From Russia—for Now Thursday’s launch to the space station will mark the end of America’s dependence on Russia for human spaceflight, but NASA may buy more seats on Soyuz rockets.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-hitches-its-final-ride-to-space-from-russia-for-now/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Paris MartineauParis Martineau iPads Are Crucial Health Care Tools in Combating Covid-19 Hospitals are deploying tablets and smartphones to protect staff, preserve protective equipment, and help patients connect with loved ones. https://www.wired.com/story/ipads-crucial-health-tools-combating-covid-19/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus After 50 Years of Effort, Researchers Made Silicon Emit Light We’re approaching the speed limit for electronic computer chips. If we want to go faster, we’ll need data-carrying photons—and some tiny lasers. https://www.wired.com/story/after-50-years-of-effort-researchers-made-silicon-emit-light/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna We Need a Covid-19 Vaccine—Let’s Get It Right the First Time The flu shot campaigns of 1976 and 2009 offer key lessons for how (and how not) to distribute, monitor, and communicate about vaccines. But will anyone listen? https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-a-covid-19-vaccine-lets-get-it-right-the-first-time/

April 8, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen To Beat Covid-19, Scientists Try to ‘See’ the Invisible Enemy Using beams of X-rays and electrons, researchers are creating a moving model of the coronavirus in order to discover its weaknesses. https://www.wired.com/story/to-beat-covid-19-scientists-try-to-see-the-invisible-enemy/

April 7, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Does Covid-19 Make Some People So Sick? Ask Their DNA Consumer genomics company 23andMe wants to mine its database of millions of customers for clues to why the virus hits some people harder than others. https://www.wired.com/story/why-does-covid-19-make-some-people-so-sick-ask-their-dna/

April 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Turns Out, Traffic Spreads Like the Coronavirus Researchers use models meant for infectious diseases to show how congestion proliferates. That may mean a vaccine for traffic jams is on the horizon. https://www.wired.com/story/traffic-spreads-like-disease/

April 7, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Power Plant of the Future Is Right in Your Home If we want more renewable energy, our grids will have to manage themselves. A small experiment in Colorado is lighting the way. https://www.wired.com/story/the-power-plant-of-the-future-is-right-in-your-home/

April 7, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber One Way to Potentially Track Covid-19? Sewage Surveillance How many people have been infected with the new coronavirus? A group of Bay Area researchers aims to find out—by tracking what’s in the local wastewater. https://www.wired.com/story/one-way-to-potentially-track-covid-19-sewage-surveillance/

April 7, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Obama’s Ebola Czar on What Strong Federal Response Looks Like Ron Klain explains why government needs to speak with one voice—and what he’d do if he were in charge. https://www.wired.com/story/ebola-czar-ron-klain-federal-coronavirus-response/

April 6, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Deliciously Surprising Science of Taste That famous map of the tongue, with the different sections for bitter, sweet, salty, and sour? Way wrong. Here’s the fascinating truth. https://www.wired.com/story/science-of-taste/

April 6, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Asian Countries That Beat Covid-19 Have to Do It Again Singapore, Hong Kong, South Korea, and Taiwan had flattened the curve. Then travelers from the US and Europe began reimporting the virus. https://www.wired.com/story/the-asian-countries-that-beat-covid-19-have-to-do-it-again/

April 5, 2020 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Why Do Matter Particles Come in Threes? Nobel Prize–winning physicist Steven Weinberg’s new paper tackles the mystery of why the laws of nature appear to have been composed in triplicate. https://www.wired.com/story/why-do-matter-particles-come-in-threes/

April 5, 2020 | Author: Graham ReadfearnGraham Readfearn 2019 Was ‘Probably the Worst Year in a Century’ for Australia A new report weighs the damage from record heat and raging bushfires, and concludes that the environmental damage is on an “unprecedented scale.” https://www.wired.com/story/2019-was-probably-the-worst-year-in-a-century-for-australia/

April 5, 2020 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff We Are in the Midst of This Coronavirus Outbreak—Now What? WIRED answers reader questions about the scientific and social consequences of the pandemic, from privacy concerns to whether it’s OK to go running. https://www.wired.com/story/we-are-midst-coronavirus-outbreak-now-what/

April 4, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Awesome Planets and Ancient Gods Earth aside, all the planets in our solar system were named after Greek and Roman gods. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-awesome-planets-ancient-gods/

April 4, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of an Elephant-Powered Slam Dunk What could be better than sailing 30 feet through the air for a two-hand jam? Staying home and analyzing it! https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-an-elephant-powered-slam-dunk/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Trials of Plasma From Recovered Covid-19 Patients Have Begun US Food and Drug Administration officials approved nationwide tests of two treatments, both derived from the blood of people who have survived the disease. https://www.wired.com/story/trials-of-plasma-from-recovered-covid-19-patients-have-begun/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Klint FinleyKlint Finley Google Reveals Location Data to Help Public Health Officials The search giant is disclosing trends in visits to broad categories of places to inform policymakers’ responses to the coronavirus pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/google-reveals-location-data-health-officials-coronavirus/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Biggest Coronavirus Myths, Busted No, drinking water won’t flush the virus out of your mouth. Here’s how to inoculate yourself against bad Covid-19 information. https://www.wired.com/story/the-biggest-coronavirus-myths-busted/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Sabrina Weiss, WIRED UK Sabrina Weiss, WIRED UK Covid-19 Is Killing More Men Than Women—Here Are Some Theories Scientists can’t say for certain why the current pandemic is discriminating by sex, but it likely comes down to biology, lifestyle, and behavior.  https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-is-killing-more-men-than-women-here-are-some-theories/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to Refuel a Nuclear Power Plant During a Pandemic To swap out the spent uranium rods, hundreds of technicians from around the country must work in close quarters for weeks. That’s a challenge during a quarantine. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-refuel-a-nuclear-power-plant-during-a-pandemic/

April 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How a Real Dog Taught a Robot Dog to Walk Instead of coding a mechanical quadruped’s movements line by line, Google researchers fed it videos of real-life pups. Now it can even chase its tail. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-real-dog-taught-a-robot-dog-to-walk/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The High-Stakes Race to Build More Ventilators The US is short of ventilators to help Covid-19 patients breathe. Ford, GM, and satellite-launch company Virgin Orbit are trying to fill the gap. https://www.wired.com/story/race-build-more-ventilators-coronavirus/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis For Homeless People, Covid-19 Is Horror on Top of Horror As the coronavirus spreads, unhoused people are among the most vulnerable to infection.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-homeless/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman The (Political) Science Behind Trump’s Approval Bump The president is presiding over a public health nightmare and a mounting economic crisis. So why are voters warming up to him? https://www.wired.com/story/political-science-behind-trump-approval-ratings/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Gregory BarberMegan Molteni and Gregory Barber How a Crispr Lab Became a Pop-Up Covid Testing Center As the government fumbled Covid-19 testing, researchers at UC Berkeley’s Innovative Genomics Institute stepped up—with their own time and funding. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-lab-turned-pop-up-covid-testing-center/

April 2, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Coronavirus Lockdown Is a Threat for Many Animals, Not a Blessing You may have seen recent videos of goats roaming an empty town. But for more vulnerable species, like rhinos, this shutdown poses a great danger. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-lockdown-conservation/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Lauren GoodeLauren Goode The State of Coronavirus Testing in the US Many Americans who may need a Covid-19 test still can’t easily get one. What’s going on? https://www.wired.com/story/video-coronavirus-testing-in-the-us/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The US Army’s Virus Research Lab Gears Up to Fight Covid-19 The Pentagon’s Institute of Infectious Diseases has been handling the world’s most dangerous organisms for decades. Now they’re researching the new coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-armys-virus-research-lab-gears-up-to-fight-covid-19/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Mary Annaïse HeglarMary Annaïse Heglar We Can’t Tackle Climate Change Without You It’s time to make a commitment to do more for the climate. Do what you’re good at, and do your best. https://www.wired.com/story/what-you-can-do-solve-climate-change/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Katie M. Palmer, Matt SimonKatie M. Palmer and Matt Simon The WIRED Guide to Climate Change The world is getting warmer, the weather is getting worse. Here’s everything you need to know about what humans can do to stop wrecking the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/guide-climate-change/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Moises Velasquez-ManoffMoises Velasquez-Manoff The Fishy Fix to a Methane-Spewing Crop Rice has the biggest carbon footprint of any grain. Bite by bite, bacteria-guzzling minnows can make it much smaller. https://www.wired.com/story/tiny-hungry-fish-fix-rice-global-warming-problem/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Political Promise of Carbon Taxes Putting a price on emissions has become a bipartisan issue. Now we just need to do it the right way. https://www.wired.com/story/political-promise-carbon-emissions-tax/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson Solar Panels Could Be the Best Fad Ever Installing an array on your roof is environmental exhibitionism—and it’s contagious. https://www.wired.com/story/solar-panels-best-social-fad-ever/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson Special Issue: How We Will All Solve the Climate Crisis We only have one Earth. And we have the technology to save it. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-issue/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Nicola TwilleyNicola Twilley A One-Time Poultry Farmer Invents the Future of Refrigeration Mechanical cooling revolutionized the global food supply—and accelerated global warming. Peter Dearman’s liquid air engine could change all that. https://www.wired.com/story/refrigeration-global-warming-food-preservation/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Emma MarrisEmma Marris GMOs Are an Ally in a Changing Climate If we want to feed a growing population without fueling global warming, we need to redefine what we think of as good food. https://www.wired.com/story/future-food-will-need-gmo-organic-hybrid/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Mmmm, Fungus. It’s the Next Big Thing in Fake Meat Fast-growing networks of mycelial filaments can replicate meat’s texture—without meat’s carbon footprint. Just add flavor and fry it up. https://www.wired.com/story/fungus-next-big-alternative-fake-meat/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Eva HollandEva Holland A Truly Green Electric Grid Will Need Very Big Batteries It takes a lot more than just solar farms and wind turbines. Storing excess electricity is essential for renewable energy to really be renewable. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-grid-needs-big-vanadium-batteries/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Brooke JarvisBrooke Jarvis The Greatest Climate-Protecting Technology Ever Devised Through the profound, irreplaceable, utterly ordinary bit of magic that is photosynthesis, old trees can hold far more carbon than anybody else. https://www.wired.com/story/trees-plants-nature-best-carbon-capture-technology-ever/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Lisa MargonelliLisa Margonelli The Battle Against Global Warming Is the New Cold War Here’s how to mobilize the same federal machinery that gave us Wi-Fi, semiconductors, GPS, and the internet—this time to fight climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/global-warming-new-cold-war-technology/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser Concrete Is Awful for the Planet. Clever Chemistry Can Help Without it, our civilization would be nowhere. With it, the Earth is suffering. But what if concrete could be used to store climate-warming carbon? https://www.wired.com/story/concrete-carbon-emissions-clever-chemistry-can-help/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Stephen WittStephen Witt Solar Power Is Sustainable for the Economy, Too We’ve been talking about the potential for the sun’s energy for decades. Now it can be more profitable to save the planet than to ruin it. https://www.wired.com/story/affordable-solar-power-sustainable-economy/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Zak Jason, Anthony LydgateZak Jason and Anthony Lydgate Geoengineering Is an Option. Just Read the Fine Print Scientists have proposed a range of techniques for reducing global warming—some commonsense, some harebrained, and some scary as hell. https://www.wired.com/story/geoengineering-climate-fine-print/

April 1, 2020 | Author: Chris OutcaltChris Outcalt Wyoming Confronts Its Wind-Powered Destiny The Cowboy State should be a renewable energy juggernaut, but it’s dominated by fossils fuels. Next step: Thinking of the future instead of digging up the past. https://www.wired.com/story/wyoming-confronts-wind-powered-destiny/

March 31, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Search for the Next Big Idea in Magnetic Field Mapping A new competition challenges scientists to innovate on how we map Earth’s constantly shifting magnetic field—and make navigation safer and more accurate. https://www.wired.com/story/a-global-contest-seeks-the-next-big-idea-in-magnetic-mapping/

March 31, 2020 | Author: Fred VogelsteinFred Vogelstein A Creator of the Ebola Vaccine Has Hope for Slowing Covid-19 Gary Kobinger says a vaccine targeting groups like the elderly could be ready in less than a year, and control measures are slowing the disease’s spread. https://www.wired.com/story/creator-ebola-vaccine-hope-slowing-covid-19/

March 31, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber In Crowded Hospitals, Who Will Get Life-Saving Equipment? As health care workers prepare for surges of Covid-19 patients, they must grapple with the ethics of rationing critical medical gear. https://www.wired.com/story/in-crowded-hospitals-who-will-get-life-saving-equipment/

March 31, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Life During a Pandemic Feels So Surreal The study of the surreal has mostly concerned Dali’s paintings and Kafka’s writings. But there are psychological reasons why every day seems so otherworldly. https://www.wired.com/story/why-life-during-a-pandemic-feels-so-surreal/

March 30, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Charge a Car Battery in 5 Minutes? That’s the Plan Several companies have built lithium-ion batteries that can fully charge in a matter of minutes. Their next goal: getting these into electric vehicles. https://www.wired.com/story/charge-a-car-battery-in-5-minutes-thats-the-plan/

March 30, 2020 | Author: Adam Rogers, Megan MolteniAdam Rogers and Megan Molteni The Mathematics of Predicting the Course of the Coronavirus Epidemiologists are using complex models to help policymakers get ahead of the Covid-19 pandemic. But the leap from equations to decisions is a long one. https://www.wired.com/story/the-mathematics-of-predicting-the-course-of-the-coronavirus/

March 29, 2020 | Author: Dana NajjarDana Najjar Where Did Plants Come From? This Ancient Algae Offers Clues A tiny seaweed fossil from a billion years ago may help scientists understand how the first plants came ashore and evolved for life on land. https://www.wired.com/story/where-did-plants-come-from-this-ancient-algae-offers-clues/

March 28, 2020 | Author: Kate Cox, Ars TechnicaKate Cox, Ars Technica Business as Usual Is On Hold—Even at the EPA The Trump administration is adding environmental protection regulations to the list of temporary cancellations due to the pandemic.  https://www.wired.com/story/business-as-usual-is-on-hold-even-at-the-epa/

March 28, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Rovers Taking Selfies—for Science Instead of likes, these snapshots provide teams with vital information about how spacecraft are faring on interplanetary surfaces. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-rovers-selfies-for-science/

March 28, 2020 | Author: Jonathan Watts and Niko KommendaJonathan Watts and Niko Kommenda The Pandemic Has Led to a Huge, Global Drop in Air Pollution Reductions in traffic and industry have lowered nitrogen dioxide levels—offering an accidental glimpse into what a low-carbon future might look like. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pandemic-has-led-to-a-huge-global-drop-in-air-pollution/

March 27, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon An ER Doctor Describes What It’s Like to Treat Covid-19 The novel coronavirus is hitting emergency rooms in the US—hard. Cedric Dark, a physician at the Baylor College of Medicine, recounts the struggle. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-emergency-rooms/

March 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Competitor OneWeb Is Reportedly Bankrupt The company planned to put 650 internet satellites into orbit. But it only managed to launch 74 before its coffers ran dry, according to a report out today. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-competitor-oneweb-is-reportedly-bankrupt/

March 27, 2020 | Author: Kate KnibbsKate Knibbs The Race to Keep Health Care Workers Protected From Covid-19 As doctors and nurses address the pandemic, they are facing an unprecedented global crisis, a lack of resources, and a fight to save their own lives.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-healthcare-risks-equipment/

March 27, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis Coronavirus Conspiracy Theories Are a Public Health Hazard It’s time to debunk the worst—and most dangerous—Covid-19 misinformation.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-misinformation-campaigns/

March 27, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Why Stress-Baking and Cleaning Make You Less Anxious You’re not the only one who finds #quarantinebaking so soothing. Turns out, it has a lot to do with the neuroscience of mindful meditation. https://www.wired.com/story/why-stress-baking-and-cleaning-make-you-less-anxious/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies France’s Virus Train Moves Patients to Less Hard-Hit Areas The national railroad system converted a TGV high-speed train to move 20 Covid-19 patients from Strasbourg to calmer hospitals in the Loire Valley. https://www.wired.com/story/frances-virus-train-patients-less-hard-hit-areas/

March 26, 2020 | Author: E. Tammy KimE. Tammy Kim A South Korean Covid-19 Czar Has Some Advice for Trump “We need global cooperation,” says Min Pok-kee, who heads the response in the hard-hit city of Daegu. “Top government leaders don’t seem to get that yet.” https://www.wired.com/story/a-south-korean-covid-19-czar-has-some-advice-for-trump/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain That 8-Star System in Star Trek: Picard  Really Could Exist You’d need just the right arrangement, and the orbital motions would be insane, but the physics of an octonary system just might work! https://www.wired.com/story/that-8-star-system-really-could-exist/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Heady, Intricate Beauty of Watching Whiskey Evaporate When American whiskey evaporates, it leaves behind webs, or fingerprints of sorts, that could help sleuths identify counterfeit swill. https://www.wired.com/story/whiskey-webs/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen How to See the World’s Reflection From a Bag of Chips Computer scientists reconstructed the image of a whole room using the reflection from a snack package. It’s useful for AR/VR research—and possibly spying. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-see-the-worlds-reflection-from-a-bag-of-chips/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The Ibuprofen Debate Reveals the Danger of Covid-19 Rumors An online furor over whether it’s safe to use the fever reducer reveals how people are sharing incomplete—and sometimes bad—information. https://www.wired.com/story/the-ibuprofen-debate-reveals-the-danger-of-covid-19-rumors/

March 26, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite Engineers Made a DIY Face Shield. Now It’s Helping Doctors After a hospital put out a call for protective gear, three friends developed a product in a few days. Their design is now being manufactured by Ford. https://www.wired.com/story/tinkerers-created-face-shield-being-used-hospitals/

March 25, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Researchers Push for Mass Blood Tests as a Covid-19 Strategy While it might seem wasteful to test the seemingly healthy, tracking antibodies could show how widely the virus has spread—and who may now be immune. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-push-for-mass-blood-tests-as-a-covid-19-strategy/

March 25, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Covid-19 Pandemic Is a Crisis That Robots Were Built For Robots can help doctors distance from patients, and help those in isolation cope. But getting the machines into hospitals is fraught with difficulties. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-pandemic-robots/

March 25, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis What Coronavirus Isolation Could Do to Your Mind (and Body) Social distancing can lead to adverse psychological and physiological effects. But there are things you can do to maintain your overall health.  https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-isolation-psychology/

March 25, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Doctors Are Pooling Data to Help Understand Covid-19 They’ve created registries of people with chronic diseases who also have the new coronavirus, in order to track symptoms and find solutions. https://www.wired.com/story/doctors-are-pooling-data-to-help-understand-covid-19/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis Covid-19 Poses a Heightened Threat in Jails and Prisons An outbreak could seriously harm staff, the incarcerated, and the surrounding community. Releasing inmates could help—if they have somewhere to go. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-jails-prisons/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Promising Math Behind ‘Flattening the Curve’ Infectious diseases spread exponentially, yes, but only in the beginning. Thank God. https://www.wired.com/story/the-promising-math-behind-flattening-the-curve/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Trump’s Itch to Reboot the Economy Would Be a Fatal Error The president promises a return to work “sooner than people think.” But public health experts say we need months of social distancing to prevent millions of deaths from Covid-19. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-itch-to-reboot-the-economy-would-be-a-fatal-error/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Squids’ Gene-Editing Superpowers May Unlock Human Cures Researchers found that the cephalopod is the only creature that can edit its RNA outside the nucleus. It’s a tool that may one day help genetic medicine. https://www.wired.com/story/squids-gene-editing-superpowers-may-unlock-human-cures/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus America’s Electricity is Safe From the Coronavirus—for Now Utilities and grid operators are well-prepared to handle the pandemic, but a second wave of the virus later this year could be disastrous. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-electricity-is-safe-from-the-coronavirus-for-now/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite The Professors Who Call ‘Bullshit’ on Covid-19 Misinformation Jevin West and Carl Bergstrom are policing Twitter feeds, Medium posts, and other sources of bad data and misleading charts.  https://www.wired.com/story/professors-call-bullshit-covid-19-misinformation/

March 24, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Blood From Covid-19 Survivors May Point the Way to a Cure A 100-year-old way to beat disease could help researchers figure out how to harness the antibodies from earlier patients to help the newly infected. https://www.wired.com/story/an-old-source-for-potential-new-covid-19-drugs-blood-serum/

March 23, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Most Kids Only Get Mildly Sick From Covid-19—but Not All New studies suggest that children still fare better than adults. But  babies, toddlers, and kids with other conditions remain at risk. https://www.wired.com/story/most-kids-only-get-mildly-sick-from-covid-19-but-not-all/

March 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon If Robots Steal So Many Jobs, Why Aren’t They Saving Us Now? We’ve been led to believe that robots and AI are replacing humans en masse. But this economic catastrophe is blowing up that myth. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-jobs-coronavirus/

March 23, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna How ProMED Crowdsourced the Arrival of Covid-19 and SARS The low-tech site run by health experts collects reports of new diseases in real time. They’ve got a shoestring budget—and a stunning track record. https://www.wired.com/story/how-promed-crowdsourced-the-arrival-of-covid-19-and-sars/

March 22, 2020 | Author: Howard LeeHoward Lee An Ancient Magma Flood Offers Clues About Global Warming Four million years ago a burst of hot rock heated the planet, causing ocean acidification, massive storms, and extinctions. What can we learn from this early example? https://www.wired.com/story/an-ancient-magma-flood-offers-clues-about-global-warming/

March 22, 2020 | Author: Preston LernerPreston Lerner DIY Rockets, Daredevils, and the Tragedy of Mad Mike Hughes The homebrew rocket maker had dreams of fame and fortune. Those dreams ended on the edge of the Mojave Desert. I shouldn’t have been there to witness it. https://www.wired.com/story/diy-rockets-tragedy-mad-mike-hughes/

March 21, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Car on a Trampoline: More Kicks With Kinetic Energy How about some fun (and bouncity) physics puzzles to solve while you’re stuck at home? https://www.wired.com/story/car-on-a-trampoline-more-fun-with-physics/

March 21, 2020 | None Space Photos of the Week: Earth Looks Peaceful From up Here Let us gaze down upon our dear pale blue dot. https://www.wired.com/story/pale-blue-dot/

March 21, 2020 | Author: Adam WelzAdam Welz Fallout from Australia’s Huge Wildfires Is Choking Rivers Ash and debris from the massive January fires are now clouding Australia’s waterways, killing aquatic life and threatening drinking water supplies. https://www.wired.com/story/fallout-from-australias-huge-wildfires-is-choking-rivers/

March 20, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon An Expert Answers the 50 Most Googled Coronavirus Questions How is it spread? Why’s it called “coronavirus”? Dr. Seema Yasmin answers your burning questions about the pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/50-most-googled-coronavirus-questions/

March 20, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Fast Does a Virus Spread? Let’s Do the Math Infectious diseases grow exponentially, not linearly. The number of cases seems small—until they’re not, and then it’s too late. https://www.wired.com/story/how-fast-does-a-virus-spread/

March 19, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy The Doctor Who Helped Defeat Smallpox Explains What’s Coming Epidemiologist Larry Brilliant, who warned of pandemic in 2006, says we can beat the novel coronavirus—but first, we need lots more testing. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-interview-larry-brilliant-smallpox-epidemiologist/

March 19, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Chloroquine May Fight Covid-19—and Silicon Valley’s Into It The old malaria drug is getting used against the coronavirus. Tech enthusiasts are abuzz. One missing step: clinical trials. https://www.wired.com/story/an-old-malaria-drug-may-fight-covid-19-and-silicon-valleys-into-it/

March 19, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Want Electric Ships? Build a Better Battery Large container ships are a major contributor to greenhouse gas emissions, but electrifying the world’s fleet faces steep technological hurdles. https://www.wired.com/story/want-electric-ships-build-a-better-battery/

March 18, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies The Navy Deploys Two Hospital Ships as the Coronavirus Spreads The Comfort and the Mercy won’t handle Covid-19 patients because of their close quarters. An ER doctor questions if they should be used at all.  https://www.wired.com/story/navy-deploys-2-hospital-ships-coronavirus-spreads/

March 18, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Ventilator Makers Race to Prevent a Possible Shortage Manufacturers are producing as many as they can to care for Covid-19 patients with breathing problems. Now the federal government is asking for even more.  https://www.wired.com/story/ventilator-makers-race-to-prevent-a-possible-shortage/

March 18, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Mass Panic Is Unlikely, Even During a Pandemic Hollywood tells us humans are prone to lose all rationality in a disaster, looting and trampling one another. But that’s not giving our brains any credit. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-mass-panic-unlikely-pandemic/

March 18, 2020 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Could Crispr Be Humanity’s Next Virus Killer? Stanford scientists are exploring whether gene-editing technology can be used to fight pandemics. But so far, they have just one piece of a larger puzzle. https://www.wired.com/story/could-crispr-be-the-next-virus-killer/

March 17, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Moving Your Classes Online? Here’s How to Make It Work With high schools and colleges closing, the key is finding creative ways to keep students engaged. A physics prof shares his tips. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-make-online-learning-work/

March 17, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight Researchers Will Deploy AI to Better Understand Coronavirus More than 2,000 papers have been published about the virus since December. It will take some smart algorithms to mine insights from them. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-deploy-ai-better-understand-coronavirus/

March 17, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why the Coronavirus Hit Italy So Hard The country has the second-oldest population on earth, and its young mingle more often with elderly loved ones. https://www.wired.com/story/why-the-coronavirus-hit-italy-so-hard/

March 16, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber FDA Approves the First Commercial Coronavirus Tests in the US Swiss pharmaceutical giant Roche and medical-device maker Thermo Fisher collectively have nearly 2 million tests available, with more to come. https://www.wired.com/story/fda-approves-the-first-commercial-coronavirus-tests-in-the-us/

March 16, 2020 | Author: Paris MartineauParis Martineau The ‘Surreal’ Frenzy Inside the US’ Biggest Mask Maker Prestige Ameritech typically makes 250,000 masks a day. Now it’s manufacturing 1 million daily, and turning away orders for 100 million more.  https://www.wired.com/story/surreal-frenzy-inside-us-biggest-mask-maker/

March 16, 2020 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Social Distancing: How Many People Is Too Many? Schools and sports leagues are shutting down. But experts say it’s still safe for most people to shop for groceries and meet in small groups. https://www.wired.com/story/elegant-mathematics-social-distancing/

March 16, 2020 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis What If You Can’t Avoid the Hospital as Covid-19 Spreads? Even during a pandemic, people still need to deliver babies and get medical care. With little guidance, they face difficult choices.   https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid-19-hospital-visits/

March 16, 2020 | Author: Megan Molteni, Adam RogersMegan Molteni and Adam Rogers Everything You Need to Know About Coronavirus Testing How it works, why we need it, and why it’s taking so damn long for the US to get people diagnosed. https://www.wired.com/story/everything-you-need-to-know-about-coronavirus-testing/

March 15, 2020 | Author: Will KnightWill Knight Phones Could Track the Spread of Covid-19. Is It a Good Idea?  China and South Korea used smartphone apps to monitor people with the disease. But Americans have different views of privacy and data collection. https://www.wired.com/story/phones-track-spread-covid19-good-idea/

March 15, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Physicists Chip Away at a Mystery: Why Does Glass Exist? For decades, scientists have hoped to find or create ‘ideal glass,’ a perfect specimen that would help explain the nature of this enigmatic amorphous solid.  https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-chip-away-at-a-mystery-why-does-glass-exist/

March 14, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Pretty Planets, Gorgeous Galaxies Some cosmic catharsis for all the coronavirus-related anxiety you might be feeling at the moment. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-pretty-planets-gorgeous-galaxies/

March 14, 2020 | Author: Sidney FussellSidney Fussell Telemedicine Is a Safety Valve for a Strained Health Care System “Virtual visits” can be an effective way to decide who needs to be tested for Covid-19. But remote doctors can’t diagnose or treat illness. https://www.wired.com/story/telemedicine-safety-valve-strained-health-care-system/

March 14, 2020 | Author: L.V. AndersonL.V. Anderson Covid-19 Fears Shouldn’t Trash Your Zero Waste Efforts People worried about germs might be tempted to trade their reusable mugs and bags for single-use plastics. Environmental advocates say that’s not any safer. https://www.wired.com/story/covid-19-fears-shouldnt-trash-your-zero-waste-efforts/

March 14, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Can You Calculate Pi by Drawing a Circle? Take the Pi Day challenge: How many decimal places can you nail with this method? https://www.wired.com/story/calculate-pi-by-drawing-a-circle/

March 14, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber How Long Does the Coronavirus Last on Surfaces? Researchers looked at how long the virus can survive on cardboard, plastic, and stainless steel, as well as after being aerosolized and suspended in midair. https://www.wired.com/story/how-long-does-the-coronavirus-last-on-surfaces/

March 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Is a Quarantine?  Quarantines can slow the spread of novel bugs like this coronavirus. But there’s a right way to do them—and some very, very wrong ways. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-a-quarantine/

March 13, 2020 | Author: Gilad EdelmanGilad Edelman Trump on the Coronavirus Emergency: ‘I Don’t Take Responsibility’ Surrounded by sycophantic officials and executives, the president sang his own praises while declaring a national emergency. https://www.wired.com/story/covid19-trump-coronavirus-press-conference/

March 13, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna The US’ Health Depends on How It Cares for Health Care Workers A lack of test kits has forced hospitals to send potentially exposed workers home for just-in-case quarantines. But that means fewer staff on the front lines of the coronavirus pandemic. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-health-depends-on-how-it-cares-for-healthcare-workers/

March 13, 2020 | Author: Klint FinleyKlint Finley Data Sharing and Open Source Software Help Combat Covid-19 Scientists are rapidly analyzing genetic samples from infected patients and sharing the data. But to move too fast is to risk making mistakes. https://www.wired.com/story/data-sharing-open-source-software-combat-covid-19/

March 12, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Trump Bans Travel From Europe—but Covid-19 Is Already Here Public health experts say the US should prioritize protecting vulnerable residents and halting the domestic spread of the virus. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-bans-travel-from-europe-but-covid-19-is-already-here/

March 12, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Coronavirus Pandemic Is Bringing Down Emissions, but Not for Long As industries slow and people fly less, emissions are falling. But unless we get serious about restructuring our society, they’ll bounce right back. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-emissions/

March 12, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Should Earthlings Chase ‘Oumuamua Into Interstellar Space? A mission to the mysterious asteroid is technically feasible, but it might not be the best way to study interstellar objects. https://www.wired.com/story/should-earthlings-chase-oumuamua-into-interstellar-space/

March 12, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Singapore Was Ready for Covid-19—Other Countries, Take Note  After SARS and H1N1, Singapore built a robust system for tracking and containing epidemics. South Korea, Taiwan, and others did too—here’s what they learned. https://www.wired.com/story/singapore-was-ready-for-covid-19-other-countries-take-note/

March 11, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Trump’s Coronavirus Policies Don’t Tackle the Pandemic The US president promised loans and tax holidays, but his crisis-adjacent plans didn’t offer much to support the health care system. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-coronavirus-policies-dont-tackle-pandemic/

March 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What’s a Pandemic? Your Coronavirus Questions, Answered Dr. Seema Yasmin, director of the Stanford Health Communication Initiative, shares how to protect yourself and others in this alarming time. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-a-pandemic/

March 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Teeny-Tiny Flying Dino With a Mouth Full of Needle Teeth Oculudentavis was smaller than the smallest living bird, the bee hummingbird. Tantalizing clues point to it being a diminutive but skillful hunter. https://www.wired.com/story/the-teeny-tiny-flying-dino/

March 11, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr’s Origin Story Comes to Life in a New Documentary Human Nature takes a closer look at the scientists who founded the world-altering field of gene editing—and revels in the science. https://www.wired.com/story/crisprs-origin-story-comes-to-life-in-a-new-documentary/

March 11, 2020 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite The US-China Feud Makes It Harder to Fight Coronavirus Ian Bremmer, founder of the risk consultancy Eurasia Group, says populism, nationalism, and distrust are feeding the spread of disease. https://www.wired.com/story/us-china-feud-harder-fight-coronavirus/

March 10, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Disease Tracker Backed by Gates and Zuckerberg Tackles Covid-19 The two tech titans funded an effort to bring metagenomic sequencing and software to poor countries. Now, it’s helping trace the spread of the new coronavirus. https://www.wired.com/story/a-disease-tracker-backed-by-gates-and-zuckerberg-tackles-covid-19/

March 10, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Long Could the World Run on Geothermal Power? If everyone went 100 percent geothermal today, Earth’s store of thermal energy would still outlive the sun. https://www.wired.com/story/how-long-will-earths-geothermal-energy-last/

March 9, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Two Physicists Bet Over a Quantum Computing Moon Shot Topological quantum computing has long been a beautiful dream. Two top scientists are now facing off over whether it will exist by 2030. https://www.wired.com/story/two-physicists-bet-over-a-quantum-computing-moonshot/

March 9, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Worried About Covid-19? Hospitals Have a Request: Stay Home More US health care facilities may soon need to treat coronavirus patients, so doctors don’t want to use up precious resources on the “worried well.” https://www.wired.com/story/worried-about-covid-19-hospitals-have-a-request-stay-home/

March 9, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Ultra-Fast Genome Sequencing Could Save the Lives of Newborns Whole genome tests can help identify the cause of a baby’s mysterious illness. But ethicists say it’s still too soon to use them for all infants. https://www.wired.com/story/ultra-fast-genome-sequencing-could-save-lives-newborns/

March 8, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Computer Science Proof Holds Answers for Math and Physics An advance in our understanding of quantum computing offers stunning solutions to problems that have long puzzled mathematicians and physicists. https://www.wired.com/story/a-computer-science-proof-holds-answers-for-math-and-physics/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Trump’s Coronavirus Press Event Was Even Worse Than It Looked His remarks at the CDC on Friday were misguided, misleading, and show how misinformation could hamper Covid-19 containment efforts. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-coronavirus-press-event-was-even-worse-than-it-looked/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Perfectly Safe Celestial Coronas Leave Earth and its corona-related problems behind. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-perfectly-safe-celestial-coronas/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Amit Katwala, WIRED UKAmit Katwala, WIRED UK The Coronavirus Could Put an End to Handshakes The rate of change in everyday rituals is accelerating, in part because we’re living in an era of heightened disease awareness. https://www.wired.com/story/the-coronavirus-could-put-an-end-to-handshakes/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Graham ReadfearnGraham Readfearn Dolphins Are Still Accidental Casualties of Tuna Fishing A new study estimates that about 80,000 cetaceans are swept up every year by tuna-fishing nets in the Indian Ocean. https://www.wired.com/story/dolphins-are-still-accidental-casualties-of-tuna-fishing/

March 7, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Kids Can Get Covid-19. They Just Don’t Get That Sick New data suggests that children aren’t immune to the new coronavirus. That could have huge implications for efforts to contain local outbreaks. https://www.wired.com/story/kids-can-get-covid-19-they-just-dont-get-that-sick/

March 6, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Measure the Speed of the ISS With Your iPhone Using just the technology in your pocket, you can gauge the velocity of the space station as it zips across the night sky. https://www.wired.com/story/measure-the-speed-of-the-iss-with-your-iphone/

March 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Factory Where They Engineer Massive Water Art Pieces WET, a preeminent water design firm, uses supercomputers and other cutting-edge technology to build the most iconic fountains and water features in the world. https://www.wired.com/story/wet-factory-engineering-massive-water-art-pieces/

March 5, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Race for a Coronavirus Vaccine, Cloned Car Keys, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-covid19-vaccine-hackers-keyfob-toyota-hyundai-kia/

March 5, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The US Has a ‘Plan’ to Fight Coronavirus: You So far, government officials have offered little direction and no financial support despite urging people to stay home and take care of themselves.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-has-a-plan-to-fight-coronavirus-you/

March 5, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Scientists Chase Snowflakes During the Warmest Winter Ever A NASA project to study snowstorms in the Northeast has faced a lack of storms and a broken plane. They’re not giving up. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-chase-snowflakes-during-the-warmest-winter-ever/

March 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Hungry Animals Can Change How Severely a Landscape Burns From tiny insects to big ungulates, animals and their choice of chow can make ecosystems less or more prone to go up in flames. https://www.wired.com/story/hungry-animals-wildfires/

March 4, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Everything You Need to Know About Coronavirus Vaccines As Covid-19 spreads, the pressure is on for drugmakers to get a vaccine to market. But it’s not that easy. https://www.wired.com/story/everything-you-need-to-know-about-coronavirus-vaccines/

March 4, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Spot Fake Video Stunts—With Science! This amazing soccer trick has gone viral. But does it hold up to the laws of physics? https://www.wired.com/story/spot-fake-video-stunts-with-physics/

March 4, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Deft Robotic Hand That’d Make Luke Skywalker Proud Surgeons use muscle grafts to amplify nerve signals—allowing amputees to control a new prosthetic with incredible precision. https://www.wired.com/story/a-deft-robotic-hand/

March 3, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SETI@Home Is Over. But the Search for Alien Life Continues Although the public part of the worldwide experiment is coming to an end this month, the world’s greatest extraterrestrial hunt is far from finished. https://www.wired.com/story/setihome-is-over-but-the-search-for-alien-life-continues/

March 3, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Ask the Know-It-Alls: What Is the Coronavirus? Plus: How can I avoid catching it? Is Covid-19 more deadly than the flu? Our in-house Know-It-Alls answer your questions. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-a-coronavirus/

March 3, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Your Phone May Soon Receive 4G Service … From Space! Billions of people live in areas that lack mobile coverage. Two companies are racing to build satellite networks that will provide service everywhere. https://www.wired.com/story/your-phone-may-soon-receive-4g-service-from-space/

March 3, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Spit Kits, Sperm Donors, and the End of Family Secrets At-home DNA testing is more accessible than ever. In The Lost Family, Libby Copeland learns how genetic revelations are upending lives. https://www.wired.com/story/spit-kits-sperm-donors-and-the-end-of-family-secrets/

March 3, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How UFO Sightings Became an American Obsession In 1947, a pilot spotted a fleet of “saucer-like” aircrafts speeding across the sky. It was only a matter of time until paranoia set in. https://www.wired.com/story/how-ufo-sightings-became-an-american-obsession/

March 2, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Think Flash Floods Are Bad? Buckle Up for Flash Droughts A typical drought is a slow-motion catastrophe. But scientists are trying to figure out a phenomenon called a flash drought, which forms in as little as two weeks. https://www.wired.com/story/flash-droughts/

March 2, 2020 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Plane Contrails Have a Surprising Effect on Global Warming The wispy ice clouds formed by jet exhaust help trap heat near the Earth’s surface. But small changes in altitude can dampen the effect, a study says. https://www.wired.com/story/plane-contrails-surprising-effect-global-warming/

March 2, 2020 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A New Study Challenges the Reliability of Court Psych Exams  A team of lawyers and psychologists reviewed 364 exams used in the legal system, finding a third of them don’t pass muster with forensic mental health experts.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-study-challenges-the-reliability-of-court-psych-exams/

March 1, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Science Has a New Way to Gauge the Universe’s Expansion Rate Cosmologists want to know how fast the universe is growing, but their data doesn’t match predictions. Wendy Freedman thinks red giant stars can help. https://www.wired.com/story/science-has-a-new-way-to-gauge-the-universes-expansion-rate/

February 29, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Venus Is the Spacecraft-Killer One of NASA’s proposed missions would send a spacecraft to Venus on a suicide mission in order to study its atmosphere. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-venus-is-the-spacecraft-killer/

February 29, 2020 | Author: Delilah FriedlerDelilah Friedler Think Ride Sharing Is Good for the Planet? Not So Fast Despite hopes that ride hailing would ease traffic and reduce carbon emissions, a new study finds that it’s actually driving them upward. https://www.wired.com/story/think-ride-sharing-is-good-for-the-planet-not-so-fast/

February 28, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Did a Woman Get Coronavirus Twice? Scientists Are Skeptical News reports claim that a Japanese patient was reinfected with Covid-19. But there are other possibilities, like a bad test or a flare-up of the original disease. https://www.wired.com/story/did-a-woman-get-coronavirus-twice-scientists-are-skeptical/

February 28, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Katherine Johnson’s Math Will Steer NASA Back to the Moon She mapped Apollo 11’s path to history. Now, her legacy lives on in the trajectories of future spaceflights—including the moon landing planned for 2024. https://www.wired.com/story/katherine-johnsons-math-will-steer-nasa-back-to-the-moon/

February 28, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Sea Is Getting Warmer. Will the Shrimp Get Louder? The snapping shrimp’s claws pop louder than gunshots. Rising temperatures could make them fire  faster—and disrupt their undersea neighbors. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sea-is-getting-warmer-will-the-shrimp-get-louder/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Glowing Amphibians, Extreme Weather Satellites, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/amphibians-glow-goes-satellite-climate-change/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Recycled Nuclear Waste Will Power a New Reactor Last week, the Department of Energy gave a commercial company the green light to test fuel made from spent uranium. https://www.wired.com/story/recycled-nuclear-waste-will-power-a-new-reactor/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon So, Amphibians Glow. Humans Just Couldn’t See It—Until Now Bathe an amphibian in blue light and it glows a brilliant green. But what does this all mean? https://www.wired.com/story/amphibians-glow/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Brian BarrettBrian Barrett The Smithsonian Puts 2.8 Million Images in the Public Domain The archive includes hi-res images of Muhammad Ali’s boxing gear, 15th-century manuscripts, and data that could help surface untold stories of women in science. https://www.wired.com/story/smithsonian-puts-2-8-million-images-public-domain/

February 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Extreme Weather-Tracking Satellites Prepare for Launch A new array of sats will detect nearly every bolt of lightning in the Western Hemisphere, powering an early warning system for climate-change-fueled superstorms. https://www.wired.com/story/goes-extreme-weather-satellites-ready-for-launch/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The US Has Its First ‘Community Spread’ Coronavirus Case The patient was admitted to UC Davis Medical Center on February 19 but not diagnosed until the 23rd—raising concerns about testing capabilities and health care workers’ exposure to the disease. https://www.wired.com/story/community-spread-coronavirus/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb US Coronavirus Prep, a Fatal Tesla Crash Ruling, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/covid19-coronavirus-us-tesla-autopilot-crash/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Next Generation of Batteries Could Be Built by Viruses Angela Belcher found a way to turn nature’s zombies into a tiny assembly line. But creating a new power cell might be just the beginning. https://www.wired.com/story/the-next-generation-of-batteries-could-be-built-by-viruses/

February 26, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Clever Robotic Finger Feels With Light The nerves in human fingertips are great at sensing things. For robots, learning to touch is more complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/this-clever-robotic-finger-feels-with-light/

February 25, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Could the US Contain a Coronavirus Outbreak? The World Health Organization has urged other nations to learn from China’s handling of the Covid-19 epidemic. But would an aggressive quarantine work here? https://www.wired.com/story/could-the-us-contain-a-coronavirus-outbreak/

February 25, 2020 | Author: Briana FlinBriana Flin Will Your Cat Eat Your Corpse? The short answer is maybe. The long answer won’t make you feel any better. https://www.wired.com/story/will-your-cat-eat-your-corpse/

February 24, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Australia’s Bushfires Completely Blasted Through the Models The wildfires weren’t just unprecedented—scientists didn’t think such catastrophic conflagrations would happen until the end of this century.  https://www.wired.com/story/australias-bushfires/

February 24, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Astronomy Expands Its Scope From the Heavens to Humans Every 10 years, astronomers weigh in on the state of their field. For the first time, they’re tackling Earth-centric issues like gender bias and diversity.  https://www.wired.com/story/astronomy-expands-its-scope-from-the-heavens-to-humans/

February 23, 2020 | Author: Nola Taylor ReddNola Taylor Redd A Star’s Auroras Light the Way to a New Exoplanet For the first time using this new technique, astronomers have identified an Earth-size planet by observing telltale solar flares. https://www.wired.com/story/a-stars-auroras-light-the-way-to-a-new-exoplanet/

February 22, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Triton and Io, Here We Come If approved, these missions will be the first time Neptune’s and Jupiter’s respective moons see probes dedicated to studying them. https://www.wired.com/story/triton-and-io-here-we-come-hopefully/

February 22, 2020 | Author: Maria GallucciMaria Gallucci Family Farms Try to Raise a New Cash Cow: Solar Power A ‘solar sharing’ pilot project in Colorado is testing whether farmers can profit from growing vegetables and harvesting green energy on the same plot. https://www.wired.com/story/family-farms-try-to-raise-a-new-cash-cow-solar-power/

February 21, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Wait, Is That Backpack … Floating? A new pack from HoverGlide looks like magic. But there’s a perfectly good physics explanation. https://www.wired.com/story/whoa-crazy-levitating-backpack/

February 21, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler ‘Environmental DNA’ Lets Scientists Probe Underwater Life With the help of a new kind of drone, marine biologists can sequence DNA found in the ocean to reveal what’s living in an ecosystem—and what’s missing. https://www.wired.com/story/environmental-dna-lets-scientists-probe-underwater-life/

February 21, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Look Inside a Brain? With Transparent Organs, You Can Using clever chemical wizardry, researchers have made human organs see-through. The dazzling 3D maps could one day lead to organs made in the lab. https://www.wired.com/story/transparent-organs/

February 20, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Bezos’ Earth Fund Should Invest in These Green Technologies The world’s richest man committed $10 billion to fighting climate change. We’ve got some ideas about how to spend it. https://www.wired.com/story/bezos-earth-fund-should-invest-in-these-green-technologies/

February 20, 2020 | Author: Nicole Kobie, WIRED UKNicole Kobie, WIRED UK How a Princess Cruise Became a Coronavirus Catastrophe The 2,666 passengers signed up for a two-week vacation. They ended up at the heart of a global epidemic. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-princess-cruise-became-a-coronavirus-catastrophe/

February 20, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Cities Fighting Climate Woes Hasten ‘Green Gentrification’ Seawalls, parks, and elevated buildings can protect against rising tides. But they can also push the price of housing up, and longtime residents out. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-fighting-climate-woes-hasten-green-gentrification/

February 19, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Take Their Closest Look Yet at an Antimatter Atom Scientists at CERN found a way to trap hydrogen’s mirror twin, antihydrogen, long enough to study it in greater detail than ever before. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-take-their-closest-look-yet-at-an-antimatter-atom/

February 19, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What If ‘Planetary Alignment’ Really Could Make Brooms Balance? Celestial bodies aren’t the reason broomsticks can stand up on end. If they were, it would unleash gravitational chaos. https://www.wired.com/story/be-glad-the-broom-trick-isnt-real/

February 19, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Cheap Nanoparticles Pave the Way for Carbon-Neutral Fuel A new way to produce nanoparticles—which convert carbon dioxide emissions into fuel—may help a niche green-energy technology go mainstream. https://www.wired.com/story/cheap-nanoparticles-pave-the-way-for-carbon-neutral-fuel/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Arctic Is Getting Greener. That’s Bad News for All of Us From space and with drones, scientists are watching the Arctic get greener. That’s troubling both for the region, and the planet as a whole. https://www.wired.com/story/arctic-greening/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Evan LubofskyEvan Lubofsky The Atlantic Ocean’s ‘Conveyor Belt’ Stirs Up a Science Fight Researchers are debating the best way to monitor the ocean currents that sweep through the Labrador Sea—and may foretell the planet’s climate future. https://www.wired.com/story/the-atlantic-oceans-conveyor-belt-stirs-up-a-science-fight/

February 18, 2020 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee Floating Farms Point the Way to Alternative Food Ecosystems Thirty-four Meuse-Rhine-Issels aboard a stable in Rotterdam’s harbor show that cow buoys could provide a creative way to boost food security. https://www.wired.com/story/floating-farms-global-food-ecosystem/

February 17, 2020 | Author: Damian CarringtonDamian Carrington A Car ‘Splatometer’ Study Finds Huge Insect Die-Off Measuring how many bugs fly into car windshields might sound silly. But to scientists predicting an “insect apocalypse,” the numbers are deadly serious.  https://www.wired.com/story/a-car-splatometer-study-finds-huge-insect-die-off/

February 16, 2020 | Author: Devin PowellDevin Powell Psychedelic Fiber Offers a New Twist on the Science of Knots  A stretchy plastic that changes colors as it deforms lets mathematicians and physicists model the stress points of knots, and test which is the strongest.  https://www.wired.com/story/psychedelic-fiber-offers-a-new-twist-on-the-science-of-knotsandnbsp/

February 15, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: The Stellar Women of the ISS They’re out of this world and breaking new ground for space science. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-the-stellar-women-of-the-iss/

February 15, 2020 | Author: Cathleen O’Grady, Ars TechnicaCathleen O’Grady, Ars Technica ‘Baby Talk’ Can Help Kids Learn Language (Oh Yes It Can!) The more ‘parentese’ there is at home, the more likely a child is to have an advanced vocabulary later on.  https://www.wired.com/story/baby-talk-can-help-kids-learn-language-oh-yes-it-can/

February 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Darpa Cranks Up Antibody Research to Stall Coronavirus It’s not the same as a vaccine. But a shorter-lived antibody treatment may shield health workers and family members during the early days of an outbreak. https://www.wired.com/story/darpa-cranks-up-antibody-research-to-stall-coronavirus/

February 13, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Want Unlimited Clean Energy? Just Drill the World’s Hottest Well An engineering team bored 2 miles into hot rock without causing major earthquakes—a good sign for harnessing the Earth’s heat as a power source. https://www.wired.com/story/want-unlimited-clean-energy-just-drill-the-worlds-hottest-well/

February 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Doctors on Earth Treated a Blood Clot on the ISS A scan revealed a clot in a patient’s jugular. The challenge? That patient was an astronaut, 250 miles overhead in the International Space Station. https://www.wired.com/story/blood-clot-space-station/

February 13, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni China Launches a Crush of Clinical Trials Aimed at Covid-19 The country’s health care system, with its expertise in conducting clinical research, is ready to run new drug tests. But coordinating them all is another matter. https://www.wired.com/story/china-launches-a-crush-of-clinical-trials-aimed-at-covid-19/

February 12, 2020 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica NASA Puts a Price on a 2024 Moon Landing  Last year, the vice president directed the space agency to put astronauts back on the moon. NASA crunched the numbers—and it won’t come cheap. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-puts-a-price-on-a-2024-moon-landing/

February 12, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Can a Database of Animal Viruses Help Predict the Next Pandemic? A scientist spent years building a tool to identify coronaviruses that can jump species. Then this winter’s virus emerged—and put his system to the test. https://www.wired.com/story/can-a-database-of-animal-viruses-help-predict-the-next-pandemic/

February 12, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Marsupial Dies After Marathon Mating. Now It’s Got Bigger Worries Antechinus has so much sex over three weeks that males go blind and die, yet it’s climate change that threatens the Australian mammal. https://www.wired.com/story/antechinus-climate-change/

February 11, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Coronavirus Has a Name: The Deadly Disease Is Covid-19 The virus that causes it is SARS-CoV-2. (We didn’t say they were good names.) https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-has-a-name-the-deadly-disease-is-covid-19/

February 11, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Hurling Satellites Into Space Seems Crazy—but Might Just Work A startup called SpinLaunch wants to do away with costly launch rockets. Let’s look at the physics. https://www.wired.com/story/hurling-satellites-into-space/

February 11, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Big (yet Hidden) Consequences of Antarctica’s Record Heat As the continent rapidly warms, unique communities of tiny animals like water bears are transforming in profound ways. https://www.wired.com/story/antarctica-record-heat/

February 11, 2020 | Author: Nicola TwilleyNicola Twilley Algae Caviar, Anyone? What We’ll Eat on the Journey to Mars Humans are headed for the cosmos, and we’re taking our appetites with us. What will fill the void when we leave Earth behind? https://www.wired.com/story/space-food-what-will-keep-us-human/

February 10, 2020 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles What Scientists Can Learn From Alien Hunters The history of the search for extraterrestrial life sheds light on the consequences of dismissing fringe perspectives, in science and in other disciplines. https://www.wired.com/story/what-scientists-can-learn-from-alien-hunters/

February 9, 2020 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica The Secret to Blowing Massive Soap Bubbles This physicist-approved recipe uses a dash of polymers to create world-record-scale bubbles. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-determine-optimal-soap-recipe-for-blowing-gigantic-bubbles/

February 9, 2020 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett The Universal Law of Turbulence Isn’t So Unruly After All By exploiting randomness, mathematicians have proved an elegant law that underlies the motion of rushing rivers and other chaotic fluids. https://www.wired.com/story/the-universal-law-of-turbulence-isnt-so-unruly-after-all/

February 7, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Fight Climate Change? Stop Believing These Myths In Mark Jaccard’s new book, The Citizen’s Guide to Climate Success, he argues that the key is to stop obsessing about notions like peak oil. https://www.wired.com/story/guide-to-climate-success/

February 7, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Europe’s Solar Orbiter Begins Its Journey to the Sun ESA’s orbiter will work with NASA’s Parker Solar Probe to unveil the mysteries of our home star and the origin of violent storms that spew plasma across space. https://www.wired.com/story/europes-solar-orbiter-begins-its-journey-to-the-sun/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Promising Crispr Trial, Happy-ish Tesla Investors, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-cancer-trial-tesla-stock-coronavirus/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr’d Cells Show Promise in First US Human Safety Trial Using genetically-edited cells to supercharge the immune system caused no adverse effects in cancer patients. It’s too soon to tell if it can be a cure. https://www.wired.com/story/crisprd-cells-show-promise-in-first-us-human-safety-trial/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica OneWeb Joins the Internet Satellite Gold Rush The company is scheduled to launch 34 satellites Thursday from Kazakhstan. https://www.wired.com/story/oneweb-joins-internet-satellite-gold-rush/

February 6, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Travel Bans and Quarantines Won’t Stop Coronavirus The US announced travel restrictions on Friday. But some public health experts worry that a ban won’t work—and could create new problems. https://www.wired.com/story/travel-bans-and-quarantines-wont-stop-coronavirus/

February 5, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Yes, You Can Map Out an Electric Field at Home Grab your sheet of conducting paper and you’ll be charting invisible electrostatic forces in no time. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-map-invisible-electric-fields/

February 5, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Welcome to the Era of Supercharged Lithium-Silicon Batteries Batteries with silicon anodes promise to make devices last more than 20 percent longer on a single charge. https://www.wired.com/story/welcome-to-the-era-of-supercharged-lithium-silicon-batteries/

February 5, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Terrifying Science Behind the Locust Plagues of Africa With hundreds of billions of locusts tearing through farmland, it’s the worst outbreak to strike the region in decades. https://www.wired.com/story/the-terrifying-science-behind-the-locust-plagues-of-africa/

February 4, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The US Fast-Tracked a Coronavirus Test to Speed Up Diagnoses The FDA has given emergency authorization to a new test that promises to help public health labs meet a potential surge in cases. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-fast-tracked-a-coronavirus-test/

February 4, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen This Cloth Destroys Deadly Nerve Agents in Minutes Chemists are collaborating with the US Army to build uniforms that can quickly break down toxic substances, protecting soldiers from chemical weapons. https://www.wired.com/story/this-cloth-destroys-deadly-nerve-agents/

February 4, 2020 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Amid Coronavirus Fears, a Mask Shortage Could Spread Globally Most of the world’s supply of masks and respirators comes from China, and a supply chain gap poses a risk to everyday health care beyond the viral epidemic. https://www.wired.com/story/amid-coronavirus-fears-a-mask-shortage-could-spread-globally/

February 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Permafrost Is Thawing So Fast, It’s Gouging Holes in the Arctic Normally, these terrains of frozen soil thaw gradually. But in some places, it’s thawing so abruptly that landscapes are collapsing in on themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/abrupt-permafrost-thaw/

February 2, 2020 | Author: Michele BannisterMichele Bannister Expect More Interstellar Visitors Like ’Oumuamua We live in a galaxy teeming with wandering tiny worlds, and some astronomers predict they’ll be detecting them at least once per year. https://www.wired.com/story/expect-more-interstellar-visitors-like-oumuamua/

February 1, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: There’s Nothing Like the Sun You’re gonna need shades for this one. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-week-sun-up-close-personal/

February 1, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Wuhan Coronavirus ‘Super-Spreaders’ Could Be Wildcards Tracking the spread of disease requires precision and math. But super-spreaders, who transmit germs faster and further than other patients, can confound the model. https://www.wired.com/story/wuhan-coronavirus-super-spreaders-could-be-wildcards/

January 31, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Coronavirus Research Is Moving at Top Speed—With a Catch Scientists are posting their papers on the China outbreak as fast as they can write them, skipping traditional journals. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-research-preprint-servers/

January 31, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Not to Ruin the Super Bowl, but the Sea Is Consuming Miami Huzzah for tailgates and overeating stadium food. Boo the fact that climate change is an existential threat to Miami. https://www.wired.com/story/rising-seas-are-coming-for-miamis-super-bowls/

January 30, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Coronavirus Global Health Emergency, an Amazon Rival, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/coronavirus-global-health-emergency-bookshop-amazon/

January 30, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Coronavirus Is Now Officially a Global Emergency The World Health Organization declared the China outbreak an international threat, raising questions about many countries’ health infrastructure. https://www.wired.com/story/wuhan-china-coronavirus-global-health-emergency/

January 30, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen A Tiny Glass Bead Goes as Still as Nature Allows In everyday life, stillness is an illusion. Not so in this lab, where scientists rendered an object as motionless as the laws of physics permit. https://www.wired.com/story/a-tiny-glass-bead-goes-as-still-as-nature-allows/

January 30, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Coronavirus Is Now Infecting More People Outside China Public health experts worry the outbreak is entering a dangerous new phase as cases of local transmission in other countries accumulate. https://www.wired.com/story/the-coronavirus-is-now-infecting-more-people-outside-china/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus RIP Spitzer, the Coolest Heat Telescope in the Solar System For 16 years, NASA’s trusty scope revealed a hidden infrared universe. Now it’s up to the James Webb Space Telescope to pick up where it left off. https://www.wired.com/story/rip-spitzer-telescope/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Spinning Rocket Slinger, a Bionic Jellyfish, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/spinlaunch-rocket-bionic-jellyfish/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Bionic Jellyfish Swims With Manic Speed (for a Jellyfish) Researchers equip jellyfish with electronics to turbocharge their swimming pace. It’s a fascinating new way to approach robotics. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bionic-jellyfish/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Nail a Front Flip in a Monster Truck Want to attempt this gravity-defying stunt in a 5-ton vehicle? Better know your physics. https://www.wired.com/story/monster-truck-front-flip/

January 29, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Inside SpinLaunch, the Space Industry’s Best Kept Secret The company is building a massive centrifuge to accelerate rockets and send them screaming into space. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-spinlaunch-the-space-industrys-best-kept-secret/

January 28, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The Coronavirus Is a Threat to the Global Drug Supply The world’s pharmaceutical supply chain is in danger as the virus spreads across China and jeopardizes travel and trade. https://www.wired.com/story/the-coronavirus-is-a-threat-to-the-global-drug-supply/

January 28, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Levitate Objects With Sound (and Break Your Mind) The bizarre technology is called acoustic levitation, and it’s poised to deliver advances in pharmacology, chemistry more broadly, and even robotics.  https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-levitate-objects-with-sound/

January 27, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb An AI Virus Warning System, Mac Malware, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/wuhan-coronavirus-ai-mac-malware-shlayer-trojan/

January 27, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Building High-Rises Out of Wood Can Help Save the Planet Concrete and steel come with massive emissions. So let’s ditch them and build towers out of wood. Yes, wood. https://www.wired.com/story/building-high-rises-out-of-wood-can-help-save-the-planet/

January 27, 2020 | Author: Daniel EngberDaniel Engber I Thought My Kids Were Dying. They Just Had Croup. The old-fashioned-sounding illness is mostly harmless. So why does it cause so much parental panic? https://www.wired.com/story/my-kids-were-sick-with-croup/

January 26, 2020 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz How to Be Humane to a Lab-Grown Brain Ethicists and biologists seek to head off challenges raised by tissue “organoids” as they become increasingly similar to human brains. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-be-humane-to-a-lab-grown-brain/

January 25, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler An AI Epidemiologist Sent the First Warnings of the Wuhan Virus The BlueDot algorithm scours news reports and airline ticketing data to predict the spread of diseases like those linked to the flu outbreak in China. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-epidemiologist-wuhan-public-health-warnings/

January 24, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientists Predict Wuhan’s Outbreak Will Get Much Worse New estimates of how far the virus could spread suggest an explosion of cases will hit the Chinese city and more infected individuals will show up abroad. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-predict-wuhans-outbreak-will-get-much-worse/

January 24, 2020 | Author: Francesca DeRosaFrancesca DeRosa Athletic Authorities Must Reckon With Racing Tech Again As World Athletics debates whether to ban Nike’s carbon-fiber running shoe, it should heed lessons from the case of “Bionic Olympian” Oscar Pistorius. https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-athletic-authorities-must-reckon-with-racing-tech-again/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Snakes?! The Slippery Truth of a Flawed Wuhan Virus Theory One paper advanced a controversial theory about the disease’s origin. Other scientists aren’t biting. https://www.wired.com/story/wuhan-coronavirus-snake-flu-theory/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Robot Dog With a Job, a Noise-Canceling Car, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/spot-boston-dynamics-robot-hyundai-noise-cancelling-genesis/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Germany Rejected Nuclear Power—and Deadly Emissions Spiked After Fukushima, the country opted to decommission its nuclear reactors. The US has a lot to learn from what happened next. https://www.wired.com/story/germany-rejected-nuclear-power-and-deadly-emissions-spiked/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Spot the Robot Dog Trots Into the Big, Bad World Boston Dynamics’ creation is starting to sniff out its role in the workforce: as a helpful canine that still sometimes needs you to hold its paw. https://www.wired.com/story/spot-the-robot-dog-trots-into-the-big-bad-world/

January 23, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Could You Bungee-Jump Using Only Magnets? Jumping off a high ledge without a cord … maybe we better run a simulation first. https://www.wired.com/story/bungee-jumping-with-magnets/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Would the Coronavirus Quarantine of Wuhan Even Work? It’s almost impossible to shut down a megacity. And even if you do, people (and their germs) would find a way out. https://www.wired.com/story/would-the-coronavirus-quarantine-of-wuhan-even-work/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Experts Can’t Agree If the Wuhan Virus Is a Global Crisis As the death toll and infection numbers climb, international health officials struggle to make sense of sparse data on the coronavirus from China.  https://www.wired.com/story/experts-cant-agree-if-the-wuhan-virus-is-a-global-crisis/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Could China’s New Coronavirus Become a Global Epidemic? Scientists are racing to understand just how bad things could get with a pneumonia-like disease that first appeared in China and has now spread to the US. https://www.wired.com/story/could-chinas-new-coronavirus-become-a-global-epidemic/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Most Complete Brain Map Ever Is Here: A Fly’s ‘Connectome’ It took 12 years and at least $40 million to chart a region about 250 micrometers across—about the thickness of two strands of hair. https://www.wired.com/story/most-complete-brain-map-ever-is-here-a-flys-connectome/

January 22, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Science Behind Crafting a Perfect Espresso A computational chemist unlocks the secrets of the time-grind-water axis—and develops a model for making an impeccable cup of joe. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-behind-crafting-a-perfect-espresso/

January 21, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Macabre Science of Mass Animal Die-Offs Researchers are replicating “mass mortality events” with pig carcasses. The ecological consequences could hint at what’s happening in Australia right now. https://www.wired.com/story/the-macabre-science-of-animal-mass-die-offs/

January 21, 2020 | Author: Donna Jackson NakazawaDonna Jackson Nakazawa The Tiny Brain Cells That Connect Our Mental and Physical Health A new understanding of long-overlooked cells called microglia is challenging the assumption that body and brain function are completely independent. https://www.wired.com/story/the-tiny-brain-cells-that-connect-our-mental-and-physical-health/

January 21, 2020 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee Automated Solar Arrays Could Help Incinerate Global Warming Software-driven systems can produce enough searing heat to power manufacturing processes that now gorge on fossil fuels. https://www.wired.com/story/automated-solar-arrays-could-help-incinerate-global-warming/

January 20, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Pop Culture May Evolve at the Same Rate as Birds and Bugs How quickly do music and literature change? Evolutionary biology could give us a hint. https://www.wired.com/story/pop-culture-may-evolve-at-the-same-rate-as-birds-and-bugs/

January 20, 2020 | Author: Beth GardinerBeth Gardiner A Surge of New Plastic Is About to Hit the Planet A world awash in plastic will soon get slammed by more, as major oil companies ramp up their production. https://www.wired.com/story/a-surge-of-new-plastic-is-about-to-hit-the-planet/

January 19, 2020 | Author: Shannon HallShannon Hall How Long Do We Have Before Arctic Ice Melts Away? With the frozen top of the world melting to liquid, an expedition set out to untangle the physics and help forecast its future. https://www.wired.com/story/expedition-end-of-ice/

January 18, 2020 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Betelgeuse, Betelgeuse, Betelgeuse! We’re not sure when this star will go supernova, but one thing is certain: It’ll be spectacular. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-betelgeuse/

January 18, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Watch SpaceX Blow Up a Falcon 9 Rocket to Prove It’s Safe for People On Sunday, Elon Musk’s space company will intentionally shred a Falcon 9 to smithereens—to prove it can safely carry humans, of course. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-spacex-launch-falcon9-rocket-crew-dragon/

January 17, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Superpower Does It Take to Bash a Bullet in Midair? In the upcoming movie Wonder Woman 1984, our hero is able to knock a bullet off to the side with just her arm. Let’s look at the physics. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-superpower-does-it-take-to-bash-a-bullet-in-midair/

January 16, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Even Ultra-Tough Water Bears May Be Vulnerable to Climate Change Tardigrades are known for their ability to survive extreme temperatures. But new research suggests they might be more sensitive than previously thought. https://www.wired.com/story/water-bears-climate-change/

January 15, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Feral Cat Infestation, Swarms of Snake Emoji, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/australia-fire-cat-elizabeth-warren-snake/

January 15, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Scientists Fight Back Against Toxic ‘Forever’ Chemicals The ubiquitous compounds known as PFAS are nearly indestructible. But scientists are learning to split their ultra-strong carbon-fluorine bonds. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-fight-back-against-toxic-forever-chemicals/

January 15, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Cats Are Making Australia’s Bushfire Tragedy Even Worse Cats are attracted to bushfire burn scars, where they hunt vulnerable survivors with merciless impunity. It’s devastating for ecosystems. https://www.wired.com/story/cats-australia-bushfires/

January 14, 2020 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Do Carbon Offsets Really Work? It Depends on the Details The market for offsets is booming as companies seek to burnish their green credentials. But only some investments make a difference. https://www.wired.com/story/do-carbon-offsets-really-work-it-depends-on-the-details/

January 14, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Many Water Bottles Could a Filling Station Save? Or, how long would it take to fill a swimming pool from a water fountain? Let’s have fun with numbers! https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-water-bottles-could-a-filling-station-save/

January 13, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Virus Outbreak, Netflix’s Oscar Nod Dominance, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/oscar-nominations-china-mystery-illness-wuhan-sars/

January 13, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet Xenobot, an Eerie New Kind of Programmable Organism Researchers hope the living robots, made up of masses of cells working in coordination, can help unlock the mysteries of cellular communication. https://www.wired.com/story/xenobot/

January 13, 2020 | Author: Laurie Clarke, WIRED UKLaurie Clarke, WIRED UK Australia’s Wildfires Might Intensify Future Climate Crises Wildfires release vast amounts of carbon into the atmosphere. Their broader impact is far more complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/australias-wildfires-might-intensify-future-climate-crises/

January 13, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni China’s Swift ID of a New Virus Is a Win for Public Health The mystery illness has claimed its first victim. Yet the crisis has a silver lining: It shows how much China’s public health policies have improved. https://www.wired.com/story/chinas-swift-id-of-a-new-virus-is-a-win-for-public-health/

January 12, 2020 | Author: John PavlusJohn Pavlus Computers Are Learning to See in Higher Dimensions New artificial intelligence techniques can spot patterns not only in 2D images but on spheres and other curved surfaces, lifting AI out of “flatland.” https://www.wired.com/story/computers-are-learning-to-see-in-higher-dimensions/

January 10, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Scientists Are Flying Drones Into Clouds of Whale Snot Researcher Iain Kerr was on a boat, covered in whale snot, when the idea hit him: Why not hack a drone to fly into whale snot instead? https://www.wired.com/story/snotbot/

January 10, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Scientists Made a Nearly Invincible Lithium-Ion Battery This new type of battery can be cut, bent, soaked, shot, and lit on fire—and it still powers up just fine. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-made-a-nearly-invincible-lithium-ion-battery/

January 10, 2020 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The FDA Announces Two More Antacid Recalls Due to Cancer Risk Two more companies recalled their ranitidine drugs, generic forms of Zantac, over concerns they may contain a carcinogenic substance. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-announces-two-more-antacid-recalls-due-to-cancer-risk/

January 9, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Do LEDs Cause Orange Presidents? It’s true that different light sources can alter colors. But Trump’s science is off on this one. https://www.wired.com/story/do-leds-cause-orange-presidents/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How the US Knew Iranian Missiles Were Coming Before They Hit The US has operated an extensive network of missile warning systems for over half a century, but next-generation missiles will put it to the test. https://www.wired.com/story/us-missile-defense-iranian-strike/

January 8, 2020 | None Eating More Veggies is in Your Future

https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2017/08/urbanfarming/

January 8, 2020 | Author: David ChangDavid Chang David Chang’s Unified Theory of Deliciousness The great foods of the world share the same flavor patterns. Learn the code, and crank out the hits. https://www.wired.com/2016/07/chef-david-chang-on-deliciousness/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How Building a Black Hole for Interstellar Led to an Amazing Scientific Discovery Kip Thorne looks into the black hole he helped create and thinks, “Why, of course. That’s what it would do.” This particular black hole is a simulation of unprecedented accuracy. It appears to spin at nearly the speed of light, dragging bits of the universe along with it. (That’s gravity for you; relativity is superweird.) In theory it was once a star, but instead of fading or exploding, it collapsed like a failed soufflé into a tiny point of inescapable singularity. A glowing ring orbiting the spheroidal maelstrom seems to curve over the top and below the bottom simultaneously. https://www.wired.com/2014/10/astrophysics-interstellar-black-hole/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Amy MaxmenAmy Maxmen Easy DNA Editing Will Remake the World. Buckle Up. We now have the power to easily alter DNA. It could eliminate disease. It could get really out of hand. https://www.wired.com/2015/07/crispr-dna-editing-2/

January 8, 2020 | None The Future of Affordable Housing

https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2018/06/aia-blueprint-for-better/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Ben PaynterBen Paynter The Crisis in Flint Isn’t Over. It’s Everywhere. The toxic disaster in Flint is not an isolated incident. US water infrastructure is a shambles, a haven for poisonous compounds and lethal bacteria. https://www.wired.com/2016/06/flint-water-marc-edwards/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Lee BillingsLee Billings The Ugly Battle Over Who Really Discovered the First Earth-Like Planet No one knows what the planet Gliese 667Cc looks like. We know that it is about 22 light-years from Earth, a journey of lifetimes upon lifetimes. But no one can say whether it is a world like ours, with oceans and life, cities and single-malt Scotch. Only a hint of a to-and-fro oscillation in the star it orbits, detectable by Earth’s most sensitive telescopes and spectrographs, lets astronomers say the planet exists at all. The planet is bigger than our world, perhaps made of rocks instead of gas, and within its star’s “habitable zone”—at a Goldilocks distance that ensures enough starlight to make liquid water possible but not so much as to nuke the planet clean. https://www.wired.com/2014/11/exoplanets/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Alex French, Howie KahnAlex French and Howie Kahn An Oral History of the Epic Space Film The Right Stuff Before writer-director Philip Kaufman brought Tom Wolfe’s book The Right Stuff to the big screen in 1983, onscreen astronauts were little more than alien quarry or asteroid bait. In Kaufman’s hands, however, spaceflight became a far more human pursuit—a story not of external threats but inner resolve. With its three-hour-plus run time and unconventional structure, the film—which tells the story of test pilots like Chuck Yeager and Gordon Cooper as they break the sound barrier and launch toward the exosphere—was almost as daring as its subject. (Kaufman calls it “the longest movie ever made without a plot.”) But it introduced an entire cinematic genre, what Quentin Tarantino has called the “hip epic,” inspiring everyone from Michael Bay to James Cameron, who hired its cinematographer for Titanic. Its dialog has become a go-to signifier of human accomplishment; director Rian Johnson celebrated landing his Star Wars gig by tweeting a clip from the movie. “Phil really pulled it off,” George Lucas says. None other than Christopher Nolan has called it “an almost perfect movie. https://www.wired.com/2014/11/oral-history-of-right-stuff/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Erika HayasakiErika Hayasaki How a Single Gene Could Become a Volume Knob for Pain Her skin is perpetually on fire. He can’t even feel a bone break. Together they might hold the key to ending America’s opioid epidemic. https://www.wired.com/2017/04/the-cure-for-pain/

January 8, 2020 | None Three Theories of Infinite Earths

https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2018/01/three-theories-infinite-earths/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Scott DadichScott Dadich Barack Obama Talks AI, Robo-Cars, and the Future of the World The president in conversation with MIT’s Joi Ito and WIRED editor-in-chief Scott Dadich. https://www.wired.com/2016/10/president-obama-mit-joi-ito-interview/

January 8, 2020 | None Hunting Plumbing, Not Cartoons, With Augmented Reality

https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2017/09/futureofla/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Hannah NordhausHannah Nordhaus One Scientist’s Crazy Bet to Save the Bees: Join Monsanto Jerry Hayes is on a quest to save the bees. So when Monsanto began investigating a way to help, he joined them—and kicked up a swarm of controversy. https://www.wired.com/2016/08/jerry-hayes-how-to-save-the-bees-monsanto/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Michael HaineyMichael Hainey Welcome to Spaceport America. Your Rocket Will Depart Soon. Ish. Our writer goes to Spaceport America to explore what the ambitions of Branson, Bezos, and Musk mean for the rest of us—and for our next giant leap. https://www.wired.com/2016/02/welcome-to-spaceport-america-your-rocket-will-depart-soon-ish/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Alex MarAlex Mar Are We Ready for Intimacy With Androids? Hiroshi Ishiguro builds robots. Beautiful, realistic, uncannily convincing human replicas. His quest? Untangle the ineffable nature of human connection. https://www.wired.com/2017/10/hiroshi-ishiguro-when-robots-act-just-like-humans/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Greg MillerGreg Miller Inside the Secret World of Russia’s Cold War Mapmakers The Soviet military mapped the entire world, but few have seen the actual, physical maps—until now. https://www.wired.com/2015/07/secret-cold-war-maps/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Charles C. MannCharles C. Mann Solar or Coal? The Energy India Picks May Decide Earth’s Fate India will make a choice, but it will not be India’s alone. https://www.wired.com/2015/11/climate-change-in-india/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Fred VogelsteinFred Vogelstein One Man’s Desperate Quest to Cure His Son’s Epilepsy—With Weed My son’s epilepsy caused him to have up to 100 seizures a day. Our last hope: an untested, unproven treatment. https://www.wired.com/2015/07/medical-marijuana-epilepsy/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Erika HayasakiErika Hayasaki The Strange Case of the Woman Who Can’t Remember Her Past—Or Imagine Her Future Meet the first person ever diagnosed with severely deficient autobiographical memory. She knows facts about her life but can’t mentally relive any of it. https://www.wired.com/2016/04/susie-mckinnon-autobiographical-memory-sdam/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Sarah ZhangSarah Zhang New Horizons’ Long, Dark, Amazing Journey to Pluto…And Beyond The story of how a little space probe slingshotted through space to visit the King of the Ice Dwarfs. https://www.wired.com/2015/07/pluto-new-horizons-2/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Wired MagazineWired Magazine Interstellar Almost Had 6 Wormholes and 5 Black Holes By the time Christopher Nolan signed up to direct Interstellar and started rewriting its script, astrophysicist Kip Thorne had been working with Nolan’s brother, Jonathan (who goes by Jonah), on getting his ideas onto film for years. When Chris and Thorne met, they quickly found common ground: Thorne wanted science in the story, and Nolan wanted the story to emerge from science. So in Interstellar, time dilation—the passing of time at different rates for different observers—became an emotional obstacle between a father and his daughter. Quantum gravity, the reconciliation of relativity and quantum mechanics, became the plot’s central mystery. The visual effects team even collaborated with Thorne to make sure their depictions of a black hole were accurate as well as elegant. https://www.wired.com/2014/11/metaphysics-of-interstellar/

January 8, 2020 | None The Future of Affordable Housing

https://www.wired.com/brandlab/2018/06/aia-blueprint-for-better/p/1/

January 8, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wildfires Are Obliterating Australia’s Iconic Ecosystems Australia’s bushfires aren’t just unprecedented—they’re catastrophic. The continent’s ecosystems could be forever changed. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfires-are-obliterating-australias-iconic-ecosystems/

January 7, 2020 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Iran’s Nuclear Capability, Australia’s Smoke Clouds, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/iran-nuclear-deal-australia-fire-pyrocumulonimbus-clouds/

January 7, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Mandalorian vs. TIE Fighter: Who Would Win? If a spaceship is moving at 262 miles per hour, will a bounty hunter with a grappling hook survive the acceleration? https://www.wired.com/story/mandalorian-vs-tie-fighter/

January 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How Close Is Iran to a Nuclear Weapon? Here’s What We Know Iran is no longer abiding by many of the restrictions in the landmark 2015 nuclear deal, but that doesn’t mean it’s about to build a bomb, either. https://www.wired.com/story/how-close-is-iran-to-a-nuclear-weapon-heres-what-we-know/

January 6, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch Australia’s Wildfires Spawn Massive Smoky Thunderclouds Researchers have been watching Australia’s fires produce pyrocumulonimbus clouds. Here’s why the phenomenon is so dangerous. https://www.wired.com/story/australia-wildfires-smoky-thunderclouds/

January 6, 2020 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How SpaceX’s Satellite Internet Will Actually Work Tonight, the company is launching the next big chunk of its Starlink constellation to bring gaming-quality internet to every corner of Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/how-spacexs-satellite-internet-will-actually-work/

January 6, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Gaze Into These Hyperrealistic Masks and See a Troubling Future Uncanny silicone masks used to be a Hollywood plot device. Now they’re in the real world—and they’re fooling a whole lot of people. https://www.wired.com/story/hyper-realistic-masks/

January 6, 2020 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientists Figured Out the Indian Cobra’s Genome—at Last With the genetic recipe for the snake’s lethal venom in hand, researchers will have an easier time producing an antidote. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-figured-out-the-indian-cobra-genome/

January 5, 2020 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Does Dark Energy Really Exist? Cosmologists Battle It Out A study challenged the evidence for this mysterious force, despite its wide acceptance as part of the cosmos. Then physicists shot back. https://www.wired.com/story/does-dark-energy-really-exist-cosmologists-battle-it-out/

January 3, 2020 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Make a Tree With Fractals A physicist dilates on the delights of nature’s intricate geometry. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-make-a-tree-with-fractals/

January 3, 2020 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Australia Is Blazing Into the Pyrocene—the Age of Fire Australia’s bushfires have scorched millions of acres, putting millions of people at risk. Welcome to the hellish future of life on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/australia-is-blazing-into-the-pyrocene-the-age-of-fire/

January 2, 2020 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen How the Extreme Art of Dropping Stuff Could Upend Physics Scientists are going to great lengths to try to make gravity fail, so as to link Einstein’s theory of general relativity with quantum mechanics. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-extreme-art-of-dropping-stuff-could-upend-physics/

January 2, 2020 | Author: Cathleen O’Grady, Ars TechnicaCathleen O’Grady, Ars Technica Whales Help Explain the Evolutionary Mystery of Menopause Like humans, female killer whales stop reproducing decades before the end of their lifespan. Grandmothers might show why.  https://www.wired.com/story/whales-help-explain-the-evolutionary-mystery-of-menopause/

January 1, 2020 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff Here’s What the World Will Look Like in 2030 … Right? These six visions from humans today span space colonies, a genetic panopticon, and straight-up apocalypse. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-what-the-world-will-look-like-in-2030-right/

December 31, 2019 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 2020 in Science: A SpaceX Bonanza, Lab-Grown Brains, and More The number of satellites in orbit will double. Lots more people will get Crispr’d. Organoids might demand of bill of rights. No big deal!  https://www.wired.com/story/2020-in-science-a-spacex-bonanza-lab-grown-brains-and-more/

December 30, 2019 | Author: Jim RobbinsJim Robbins It’s Not Just You—Wild Swings in Extreme Weather Are Rising As the world warms, scientists say that abrupt shifts in weather patterns, like droughts followed by severe floods, are intensifying. https://www.wired.com/story/wild-swings-in-extreme-weather-are-rising/

December 29, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Now Entering Orbit: Tiny Lego-like Modular Satellites Space is getting closer, thanks to small, cheap “satlets” that network themselves to solve problems in flight. https://www.wired.com/story/now-entering-orbit-tiny-lego-like-modular-satellites/

December 28, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler What’s in the Forecast: Private Weather Predictions A growing industry might take over the job of predicting sunny days and snowstorms. Are you ready for Big Weather? https://www.wired.com/story/whats-in-the-forecast-private-weather-predictions/

December 27, 2019 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica This Cave Contains the Oldest Story Ever Recorded Archaeologists say the 43,900-year-old cave painting might also include the oldest known religious images. https://www.wired.com/story/cave-with-oldest-story-ever-recorded/

December 25, 2019 | Author: Isabella KaminskiIsabella Kaminski We Might Not Be Planting the Right Kinds of Forests As the world scrambles to combat deforestation, experts warn our efforts could have far fewer benefits than we think. https://www.wired.com/story/we-might-not-be-planting-the-right-kinds-of-forests/

December 24, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Got the Flu? These Doctors Really Want to See You—Virtually Getting sick is the worst. But if you’re trying to lure customers who are reluctant or unable to leave home, the virus can be an ally. https://www.wired.com/story/got-the-flu-these-doctors-really-want-to-see-youvirtually/

December 23, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Expanse Is Sci-Fi Like TV Has Never Seen The series embraces the true weirdness of life off planet, says showrunner Naren Shankar, making space itself a character in the drama. https://www.wired.com/story/the-expanse-is-sci-fi-like-tv-has-never-seen/

December 23, 2019 | Author: Laurie Clarke, WIRED UKLaurie Clarke, WIRED UK Science Explains Why We Should All Work Shorter Hours in Winter People tend to get gloomy when night comes early and cold weather descends. But adjusting our workday to the season could lift our mood. https://www.wired.com/story/science-explains-why-we-should-work-shorter-hours-winter/

December 23, 2019 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 12 Science Books You Should Read Right Now Snuggle up with these 2019 books on the so-called language of God, dirty drugmakers, and the future of food and booze. https://www.wired.com/story/12-top-science-books-2019/

December 23, 2019 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff WIRED’s 7 Big Science Stories That Shaped 2019 The police went nuts for DNA, the vaping wars heated up, and a black hole pic grabbed the internet: These were some of 2019’s standout themes. https://www.wired.com/story/wireds-7-big-science-stories-that-shaped-2019/

December 22, 2019 | Author: Rebecca BoyleRebecca Boyle The Science Behind Why No Two Snowflakes Are Alike A physicist’s obsession with unusual snow crystals has led him to pursue a grand unified theory of how they form. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-behind-why-no-two-snowflakes-are-alike/

December 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon So You Think You Know Gravity? Let Us Drop Some Knowledge Join astrophysicist Janna Levin on a mind- and space-time-bending journey into the force to end all forces. https://www.wired.com/story/so-you-think-you-know-gravity-let-us-drop-some-knowledge/

December 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 2019 Is the Year Humanity Declared War on Microplastics The pollutants are absolutely everywhere—blowing in the wind and swirling in the ocean. Here’s how we can clean up our act. https://www.wired.com/story/the-year-humanity-declared-war-on-microplastics/

December 19, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Giant Surveillance Balloons Are Lurking at the Edge of Space Companies are sending massive, high-altitude balloons to the stratosphere to snap images of Earth with unprecedented resolution. Say cheese! https://www.wired.com/story/giant-surveillance-balloons-are-lurking-at-the-edge-of-space/

December 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Acidifying Oceans Could Eat Away at Sharks’ Skin and Teeth Researchers show that prolonged exposure to acidified water corrodes the scales that make up a shark’s skin. https://www.wired.com/story/acidifying-oceans-shark-skin/

December 19, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill New Tests Use Epigenetics to Guess How Fast You’re Aging Companies claim they can now easily calculate your biological age. Should you take them up on it? https://www.wired.com/story/new-tests-use-epigenetics-to-guess-how-fast-youre-aging/

December 18, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb How to Not Get Sick While Traveling, 5G’s Health Effects, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/not-get-sick-traveling-plane-5g-health-effects/

December 18, 2019 | Author: Sarah SaxSarah Sax Geoengineering’s Gender Problem Could Put the Planet at Risk A lack of diversity among scientists may skew how the public perceives the idea of hacking the climate. https://www.wired.com/story/geoengineerings-gender-problem-could-put-the-planet-at-risk/

December 18, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Traveling for the Holidays? Here’s How to Not Get Sick Airplanes may seem like the perfect place to catch a cold or flu, but the real threat isn’t in the sky. It’s on the ground.  https://www.wired.com/story/traveling-for-the-holidays-heres-how-to-not-get-sick/

December 17, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Earth’s Largest Scientific Structure, a WhatsApp Flaw, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/largest-scientific-structure-whatsapp-group-chat-hack/

December 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What a 5,700-Year-Old Piece of Gum Reveals About Its Chewer From a wad of pitch less than an inch long, researchers have painted a detailed portrait of an ancient human—and added another layer to the story of human evolution. https://www.wired.com/story/5700-year-old-piece-of-gum/

December 17, 2019 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee The Largest Scientific Structure Ever Powers Up in Africa When the Square Kilometre Array is complete, the telescope will scan the universe to probe some of science’s deepest mysteries. https://www.wired.com/story/square-kilometre-array-largest-scientific-structure-ever-africa/

December 17, 2019 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson Nature Deserves Legal Rights—and the Power to Fight Back If we want to forestall the worst of climate change, we need innovation not just in tech but in law, the rule sets that guide our behavior. https://www.wired.com/story/nature-deserves-legal-rights-power-to-fight-back/

December 16, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb An Early Flu Season, a Flight Simulator Revival, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/flu-season-early-microsoft-flight-simulator-bing/

December 16, 2019 | Author: Beth Mole, Ars TechnicaBeth Mole, Ars Technica This Year’s Flu Season Is Off to a Weird (and Early) Start According to the CDC’s latest influenza update, both the timing and the strain are highly unusual.  https://www.wired.com/story/flu-season-off-to-a-weird-and-early-start/

December 15, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Mathematician Terence Tao Cracks a ‘Dangerous’ Problem Tao has made huge progress on the Collatz conjecture, a simple-seeming puzzle that has bedeviled hapless mathematicians for decades. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematician-terence-tao-cracks-a-dangerous-problem/

December 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon When a Mantis Shrimp Fights a Disco Clam, It Meets Its Match The mantis shrimp beats the hell out of almost anything it can get its hammers on. Except, that is, for the disco clam, which unleashes a dazzling defense. https://www.wired.com/story/when-a-mantis-shrimp-fights-a-disco-clam/

December 13, 2019 | Author: Emily Holden, Ron Fonger, Jessica GlenzaEmily Holden, Ron Fonger, and Jessica Glenza Utility Executives Kept Flint’s Tainted Water a Secret Email exchanges show senior employees and Flint officials knew the tap water was poisoned with lead months before the city alerted residents. https://www.wired.com/story/utility-executives-kept-flints-tainted-water-a-secret/

December 13, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Next Nuclear Plants Will Be Small, Svelte, and Safer A new generation of reactors will start producing power in the next few years. They’re comparatively tiny—and may be key to hitting our climate goals.  https://www.wired.com/story/the-next-nuclear-plants-will-be-small-svelte-and-safer/

December 12, 2019 | Author: Chris D’AngeloChris D’Angelo Greta Thunberg Blasts ‘Creative PR’ in Her Climate Speech In her latest talk at a major climate change conference, the Swedish activist accused politicians and big business of misleading the public. https://www.wired.com/story/greta-thunberg-blasts-creative-pr-in-her-climate-speech/

December 12, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Revolt! Scientists Say They’re Sick of Quantum Computing’s Hype A Twitter account called Quantum Bullshit Detector reflects some researchers’ angst about overhyped claims and other troubling trends. https://www.wired.com/story/revolt-scientists-say-theyre-sick-of-quantum-computings-hype/

December 12, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Anti-Vape Laws Could Do More Harm Than Good Banning vaping just might drive teens to the black market—and send adult smokers back to their cancer sticks. https://www.wired.com/story/anti-vape-laws-could-do-more-harm-than-good/

December 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Kung Fu Master’s Leap Breaks the Internet—but Not Physics A viral video appears to show a man jumping off water. What’s really going on here? https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-kung-fu-master-jumps-on-water/

December 12, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Forget Earth: In Space, Libertarian Ideas Are Thriving Space entrepreneurs tend to share a fondness for libertarian principles. So before checking into your space hotel, be sure to read your Heinlein. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-earth-in-space-libertarian-ideas-are-thriving/

December 11, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Science of New Zealand’s Eruption, Toy Store Surveillance, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/new-zealand-volcano-eruption-toys-r-us-surveillance/

December 10, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Volcanologists Didn’t Predict New Zealand’s Deadly Eruption Scientists knew White Island was showing signs of “volcanic unrest,” but their arsenal of data and sensors couldn’t prepare them for tragedy. https://www.wired.com/story/why-volcanologists-didnt-predict-new-zealands-deadly-eruption/

December 10, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How the Mandalorian Might See Through Walls Mando’s sci-fi ability isn’t as far-fetched as you think. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-mandalorian-might-see-through-walls/

December 10, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Amazon, Google, Microsoft: Here’s Who Has the Greenest Cloud A WIRED report card on the top three cloud providers shows how their environmental claims stack up. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-google-microsoft-green-clouds-and-hyperscale-data-centers/

December 9, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A DNA Firm That Caters to Police Just Bought a Genealogy Site In 2018, GEDmatch played a key role in reopening the 40-year-old Golden State Killer case. Now a company that serves law enforcement is gobbling it up. https://www.wired.com/story/a-dna-firm-that-caters-to-police-just-bought-a-genealogy-site/

December 9, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Scientists Find a Weak Spot in Some Superbugs’ Defenses Treatment-resistant infections are increasingly common—and increasingly deadly. Now researchers have found a new way to attack some of those bacteria. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-find-a-weak-spot-in-some-superbugs-defenses/

December 9, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni These Plastic Bunnies Got a DNA Upgrade. Next up, the World? Scientists infused a 3D-printed rabbit with genetic material, the first step toward a potential “DNA of things” where biology makes gadgets smarter. https://www.wired.com/story/these-plastic-bunnies-got-a-dna-upgrade-next-up-the-world/

December 8, 2019 | Author: Chris Baraniuk, WIRED UKChris Baraniuk, WIRED UK Melting Ski Resorts Have a Snow Machine Problem The changing climate is warming the slopes, forcing resorts to turn to snow-generating beasts that take a heavy environmental toll. https://www.wired.com/story/melting-ski-resorts-have-a-snow-machine-problem/

December 7, 2019 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Parker’s Potential NASA’s new solar probe is racing towards the sun—here’s what it will see once it gets there. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-parkers-potential/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Will Bedingfield, WIRED UKWill Bedingfield, WIRED UK Physics Explains Why You Can’t Open a Plane Door in the Air A British Airways passenger caused chaos after trying to open the aircraft door during a flight, but air pressure and clever design make it impossible.  https://www.wired.com/story/physics-explains-why-you-cant-open-a-plane-door-mid-flight/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Rocket Wrecks the Ravagers With Physics In Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2, our favorite furry antihero deals out cosmic justice—and some great material for video analysis. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-how-rocket-raccoon-wrecked-the-ravagers/

December 6, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Police Shootings May Be Causing Black Infants Long-Term Harm By looking at data on millions of births, a researcher shows how violence against unarmed African American men might cause acute stress on pregnancies. https://www.wired.com/story/police-shootings-may-be-causing-black-infants-long-term-harm/

December 5, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A SpaceX Beer Supply Run, Sketchy Baby Yoda Merch, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launch-mice-beer-iss-baby-yoda-merchandise/

December 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Launched Its Last Rocket of the Decade to the ISS A SpaceX rocket, slated to launch Wednesday, is carrying experiments on beer brewing, muscle decay, and fire behavior to the International Space Station. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-will-bring-the-science-of-fire-and-beer-to-the-iss/

December 5, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler With Shovels and Drones, Volcano Hunters Probe Kilauea New studies reveal inner workings of the massive 2018 Hawaiian flow—the “Super Bowl” of eruptions. https://www.wired.com/story/with-shovels-and-drones-volcano-hunters-probe-kilauea/

December 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus No One Knows Why Rocks Are Exploding From Asteroid Bennu NASA’s OSIRIS-REx spacecraft spotted the asteroid spitting out rocks—more evidence that these alien worlds aren’t so inert after all. https://www.wired.com/story/no-one-knows-why-rocks-are-exploding-from-asteroid-bennu/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Once-a-Month Birth Control Pill, an Arctic Warning, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/new-birth-control-pill-monthly-arctic-warming-ice-climate-change/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Arctic Is Warming Much Faster Than the Rest of Earth Rising temperatures in the northern polar cap are driving extreme heat, drought, and sea level rise in the continental US, a study says. https://www.wired.com/story/the-arctic-is-warming-much-faster-than-the-rest-of-earth/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Once-a-Month Birth Control Pill Is Coming—Here’s How It Works The shape of the pill does the trick of gradually drip-feeding contraceptive hormones through the stomach. https://www.wired.com/story/a-once-a-month-birth-control-pill-is-coming-heres-how-it-works/

December 4, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Calculate the Thrust Force on Your Drone! A physicist puts his quadcopter through the paces to see what kind of mojo those little rotors throw down. https://www.wired.com/story/calculate-thrust-force-on-a-drone/

December 3, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The WIRED Guide to Genetic Testing Everything you need to know about DNA, medical breakthroughs, and genetic privacy. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-genetic-testing/

December 2, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Cheap at Last, Batteries Are Making a Solar Dream Come True Solar power is increasingly available around the clock as energy storage become more affordable. https://www.wired.com/story/cheap-at-last-batteries-are-making-a-solar-dream-come-true/

December 2, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to Get Solar Power on a Rainy Day? Beam It From Space A decades-old idea is finally getting a chance to shine—that is, a chance to send sunshine harvested by a satellite down to Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-get-solar-power-on-a-rainy-day-beam-it-from-space/

December 1, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Stop Obsessing Over Sleep—Your Brain Will Thank You Worrying about sleep is perhaps the most counterproductive thing you can do, no matter how many gadgets try to tell you otherwise. https://www.wired.com/story/stop-obsessing-over-sleepyour-brain-will-thank-you/

November 30, 2019 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Eyes in the Sky New satellite imagery of the Milky Way, plus an astronaut-shot photo of Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-eyes-in-the-sky/

November 30, 2019 | Author: Veronique GreenwoodVeronique Greenwood How Overexcited Neurons Might Affect How You Age New research makes a molecular connection between the brain and aging—and shows that overactive neurons can shorten life span. https://www.wired.com/story/overexcited-neurons/

November 30, 2019 | Author: Fred PearceFred Pearce This Is an Extinction Crisis, and Some Species Are Loving It A controversy over how many species are disappearing is raising questions about how species adapt, and which ones are the ultimate winners and losers. https://www.wired.com/story/this-is-an-extinction-crisis/

November 30, 2019 | Author: Kate S. PetersenKate S. Petersen A New Way to Make Comfy, Durable Smart Garments Long-lasting, electronics-laced PJs and gloves may help you sleep better and keep your trigger finger toasty when you jump out of a plane into battle. https://www.wired.com/story/new-way-make-comfy-durable-smart-garments/

November 29, 2019 | Author: Dawn StoverDawn Stover SUVs Are Worse for the Climate Than You Ever Imagined But if you drive one, you can still reduce your carbon footprint—and you can vote for climate change policies with even bigger impact. https://www.wired.com/story/suvs-are-worse-for-the-climate-than-you-ever-imagined/

November 28, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Spot an Undersea Fault Using Fiber-Optic Cables Unused telecom cables, known as dark fiber, could help scientists finally map the ocean floor and discover new earthquake hot spots. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-spot-an-undersea-fault-using-fiber-optic-cables/

November 27, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Our Planet May Be Barreling Toward a Tipping Point A thawing Antarctica, a transforming Amazon, and other devastating changes may be more likely than scientists previously believed. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-tipping-point/

November 27, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus China Is Still Building an Insane Number of New Coal Plants While the rest of the world turns away from the fossil fuel, China is investing big in coal-powered electricity. https://www.wired.com/story/china-is-still-building-an-insane-number-of-new-coal-plants/

November 26, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Case for Sending Robots to Day Care, Like Toddlers Robots are terrible at manipulating objects and adapting to new environments. A potential solution? Let them grow up playing, like children. https://www.wired.com/story/the-case-for-sending-robots-to-day-care-like-toddlers/

November 25, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Tesla Cybertruck vs. Ford F-150: It’s All About the Friction Elon Musk tweeted a clip of the Cybertruck tugging an F-150 uphill. A display of superior torque? Nope, it only proves the Cybertruck is heavier. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-cybertruck-vs-a-ford-f-150-its-all-about-friction/

November 25, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Change Is Brutal for Everyone, but Worse for Women Researchers find the climate crisis is imperiling the agency of women in Africa and Asia. It will only deteriorate further—unless we act. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-and-gender/

November 24, 2019 | Author: Robin George AndrewsRobin George Andrews Are Saturn’s Rings Really as Young as the Dinosaurs? A debate is raging over the age of the rings. Resolving it could produce the best clue yet to the rings’ mysterious origin. https://www.wired.com/story/are-saturns-rings-really-as-young-as-the-dinosaurs/

November 23, 2019 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Terrific, Tantalizing Titan It has methane lakes! And an atmosphere! Oh but it’s very, very, cold. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-week-terrific-tantalizing-titan/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Physics Analysis of Tesla’s Shattered Cybertruck Windows During the big reveal of Tesla’s electric pickup truck, the vehicle’s windows failed an onstage smash test. Here’s what might have gone wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/a-physics-analysis-of-teslas-shattered-cybertruck-windows/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Metal Wants to Float, Once It’s Etched With a Fricking Laser An absurdly powerful laser can trap an air bubble in a layer of metal, so that it’ll float no matter what. https://www.wired.com/story/floating-metal/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Robots Should Learn to Build Crappy Ikea Furniture Researchers built a simulator that teaches robots to deal with everyone’s favorite particle-board nightmare—and that’s just the beginning. https://www.wired.com/story/why-robots-should-learn-to-build-crappy-ikea-furniture/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen What Makes an Element? The Frankenstein of Sodium Holds Clues By crafting massive versions of sodium, neon, and other elements, physicists are testing what’s possible—and impossible—in nature. https://www.wired.com/story/what-makes-an-element-the-frankenstein-of-sodium-holds-clues/

November 22, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Solar ‘Breakthrough’ Won’t Solve Cement’s Carbon Problem A Bill Gates–backed startup called Heliogen uses concentrated solar power to produce cement. The carbon-belching industry needs that—and much more. https://www.wired.com/story/a-solar-breakthrough-wont-solve-cements-carbon-problem/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Ryan LoughlinRyan Loughlin Meet the Elite Shot-Putter Chasing a World Record Ryan Crouser is one of the best shot put throwers in history. In this WIRED video, he talks about the limits of his sport—and how to break them. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-elite-shot-putter-chasing-a-world-record/

November 21, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Hey Surgeon, Is That a HoloLens on Your Head?  Mixed reality displays are entering the operating room, first as surgical planning tools and soon as real-time guides to help doctors zap tumors. https://www.wired.com/story/hey-surgeon-is-that-a-hololens-on-your-head/

November 20, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison An Origami Artist Shows How to Fold Ultra-Realistic Creatures Robert Lang ditched a career as a physicist to pursue origami full time. In WIRED’s latest video, he reveals the tricks to folding complex shapes. https://www.wired.com/story/an-origami-artist-shows-how-to-fold-ultra-realistic-creatures/

November 20, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Air Pollution Is Still Killing Thousands of People in the US Soot steals lives through dementia, kidney disease, and hypertension—even when the air quality is within the permitted levels. https://www.wired.com/story/air-pollution-is-still-killing-thousands-of-people-in-the-us/

November 20, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why Good Teachers Are Like Pokémon A science professor’s journey through the three levels of pedagogical wisdom. https://www.wired.com/story/why-good-teachers-are-like-pokemon/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Astronomers Detect Water Vapor Around Jupiter’s Moon Europa Scientists caught Europa spewing enough water vapor to fill an Olympic-sized swimming pool in minutes. But where is it coming from? https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-detect-water-vapor-around-jupiters-moon-europa/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Most Iconic Space Movies Get a Very Grounded Fact-Check Astronaut Nicole Stott unpacks (and debunks) some of the more memorable Hollywood depictions of outer space. https://www.wired.com/story/the-most-iconic-space-movies-get-a-very-grounded-fact-check/

November 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Can Fake Horns Save the Rhino? That’s … Extremely Thorny Scientists can now flood the black market for rhino horns with horsehair fakes. Conservationists, however, have serious concerns. https://www.wired.com/story/fake-rhino-horns/

November 18, 2019 | Author: Carrie ArnoldCarrie Arnold Cells That ‘Taste’ Danger Set Off Immune Responses Taste and smell receptors in unexpected organs monitor the state of the body’s natural microbial health and raise an alarm over invading parasites. https://www.wired.com/story/cells-that-taste-danger-set-off-immune-responses/

November 18, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Earnest Research Into Gay Genetics Went Wrong When a well-intentioned study led to a dubious DNA test for same-sex attraction, it exposed the need for safeguards on research in the age of big genetic data. https://www.wired.com/story/how-earnest-research-into-gay-genetics-went-wrong/

November 17, 2019 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Mercury the Mighty Mite Our solar system’s innermost planet just passed between the Sun and Earth. It won’t happen again for more than a decade. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-mercury-transit/

November 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Alien Hunters Need the Far Side of the Moon to Stay Quiet The far side is normally protected from all the radio noise emanating from Earth, but SETI researchers worry that new visitors will gunk it up. https://www.wired.com/story/alien-hunters-need-far-side-moon-to-stay-quiet/

November 14, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Vape Detectors in Schools, Mental Health on Pinterest, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/vape-detectors-schools-pinterest-compassion-search/

November 14, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison How Wily Teens Outwit Bathroom Vape Detectors Schools are shelling out thousands for vape detectors, yet students easily circumvent them. Teen vaping solutions need an educational component as well. https://www.wired.com/story/how-wily-teens-outwit-bathroom-vape-detectors/

November 14, 2019 | Author: Arielle PardesArielle Pardes Pinterest Has a New Plan to Address Self-Harm The company has gotten better at removing distressing content. Now it wants to help users feel better. https://www.wired.com/story/pinterest-self-harm-help/

November 14, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Don’t Underestimate the Forces, Mandalorian A physicist analyzes a fight scene in the new TV series and asks: Do the shoes make the Mandalorian? https://www.wired.com/story/dont-underestimate-the-forces-mandalorian/

November 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How the Climate Crisis Is Killing Us, in 9 Alarming Charts A new report from over 100 experts paints a devastating picture of how climate change is already imperiling human health. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-climate-crisis-is-killing-us/

November 13, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The EPA’s Anti-Science ‘Transparency’ Rule Has a Long History The federal agency plans to adopt a long-sought regulation that would let it ignore large swaths of environmental science in its rulemaking. https://www.wired.com/story/the-epas-anti-science-transparency-rule-has-a-long-history/

November 13, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Adam Savage on Juggling and How Obsession Makes You Smarter Genius is a myth, the former MythBusters cohost believes. You get smarter by investing time and energy in something you love. https://www.wired.com/story/adam-savage-adventures-in-science-wired25/

November 12, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The Science Is Extremely Clear: You Need to Prioritize Sleep The more scientists learn about the slumbering brain, the more they realize how vital sleep actually is. Now some researchers hope to develop it into a form of medicine. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-is-extremely-clear-you-need-to-prioritize-sleep/

November 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Mesmerizing Science of Garden Sprinklers Don’t trust your eyes—the water’s not moving the way you think it is. https://www.wired.com/story/the-mesmerizing-science-of-garden-sprinklers/

November 11, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Baby Fish Crisis, the Terrible Microsoft Surface Pro X, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/fish-microplastics-microsoft-surface-pro-x/

November 11, 2019 | Author: Louise MatsakisLouise Matsakis How Crime Scene Analysts Collect and Preserve Fingerprints A veteran analyst explains the work of gathering fingerprints that can link a suspect to a crime—even after it rains. https://www.wired.com/story/technique-tutorial-crime-scene-fingerprints/

November 11, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Baby Fish Feast on Microplastics, and Then Get Eaten Fish larvae off the coast of Hawaii are mistaking tiny pieces of plastic for prey, an alarming finding with big implications for the oceanic food web. https://www.wired.com/story/baby-fish-are-feasting-on-microplastics/

November 10, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall Astro Teller on How to Handle Failure And what Alphabet’s moonshot factory, X, is going after next. https://www.wired.com/story/astro-teller-google-moonshot-factory-wired25/

November 10, 2019 | Author: Matthew HutsonMatthew Hutson The Pursuit of Creativity Can Make Algorithms Much Smarter Neural networks are demonstrating profound leaps in their abilities when they’re tasked with open exploration instead of a narrowly focused goal. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pursuit-of-creativity-can-make-algorithms-much-smarter/

November 9, 2019 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Icelandic Walruses May Have Been Early Victims of Human-Driven Extinction The timing of the walrus’s disappearance suggests the Vikings, and their ivory trade, had something to do with it.  https://www.wired.com/story/icelandic-walruses-may-have-been-early-victims-of-human-driven-extinction/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber AI Researcher Anca Dragan on Helping Robots Understand Humans  The UC Berkeley professor talks about using algorithms to make it safer for robots and people to cross paths. https://www.wired.com/story/anca-dragan-artificial-intelligence-berkeley-wired25/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Race to Bring Meat Alternatives to Scale Memphis Meats’ lab-grown flesh approach is still far off, but Impossible Foods’ plant-based approach is already on the menu at Burger King. https://www.wired.com/story/uma-valeti-memphis-meats-wired25/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Kids Suing to Save the World from Climate Change At the WIRED25 festival in San Francisco, three Juliana v. United States plaintiffs talk about suing the government to force it to save us from climate doom. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-kids-juliana-plantiffs-wired25/

November 8, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen A Scientist’s Tiny Black Hole Brings the Cosmos Into the Lab Single-purpose quantum computers are helping physicists build simulations of nature’s greatest hits and observe them up close. https://www.wired.com/story/a-scientists-tiny-black-hole-brings-the-cosmos-into-the-lab/

November 7, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A ‘Safe’ Smoking Gadget, Vodka Made From Air, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/smoke-e-cigarette-iqos-vodka-air/

November 7, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The Enduring Power of Asperger’s, Even as a Non-Diagnosis Six years after it ceased to be an official diagnosis, Asperger’s lives on as a unifying label and a source of strength. https://www.wired.com/story/the-enduring-power-of-aspergers-even-as-a-non-diagnosis/

November 7, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison FDA Permits the Sale of a New Smoking Device. Is It Safe? Not quite an e-cigarette and not the old paper kind either, the Iqos is the latest controversial device to enter the vaping wars. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-smoking-gadget-says-its-safe-should-you-trust-it/

November 7, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers This Martini Wants to Kill Climate Change One Sip at a Time A carbon-negative vodka company makes its beverage literally out of thin air. Now that’s booze you can use. https://www.wired.com/story/this-martini-wants-to-kill-climate-change-one-sip-at-a-time/

November 6, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Aerial Scans Help Bust California’s Worst Methane Leakers The state may emit much more of the greenhouse gas than expected. But a new survey has revealed the top offenders, making leaks easier to control. https://www.wired.com/story/aerial-scans-help-bust-californias-worst-methane-leakers/

November 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Measurements Are Often Full of Lies—and That’s OK Does a balance measure mass or weight? This common question reveals a core confusion about lab instruments: It’s not always obvious what they measure. https://www.wired.com/story/measurements-are-often-full-of-lies-and-thats-ok/

November 6, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon If You Want a Robot to Learn Better, Be a Jerk to It When humans give robots “tough love” by trying to knock objects out of their hands, it actually helps them find the best ways to hold things. https://www.wired.com/story/if-you-want-a-robot-to-learn-better-be-a-jerk-to-it/

November 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX and Boeing Still Need a Parachute That Always Works The two companies are racing to send astronauts into space. But they also need to bring them home safe, with parachutes that won’t fail. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-and-boeing-still-need-a-parachute-that-always-works/

November 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Do We Need a Special Language to Talk to Aliens? Scientists have tried contacting extraterrestrials with a number of bespoke linguistic systems. But we might be better off using our own languages. https://www.wired.com/story/do-we-need-a-special-language-to-talk-to-aliens/

November 4, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Trump Begins Paris Accord Exit, Devices Hacked With Lasers, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-paris-accord-withdraw-pompeo-climate-laser-hack/

November 4, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Trump Can Now Exit the Paris Accord. It’s Still a Bad Idea Today the president can start formally withdrawing from the Paris climate pact. The biggest loser may be the US, some experts say. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-can-now-exit-the-paris-accord-its-still-a-bad-idea/

November 4, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Where Do Hippos Wander? An Aquatic Mystery, Solved Hippos need water to survive, and water is disappearing, leading to growing social unrest among the beasts. https://www.wired.com/story/where-do-hippos-wander/

November 3, 2019 | Author: Beth Mole, Ars TechnicaBeth Mole, Ars Technica Here’s What Happens When You Leave Weed Up Your Nose for 18 Years A man thought he had swallowed the balloon-wrapped marijuana he was smuggling. He hadn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/what-happens-when-you-leave-marijuana-up-nose-18-years/

November 3, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Cosmic Triangles Open a Window to the Origin of Time Physicists have found a new way to conceive of time as an emergent dimension, a kind of hologram springing from the universe’s spatial correlations. https://www.wired.com/story/cosmic-triangles-open-a-window-to-the-origin-of-time/

November 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Rats Drive Tiny Cars—for Science The rodents that lived in an enriched environment did better at driver’s ed than the rats brought up in standard cages. The implications are fascinating. https://www.wired.com/story/these-rats-drive-tiny-cars-for-science/

November 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wildfire Chasers Are the New Tornado Chasers A strike team of specially trained researchers drive a highly sophisticated truck into the literal line of fire. Their mission: unravel the extreme complexities of wildfire. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-chasers/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Your Brain Cleans Itself, This Jet Lands Itself, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/brain-cleans-itself-cirrus-jet-autopilot-lands-today-news/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Scientists Now Know How Sleep Cleans Toxins From the Brain The synchronized brain waves of non-REM sleep may play a key role in preventing toxins from accumulating in a person’s brain. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-now-know-how-sleep-cleans-toxins-from-the-brain/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Measles Leaves Kids Exposed to Other Diseases New techniques allow researchers to get definitive numbers on how the virus depletes its victims’ antibodies and the memory cells that make them. https://www.wired.com/story/how-measles-virus-induces-immune-amnesia/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Aarian MarshallAarian Marshall The Delicate Art—and Evolving Science—of Wildfire Evacuations The still-burning Kincade Fire prompted one of the largest wildfire-related evacuations in California history—a legacy, in part, of two earlier deadly blazes. https://www.wired.com/story/delicate-art-evolving-science-wildfire-evacuations/

October 31, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Is Getting Serious About an Interstellar Mission Only two spacecraft have ever escaped our solar system to dip into interstellar space. Now NASA wants to go back—and soon. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-is-getting-serious-about-an-interstellar-mission/

October 30, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Fly Me to the Moon … With Elephants! So, what would it look like if the Saturn V ran on pachyderms instead of rocket fuel? https://www.wired.com/story/fly-me-to-the-moon-with-elephants/

October 30, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How Lasers Work, According to the World’s Top Expert Lasers help us pay for groceries and zap us back into health, but what’s their secret? Nobel laureate Donna Strickland steps us through the science. https://www.wired.com/story/how-lasers-work-according-to-the-worlds-top-expert/

October 29, 2019 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Ants Never Get Stuck in Traffic Jams. Here’s Why Humans, take notes.  https://www.wired.com/story/ants-never-get-stuck-in-traffic-jams-heres-why/

October 29, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Prepping Bees for Mars, New Google Shortcuts, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/google-new-shortcut-bees-mars/

October 29, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Shifting Winds and the Changing Shape of California Fires Climate change might actually make the Santa Ana winds later and milder in the south, but the dry grass and delayed rain mean that the fires will still come. https://www.wired.com/story/santa-ana-winds-might-dwindle-but-fire-danger-remains/

October 29, 2019 | Author: WIRED InsiderWIRED Insider IL-23: The Master Regulator Behind Plaque Psoriasis

https://www.wired.com/wiredinsider/2019/10/il-23-vs-plaque-psoriasis/

October 29, 2019 | Author: Christie AschwandenChristie Aschwanden Trans Athletes Are Posting Victories and Shaking Up Sports Transgender athletes at all levels of sport are winning medals, spurring a contentious debate over the future of gendered competition. https://www.wired.com/story/the-glorious-victories-of-trans-athletes-are-shaking-up-sports/

October 29, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Bees, Please: Stop Dying in Your Martian Simulator Future space colonists will need pollinators to grow food on the moon and Mars. But first scientists need to figure out how to keep them alive. https://www.wired.com/story/bees-please-stop-dying-in-your-martian-simulator/

October 28, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon California’s Wildfires Are the Doom of Our Own Making The state is being squeezed by uber-wildfires and rising seas—climate change’s twin agents of chaos. It’s a struggle that will define us. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-wildfires-are-the-doom-of-our-own-making/

October 28, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Secret Space Plane Just Landed After a Record Stay in Orbit The plane spent 780 continuous days in orbit conducting classified experiments for the US Air Force before autonomously landing itself. https://www.wired.com/story/a-secret-space-plane-just-landed-after-a-record-stay-in-orbit/

October 27, 2019 | Author: Marcus WooMarcus Woo Physicists Get Close to Knowing the Mass of the Neutrino The KATRIN experiment is working to “weigh the ghost,” which could point to new laws of particle physics and reshape theories of cosmology. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-get-close-knowing-mass-neutrino/

October 27, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Scientists Take Baby Steps Toward Extraterrestrial Babies Can sperm survive microgravity? Do eggs hold up to radiation? The new science of off-planet procreation is now getting underway. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-take-baby-steps-toward-extraterrestrial-babies/

October 26, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Ocean Cleanup’s New Plastic-Catcher … Kinda Already Exists? The anti-plastic crusaders have another plan to keep junk from reaching the sea: trash-eating barges in rivers. https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-cleanup-interceptor/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Can We Plant 20 Million Trees for 2020? The Math Says Yes How much land will the #TeamTrees plan require? A science prof roughs it to assess the feasibility. https://www.wired.com/story/20-million-trees-by-2020-how-much-land-would-it-take/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Slime Blob That Won the Internet Is Weirder Than You Think A zoo puts a mysterious slime mold on display, and the internet gushes. Here’s everything you need to know about the weirdest blob on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/slime-mold/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How Ultra-Flexible Teens Turned ‘Tricking’ Into a Sport For more than a decade, Michael Guthrie has dominated the world of tricking, a sport he describes as “emotion and personality, expressed with flips.” https://www.wired.com/story/how-ultra-flexible-teens-turned-tricking-into-a-sport/

October 25, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Trying to Plant a Trillion Trees Won’t Solve Anything We’re not going to stop climate change with just seedlings and fancy agriculture. We also need to reduce emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/trees-regenerative-agriculture-climate-change/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Age of Flames Is Consuming California   Yet another massive wildfire is ravaging Northern California. Welcome to the Pyrocene—think of it like the Ice Age, but with fire. https://www.wired.com/story/kincade-fire/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Most Diabolical Race and the Rise of Women Endurance Stars Maggie Guterl is the first woman to win the Big’s Backyard Ultra, an endurance running race so twisted and extreme it’s in a class of its own. https://www.wired.com/story/the-most-diabolical-race-and-the-rise-of-women-endurance-stars/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Tom SimoniteTom Simonite A Health Care Algorithm Offered Less Care to Black Patients A study shows the risks of making decisions using data that reflects inequities in American society. https://www.wired.com/story/how-algorithm-favored-whites-over-blacks-health-care/

October 24, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus We Should Just Build Giant Telescopes … in Space Launching a huge observatory poses big risks, so scientists are plotting a new approach: Send it up in pieces, then have robots put it together. https://www.wired.com/story/we-should-just-build-giant-telescopes-in-space/

October 23, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why Did Oklahoma’s Sooner Schooner Tip Over? A physicist explains how a touchdown celebration went awry and offers some advice for future designers of covered wagons. https://www.wired.com/story/why-did-oklahomas-sooner-schooner-tip-over/

October 23, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Wants to Send a Probe to the Hellish Surface of Venus The longest a spacecraft has survived on Earth’s “evil twin” is just 127 minutes. Now NASA is building one to last 60 days. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-wants-to-send-a-probe-to-the-hellish-surface-of-venus/

October 23, 2019 | Author: Andrew McAfeeAndrew McAfee Technology Will Keep Us From Running Out of Stuff Opinion: Such dire warnings ignore the force of capitalism and technological progress, what Abraham Lincoln called “the fuel of interest to the fire of genius.” https://www.wired.com/story/technology-will-keep-us-from-running-out-of-stuff/

October 22, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb NASA’s Biggest Telescope Yet, Facebook’s 2020 Plan, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-james-webb-telescope-facebook-2020-zuckerberg/

October 22, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Scientists Are Literally Spinning Up Lab-Grown Meat Researchers take inspiration from cotton candy to make a gelatin scaffolding, which could help realize the dream of more sustainable steaks and chicken breasts. https://www.wired.com/story/gelatin-fibers-lab-grown-meat/

October 22, 2019 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee NASA’s Biggest Telescope Ever Prepares for a 2021 Launch Once the $10 billion Webb Telescope is blasted into orbit, it will seek out water on Earth-like planets, stars being born, and more elusive interstellar quarry. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-biggest-telescope-ever-prepares-2021-launch/

October 21, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb New DNA Editing for Diseases, Dining Surveillance, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-technique-genetic-disease-outback-surveillance/

October 21, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A New Crispr Technique Could Fix Almost All Genetic Diseases A less error-prone DNA editing method could correct many more harmful mutations than was previously possible. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-crispr-technique-could-fix-many-more-genetic-diseases/

October 21, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Andrew Yang Wants a Thorium Reactor by 2027. Good Luck, Buddy The presidential candidate backs a type of reactor that promises cleaner, safer nuclear energy. But it may not be the best way to ditch fossil fuels. https://www.wired.com/story/andrew-yang-wants-a-thorium-reactor-by-2027-good-luck-buddy/

October 21, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Bizarre Aye-Aye Isn’t Giving Us the Finger After All The primate uses its long middle finger to fish for grubs. But scientists just discovered its “pseudothumb,” meaning it’s got six digits, not five. https://www.wired.com/story/aye-aye-pseudothumb/

October 20, 2019 | Author: John PavlusJohn Pavlus Computers Are Learning to Read—But They’re Still Not So Smart A tool called BERT can now outperform us on advanced reading-comprehension tests. It’s also revealed how far AI has to go. https://www.wired.com/story/computers-are-learning-to-read-but-theyre-still-not-so-smart/

October 19, 2019 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK All Hail the Blob, the Smart Slime Mold Confounding Science A Parisian zoo has opened an unusual new exhibit: a blob of slime mold with almost 720 sexes. https://www.wired.com/story/all-hail-the-blob-smart-slime-mold-confounding-science/

October 18, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Juul Pulls Pods, Roll-Royce Builds a Flying Lab, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/juul-fruit-flavored-pods-rolls-royce-747/

October 18, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Could an Astronaut Lost in Space Use Gravity to Get Around? With some basic physics, there are several ways to figure it out in real time. Which is good, because you’re going to run out of air. https://www.wired.com/story/could-an-astronaut-lost-in-space-use-gravity-to-get-around/

October 18, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Netflix Series Explores the Brave New World of Crispr From malaria-ridden villages in Burkina Faso to fertility clinics in Ukraine, Unnatural Selection takes viewers deep into the gene-editing revolution. https://www.wired.com/story/a-netflix-series-explores-the-brave-new-world-of-crispr/

October 18, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can Tiny Glass Beads Keep Arctic Ice From Melting? Maaaybe A geoengineering nonprofit wants to spread silicate beads over polar sea ice to prevent the absorption of heat, but some scientists have their doubts. https://www.wired.com/story/geoengineering-tiny-glass-beads-prevent-arctic-ice-from-melting/

October 17, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Juul, Under Heavy Fire, Pulls Fruit-Flavored Pods From US Vaping opponents criticize plan to continue selling the popular mint and menthol flavors.  https://www.wired.com/story/juul-pulls-fruit-flavored-pods-us/

October 17, 2019 | Author: Adnan Hirad, Brad MahonAdnan Hirad and Brad Mahon The NFL’s Helmet Tests Are Brainless Opinion: Current testing on helmets ignores the kinds of impacts that cause most of the concussions. It’s time for football to wise up. https://www.wired.com/story/the-nfls-helmet-tests-are-brainless/

October 17, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus What Is a Dimension? The Answer Will Bend Your Mind Caltech physicist Sean Carroll explains dimensions in ways that even a 5-year-old can understand. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-a-dimension-the-answer-will-bend-your-mind/

October 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Chaos Will Unfold if Trump Opens the Tongass to Logging Tongass National Forest is a massive yet fragile treasure—logging and slicing roads into it will set off horrifying effects that will ripple through the ecosystem. https://www.wired.com/story/tongass-logging/

October 16, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA’s New Space Suits Will Fit Men and Women Alike (for Once) Seven months after a debacle in which the agency ran short on space suits for women, NASA is showing off a new, more flexible design. https://www.wired.com/story/no-more-spacewalk-snafus-nasas-new-space-suit-fits-everyone/

October 16, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison A New Gene Helps Explain Why Some People Need Less Sleep The lucky devils who thrive on just a few hours’ sleep may be benefiting from a gene mutation that increases wakefulness and keeps memory intact. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-gene-helps-explain-why-some-people-need-less-sleep/

October 16, 2019 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Archaeologists Found the World’s Oldest Leftovers Unearthed Tupperware from the Stone Age shows that humans had “doggy bags” before we had dogs. https://www.wired.com/story/archaeologists-found-the-worlds-oldest-leftovers/

October 15, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon UC Berkeley Was About to Launch a Satellite. Then PG&E Said It Was Cutting Power To lower the risk of fire during a wind event, the utility cut power across Northern California. Here’s how scientists launched a satellite at the same time. https://www.wired.com/story/icon-launch-blackout/

October 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Tips for Puking in Microgravity and Staying Healthy in Space To avoid medical debacles in orbit, don’t forget your quarantine or daily trips to the zero-g gym aboard the ISS. https://www.wired.com/story/tips-for-puking-in-microgravity-and-staying-healthy-in-space/

October 15, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Wrong Answer, Class. Excellent Work! The best way to teach science? Rig your experiments to confound students’ predictions. https://www.wired.com/story/the-power-of-wrong-answers-in-science-education/

October 15, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Ancestry Branches Out Into Genetic Health Screening AncestryHealth offers a test for hereditary conditions such as breast cancer or heart disease, building on the company’s tools for tracking family history. https://www.wired.com/story/ancestry-branches-out-into-genetic-health-screening/

October 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Trove of Mouse Data Points Toward Brain-Computer Interfaces Some 850 gigabytes of mouse brain data just got released. That’s great for reading the minds of mice now, and for building brain-controlled computers later. https://www.wired.com/story/a-trove-of-mouse-data-points-toward-brain-computer-interfaces/

October 14, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Robot Rocket Printers, Fornite Disappears, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/fortnite-blackout-3d-printed-rockets/

October 14, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How Eliud Kipchoge Pulled Off His Epic, Sub-2-Hour Marathon Sports physiologist Michael Joyner breaks down what it takes to run a marathon in less than two hours—and how it could happen again. https://www.wired.com/story/how-eliud-kipchoge-pulled-off-his-epic-sub-2-hour-marathon/

October 14, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Listen to an Underwater Volcano Burp 750-Foot Bubbles Microphones catch a submarine vent firing uberbubbles that floated to the surface and formed massive water domes.  https://www.wired.com/story/underwater-volcano-bubbles/

October 14, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Massive, AI-Powered Robots Are 3D-Printing Entire Rockets Relativity Space may have the biggest metal 3D printers in the world, and they’re cranking out parts to reinvent the rocket industry here—and on Mars. https://www.wired.com/story/massive-ai-powered-robots-are-3d-printing-entire-rockets/

October 13, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Is the Equal Sign Overrated? Mathematicians Hash It Out Many of them avoid the equal sign, hoping to promote a looser relationship of “equivalence” instead. It’s been controversial. https://www.wired.com/story/is-the-equal-sign-overrated-mathematicians-hash-it-out/

October 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Be Master of the Midway—With Physics! Don’t be a chump, study angular momentum(p). https://www.wired.com/story/master-the-midway-with-physics/

October 11, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Eliud Kipchoge Is Set to Break the 2-Hour Marathon Barrier On Saturday, the best marathoner on earth could make history on a straight, flat course, aided by controversial shoes and a phalanx of 41 pacers. https://www.wired.com/story/eliud-kipchoge-is-set-to-break-the-2-hour-marathon-barrier/

October 10, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers California’s Power Outages Are About Wildfires—But Also Money PG&E turned off the power for more than 700,000 customers to keep them safe from wildfires. Its bankruptcy likely played a role as well. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-power-outages-are-about-wildfiresbut-also-money/

October 10, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The ‘Forever Chemicals’ You Eat, a $200 Spy Setup, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/pfas-chemicals-bloodstream-plant-spy-chips-bloomberg-apple/

October 10, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill ‘Forever Chemicals’ Are in Your Popcorn—and Your Blood Food packaging can contain a group of chemicals called PFAS, which have been linked to immune, thyroid, kidney, and reproductive health problems. https://www.wired.com/story/pfas-forever-chemicals-are-in-your-popcornand-your-blood/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Mass Power Outage, Twitter’s Data Misuse, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/pge-power-outage-california-bay-twitter-data-two-factor-privacy/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Two Nobel Laureates Spotted the First Exoplanet Swiss scientists “started a revolution in astronomy” by noticing a tiny stutter in the starlight. https://www.wired.com/story/how-two-nobel-laureates-spotted-the-first-exoplanet/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Wealthy Counties Benefited Most From a Flood Relief Program When the government offered to buy up houses in flood zones, wealthier homeowners took advantage while poorer residents stayed put or fled. https://www.wired.com/story/wealthy-counties-benefited-most-from-a-flood-relief-program/

October 9, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Nobel for Gadgets! Lithium-Ion Batteries Win the Prize The 2019 Nobel Prize in Chemistry went to an invention at the heart of modern life: the rechargeable lithium-ion battery. https://www.wired.com/story/a-nobel-for-gadgets-lithium-ion-batteries-win-the-prize/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Power Shutoffs Can’t Save California From Wildfire Hell A staggering 800,000 customers will lose power across the state starting Wednesday. But that won’t fix the mess California’s made. https://www.wired.com/story/pge-california-power-outage/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Nicholas Thompson, Knox RobinsonNicholas Thompson and Knox Robinson High Drama—and Erasure—at the Track World Championships WIRED editor Nick Thompson and running expert Knox Robinson discuss the showstoppers at the IAAF track and field championships in Qatar. https://www.wired.com/story/these-astounding-performances-made-tracks-top-event-a-hit/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen The Physics Nobel Goes to the Big Bang and Exoplanets James Peebles, Michel Mayor, and Didier Queloz share the 2019 Nobel Prize in Physics for their discoveries of the universe beyond our solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-nobel-goes-to-the-big-bang-and-exoplanets/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Microfibers Are the New Microbeads. Grab Your Pitchforks We must declare war on microfibers. But keeping the tiny plastics out of the environment won’t be so easy as an outright ban. https://www.wired.com/story/microfibers-are-the-new-microbeads/

October 8, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Cow, a Controversy, and a Dashed Dream of More Humane Farms The gene-edited bull was a marvel, with calves who’d inherited his trait. But a surprise in his DNA ignited a scientific feud and doomed them all. https://www.wired.com/story/a-cow-a-controversy-and-a-dashed-dream-of-more-humane-farms/

October 7, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Ancient Sippy Cups, A Full-Control Android Hack, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-sippy-cup-android-hack-vulnerability-pixel-galaxy/

October 7, 2019 | Author: SHANNON PALUSSHANNON PALUS Airbnb Wants to Send You to Antarctica. Don’t Fall for It The company is seeking five volunteers to go collect snow samples, but the stunt looks more like advertising than actual science. https://www.wired.com/story/airbnb-wants-to-send-you-to-antarctica-dont-fall-for-it/

October 7, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Nobel Prize in Medicine Goes to Your Body’s Oxygen Detector Three scientists won the award for uncovering the molecular switch that regulates how cells behave when oxygen levels drop. https://www.wired.com/story/the-nobel-prize-in-medicine-goes-to-your-bodys-oxygen-detector/

October 7, 2019 | Author: Arielle PardesArielle Pardes The Style-Quantifying Astrophysicists of Silicon Valley Space scientists are abandoning the heavens to help you decide what to wear and watch and listen to. Whether it’s stars or Stitch Fix, it’s all about machine learning. https://www.wired.com/story/the-style-maven-astrophysicists-of-silicon-valley/

October 6, 2019 | Author: John PreskillJohn Preskill Why I Coined the Term ‘Quantum Supremacy’ Researchers at Google finally seem to have a quantum computer that can outperform a classical computer. Here’s what that really means. https://www.wired.com/story/why-i-coined-the-term-quantum-supremacy/

October 5, 2019 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Ancient Sippy Cups Could Help Explain a Prehistoric Baby Boom  By weaning their infants off breast milk, mothers may have helped early European farming populations expand. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-sippy-cups-prehistoric-baby-boom/

October 4, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Netflix’s ‘Unnatural Selection’ Trailer Makes Crispr Personal A new docuseries digs into the existential promise and peril of the gene-editing revolution. https://www.wired.com/story/netflixs-unnatural-selection-trailer-makes-crispr-personal/

October 4, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Hurricanes May Be Reshaping Big Parts of the Ocean Scientists are just starting to tease out the long-distance changes that hurricanes inflict on coastlines and the deep ocean alike. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricanes-may-be-reshaping-big-parts-of-the-ocean/

October 4, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison So You Want to Quit Vaping? No One Actually Knows How E-cigarettes can be more addictive and even harder to quit than regular cigarettes, so kicking the habit may take even more vigilance. https://www.wired.com/story/so-you-want-to-quit-vaping-no-one-actually-knows-how/

October 3, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain If Each of Us Planted a Tree, Would It Slow Global Warming? Ask a physicist: Just how much carbon could 7.5 billion new trees pull out of the atmosphere? https://www.wired.com/story/plant-a-tree-for-climate-change/

October 3, 2019 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Want to Find the Best Parking Spot? Do the Math Here’s how to strike the optimal balance of parking close to the entrance without wasting too much time circling. https://www.wired.com/story/find-the-best-parking-spot-do-math/

October 3, 2019 | Author: Nicholas Thompson, Knox RobinsonNicholas Thompson and Knox Robinson Alberto Salazar, World Records, and Athletics’ Greatest ‘Hug’ Do negative splits actually matter? Did Salazar deserve a 4-year doping ban? WIRED editor Nicholas Thompson and elite runner Knox Robinson hash it out. https://www.wired.com/story/alberto-salazar-world-records-and-athletics-greatest-hug/

October 3, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon 7 Trillion Microplastic Particles Pollute the San Francisco Bay Each Year A new report shows an astounding amount of microplastics, largely from car tires, are tainting the watershed. https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-san-francisco-bay/

October 2, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Even a Small Nuclear War Could Trigger a Global Apocalypse Nuclear war doesn’t have to be big to devastate the world, inducing years of famine and climate catastrophe alongside all that death and radiation. https://www.wired.com/story/even-a-small-nuclear-war-could-trigger-a-global-apocalypse/

October 2, 2019 | Author: Michelle Lujan Grisham, Mark JohnsonMichelle Lujan Grisham and Mark Johnson Every State Should Monitor Methane to Meet Climate Goals Opinion: A new plan to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in New Mexico using satellites and big data sets a standard that other states should follow. https://www.wired.com/story/every-state-should-monitor-methane-to-meet-climate-goals/

October 2, 2019 | Author: Christie AschwandenChristie Aschwanden Football’s Concussion Crisis Is Awash With Pseudoscience Products that offer a “seat belt” or “bubble wrap” for the brain claim to reduce head trauma. If only the laws of physics worked that way. https://www.wired.com/story/footballs-concussion-crisis-is-awash-with-pseudoscience/

October 1, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Whoa! Is That Death Star Wreckage on That Planet? A physicist analyzes a colossal Easter egg in the latest Star Wars trailer. Do the filmmakers understand the gravity of the situation? https://www.wired.com/story/whats-up-with-that-death-star-wreckage-in-rise-of-skywalker/

October 1, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Massive, Overlooked Potential of African DNA Genetic studies rely almost entirely on DNA from people of European descent. A startup called 54gene wants to fix that, and fast. https://www.wired.com/story/the-massive-overlooked-potential-of-african-dna/

September 30, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Wildfire Vaccine, Elon’s New Starship, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/gel-wildfire-elon-musk-spacex-starship/

September 30, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez What’s the Hardest Shot in Bowling? It’s Complicated Is it the 7-10 Split? The Greek Church? The Big Four? The answer depends on whom you ask, but many bowlers agree: The 7-10 split deserves the title. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-the-hardest-shot-in-bowling-its-complicated/

September 30, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Clever Gel Works Like a Vaccine for Wildfires Spray the flame-retardant goo on vegetation, and it’ll protect the plants from igniting for months. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-gel/

September 29, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Big Question About Prime Numbers Gets a Partial Answer The twin primes conjecture has bedeviled mathematicians for more than a century. Now there’s a solution for one version of it. https://www.wired.com/story/a-big-question-about-prime-numbers-gets-a-partial-answer/

September 28, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Elon Musk Just Unveiled Starship, SpaceX’s Human-Carrying Rocket After years of speculation and hype, the SpaceX CEO finally explains how Starship will carry humans to the moon and eventually to Mars. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-just-unveiled-starship-spacexs-human-carrying-rocket/

September 27, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb NASA’s Nuclear Idea, an Unfixable Apple Flaw, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-nuclear-rocket-apple-iphone-jailbreak-ios/

September 27, 2019 | Author: Nicholas Thompson, Knox RobinsonNicholas Thompson and Knox Robinson Big Dreams and Extreme Heat: What to Expect from the World Track Championships Editor in Chief Nick Thompson and running expert Knox Robinson break down the highlights of the IAAF World Athletics Championships, which start tonight. https://www.wired.com/story/big-dreams-and-extreme-heat-what-to-expect-from-the-world-track-championships/

September 27, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Three Simple Tests Might Help Prevent Athletes’ Injuries Coaches in the NFL and elsewhere are using software that claims to identify a player’s weak spots. All it takes is a force plate—and a leap of faith. https://www.wired.com/story/three-simple-tests-might-help-prevent-athletes-injuries/

September 27, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Wants to Send Nuclear Rockets to the Moon and Mars It’s baaaack: Nuclear propulsion, first floated in the ’60s, is hot again. President Trump’s Mars ambitions might even hinge on it. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-wants-to-send-nuclear-rockets-to-the-moon-and-mars/

September 26, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Why Google’s Quantum Victory Is a Huge Deal—and a Letdown When news leaked that Google scientists had achieved “quantum supremacy,” researchers immediately clashed on its implications. https://www.wired.com/story/why-googles-quantum-computing-victory-is-a-huge-deal-and-a-letdown/

September 26, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Lots of Athletes Say CBD Is a Better Painkiller. Is It? There’s almost no data on how the cannabis extract works in humans, but the sports world is embracing it anyway. https://www.wired.com/story/lots-of-athletes-say-cbd-is-a-better-painkiller-is-it/

September 25, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The FDA Tells Congress E-Cigarettes Are Unsafe—and Illegal At a hearing, politicians spar over vaping’s lax enforcement, while Juul and other e-cigarette makers face a growing backlash. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-tells-congress-e-cigarettes-are-unsafe-and-illegal/

September 25, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We’re Killing the Oceans, and We’ll Pay Dearly for It Depending on whom you ask, the IPCC’s latest report is either startling, depressing, or dire—or more likely a combination of all three. https://www.wired.com/story/ipcc-oceans-report/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Robot Dog for Rent, Apple’s Secret AR Glasses, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-apple-ar-glasses-ios/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Remember The Dress? Here’s Why We All See Colors Differently Watch neuroscientist David Eagleman explain how that internet-shattering visual illusion—and others like it—mess with our perception of color. https://www.wired.com/story/remember-the-dress-heres-why-we-all-see-colors-differently/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Spot, the Internet’s Wildest 4-Legged Robot, Is Finally Here A select few can now lease the famous robot, formerly known as SpotMini, from Boston Dynamics. But what exactly is it good for? https://www.wired.com/story/spot-boston-dynamics/

September 24, 2019 | Author: Gloria DickieGloria Dickie How Amateur Video Is Helping Us Understand Deadly Tsunamis In 2004, when a tsunami devastated communities in southern Asia, videos shot by tourists and locals became a new tool for analyzing the deadly waves. https://www.wired.com/story/amateur-video-helping-understand-deadly-tsunamis/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Tesla’s Million-Mile Battery, Greta Thunberg’s UN Speech, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/greta-thunberg-un-climate-change-tesla-million-mile-battery/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus We Are Nowhere Close to Meeting Our Climate Goals A UN report says the world needs to triple the aggressiveness of its climate commitments to stave off environmental collapse. https://www.wired.com/story/we-are-nowhere-close-to-meeting-our-climate-goals/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Even Huge Molecules Follow the Quantum World’s Bizarre Rules A record-breaking experiment shows an enormous molecule is also both a particle and a wave—and that quantum effects don’t only apply at tiny scales. https://www.wired.com/story/even-huge-molecules-follow-the-quantum-worlds-bizarre-rules/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why These Geese Wear Tiny Backpacks and Fly in a Wind Tunnel The bar-headed goose flies 26,000 feet high during its migration. To find out how, scientists devised an adorable experiment. https://www.wired.com/story/why-these-geese-wear-tiny-backpacks-and-fly-in-a-wind-tunnel/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Brendan I. KoernerBrendan I. Koerner How Cities Reshape the Evolutionary Path of Urban Wildlife If researchers can figure out how pigeons and rats evolve to thrive in hostile city habitats, it could help other beasts—including us—adapt to climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/urban-wildlife-evolution-climate-change/

September 23, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Tesla May Soon Have a Battery That Can Last a Million Miles Elon Musk promised Tesla would soon have a million-mile battery, more than double what drivers can expect today. A new paper suggests he wasn’t exaggerating. https://www.wired.com/story/tesla-may-soon-have-a-battery-that-can-last-a-million-miles/

September 22, 2019 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica Knives Made of Frozen Feces Are Kinda Crappy Anthropologists have disproved the urban legend once and for all. https://www.wired.com/story/knives-frozen-feces-kinda-crappy/

September 22, 2019 | Author: Ashley SmartAshley Smart AI Helps Seismologists Predict Earthquakes Machine learning is bringing seismologists closer to an elusive goal: forecasting quakes well before they strike. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-helps-seismologists-predict-earthquakes/

September 21, 2019 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica How Vikings Went Into a Trancelike Rage Before Battle Ethnobotanists have a new theory on which plant the berserkers ingested. https://www.wired.com/story/how-vikings-went-into-trancelike-rage-before-battle/

September 20, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Area 51 Raid Was the Worst Way to Spot an Alien or UFO Dozens of revelers gathered near the top-secret base, purportedly hoping to glimpse some extraterrestrial life—but all they got were memes and selfies. https://www.wired.com/story/the-area-51-raid-was-the-worst-way-to-spot-an-alien-or-ufo/

September 20, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Global Climate Strike, a Dangerous Huawei Move, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/global-climate-strike-protest-greta-thunburg-teens-huawei-sanctions-security/

September 20, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What to Expect From a Pooch on a Paddleboard Sharing your deck with a dog is risky, but knowing about conservation of momentum might help you stay dry. https://www.wired.com/story/pooch-on-a-paddleboard/

September 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Capitalism Made This Mess, and This Mess Will Ruin Capitalism To understand climate change, one environmental historian says we need to realize we’ve entered a new era: the Capitalocene. https://www.wired.com/story/capitalocene/

September 19, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni You Can Soon Get Your DNA Sequenced Anonymously Using a blockchain, Nebula Genomics has crafted a way for customers to get their genomes sequenced without revealing personally identifying data. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-soon-get-your-dna-sequenced-anonymously/

September 19, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus How to Go to the Bathroom in Space Hear from a real-live astronaut about pee rainbows, poop practice, and the cosmic quest for good hygiene in zero gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-go-to-the-bathroom-in-space/

September 19, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni AI Could Reinvent Medicine—Or Become a Patient’s Nightmare The Mayo Clinic will store health data in Google’s cloud and use its AI expertise to unearth insights. But Google has made mistakes before. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-could-reinvent-medicineor-become-a-patients-nightmare/

September 18, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb An Area 51 Warning, Trump Takes on California, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/storm-area-51-dont-trump-california-emissions/

September 18, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Does the FDA Even Regulate E-Cigs? Actually Kinda Not That’s why all those weird, possibly toxic flavorings are allowed—and the lax regulatory environment goes back a century. https://www.wired.com/story/dangerous-levels-of-carcinogen-in-mint-flavored-vapes/

September 18, 2019 | Author: Steven LevySteven Levy Richard Stallman and the Fall of the Clueless Nerd The controversial pioneer of free software resigned from MIT over his remarks on Jeffrey Epstein and Marvin Minsky. Stallman won’t be the last. https://www.wired.com/story/richard-stallman-and-the-fall-of-the-clueless-nerd/

September 18, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Don’t Storm Area 51, Begs the Webmaster of the UFO Kingdom Joerg Arnu loves the secretive military base, documents it on an exhaustive fan site, and wants people to visit—just not all at once. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-storm-area-51-begs-the-webmaster-of-the-ufo-kingdom/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Got What It Takes to Compete in Speed Climbing? Let’s compute the power output required to sprint up a vertical wall. https://www.wired.com/story/power-demands-of-speed-climbing/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Evan D. MorrisEvan D. Morris Why We Need Guidelines for Brain Scan Data Opinion: Brain scans, aided by AI, reveal as much about you as your DNA. Grappling with their ethical implications is vital to scientific integrity. https://www.wired.com/story/why-we-need-brain-scan-data-guidelines/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The First Hurricane Relief Drone Was Ready to Fly—Then Dorian Hit A drone company on Great Abaco, in the Bahamas, was prepared to deliver emergency supplies if the hurricane struck. Dorian had other plans. https://www.wired.com/story/the-first-hurricane-relief-drone-was-ready-to-fly-then-dorian-hit/

September 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon James Cameron, Victor Vescovo, and the Saga of the Deepest* Solo Dive Ever Vescovo says he dove deeper than Cameron. Cameron says not so fast. Perhaps only Poseidon knows for sure. https://www.wired.com/story/deepest-solo-dive-ever/

September 16, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Buzz-Kill Physics Discovery, a Deadly Miracle Drug, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/proton-size-opioid-addict-cure-ibocaine/

September 15, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Physicists Finally Nail the Proton’s Size, and Hope Dies A new measurement seems to eliminate an anomaly that has captivated physicists for nearly a decade. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-finally-nail-the-protons-size-and-hope-dies/

September 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How Rich Donors Like Epstein (and Others) Undermine Science MIT’s Media Lab, Harvard, Stanford, hospitals—they all take money from donors. Whether it’s to truly help the world or merely burnish a reputation, the money nevertheless bends the arc of the innovation universe. https://www.wired.com/story/the-problem-with-rich-people-funding-science/

September 13, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Super Planetary-Motion Smackdown: Kepler v. Newton In science, progress is all about building a better model—explaining more with less. https://www.wired.com/story/planetary-motion-smackdown/

September 13, 2019 | Author: Kiona N. Smith, Ars TechnicaKiona N. Smith, Ars Technica Mass Graves in Russia Tell the Grim Story of Mongol Invasion After years of digging, archaeologists discover nine medieval graves holding the remains of at least 300 people. https://www.wired.com/story/mass-graves-russia-tell-grim-story-mongol-invasion/

September 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet a Mad Scientist Who Flies Into Hurricanes A hurricane bounces NOAA’s sensor-packed plane around with such violence, the crew spends a good amount of time in zero G. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-forecasting/

September 12, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Riddle, and Controversy, of All That Missing Plastic The contentious Ocean Cleanup campaign has an idea where marine plastic ends up. But it’s already stirring debate. https://www.wired.com/story/missing-plastic/

September 12, 2019 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson How to Practice Long-Term Thinking in a Distracted World Bina Venkataraman, author of The Optimist’s Telescope, talks about the future: how to imagine it, how to be optimistic, how to not kill a million babies. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-practice-long-term-thinking-in-a-distracted-world/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Chinese Scientists Try to Cure One Man’s HIV With Crispr For the first time, a patient got treated for HIV and cancer at the same time, with an infusion of gene-edited stem cells. The results? Mixed. https://www.wired.com/story/chinese-scientists-try-to-cure-one-mans-hiv-with-crispr/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A New Water Vapor Discovery in Space, SFO Delays, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/water-vapor-exoplanet-discovery-sfo-delays-911/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Scientists Find Water Vapor on the Most Habitable Exoplanet Yet A so-called super-Earth with water in its atmosphere has many appealing attributes. But that doesn’t mean it hosts life. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-find-water-vapor-on-the-most-habitable-exoplanet-yet/

September 11, 2019 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Best Place to Make Undersea Cables Might Be … in Space A startup plans to manufacture fiber-optic cable on the International Space Station and ship it back to customers on Earth. Easy! https://www.wired.com/story/the-best-place-to-make-undersea-cables-might-be-in-space/

September 10, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Sean Carroll Thinks We All Exist on Multiple Worlds In his book Something Deeply Hidden, the physicist explores the idea of Many Worlds, which holds that the universe continually splits into new branches. https://www.wired.com/story/sean-carroll-thinks-we-all-exist-on-multiple-worlds/

September 10, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Three Ways to Fix the Drug Industry’s Rampant Dysfunction Big Pharma has come under fire for mislabeled drugs, price spikes, and life-threatening shortages. Now a handful of startups hope to clean up the industry. https://www.wired.com/story/three-ways-to-fix-the-drug-industrys-rampant-dysfunction/

September 9, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Myth of Processed Foods, an Amazon Walkout, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/processed-foods-amazon-walkout/

September 9, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Unusual Fluids Flip, Twirl, and Redefine How Liquids Work New shape-shifting liquids can move or morph on command. One scientist even used them to make liquid cables for his headphones. https://www.wired.com/story/unusual-fluids-flip-twirl-and-redefine-how-liquids-work/

September 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Let’s All Just Chill About Processed Foods Processed foods are bad for you, right? So super-processed, plant-based meat must be terrible, right? Not so fast on either count. https://www.wired.com/story/processed-foods/

September 8, 2019 | Author: Brendan Z. FosterBrendan Z. Foster Are We All Wrong About Black Holes? A philosopher of science worries that the analogy between black holes and thermodynamics has been stretched too far. https://www.wired.com/story/are-we-all-wrong-about-black-holes/

September 7, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Is It OK to Change Hurricane Forecasts With a Sharpie Doodle? A physicist wades into the dreaded “cone of uncertainty” surrounding White House weather advisories. https://www.wired.com/story/changing-hurricane-forecasts-with-a-sharpie/

September 6, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Moon Landing Goes Awry, Apple Opens Up on iOS Hacks, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/indian-lunar-lander-apple-iphone-hack-google/

September 6, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus India’s Moon Landing May Be Doomed The Indian Space Research Organization says it lost contact with its lunar lander shortly before touchdown. https://www.wired.com/story/indias-moon-landing-may-be-doomed/

September 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Rip a Crazy Skateboard Loop With Physics All you need is some topsy-turvy force analysis and this simple equation. https://www.wired.com/story/rip-a-skateboard-loop-with-physics/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus India Is Ready to Touch Down Near the Moon’s South Pole If successful, India will become the fourth country to put a lander on lunar soil. The spacecraft will then collect data on the south pole’s many mysteries. https://www.wired.com/story/india-chandrayaan-2-lunar-lander-is-ready-to-touch-down-near-the-moons-south-pole/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Retreat? Pish. Democrats Dare Not Speak Climate Change’s ‘R’ Word Canadians call the abandonment of coasts and floodplains a “strategic retreat.” American politicians call it literally anything else they can. https://www.wired.com/story/democrats-climate-change-retreat/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How to Solve a Rubik’s Cube, Step by Step Follow the eight steps described in this video and you too can start solving Rubik’s cubes faster … and faster … and faster. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-solve-a-rubiks-cube-step-by-step/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Huge Electric Dump Truck Never Needs to Plug In Called the eDumper, the massive truck relies on regenerative braking to recover some of its energy as it slows down. Let’s break down the physics. https://www.wired.com/story/this-huge-electric-dump-truck-never-needs-to-plug-in/

September 5, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon CNN’s Town Hall Made Climate Change Personal—and It Worked Democratic candidates in the network’s event devoted to climate weaponize a uniquely human tool: stories. https://www.wired.com/story/cnn-town-hall-climate-change/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Hurricane Dorian Science, a Vaping Mouse Experiment, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-dorian-prediction-vape-deadly-mice-experiment/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Vaping May Hamper the Lungs’ Ability to Fend off Infections A study in mice finds that inhaling the vapor from an e-cigarette—no nicotine needed—raised their odds of dying after exposure to the flu virus. https://www.wired.com/story/vaping-may-hamper-the-lungs-ability-to-fend-off-infections/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What to Look for in CNN’s ‘Climate Crisis’ Town Hall Tonight Over the course of seven hours, 10 candidates will describe their climate policies. Here are the words and issues to watch for in their answers. https://www.wired.com/story/what-to-look-for-in-cnns-climate-crisis-town-hall-tonight/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Plastic Will Be the Shameful Artifact Our Descendants Dig Up Sediment samples show microplastics have been accumulating on the sea floor since the 1940s, the deposition rates doubling every 15 years. https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-core-samples/

September 4, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Why Hurricane Dorian Defied Forecasts and Sank the Bahamas The storm evolved swiftly and unpredictably. But it was other weather phenomena that caused Dorian to stall, devastating the island nation. https://www.wired.com/story/why-hurricane-dorian-defied-forecasts-and-sank-the-bahamas/

September 3, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Trump Tweeted a Sensitive Photo. Internet Sleuths Decoded It Within hours of the president’s post, amateur satellite trackers had hunted down the secret spy satellite that photographed a charred Iranian launchpad. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-tweeted-a-sensitive-photo-internet-sleuths-decoded-it/

September 3, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Watch Atoms Fall to See Earth’s Changing Structure A new instrument is so sensitive it can discern a 1.5-centimeter change in sea level. “It was detecting the food in our stomachs,” one physicist says. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-watch-atoms-fall-to-see-earths-changing-structure/

September 2, 2019 | Author: Jennifer Ouellette, Ars TechnicaJennifer Ouellette, Ars Technica The Rock That Vibrates in Time With Earth, Wind, and Waves How vulnerable are landmark stone formations to tremors from earthquakes or human activities? https://www.wired.com/story/rock-that-vibrates-time-with-earth-wind-waves/

September 1, 2019 | Author: John Timmer, Ars TechnicaJohn Timmer, Ars Technica Scientists Avoid Bias When They Know They’re Being Tested A new paper tracked possible bias among scientists awarding prestigious research positions. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-are-good-at-avoiding-bias-when-they-know-theyre-being-tested-for-it/

September 1, 2019 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz Humans and Neanderthals Kept Breeding—and Breeding—for Ages Modern humans and Neanderthals commingled at many points in history, raising the possibility that the ancient hominins were just another version of us. https://www.wired.com/story/humans-neanderthals-interbreeding/

August 31, 2019 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Tune Into Neptune Voyager 2 completed its historic flyby 30 years ago. No probe has been back since. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-tune-into-neptune/

August 30, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The EPA Says Methane Rules Are Bad for Industry—It’s Wrong Drones and satellites make it easy to detect and plug methane leaks, benefitting oil and gas companies and the environment alike. https://www.wired.com/story/the-epa-says-methane-rules-are-bad-for-industry-its-wrong/

August 30, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus This DIY Implant Lets You Stream Movies From Inside Your Leg Biohackers inserted a device—a hard drive plus router—into their legs. They say it could improve data security, but it also raises knotty legal issues. https://www.wired.com/story/this-diy-implant-lets-you-stream-movies-from-inside-your-leg/

August 30, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Elite Athletes Are Changing How They Train for Extreme Heat Runners are prepping for the high heat of next month’s IAAF World Championships in Doha. Under climate change, that training may become the norm. https://www.wired.com/story/elite-athletes-are-changing-how-they-train-for-extreme-heat/

August 30, 2019 | Author: Sarah Elizabeth RichardsSarah Elizabeth Richards One Scientist’s Quest to Bring DNA Sequencing to Every Sick Kid Ryan Taft didn’t know that he would become one of the world’s leading experts in diagnosing rare genetic diseases. Then he met Stephen Damiani. https://www.wired.com/story/one-scientists-quest-to-bring-dna-sequencing-to-every-sick-kid/

August 29, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How America’s Spooks Seek to Spy on Distant Satellites The intelligence community has plans for a telescope network that can see not just a blob in orbit but details such as a satellite’s solar panels. https://www.wired.com/story/how-americas-spooks-seek-to-spy-on-distant-satellites/

August 28, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Capitalism Burns the Amazon, Lawsuits Burn YouTube, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-rainforest-fire-youtube-lawsuit/

August 28, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Behold the Firenado’s Twisting, Infernal Column of Flames Call them fire tornadoes or fire whirls, these spinning conflagrations can tear roofs off houses and spread flames unpredictably. Here’s how they work. https://www.wired.com/story/behold-the-firenados-twisting-infernal-column-of-flames/

August 28, 2019 | Author: Timothy A. WiseTimothy A. Wise Big Ag Is Sabotaging Progress on Climate Change Opinion: Grim as the UN’s latest climate report is, it doesn’t confront the dangerous, government-hijacking power of agribusiness. https://www.wired.com/story/big-ag-is-sabotaging-progress-on-climate-change/

August 28, 2019 | Author: Molly EnkingMolly Enking Flint, Newark, and the Persistent Crisis of Lead in Water The contaminated water in Flint and Newark is not unusual, and some experts think they know where the next “next Flint” will be. https://www.wired.com/story/first-flint-now-newark-the-water-crisis-is-far-from-over/

August 28, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Who’s Burning the Amazon? Rampant Capitalism Market forces and the administration of Jair Bolsonaro are supercharging the deforestation that’s imperiling the world’s biggest tropical rainforest. https://www.wired.com/story/whos-burning-the-amazon-rampant-capitalism/

August 27, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What on Earth Is Water Doing in Hawaii’s Kilauea Volcano? WIRED sits down with a geologist to learn how scientists might sample the newfound water—and why you shouldn’t panic and cancel your island getaway. https://www.wired.com/story/kilauea-volcano-water/

August 27, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You’re Racing Toward a Wall. Should You Brake Hard—or Swerve? Say you’re driving and come upon an obstacle. Is it best to slam on the brakes, turn, or start weaving? Here’s how to crunch the numbers. https://www.wired.com/story/youre-racing-toward-a-wall-should-you-brake-hardor-swerve/

August 27, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Jeffrey Epstein and the Power of Networks The billionaire child rapist bought his way into an elite crowd of intellectuals that defined the last three decades of science, tech, and culture. https://www.wired.com/story/jeffrey-epstein-and-the-power-of-networks/

August 26, 2019 | Author: Lydia HorneLydia Horne China Trade Spillover, LA’s Pollution by Block, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/china-trade-spillover-las-pollution-by-block-and-more-news/

August 26, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon See How LA Belches Emissions, Block by Block Researchers quantify the emissions of every road and building in the nearly 5,000 square miles of the Los Angeles metro area. Your city could be next. https://www.wired.com/story/la-emissions-block-by-block/

August 26, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Brazil’s Plans for Gene-Edited Cows Got Scrapped—Here’s Why The country was going to breed a herd of genetically dehorned cows. Then errors in the cows’ DNA cropped up. https://www.wired.com/story/brazils-plans-for-gene-edited-cows-got-scrappedheres-why/

August 25, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Single Math Model Explains Many Mysteries of Vision The first anatomically correct model of the visual cortex seeks to capture how the brain sees the world. https://www.wired.com/story/a-single-math-model-explains-many-mysteries-of-vision/

August 23, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Vaping May Have Killed Someone, Health Officials Say An investigation into respiratory illnesses connected to e-cigs by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention turned up the first known death this week. https://www.wired.com/story/vaping-may-have-killed-someone/

August 23, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Why the Amazon’s On Fire, a Robocall Fight, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-fires-cause-brazil-president-robocalls/

August 23, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Horrifying Science of the Deforestation Fueling Amazon Fires At the core of Brazil’s out-of-control fires in the Amazon is deforestation. Here’s how human meddling fundamentally transforms a rainforest. https://www.wired.com/story/the-horrifying-science-of-the-deforestation-fueling-amazon-fires/

August 22, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Why the NFL’s Field Goal Record Is Waiting to Be Smashed Players, coaches, and scientists alike say that the current record of 64 yards is well shy of what humans are capable of kicking. https://www.wired.com/story/why-the-nfls-field-goal-record-is-waiting-to-be-smashed/

August 22, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Tugboat in Space, Microplastics In Your Water, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/space-tug-microplastic-pollution/

August 22, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Humans, More Than Drought, Are Fueling the Amazon’s Flames Economic activity appears to be causing the rainforest to burn, unlike the other epic fires ravaging the world. https://www.wired.com/story/humans-more-than-drought-are-fueling-the-amazons-flames/

August 22, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Hey Teachers, Get to Know Your Students’ Preconceptions People in an intro to physics class may make some basic errors, but that doesn’t mean their ideas are bad. Effective teachers know to look deeper. https://www.wired.com/story/hey-teachers-get-to-know-your-students-preconceptions/

August 22, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Here Come the Space Tugs, Ready to Tidy Up Earth’s Orbits SpaceX is teaming up with the maker of a space tugboat, which would nudge satellites around, clean up space junk, and do other orbital housekeeping. https://www.wired.com/story/here-come-the-space-tugs-ready-to-tidy-up-earths-orbits/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon You’ve Been Drinking Microplastics, But Don’t Worry—Yet A new WHO report says drinking microplastic particles isn’t yet a threat to human health. But we need way more research. https://www.wired.com/story/microplastic-who-study/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Potent Cancer Therapy, an Instagram Hoax, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/cancer-carbon-ion-therapy-instagram-hoax/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Jim MorrisonJim Morrison The Cost of Rising Seas: More Than $400 Billion (and Lots of Angst) Coastal US cities will need massive new infrastructure to protect against climate change—and someone has to pay the bill. https://www.wired.com/story/the-cost-of-rising-seas-more-than-dollar400-billion-and-lots-of-angst/

August 21, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Why a Promising, Potent Cancer Therapy Isn’t Used in the US Carbon ion radiation therapy is being used to blast tumors all over the world. Just not in the country that invented it. https://www.wired.com/story/why-a-promising-potent-cancer-therapy-isnt-used-in-the-us/

August 20, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Dangers of Vaping, a Texas Ransomware Attack, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/vape-e-cigarette-blood-ransomware-texas/

August 20, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Vaping May Harm Your Blood Flow—Even Without Nicotine Inhaling e-cigarette vapor alone had an immediate, negative impact on the vascular systems of first-time vapers. https://www.wired.com/story/vaping-may-harm-your-blood-flow-even-without-nicotine/

August 20, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore Mass Shootings May Be Contagious. Can We Contain Them? Mounting evidence suggests mass shootings could spread like a virus, and the media is a vector. Changing how news outlets report on these tragedies could help. https://www.wired.com/story/mass-shootings-may-be-contagious-can-we-contain-them/

August 20, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA’s Next Martian Rover Is Almost Ready to Rock The all-terrain bot will use its 7-foot-long, turret-tipped arm to drill core samples from the red planet’s surface, searching for signs of life. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-next-rover-almost-ready-to-rock-mars/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Bananas in Crisis, Aggressive Social Spiders, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/bananas-fungus-spiders-aggressive-hurricanes/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Melting Glaciers Are Helping Capture Carbon Glaciers melting under the weight of global warming can help sequester carbon, making such watersheds a previously unrecognized CO2 sink. https://www.wired.com/story/melting-glaciers-are-helping-capture-carbon/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Colonies of Aggressive, Social Spiders Boom After a Hurricane Add skittering groups of extra-bold spiders to the list of post-storm delights. As if flooded homes and downed trees aren’t enough. https://www.wired.com/story/colonies-of-aggressive-social-spiders-boom-after-a-hurricane/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Liz SpechtLiz Specht Alt-Meat Trounces Animal Meat’s Massive Inefficiencies Opinion: Animal meat production is slow, rigid, and wasteful. Plant- and cell-based meat production is swift, nimble, and sustainable. https://www.wired.com/story/alt-meat-trounces-animal-meats-massive-inefficiencies/

August 19, 2019 | Author: Matt Reynolds, WIRED UKMatt Reynolds, WIRED UK A Fungus Could Wipe Out the Banana Forever Tropical Race 4 has spread to the region where most exported bananas are grown. https://www.wired.com/story/fungus-could-wipe-out-banana-forever/

August 18, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Major Proof Shows How to Approximate Numbers Like Pi The ancient Greeks wondered when irrational numbers, like pi, can be represented with fractions. Two mathematicians now have a complete answer. https://www.wired.com/story/a-major-proof-shows-how-to-approximate-numbers-like-pi/

August 16, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Even Physics Textbooks Tend to Get Friction Slightly Wrong No matter what that Intro to Physics book says, you can’t calculate the “work done by friction.” Nope. Doesn’t work. Don’t even try it. https://www.wired.com/story/even-physics-textbooks-tend-to-get-friction-slightly-wrong/

August 16, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Bonkers Tech That Detects Lightning 6,000 Miles Away If lightning strikes near the North Pole, and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound? Yes, because a global sensor network is always listening. https://www.wired.com/story/lightning-tech/

August 15, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Rocket-Catchin’ Copter, a Radioactive Russian Cloud, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/rocket-helicopter-russian-nuclear-cloud/

August 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Catch Rockets With a Helicopter? Yep, That’s the Plan SpaceX was the first to bring a booster back from space and use it again. Other companies are now following in its footsteps—kind of. https://www.wired.com/story/catch-rockets-with-a-helicopter-yep-thats-the-plan/

August 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Actually, Gender-Neutral Pronouns Can Change a Culture In 2012 a nongendered pronoun dropped into Swedish discourse. Today it’s widely used—and it’s nudging people to see the world a little differently. https://www.wired.com/story/actually-gender-neutral-pronouns-can-change-a-culture/

August 15, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore A Strange Radioactive Cloud Likely Came From Russia In 2017 a plume of radioactive gas wafted across Europe. A study now shows it probably stemmed from a nuclear accident in southern Russia. https://www.wired.com/story/a-strange-radioactive-cloud-likely-came-from-russia/

August 14, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Arctic Plastic Pollution, a Hacker Joke Gone Awry, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/null-license-hacker-microplastics-arctic/

August 14, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Microplastics Are Blowing Into the Pristine Arctic In snow samples collected across the Arctic and Europe, researchers find tens of thousands of microplastic particles per liter of snow—even in remote areas. https://www.wired.com/story/microplastics-are-blowing-into-the-pristine-arctic/

August 14, 2019 | Author: Emily HoldenEmily Holden 3 Animals Hurt By the New Endangered Species Act These three creatures illustrate the harm that could come from the loss of protections, which the Trump administration announced Monday. https://www.wired.com/story/3-animals-hurt-by-the-new-endangered-species-act/

August 14, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Tax Credit Fueled the Solar Energy Boom. Now It’s in Limbo A federal subsidy that helped launch the US solar industry is about to expire. The industry is likely to stumble without some replacement. https://www.wired.com/story/a-tax-credit-fueled-the-solar-energy-boom-now-its-in-limbo/

August 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Lightning Strikes in an Arctic Gone Bizarro Some rather peculiar weather over the weekend struck 300 miles from the North Pole. Here’s why that may be the new normal. https://www.wired.com/story/why-lightning-strikes-in-an-arctic-gone-bizarro/

August 13, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Biomechanical Perfection of Simone Biles in Flight Behold the triple double: The gymnast’s precise control of her body as she moves through space sets her apart. Add tremendous strength and speed, and you’ve got a champion. https://www.wired.com/story/the-biomechanical-perfection-of-simone-biles-triple-double/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Cure for Ebola, A Home-Speaker Cyberattack, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ebola-cure-trial-hack-home-speaker-defcon/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Twisty Physics of Simone Biles’ Historic Triple-Double The star gymnast appears to defy physics in her epic tumbling pass. Here’s how she managed to jump, twist, and flip her way into sports legend. https://www.wired.com/story/the-twisty-physics-of-simone-biles-historic-triple-double/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Ebola Is Now Curable. Here’s How the New Treatments Work Officials cut short a clinical trial in the Democratic Republic of Congo after two treatments appear to greatly increase patients’ survival rates. https://www.wired.com/story/ebola-is-now-curable-heres-how-the-new-treatments-work/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore A Newfound Neuron Might Help Keep the Brain’s Cells in Sync The discovery of a clock-like cell in mouse brains adds a new twist to the debate over how information travels across neurons. https://www.wired.com/story/a-newfound-neuron-might-help-keep-the-brains-cells-in-sync/

August 12, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Photographer Made a Working Replica of NASA’s Moon Camera Cole Rise sold a startup, designed the first Instagram logo, and became obsessed with creating a copy of the Apollo 11 camera. https://www.wired.com/story/a-photographer-made-a-working-replica-of-nasas-moon-camera/

August 11, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Fractal Patterns Offer Clues to the Universe’s Origin A new look at a ubiquitous phenomenon has uncovered unexpected fractal behavior that could help explain the birth of the universe and the arrow of time. https://www.wired.com/story/fractal-patterns-offer-clues-universes-origin/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why These Praying Mantises Are Wearing Itty-Bitty 3D Glasses How do mantises see in 3D? Researchers find out by gluing tiny 3D glasses to a mantis’ face and showing the insect movies. https://www.wired.com/story/why-these-praying-mantises-are-wearing-itty-bitty-3d-glasses/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Falling Magnets in Stranger Things Season 3 Can magnets really just demagnetize suddenly and fall off a fridge? Yes—sort of, though the show doesn’t quite nail it. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-falling-magnets-in-stranger-things-season-3/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Soccer Is Getting Slower and More Fair—and That’s a Problem Video replay tech, known as VAR, is taking over soccer. Now the data is in: It’s changing the game in controversial ways, and fans aren’t totally sold. https://www.wired.com/story/video-review-is-changing-soccer-and-no-one-seems-to-want-it/

August 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Sorry, But We Can’t Just Hack Our Way Out of Climate Doom It’s clear that we have to suck carbon out of the atmosphere to avoid catastrophic warming. That alone won’t fix the mess we’ve made. https://www.wired.com/story/ipcc-report-carbon-capture/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Devastating Climate Change Report, a Phone Bug Returns, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-ipcc-avaya-desk-phone-bug/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr Can Help Solve Our Looming Food Crisis—Here’s How There’s not enough land to feed everyone on Earth without ruining the climate, a new IPCC report shows. Gene-edited crops could help reduce agriculture’s footprint. https://www.wired.com/story/gene-editing-food-climate-change/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Surprisingly Cozy Truths of Sleeping in Space Sleeping astronauts look like strapped-in zombies surrounded by whirring machines and always-on lights. But for Mike Massimino, it might have been the best sleep of his life. https://www.wired.com/story/sleeping-in-space/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon New IPCC Report Shows How Our Abuse of Land Drives Climate Change Cutting out fossil fuels, which the IPCC has called for repeatedly, isn’t enough—we as a species need to fundamentally transform our relationship with the land. https://www.wired.com/story/ipcc-land-report/

August 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We’re Eating This Planet to Death A new IPCC report is clear: If we can’t figure out how to feed our species more sustainably, climate change will accelerate and make it harder to grow food. https://www.wired.com/story/ipcc-land-report-food/

August 7, 2019 | Author: Matt LasloMatt Laslo The CDC Could Totally Study Gun Violence—It Just Needs Money Congress clarified last year that the CDC can use its budget for gun research, after decades of effectively banning it. But Democrats are still fighting to get actual funding approved. https://www.wired.com/story/cdc-gun-violence-research-money/

August 7, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Fact-Check the Physics of Captain America Hammering Thanos Sure, Captain America and Thanos (and their superpowers) break some laws of physics. But let’s see if they obey the momentum principle in Avengers: Endgame. https://www.wired.com/story/fact-check-the-physics-of-captain-america-hammering-thanos/

August 7, 2019 | Author: Katherine EbanKatherine Eban 8 Ways Overseas Drug Manufacturers Dupe the FDA From taking inspectors hostage to making stuff up, generic drug makers can try to look like they were following the regulations while actually subverting them. https://www.wired.com/story/8-ways-overseas-drug-manufacturers-dupe-fda/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The Gap in State Gun Laws, Apple Card Is Sorta Here, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/state-gun-laws-mass-shootings-apple-card/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Looser a State’s Gun Laws, the More Mass Shootings It Has Researchers have begun to see a trend: The rate of mass shootings is consistently much higher for places with fewer restrictions on guns. https://www.wired.com/story/the-looser-a-states-gun-laws-the-more-mass-shootings-it-has/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Get to Know Maxwell’s Equations—You’re Using Them Right Now James Clerk Maxwell’s equations are a big deal in physics, explaining the fundamentals of electricity and magnetism. Here’s the gist of how they work. https://www.wired.com/story/get-to-know-maxwells-equationsyoure-using-them-right-now/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How to Reduce Gun Violence: Ask Some Scientists Researchers have clear policy suggestions on how to see fewer gun deaths. They’d have many more, if they weren’t starved for funding and data. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-reduce-gun-violence-ask-some-scientists/

August 6, 2019 | Author: Carolyn Beeler, PRI’s The WorldCarolyn Beeler, PRI’s The World A Submarine Goes Under a Failing Glacier to Gauge Rising Seas Scientists believe Antarctica’s massive Thwaites Glacier is teetering on the brink of collapse, though just how fast that could happen remains an open question. https://www.wired.com/story/submarine-under-thwaites-glacier-gauge-rising-seas/

August 5, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Water Bears Crash Onto the Moon, Cloudflare Ditches 8Chan, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tardigrades-moon-space-water-bear-lunar-lander-cloudflare-8chan-el-paso/

August 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Crashed Israeli Lunar Lander Spilled Tardigrades on the Moon The Beresheet lunar lander carried thousands of books, DNA samples, and a few thousand water bears to the moon. But did any of it survive the crash? https://www.wired.com/story/a-crashed-israeli-lunar-lander-spilled-tardigrades-on-the-moon/

August 4, 2019 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich A Decades-Old Computer Science Puzzle Was Solved in Two Pages With a stunningly simple proof, a researcher has finally cracked the sensitivity conjecture, “one of the most frustrating and embarrassing open problems.” https://www.wired.com/story/a-decades-old-computer-science-puzzle-was-solved-in-two-pages/

August 2, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Voracious Vineyard-Killer, Apple’s Siri Snoopers, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-siri-listening-spotted-lanterfly-vineyards-todays-news/

August 2, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Americans Trust Scientists, Until Politics Gets in the Way A report from Pew Research Center shows that Americans have great confidence in scientists—except for Republicans when the issue is the environment. https://www.wired.com/story/americans-trust-scientists-until-politics-gets-in-the-way/

August 2, 2019 | Author: Henry FarrellHenry Farrell Don’t Ask How to Pay for Climate Change. Ask Who Opinion: Asking presidential candidates how they’ll pay for the cost of climate change is naive. We should be asking, “Who is going to pay?” and “How much?” https://www.wired.com/story/dont-ask-how-to-pay-for-climate-change-ask-who/

August 2, 2019 | Author: Claire Marie PorterClaire Marie Porter This Voracious, Unstoppable Bug Is Killing Off Vineyards Some Pennsylvania wine growers have reported losing 90 percent of their grapes due to damage from the invasive spotted lanternfly. https://www.wired.com/story/this-voracious-unstoppable-bug-is-killing-off-vineyards/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Poisoned Air in Paris, Intel’s New Chips, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/intel-ice-lake-chip-notre-dame-cathedral-paris-lead-poisoning/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How a 6,000-Year-Old Dog Cancer Spread Around the World A massive collection of dog tumor samples is revealing the secrets of a contagious, parasite-like cancer that could help explain human cancers too. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-6000-year-old-dog-cancer-spread-around-the-world/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Feargus O’SullivanFeargus O’Sullivan The Notre Dame Fire Spread Toxic Lead Dust Over Paris The fire at the cathedral in April appears to have caused widespread lead dust contamination, prompting a lawsuit against the city. https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-spread-toxic-lead-dust-over-paris/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Icy Waterfalls Are Roaring as a Heat Wave Sizzles Greenland Glaciologists are rappelling into a glacial plumbing system to probe the effects of climate change on the melting of Greenland’s ice sheet. https://www.wired.com/story/icy-waterfalls-are-roaring-as-a-heat-wave-sizzles-greenland/

August 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Finally, a Robot That Moves Kind of Like a Tongue Octopus arms and elephant trunks and human tongues move in a fascinating way, which has now inspired a fascinating new kind of robot. https://www.wired.com/story/soft-robotics-actuator/

July 31, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Jakarta’s Doomed Sea Wall, Russia Takes Aim at 2020, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/russia-2020-election-jakarta-sinking-sea-wall/

July 31, 2019 | Author: Tom Simonite, Gregory BarberTom Simonite and Gregory Barber Alphabet’s AI Might Be Able to Predict Kidney Disease In a study involving 700,000 VA patients, an algorithm from DeepMind predicted 90% of cases of acute kidney injury up to 48 hours before it occurred. https://www.wired.com/story/alphabets-ai-predict-kidney-disease/

July 31, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Let’s Break Down the Physics of a Wickedly Curving Baseball An epic pitch by Oliver Drake of the Tampa Bay Rays appears to defy physics. It doesn’t, of course—and here’s how you can model it yourself. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-break-down-the-physics-of-a-wickedly-curving-baseball/

July 31, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Jakarta’s Giant Seawall Is Useless if the City Keeps Sinking If Indonesia’s capital can’t find a way to hydrate its people without overexploiting groundwater, it’ll keep sinking, pulling that new seawall down with it. https://www.wired.com/story/jakarta-giant-sea-wall/

July 30, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The World Health Organization Says No More Gene-Edited Babies The public health authority is asking countries to put a stop to any Crispr experiments that would lead to the birth of altered humans. https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-health-organization-says-no-more-gene-edited-babies/

July 30, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison PrEP Made HIV Prevention Easier—and It’s Getting Even Simpler The drug Truvada, or PrEP, has helped drastically reduce new HIV infections, but taking a daily pill can be onerous. Now there might be other options. https://www.wired.com/story/prep-made-hiv-prevention-easier-and-its-getting-even-simpler/

July 30, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain An Electric Pickup Truck Really Could Pull a Freight Train—Here’s How Ford showed off an all-electric F-150 pickup truck towing a freight train full of more F-150s. The stunt relies heavily on one force to work: friction. https://www.wired.com/story/electric-ford-f150-pulls-a-train-friction-physics/

July 29, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Made a Blazing Hot Plasma Doughnut to Study Solar Wind Temperatures inside the Big Red Ball apparatus reached more than 150,000 degrees. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-made-a-blazing-hot-plasma-doughnut-to-study-solar-wind/

July 29, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Bizarre, Peaty Science of Arctic Wildfires Peat is the organic material that gives Scotch its characteristic taste. But it’s also a potent fuel that’s powering unprecedented Arctic wildfires. https://www.wired.com/story/the-bizarre-peaty-science-of-arctic-wildfires/

July 28, 2019 | Author: Philip BallPhilip Ball Quantum Darwinism Could Explain What Makes Reality Real Some physicists believe that our experience of the universe is just a big game of subatomic survival of the fittest. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-darwinism-could-be-what-makes-reality-real/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Great Stunt, Spider-Man! Now Let’s Fine-Tune the Physics This rehearsal clip is amazing, but something in the hero’s motion might set your Spidey senses tingling. https://www.wired.com/story/spider-man-stunt-physics-tom-holland-projectile-motion/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb SpaceX’s Starship Rocket Test, Equifax Owes You, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-rocket-test-starhopper-equifax-settlement-money/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Why Big Banks Could Soon Jump on the Quantum Bandwagon If you’re trying to model an uncertain economic future, consider using a machine that runs on probability. https://www.wired.com/story/why-big-banks-could-soon-jump-on-the-quantum-bandwagon-financial-modeling/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientists Can Finally Build Feedback Circuits in Cells The circuitry could act as control mechanisms in safe, smart cells programmed to kill tumors and treat brain injuries. https://www.wired.com/story/feedback-circuits-in-cells/

July 26, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Just Unleashed Its Starship Rocket for the First Time The prototype, called Starhopper, hovered in the air for a few moments. Next stop: space. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-starhopper-starship-rocket-first-test-flight/

July 25, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Jill Tarter Swears She’d Tell Us If She’d Seen an Alien In a special extraterrestrial edition of WIRED’s Tech Support series, the legendary astronomer takes questions from Twitter. https://www.wired.com/story/seti-astronomer-jill-tarter-swears-shed-tell-us-if-shed-seen-an-alien/

July 25, 2019 | Author: Charles GraeberCharles Graeber How Scientists Built a ‘Living Drug’ to Beat Cancer Researchers didn’t know if it would work, but they had little to lose when they tried a new drug—a living cell reprogrammed to recognize and kill leukemia—on a dying 6-year-old. https://www.wired.com/story/how-scientists-built-living-drug-to-beat-cancer/

July 24, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Scientists Are Getting Better at Predicting Killer Heat Waves And not a moment too soon. As the world warms, they’re becoming a lot more common. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-are-getting-better-at-predicting-killer-heat-waves/

July 23, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Many Animals Can’t Adapt Fast Enough to Climate Change In sifting through 10,000 studies, researchers find some species seem to be able to cope with global warming, but are still running out of time. https://www.wired.com/story/many-animals-arent-adapting-fast-enough-to-survive-climate-change/

July 22, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Bringing Clarity to the Murky World of Sports Supplements Americans gorge themselves on vitamins and protein powders, hoping for personal transformation. But what does the science say? https://www.wired.com/story/wild-unregulated-world-sports-supplements/

July 21, 2019 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch An Alien-Hunting Tech Mogul May Help Solve a Space Mystery Russian billionaire Yuri Milner has invested a fortune to help SETI find the source of cosmic flashes that emit the energy of 500 million suns. https://www.wired.com/story/alien-hunting-russian-billionaire-fast-radio-bursts/

July 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Sea Is Consuming Jakarta, and Its People Aren’t Insured What happens when your city is sinking and flooding and you don’t have insurance? https://www.wired.com/story/jakarta-insurance/

July 18, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore Where Do Supermassive Black Holes Come From? Born shortly after the Big Bang, these cosmic monsters have perplexed astronomers for years. A new study may shed light on their origins. https://www.wired.com/story/where-do-supermassive-black-holes-come-from/

July 18, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Long Would It Take to Bicycle to the Moon? To follow in Apollo 11’s footsteps, all you need is a space bike, 240,000 miles of cable, and a whole lot of sandwiches. https://www.wired.com/story/how-long-would-it-take-to-bicycle-to-the-moon/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Now We Know How the Zombie Ant Gets Its Bite Scientists solve part of the mystery of how a murderous fungus orders an ant to bite onto a twig, sealing its fate. https://www.wired.com/story/now-we-know-how-the-zombie-ant-gets-its-bite/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Elon’s Brain Computer, Big Tech’s Big Day in Congress, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-brain-computer-neurolink-congress-apple-facebook-google/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Change Is Very Real. But So Much of It Is Uncertain Researchers bring new clarity to a key measure of climate change, which could help the fight to save our planet. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-very-real-but-so-much-of-it-is-uncertain/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Here’s How Elon Musk Plans to Stitch a Computer into Your Brain To hear Musk tell it, Neuralink’s hardware is either a state-of-the-art tool for understanding the brain, a clinical advance for people with neurological disorders, or the next step in human evolution https://www.wired.com/story/heres-how-elon-musk-plans-to-stitch-a-computer-into-your-brain/

July 17, 2019 | Author: Dov FoxDov Fox What Happens When Reproductive Tech Like IVF Goes Awry? Opinion: Freezers fail. Samples are mislabeled. Embryos get switched. But a lack of regulation leaves those harmed by such negligence without clear recourse. https://www.wired.com/story/when-ivf-goes-awry/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Not Everyone on 23andMe Will Get the Latest Gene Chip Updates Science gets better and better at decoding people’s genomes … which might be bad news for people who bought into 23andMe too early. https://www.wired.com/story/not-everyone-on-23andme-will-get-the-latest-gene-chip-updates/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus An Astronaut’s Guide to Eating in Space Try the turkey tetrazzini, skip the ice cream, and don’t miss your chance to steal the commander’s shrimp cocktail. https://www.wired.com/story/an-astronauts-guide-to-eating-in-space/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Meghan HerbstMeghan Herbst A WIRED Booklover’s Guide to the Moon We sifted through dozens of new books released in honor of the 50th anniversary of Apollo 11. Here are the giant leaps for lunar literature. https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-readers-guide-moon/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Adrienne SoAdrienne So The Best Gear to Take to the Moon You’re embarking on the craziest 76-hour journey of your life. What on earth (literally) do you bring? https://www.wired.com/gallery/apollo-11-best-gear-moon/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Anna Goldwater AlexanderAnna Goldwater Alexander The World Watched Apollo 11 Unfold—Together From the beaches of Florida and department store TVs to mission control and Parisian living rooms, everyone witnessed the mission’s launch and landing. https://www.wired.com/story/world-watched-apollo-11-moon-photos/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Alex DaviesAlex Davies Why ‘Moon Shot’ Has No Place in the 21st Century Today’s challenges are vast and nebulous—and demand a different kind of ambition and approach. We need a new name for them. https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-moonshot-21st-century/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Lunar Mysteries That Science Still Needs to Solve What scientists most want to know about our closest planetary neighbor. https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-lunar-mysteries-moon-science/

July 16, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Spaceflight and Spirituality, a Complicated Relationship The earliest days of American human spaceflight were dominated by white Christian protestants. Does religion have a place in the future of space exploration? https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-spaceflight-spirituality-complicated-relationship/

July 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Leaky Component Caused the SpaceX Crew Dragon Explosion The company still hopes to send two astronauts to the International Space Station this year but says the goal will be “increasingly difficult” to reach. https://www.wired.com/story/a-leaky-component-caused-the-spacex-crew-dragon-explosion/

July 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Headed to Mars? Pack Some Aerogel—You Know, for Terraforming Armed with the right materials, Martian colonizers could unlock frozen carbon dioxide beneath its surface, making the Red Planet warm enough to support life. https://www.wired.com/story/headed-to-mars-pack-some-aerogelyou-know-for-terraforming/

July 15, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Robots Alone Can’t Solve Amazon’s Labor Woes This Prime Day, some Amazon workers are striking. But the company can’t just automate its labor problems away. https://www.wired.com/story/robots-alone-cant-solve-amazons-labor-woes/

July 14, 2019 | Author: KC ColeKC Cole The Simple Idea Behind Einstein’s Greatest Discoveries Einstein’s theory of gravity and modern particle physics both rely on the idea of symmetry. But physicists are now wondering if symmetry has much more to offer. https://www.wired.com/story/the-simple-idea-behind-einsteins-greatest-discoveries/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Tropical Storm Barry Pits New Orleans Against Water—Again In the forever war between the Big Easy and the deluge, engineering keeps coming up short. Climate change is making it worse. https://www.wired.com/story/tropical-storm-barry-pits-new-orleans-against-water-again/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb How Dogs Help Cancer Research, an Amazon Email Scam, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-phishing-scam-prime-day-dogs-cancer-cure-facebook-ftc/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How Elite Tennis Players Crank Out Serves at 150 MPH Serve speeds have been climbing for decades—topping out at 163.7 mph. Here’s how players store all that energy in their bodies to release it in a coordinated strike. https://www.wired.com/story/how-elite-tennis-players-crank-out-serves-at-150-mph/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Rocky KistnerRocky Kistner Gulf Fisheries Are Under Siege—Now Comes Tropical Storm Barry Surges of polluted water have decimated crab, oyster, and shrimp populations and killed hundreds of dolphins. To fishermen, Tropical Storm Barry is very bad news. https://www.wired.com/story/gulf-fisheries-are-under-siege-now-comes-tropical-storm-barry/

July 12, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Why Dogs Now Play a Big Role in Human Cancer Research There’s a strong chance your aging dog will get cancer—but your pupper could also help humans survive it. https://www.wired.com/story/why-dogs-now-play-a-big-role-in-human-cancer-research/

July 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus New Designs Could Boost Solar Cells Beyond Their Limits A material that effectively splits a photon in two is one way scientists are trying to increase solar cells’ efficiency beyond what they’d thought possible. https://www.wired.com/story/new-designs-could-boost-solar-cells-beyond-their-limits/

July 11, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Strange Saga of the Butt Plug Turned Research Device How one scientist started with a butt plug from Amazon and ended up inventing an “anal pneumatic base” to measure orgasms. https://www.wired.com/story/the-strange-saga-of-the-butt-plug-turned-research-device/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Rocket-Launching Plane, Nintendo’s New Switch, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-orbit-rocket-plane-nintendo-switch-lite/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Virgin Orbit Just Dropped a Rocket From a Boeing 747 Richard Branson’s air-launch system is getting very close to opening for business after successfully completing one of its last big tests. https://www.wired.com/story/virgin-orbit-just-dropped-a-rocket-from-a-boeing-747/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Vanessa ChangVanessa Chang How Phone Taps and Swipes Train Us to Be Better Consumers Opinion: Smartphone interfaces train our motions, closing the gap between our bodies and our virtual selves. But what does that mean when our movements are choreographed by corporate interests? https://www.wired.com/story/phone-interface-trains-us-to-be-consumers/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Awesome Bowling Robot Is Surely Fake. Here’s How to Tell The viral video of BowlBot 5000 throwing a strike inspires great physics questions, even if robots aren’t yet coming for our bowling alleys. https://www.wired.com/story/the-awesome-bowling-robot-is-surely-fake-heres-how-to-tell/

July 10, 2019 | Author: Julissa TreviñoJulissa Treviño Little Plastic ‘Nurdles’ Are Flooding Beaches and Waterways These lentil-sized pellets are used to make nearly all plastic goods. But they often escape and end up polluting oceans and coastal communities. https://www.wired.com/story/little-plastic-nurdles-are-flooding-beaches-and-waterways/

July 9, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Should You Wear White or Black on Hot Days? Here’s the Data Quick experiments can help you answer the eternal question of whether to wear black or white on hot summer days. Turns out, it’s complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/should-you-wear-white-or-black-on-hot-days-heres-the-data/

July 9, 2019 | Author: Fred PearceFred Pearce Trees Emit a Surprisingly Large Amount of Methane Figuring out trees’ net emissions is becoming an urgent priority as countries and companies adopt tree-planting programs to offset their carbon footprints. https://www.wired.com/story/trees-emit-a-surprisingly-large-amount-of-methane/

July 9, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Real Challenge for the Green New Deal Isn’t Politics Generating clean energy is easy. Getting the transmission lines to pipe it to cities is the hard part. https://www.wired.com/story/real-challenge-green-new-deal-isnt-politics/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Deadly Tick Virus, Extreme Seasonal Weirdness, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/lonestar-tick-bourbon-virus-waze-car-crash-avoidance/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Why We See the Colors of Faces Differently Than Other Things Remember the Dress? That viral image revealed some of the oddness of color vision. Now scientists are finding more quirks in how people see faces. https://www.wired.com/story/why-we-see-the-colors-of-faces-differently-than-other-things/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Zak JasonZak Jason A Global Pollution Observatory Hunts for Hidden Killers The first worldwide effort to measure all forms of pollution is calculating staggering numbers on its human toll. https://www.wired.com/story/a-global-pollution-observatory-hunts-for-hidden-killers/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers This Summer’s Weird Weather Is the Death of Predictability Extreme heat, hailstorms, and monstrous floods have made for an intense summer. But there’s still more seasonal strangeness to come. https://www.wired.com/story/this-summers-weird-weather-is-the-death-of-predictability/

July 8, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Meat-Allergy Tick Also Carries a Mystery Killer Virus A tick best known for making people allergic to red meat can also infect its victims with the deadly Bourbon virus. https://www.wired.com/story/the-meat-allergy-tick-also-carries-a-mystery-killer-virus/

July 5, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore Magnetic Materials Help Explain How Arctic Ice Melts The discovery of an unlikely relationship between melting sea ice and magnets could help scientists produce better models of the global climate. https://www.wired.com/story/magnetic-materials-help-explain-how-arctic-ice-melts/

July 5, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Forget the Moon—We Should Go to Jupiter’s Idyllic Europa NASA’s Europa mission is struggling, but scientists are keeping the dream alive with exotic approaches to sampling that moon and its mysterious ocean. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-the-moon-we-should-go-to-jupiters-idyllic-europa/

July 4, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams A Drone, a $12,000 Lens, and the Magic of a Total Solar Eclipse Eclipse chasers plan for months for the jaw-dropping spectacle of a total solar eclipse. But when totality hits, even the ultra-prepared can end up scrambling. https://www.wired.com/story/south-america-total-solar-eclipse-2019/

July 4, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Colorful Science of Why Fireworks Look Bad on TV Even the best TVs fall short of capturing all the colors in fireworks that humans can perceive. https://www.wired.com/story/the-colorful-science-of-why-fireworks-look-bad-on-tv/

July 4, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon An Itty-Bitty Robot That Lifts Off Like a Sci-Fi Spaceship Ion propulsion is a fantastical new way to power robots by accelerating ions instead of burning fuel or spinning rotors. https://www.wired.com/story/ion-robot/

July 3, 2019 | Author: Meredith ForeMeredith Fore What Makes a Good Cooler (According to Physics)? Coolers don’t keep “coldness” in, they keep heat out. How effectively depends on three key factors: insulation, air, and ice. https://www.wired.com/story/what-makes-good-cooler-from-physics-perspective/

July 3, 2019 | Author: Safi BahcallSafi Bahcall NASA Needs to Out-Crazy Elon Musk Opinion: The once-revolutionary space agency is being upstaged by unapologetic capitalists. Here’s how it can reclaim its relevance. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-needs-to-out-crazy-elon-musk/

July 3, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill How Extreme Heat Overwhelms Your Body and Becomes Deadly Europe’s record-breaking heat wave serves as a warning of just how dangerous high temperatures can be. https://www.wired.com/story/how-extreme-heat-overwhelms-your-body-and-becomes-deadly/

July 2, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Jellyfish Robot Is Much More Than Just a Good Swimmer At less than a quarter inch across, the magnetically activated robot can manipulate water flow to manipulate objects. https://www.wired.com/story/this-jellyfish-robot-is-much-more-than-just-a-good-swimmer/

July 2, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain SpaceX Recovered Its First Rocket Fairing. Let’s Crunch the Numbers! SpaceX recovered its first fairing last week after a Falcon Heavy launch. Here’s how to estimate the challenge faced by Ms. Tree, the retrieval boat. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-recovered-its-first-rocket-fairing-lets-crunch-the-numbers/

July 1, 2019 | Author: Eric AdamsEric Adams The Blazing Science of This Year’s Total Solar Eclipse Eclipse-chasing scientists are gathered in South America for the total solar eclipse on July 2. Here’s what they’re hoping to see. https://www.wired.com/story/the-blazing-science-of-this-years-total-solar-eclipse/

July 1, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen New Analysis Techniques Unearth a Trove of Unusual Minerals Special x-rays mean that ever-smaller slivers of material can be scanned without destroying the surrounding rock. https://www.wired.com/story/geologists-discover-specks-new-minerals-earths-extremes/

July 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Remote Lakes Could Help Unravel the Mysteries of Microplastic The Experimental Lakes Area is a one-of-a-kind platform for potentially testing how omnipresent microplastics are stressing ecosystems. https://www.wired.com/story/remote-lakes-microplastic/

June 30, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover A ‘Sonic Black Hole’ Could Help Solve a Cosmic Paradox If a sound-trapping fluid on Earth really does behave like a black hole, its behavior could offer insight into the famous information paradox. https://www.wired.com/story/a-sonic-black-hole-could-help-solve-a-cosmic-paradox/

June 28, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Man Found Guilty in a Murder Mystery Cracked By Cousins’ DNA The trial of William Earl Talbott II hinged on a lead from a genealogy site. The verdict will shape the future of crime-fighting and genetic privacy. https://www.wired.com/story/man-found-guilty-in-a-murder-mystery-cracked-by-cousins-dna/

June 28, 2019 | Author: Kafui DzirasaKafui Dzirasa A New Approach to Treat Mental Illness: Electrical Engineering Opinion: An electrical device has the potential to treat Alzheimer’s, PTSD, and other brain disorders. But do the risks outweigh the potential? https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-approach-to-treat-mental-illness-electrical-engineering/

June 28, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Want Your Kid to Play Pro Soccer? Sign Her Up for Basketball Elite athletes are specializing in their sports earlier and earlier, but some sports medicine experts say that won’t help you make it to the pros. https://www.wired.com/story/want-your-kid-to-play-pro-soccer-sign-her-up-for-basketball/

June 28, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Senators Try—Again—to Solve the Nuclear Waste Debacle A bipartisan group is trying to find a place, or perhaps many places, to bury nuclear waste by making it harder for everyone to say no. https://www.wired.com/story/senators-tryagainto-solve-the-nuclear-waste-debacle/

June 27, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Will Send a Helicopter to Hunt for Life on Saturn’s Biggest Moon The Dragonfly mission will spend two years flying around the surface of Titan, studying the moon’s composition and searching for signs of life. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-will-send-a-helicopter-to-hunt-for-life-on-saturns-moon-titan/

June 27, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain That Viral ‘Gyro Drop’ Ride Was Fake. Here’s How You Can Tell A popular video about an amusement park ride with a crazy drop turned out to be fake. This physics analysis spells it out. https://www.wired.com/story/that-viral-gyro-drop-ride-was-fake-heres-how-you-can-tell/

June 27, 2019 | Author: Jim RobbinsJim Robbins Desalination Is Booming as Cities Run out of Water In California alone there are 11 desalination plants, with 10 more proposed. But there are big downsides to making seawater drinkable. https://www.wired.com/story/desalination-is-booming-as-cities-run-out-of-water/

June 27, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The Health Effects of Wildfire Smoke May Last a Lifetime Emerging research suggests exposure to wildfire smoke may alter the immune system for years. https://www.wired.com/story/the-health-effects-of-wildfire-smoke-may-last-a-lifetime/

June 26, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Could Possibly Be Cooler Than RoboBee? RoboBee X-Wing The new RoboBee is the lightest aerial vehicle to manage sustained untethered flight. One day that could make it ideal for navigating tight, sensitive spaces. https://www.wired.com/story/robobee-x-wing/

June 26, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Debates Will Be About Climate—Disguised as Other Issues Every issue the presidential hopefuls will debate this week is deeply tied to climate change. The question is what the candidates will do about it. https://www.wired.com/story/democratic-debates-climate-change-election-2020/

June 25, 2019 | Author: Carolyn Beeler, PRI’s The WorldCarolyn Beeler, PRI’s The World Fitted With Sensors, Antarctic Seals Track Water Temperatures Scientists have outfitted an army of Antarctic pinnipeds with trackers to monitor warming oceans. https://www.wired.com/story/seals-sensors-antarctica-tracking-water-temperatures/

June 25, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Physics Tricks to Make Steph Curry’s Golf Show More Extreme Holey Moley forces mini-golfers to surmount an obstacle course to win. But the options for physics-inspired golf stunts are endless—here are a few ideas. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-tricks-to-make-steph-curry-holey-moley-golf-show-more-extreme/

June 25, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles A New Kind of Space Camp Teaches the Art of Martian Medicine Enrollees—mainly engineers and health workers—pretend to live on Mars, wear spacesuits, and ride in ATVs as medical disasters crop up around them. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-kind-of-space-camp-teaches-the-art-of-martian-medicine/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Is Mars’ Methane Spike a Sign of Life? Here’s How We’ll Know The Curiosity rover detected a high concentration of methane on the red planet. Two Mars orbiters may soon clarify what that sighting really means. https://www.wired.com/story/is-marss-methane-spike-a-sign-of-life-heres-how-well-know/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Space X’s Launch Tonight, An Illegal Airbnb Empire, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launch-falcon-heavy-airbnb-new-york-todays-news/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Watch SpaceX Launch a Solar Sail the Size of a Boxing Ring A Falcon Heavy rocket is slated to carry the LightSail2 into orbit tonight. It is the most ambitious solar sail yet. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-is-launching-a-solar-sail-the-size-of-a-boxing-ring/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Stephen WittStephen Witt Apollo 11: Mission Out of Control The inside story of how Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin struggled to touch down on the moon, while their guidance computer kept crashing. Again and again. https://www.wired.com/story/apollo-11-mission-out-of-control/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Amanda SchafferAmanda Schaffer Fear, Misinformation, and Measles Spread in Brooklyn Measles is back, health care workers are racing to contain it, and parents of vulnerable children are frantic. How a fever spread in a tight-knit community. https://www.wired.com/story/fear-misinformation-measles-spread-in-brooklyn/

June 24, 2019 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson We Need a Data-Rich Picture of What’s Killing the Planet If we’re going to save Earth, we need a clear picture of all the forces that are destroying it. And that means capturing more data. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-data-rich-picture-climate-change/

June 23, 2019 | Author: Anil AnanthaswamyAnil Ananthaswamy Quantum Computers Could Be True Randomness Generators Pure, verifiable randomness is essential to encryption yet hard to come by. Quantum computers could be the answer. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-computers-could-be-true-randomness-generators/

June 21, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Right Ball for Playing Catch While Skydiving You and a buddy are plummeting through the clouds. Perfect time for a game of catch—if you have the exact right type of ball. https://www.wired.com/story/the-right-ball-for-playing-catch-while-skydiving/

June 21, 2019 | Author: David LangDavid Lang Planet-Saving Robots? Robert Downey Jr. Is on to Something Opinion: Go ahead, roll your eyes at his vague plans to “clean up the planet” with nanotech. I welcome these new conservation technologists. https://www.wired.com/story/planet-saving-robots-robert-downey-jr-is-on-to-something/

June 21, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Let’s Build a Global Skyscraper Network to Save the Planet A network of skyscrapers that communicate and trade their carbon emissions around the world could form the backbone of a climate change solution. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-build-a-global-skyscraper-network-to-save-the-planet/

June 21, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Argentina’s Blackout and the Storm-Battered Future of the Grid The countrywide blackout comes after a period of heavy rains, a reminder that the US electric grid itself isn’t ready for extreme weather either. https://www.wired.com/story/argentinas-blackout-and-the-storm-battered-future-of-the-grid/

June 20, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Deer DNA Starts Spilling Its Weird, Cancer-Fighting Secrets The Ruminant Genome Project just released the DNA of 44 species of the multi-stomached, headgear-bearing animals, revealing a host of biological curiosities. https://www.wired.com/story/wildebeest-okapi-giraffe-ibex-come-peruse-their-genomes/

June 20, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Hack the Uncertainty Principle to See an Ion Wiggle Heisenberg’s famous principle can’t be violated, but it can be gamed. A new study shows a way to measure particles with far more precision than before. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-hack-the-uncertainty-principle-to-see-an-ion-wiggle/

June 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Facebook Unleashes Software to Make Programming Robots Easy PyRobot could simplify the way researchers program their machines, and could even make it easier for non-robotics types to jump into the field. https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-unleashes-software-to-make-programming-robots-easy/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Cold War Spy Photos Show How Fast Himalayan Glaciers Are Melting By turning declassified images into a 3D model, scientists find that the mountain range’s glaciers are melting twice as fast as before 2000. https://www.wired.com/story/cold-war-spy-photos-show-how-fast-himalaya-glaciers-are-melting/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Robot Fish Powers Itself With Fake Blood A new robot lionfish uses a rudimentary vasculature and “blood” to both energize itself and hydraulically power its fins. https://www.wired.com/story/this-robot-fish-powers-itself-with-fake-blood/

June 19, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Hospitals Aren’t Ready for a Mass Casualty Wildfire With wildfires intensifying, the number of burn victims is likely to rise. But hospitals have been losing their burn treatment expertise, leaving the country unprepared. https://www.wired.com/story/hospitals-arent-ready-for-a-mass-casualty-wildfire/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Weather Forecasts Will Soon Use Weird, Bendy GPS Signals SpaceX will soon launch weather-prediction satellites that track how GPS signals bend as they travel through the atmosphere. https://www.wired.com/story/weather-satellites-gps-radio-occultation/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The Midwest’s Farms Face an Intense, Crop-Killing Future The flooding that struck the Midwest is just one way climate change is causing plants to fail, complicating life for the region’s growers. https://www.wired.com/story/midwest-farms-face-an-intense-crop-killing-future/

June 18, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Actually Flying Around in an Iron Man Suit In the first episode of Savage Builds, Adam Savage tries to build and control an Iron Man flying suit. But he didn’t quite figure out the controls. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-actually-flying-around-in-an-iron-man-suit/

June 17, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Lawyers in a Murder Trial Clash Over a DNA Forensics Method The first trial in which genetic genealogy helped identify a suspect is now underway, and the two sides are sparring over the limits of the new technique. https://www.wired.com/story/lawyers-in-a-murder-trial-clash-over-a-dna-forensics-method/

June 17, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Neptune Is a Windy, Chilly, and Baffling Planet. Let’s Go! Scientists are building a case for a mission to Neptune, an ice giant that’s only been visited by a spacecraft once. But the window to act is closing. https://www.wired.com/story/neptune-is-a-windy-chilly-and-baffling-planet-lets-go/

June 17, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni These Protein Picker-Uppers Keep Your Cells Clean and Healthy New drugs based on proteasomes could treat previously undruggable diseases. https://www.wired.com/story/protein-picker-uppers-keep-your-cells-clean-healthy/

June 16, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Cosmologists Clash Over the Beginning of the Universe What happened before the Big Bang? And what happened before that? Stephen Hawking’s answer—there was no beginning—is now the subject of intense debate. https://www.wired.com/story/cosmologists-clash-over-the-beginning-of-the-universe/

June 14, 2019 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson Remembering Gabriele Grunewald, Who Ran For Herself and Others Gabe Grunewald wanted to help scientists working to fight the rare cancers that strike so many of us. She died on Tuesday, at the age of 32. https://www.wired.com/story/remembering-gabriele-grunewald/

June 14, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Golf’s Longest Drives Are Creeping Up and Changing the Sport The average distance of PGA drives has been rising steadily due to changes in equipment and training. But it’s still almost impossible to hit 450 yards. https://www.wired.com/story/almost-impossible-golf/

June 14, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni YouTube Testimonials Lure Patients to Shady Stem-Cell Clinics Emotional videos, often paid for by clinics, are attracting desperate patients to unproven stem-cell treatments that can be dangerous—or even deadly. https://www.wired.com/story/youtube-testimonials-lure-patients-to-shady-stem-cell-clinics/

June 14, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Blame Utilities for Wildfires, But Blame Everyone Else Too California is built to burn—explosively. Given we can’t depopulate the entire state, what has made the wildfire problem so bad, and how do we fix it? https://www.wired.com/story/utilities-wildfires/

June 13, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb How Kevin Durant Got Hurt, Why Coffee May Soon Be Gone, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/kevin-durant-achilles-climate-change-fathers-day-gifts/

June 13, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Why Kevin Durant’s Achilles Tendon Was His Achilles’ Heel When the Golden State Warriors star limped off the court, his Achilles tendon had been pulled to the point of rupture. Here’s how that may have happened. https://www.wired.com/story/why-kevin-durants-achilles-tendon-was-his-achilles-heel/

June 13, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Estimate the Energy of an Utterly Massive Wind Turbine The Hornsea Wind Farm is expected to be the largest offshore wind farm in the world. Here’s how much energy is generated from one rotation of a turbine. https://www.wired.com/story/estimate-the-energy-of-an-utterly-massive-wind-turbine/

June 13, 2019 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson The Most Delicious Foods Will Fall Victim to Climate Change Author Amanda Little explains why high-nutrient, high-flavor crops are the most likely to suffer in a less predictable environment. https://www.wired.com/story/the-most-delicious-foods-will-fall-victim-to-climate-change/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Ancient Potheads, a Russian Troll Controversy, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-cannabis-weed-alphabet-russian-troll/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A New Fuel for Satellites Is So Safe It Won’t Blow Up Humans SpaceX’s next Falcon Heavy launch will carry a satellite that will test, for the first time, a “green” fuel that is even less toxic than caffeine. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-fuel-for-satellites-is-so-safe-it-wont-blow-up-humans/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Ancient Peoples Smoked the Chronic at Funerals A finding in western China suggests humans were seeking out high-octane weed for rituals 2,500 years ago. https://www.wired.com/story/ancient-cannabis/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Jon GertnerJon Gertner The Top Secret Cold War Project That Pulled Climate Science From the Ice A classified US nuke installation in Greenland was supposed to end with 600 missiles aimed at the USSR. Instead it opened the door to a huge breakthrough in climate research. https://www.wired.com/story/the-top-secret-cold-war-project-that-pulled-climate-science-from-the-ice/

June 12, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison These Sumptuous Images Give Deep Space Data an Old-World Look Eleanor Lutz is a biologist with a knack for producing rich data visualizations. She released her latest series, Atlas of Space, this month. https://www.wired.com/story/these-sumptuous-images-give-deep-space-data-an-old-world-look/

June 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Here’s What a $52 Million Ticket to the ISS Will Get You A tourist’s jaunt to the ISS is the most expensive camping trip possible, complete with sleeping bag and dehydrated food. But the views are out of this world. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-what-a-52-million-dollar-ticket-to-the-iss-will-get-you/

June 11, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Murder Trial Will Allow DNA Evidence From a Genealogy Site The trial, which hinges on a lead found using DNA on a genealogy site, will not address whether the new sleuthing method is legal, however. https://www.wired.com/story/a-murder-trial-will-allow-dna-evidence-from-a-genealogy-site/

June 11, 2019 | Author: Fred PearceFred Pearce More Scientists Now Think Geoengineering May Be Essential With carbon emissions soaring, plans to study and develop geoengineering technologies are gaining traction as a last resort. https://www.wired.com/story/more-scientists-now-think-geoengineering-may-be-essential/

June 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus New Space Telescopes Could Look Like Giant Beach Balls Inflatable balloon reflectors could peer into deep space, scanning for signs of water, at a fraction of the cost of a traditional telescope. https://www.wired.com/story/new-space-telescopes-could-look-like-giant-beach-balls/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The First Murder Case to Use Family Tree Forensics Goes to Trial A 32-year-old murder case has its first arrest after police turn to genetic genealogy. The technique’s legality is now getting scrutiny in the courtroom. https://www.wired.com/story/the-first-murder-case-to-use-family-tree-forensics-goes-to-trial/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Post-Apocalyptic Survival Skills: How to Measure Acceleration Before the internet or any electronics at all, people used a gadget called the Atwood machine. It might come in handy should modern society take a hit. https://www.wired.com/story/post-apocalyptic-survival-skills-how-to-measure-acceleration/

June 10, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Heady, Thorny Journey to Decriminalize Magic Mushrooms The movement to decriminalize psilocybin is progressing so quickly it’s even surprised psychedelics advocates. The potential complications, though, are plenty. https://www.wired.com/story/the-heady-thorny-journey-to-decriminalize-magic-mushrooms/

June 9, 2019 | Author: Philip BallPhilip Ball Physicists See a Quantum Leap, Halt It, and Reverse It An experiment observed quantum leaps as they happened, revealing that these speedy little jumps are in fact gradual, rather than instantaneous. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-see-a-quantum-leap-halt-it-and-reverse-it/

June 7, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb NASA Is Ready to Get Down to Space Business, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-iss-private-business-california-measles-fathers-day/

June 7, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus NASA Went to the Stock Exchange to Try to Sell the ISS The Trump administration is trying to turn the International Space Station into a business. It could learn from the first guy to try that: Ronald Reagan. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-went-to-the-stock-exchange-to-try-to-sell-the-iss/

June 7, 2019 | Author: Joanna PearlsteinJoanna Pearlstein California’s Vaccination Rate Slips as Medical Exemptions Rise The state tried to lift measles vaccination rates by blocking parents from opting out based on personal beliefs. But then medical exemptions started to rise. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-vaccination-rate-slips-as-medical-exemptions-rise/

June 6, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Monterey Bay Is a Natural Wonder—Poisoned With Microplastic At some depths, microplastic is swirling in Monterey Bay in concentrations greater than at the surface of the infamous Great Pacific Garbage Patch. https://www.wired.com/story/monterey-bay-microplastic/

June 6, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler What to Do About CO2? Try Stuffing It Into the Gulf of Mexico The gulf’s seabed could be an ideal place to bury Texas’ carbon emissions. The state is the sixth-highest emitter in the world, behind Germany. https://www.wired.com/story/what-to-do-about-co2-try-stuffing-it-into-the-gulf-of-mexico/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Lydia HorneLydia Horne Telemedicine as a Workaround to Abortion Regulations, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/telemedicine-as-a-workaround-to-abortion-regs-and-more-news/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Congress Is Debating—Again—Whether Genes Can Be Patented Critics worry that a new bill would overturn existing protections of DNA sequences and carve up the world’s genetic resources into commercial fiefdoms. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-is-debating-again-whether-genes-can-be-patented/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Telemedicine Makes It Safe to Get Abortion Drugs in the Mail Abortion over the internet can be an effective, practical alternative for women in areas where clinics are scarce. https://www.wired.com/story/telemedicine-makes-it-safe-to-get-abortion-drugs-in-the-mail/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Amazon Warehouse Where Humans and Machines Become One In an Amazon sorting center, a swarm of robots works alongside humans. Here’s what that says about Amazon—and the future of work. https://www.wired.com/story/amazon-warehouse-robots/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Mythical Form of Space Propulsion Finally Gets a Real Test Scientists have debated for decades whether the propulsion concept known as EmDrive is real or wishful thinking. A sensitive new tool may at last provide an answer. https://www.wired.com/story/a-mythical-form-of-space-propulsion-finally-gets-a-real-test/

June 5, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The WIRED Guide to Aliens Everything you need to know about SETI, the Drake equation, ’Oumuamua, and hot tubs. https://www.wired.com/story/wired-guide-aliens/

June 4, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison Companies Expect Climate Change to Cost Them $1 Trillion in 5 Years Many corporations see climate change posing a significant threat to their business within the decade, according to a new report. https://www.wired.com/story/companies-expect-climate-change-to-cost-them-one-trillion-dollars-in-5-years/

June 4, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Apple Watch Is Now the Control Center for Your Health Apple announced new health and fitness features for its wearable that make the Apple Watch uniquely powerful as a personal monitoring tool. https://www.wired.com/story/the-apple-watch-is-now-the-control-center-for-your-health/

June 4, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of the Millennium Falcon’s Jump to Hyperspace The faster-than-light travel in Star Wars involves some otherworldly acceleration. Here’s how to calculate the g-forces of a hyperspace jump. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-the-millennium-falcons-jump-to-hyperspace/

June 3, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Study Exposes the Health Risks of Gene-Editing Human Embryos Last year, a Chinese scientist tried to give two babies a mutation to protect them from HIV. But that mutation also seems to shave years off people’s lives. https://www.wired.com/story/a-study-exposes-the-health-risks-of-gene-editing-human-embryos/

June 3, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Best Way for a Mouse to Escape a Cat, According to Math A mouse is stuck swimming in a pool while a cat paces, ready to strike. Here’s how to calculate the mouse’s optimal strategy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-best-way-for-a-mouse-to-escape-a-cat-according-to-math/

June 3, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Tired: Eating Bugs. Wired: Eating Bug Meat Grown in a Lab According to a group of researchers, culturing insect cells could be easier and more efficient than culturing cow cells. https://www.wired.com/story/bug-meat-grown-in-a-lab/

June 2, 2019 | Author: Claudia DreifusClaudia Dreifus At 90, E. O. Wilson Still Thrives on Being a Scientific Provocateur Over six decades, the biologist (and workaholic) Edward O. Wilson has made huge contributions to science, often sparking controversies along the way. https://www.wired.com/story/at-90-e-o-wilson-thrives-on-being-a-scientific-provocateur/

June 1, 2019 | Author: Richard ConniffRichard Conniff An Illicit Chemical Is Again Jeopardizing the Ozone Layer An unwelcome spike in emissions from a long-banned chemical has been traced to Chinese factories, raising concerns about the ozone layer’s integrity. https://www.wired.com/story/an-illicit-chemical-is-again-jeopardizing-the-ozone-layer/

May 31, 2019 | Author: Wonbo WooWonbo Woo How a Group of Students Built and Launched a Rocket to Space It’s hard to make a rocket when the senior members of your team keep graduating, taking their expertise with them. But these undergrads found a way. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-group-of-students-built-and-launched-a-rocket-to-space/

May 31, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Everyone Needs a Good Pillow—Even Astronauts Bound for Mars Sure, long-haul space travel demands a solid vehicle and ample food. But to stay sane during those lonely days, you might just want a good ol’ pillow. https://www.wired.com/story/everyone-needs-a-good-pillow-even-astronauts-bound-for-mars/

May 31, 2019 | Author: Alexander C. KaufmanAlexander C. Kaufman Trump’s Latest Attack on Federal Climate Science May Backfire The Trump administration’s bid to weaken federal climate science comes at a time when voters increasingly agree that a climate crisis is imminent. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-latest-attack-on-federal-climate-science-may-backfire/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Nathanael JohnsonNathanael Johnson Geothermal Energy Could Save the Climate—or Trigger Lots of Quakes Unlike wind or solar, geothermal energy is always available, rain or shine, day and night. There’s just one thing: earthquakes. https://www.wired.com/story/geothermal-energy-could-save-the-climateor-trigger-lots-of-quakes/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Why Tracking Your Symptoms Can Make You Feel Worse Health apps can trigger the nocebo effect: Obsessively tracking how you feel, what you ate, and how you slept can end up being a drag on your health. https://www.wired.com/story/why-tracking-your-symptoms-can-make-you-feel-worse/

May 30, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Fertility Treatment Gets Less Clinical, More ’Grammable Boutique egg freezing and IVF services are bringing personal coaches, relaxation retreats, and more to modern baby-making. https://www.wired.com/story/concierge-fertility-services/

May 29, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Secret to Soap Bubbles’ Iridescent Rainbows The interaction of light reflecting off the front and back of a soap bubble gives it its colorful appearance. A similar effect explains color-shifting cars. https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-to-soap-bubbles-iridescent-rainbows/

May 29, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Wagon Wheel Effect Shows the Limits of the Human Brain This famous optical illusion, ubiquitous in car commercials and movies, helps neuroscientists study how the mind perceives the world. https://www.wired.com/story/the-wagon-wheel-effect-shows-the-limits-of-the-human-brain/

May 29, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Distant Neutron Stars Could Reveal the Quirks of Quarks Physicists are studying gravitational waves from neutron stars for clues about quarks, “quark matter,” and their role in the universe’s evolution. https://www.wired.com/story/distant-neutron-stars-could-reveal-the-quirks-of-quarks/

May 28, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Military vs. Wind Farms, Facebook vs. Fake Accounts, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-fake-account-iran-military-windfarm/

May 28, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen This AI Uses Echolocation to Identify What You’re Doing A research team built a device that can emit an ultrasonic pitch and pick up its echoes to tell if a person is sitting, standing, or walking. https://www.wired.com/story/this-ai-uses-echolocation-to-identify-what-youre-doing/

May 28, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Military Is Locked in a Power Struggle With Wind Farms A nationwide fight between wind developers and the military highlights the challenge of transitioning to a future of renewable energy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-military-is-locked-in-a-power-struggle-with-wind-farms/

May 28, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Drugs That Boost Our Circadian Rhythms Could Save Our Lives Almost all of the cellular functions in your body run on a 24-hour schedule. Keep that clock regular, and you could stay healthier, and maybe even live longer. https://www.wired.com/story/drugs-could-control-circadian-rhythms-save-our-lives/

May 27, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Crafty Robot Can Write in Languages It’s Never Seen Before After training to hand-write Japanese characters, the robot could then copy words in Hindi, Greek, and English just by looking at examples. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-writing/

May 26, 2019 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol These Hidden Women Helped Invent Chaos Theory Two programmers played a key role in developing chaos theory and the famous butterfly effect, but they’ve been left out of virtually all accounts of the work. https://www.wired.com/story/these-hidden-women-helped-invent-chaos-theory/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Mysterious Midwest Tornadoes, Airbnb’s NYC Truce, and More News Catch up on the most important news from today in two minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/tornado-midwest-climate-change-airbnb-nyc/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni For the Midwest, Epic Flooding Is the Face of Climate Change We often focus on coastal cities when we talk about rising waters, but massive rainfall in the middle of the US has put millions at risk, harming the nation’s ability to produce food. https://www.wired.com/story/for-the-midwest-epic-flooding-is-the-face-of-climate-change/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why It’s So Hard to Predict Where a Tornado Will Strike A series of tornadoes has brought devastation to the Midwest. Ideally, we could forecast such twisters, but the phenomenon is confounding. https://www.wired.com/story/why-its-so-hard-to-predict-where-a-tornado-will-strike/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Tricky Physics of How the Avengers Manage to Fly To understand how Star-Lord flies, you have to consider both the forces acting on him (hello, jet boots) and the torque. https://www.wired.com/story/the-tricky-physics-of-how-the-avengers-manage-to-fly/

May 24, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How to Solve a Rubik’s Cube in 5 Seconds—or Less The world record for unscrambling a Rubik’s cube keeps dropping, as fleet-fingered speedcubers hone their pattern recognition and “lookahead” skills. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-solve-a-rubiks-cube-in-5-seconds-or-less/

May 23, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientists Find a Volume Knob for Emotional Memories Using mice whose neurons had been engineered to respond to light, researchers can dial up or down the emotional intensity of a memory. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-find-a-volume-knob-for-emotional-memories/

May 23, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Pentagon Launched Another Space Agency. Do We Need It? By going big on small satellites, the new Space Development Agency plans to defend the country against all manner of orbital attacks. https://www.wired.com/story/the-pentagon-launched-another-space-agency-do-we-need-it/

May 22, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Rocket Built by Students Reached Space for the First Time A USC team won the collegiate space race by sending a rocket above the Kármán line, the imaginary boundary that marks the end of Earth’s atmosphere. https://www.wired.com/story/a-rocket-built-by-students-reached-space-for-the-first-time/

May 22, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Scientists Go Back in Time to Find More Troubling News About Earth’s Oceans A clever study finds communities of foraminifera, a hard-shelled kind of plankton, have transformed dramatically since the Industrial Revolution. https://www.wired.com/story/foraminifera-plankton/

May 22, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Measles Had Been Eliminated. Now It’s Nearly a Daily Threat The US declared measles eliminated in 2000, but it could lose that status in September—entering a darker era of heightened infectious disease risk. https://www.wired.com/story/measles-had-been-eliminated-now-its-nearly-a-daily-threat/

May 21, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Basic Physics of the Kilogram’s Fancy New Definition The kilogram is now based on energy changes in the quantum world rather than a physical object. Here’s how that works. https://www.wired.com/story/the-basic-physics-of-the-kilograms-fancy-new-definition/

May 21, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill The Unseen Victims of the Opioid Crisis Are Starting to Rebel The push to end opioid abuse has ended up hurting the people who use the drugs legitimately. Now those chronic pain patients are starting a movement of their own. https://www.wired.com/story/the-true-victims-of-the-opioid-crisis-are-starting-to-rebel/

May 21, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Abortion Bans Create a Public Health Nightmare Making abortion mostly illegal will kick off an unintentional, vast experiment in public health—one where the outcomes are sick or dying women and children. https://www.wired.com/story/abortion-bans-create-a-public-health-nightmare/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Mississippi Flood Control Louisiana’s Bonnet Carré Spillway diverts some of the Mississippi’s floodwaters. But it also offers up a wealth of good physics questions. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-mississippi-flood-control/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside Facebook’s New Robotics Lab, Where AI and Machines Friend One Another The social network has a plan to merge the worlds of artificial intelligence and real-world machines, so that both may grow more powerful. https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-robots/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Inside Swamp Works, the NASA Lab Learning to Mine the Moon NASA’s Swamp Works may be humanity’s best hope for figuring out how to live and work on other planets. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-swamp-works-the-nasa-lab-learning-to-mine-the-moon/

May 20, 2019 | Author: Ceridwen DoveyCeridwen Dovey Moondust Could Cloud Our Lunar Ambitions It’s superfine. It’s sharp. It sticks to everything. Before we return to the moon, we’ll have to conquer one of the weirdest substances in the solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/moondust-nasa-lunar-ambitions/

May 19, 2019 | Author: Rebecca BoyleRebecca Boyle The Mystifying Case of the Missing Planets There’s a puzzling lack of planets slightly bigger than Earth, which is making astronomers rethink how planets form in the first place. https://www.wired.com/story/the-mystifying-case-of-the-missing-planets/

May 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Now Ocean Plastics Could Be Killing Oxygen-Making Bacteria The toxins that leach into seawater severely affect bacteria that provide perhaps 20 percent of Earth’s oxygen. That’s where things get complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-plastics-bacteria/

May 17, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler 5G Networks Could Throw Weather Forecasting Into Chaos The FCC is clashing with scientists who argue that 5G networks could interfere with weather sensors and compromise weather predictions. https://www.wired.com/story/5g-networks-could-throw-weather-forecasting-into-chaos/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Jonathan MingleJonathan Mingle Atmospheric Methane Levels Are Going Up—And No One Knows Why Levels of heat-trapping methane are rising faster than climate experts anticipated, triggering intense debate about why it’s happening. https://www.wired.com/story/atmospheric-methane-levels-are-going-up-and-no-one-knows-why/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Casino’s Microgrid Might Be the Future of Energy Fearing isolation in case of disaster, the Blue Lake Rancheria teamed with researchers to develop a one-of-a-kind microgrid. Here’s how they did it. https://www.wired.com/story/casino-microgrid-future-of-energy/

May 16, 2019 | Author: Sara HarrisonSara Harrison The Quest to Make a Bot That Can Smell as Well as a Dog Scientists are trying to crack the code of how smell works—and create robots that can sniff out the world’s secrets like a dog. https://www.wired.com/story/quest-to-make-robot-smell-cancer-dog/

May 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Is Banking on Satellite Internet. Maybe It Shouldn’t The first satellites of Elon Musk’s mega-constellation Starlink are heading to space, but the satellite internet project faces tough economics on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-starlink-satellite-internet/

May 15, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus What’s So Special About Human Screams? Ask a Screamologist A better understanding of the acoustics of screaming could help scientists understand how and why humans shriek—and add a new dimension to the surveillance state! https://www.wired.com/story/whats-so-special-about-human-screams-ask-a-screamologist/

May 15, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why a Golf Ball Compresses Like a Spring—Until It Shatters An experiment with a paper clip reveals both its elastic and plastic properties, a distinction that’s key to how any material compresses or deforms. https://www.wired.com/story/why-a-golf-ball-compresses-like-a-springuntil-it-shatters/

May 14, 2019 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica NASA Needs $1.6 Billion More to Send a Human to the Moon The space agency’s new budget amendment has been called a “down payment” on what will be needed in future years to fund the program. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-budget-human-moon-mission/

May 14, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Tram Bowling Is an Actual Sport. Let’s Look at the Physics Driving a tram into a ball such that it knocks down pins—tram bowling, naturally—raises some physics questions: What does the speed of the ball depend on? What’s its change in momentum? https://www.wired.com/story/tram-bowling-is-an-actual-sport-lets-look-at-the-physics/

May 14, 2019 | Author: Alexander C. KaufmanAlexander C. Kaufman Daimler Plans to Make Its Cars Carbon Neutral by 2039 The carmaker’s new climate plan is bold—for a company. But it falls short of recommended emissions cuts and shows the limits of corporate self-policing. https://www.wired.com/story/daimler-plans-to-make-its-cars-carbon-neutral-by-2039/

May 14, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers ‘Heartbeat’ Bills Get the Science of Fetal Heartbeats All Wrong Anti-abortion laws lean on the heartbeat as a defining moment of aliveness. But at six weeks, it indicates little more than cells and electrical activity. https://www.wired.com/story/heartbeat-bills-get-the-science-of-fetal-heartbeats-all-wrong/

May 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Spider Uses a Silk Slingshot to Hurl Itself at Prey At first glance, the triangle-weaver spider builds a web like any other spider. But once an insect hits that web, something damn near logic-defying happens. https://www.wired.com/story/spider-slingshot/

May 13, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Chernobyl Disaster May Have Also Built a Paradise An HBO show tells the story of the nuclear explosion, but some scientists think the radioactive, human-free landscape might now be a haven for plants and animals. https://www.wired.com/story/the-chernobyl-disaster-might-have-also-built-a-paradise/

May 12, 2019 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol A Bizarre Form of Water May Exist All Over the Universe A new experiment confirms the existence of superionic ice, a black and hot form of water that might make up the bulk of giant icy planets. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bizarre-form-of-water-may-exist-all-over-the-universe/

May 11, 2019 | Author: Katelyn BurnsKatelyn Burns Caster Semenya and the Twisted Politics of Testosterone The ruling that Olympic gold medalist Caster Semenya will need to take testosterone suppressants is already affecting other runners. https://www.wired.com/story/caster-semenya-and-the-twisted-politics-of-testosterone/

May 10, 2019 | Author: Emily HoldenEmily Holden How the Climate Plans of Presidential Hopefuls Stack Up Scientists warn that governments have about 11 years to enact large-scale changes to stop global warming. The next administration will have even less time. https://www.wired.com/story/only-two-democratic-presidential-hopefuls-have-a-climate-plan/

May 10, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Obsessive, Tumultuous Lives of SpaceX Rocket Chasers In 2017 Ryan Chylinski quit his job and hit the road in a camper to photograph rockets. A full-time rocket chaser, he’s helping dig up details on how SpaceX really works. https://www.wired.com/story/the-obsessive-tumultuous-lives-of-spacex-rocket-chasers/

May 9, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Bad Air Linked To Dementia, Bezos’ Lunar Lander, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/air-pollution-dementia-bezos-blue-origin/

May 9, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Jeff Bezos Unveils Blue Origin’s Prototype of a Lunar Lander The Amazon founder today revealed the details of Blue Moon, the lander he will use to ferry supplies—and eventually humans—to the lunar surface. https://www.wired.com/story/jeff-bezos-unveils-blue-origins-prototype-of-a-lunar-lander/

May 9, 2019 | Author: Aaron ReubenAaron Reuben The Evidence Is Strong: Air Pollution Seems to Cause Dementia Air pollution is much worse for health than people had thought, increasing the risk of Alzheimer’s significantly. Meanwhile, air quality is getting worse. https://www.wired.com/story/air-pollution-dementia/

May 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Humans Made This Planet Hell. Hopefully We Can Help Some Species Adapt A new UN report paints a dire portrait of Earth’s human-made biodiversity crisis. But with new genetic techniques in conservation, perhaps we can help save species before it’s too late. https://www.wired.com/story/humans-made-this-planet-hell/

May 8, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Scientists Save a Sick Teen, Hackers Steal $40 Million, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/virus-saved-teenager-binance-hack/

May 8, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Genetically Tweaked Viruses Just Saved a Very Sick Teen With a stroke of last-minute luck, scientists engineered bacteria-killing viruses to help an ailing girl recover from a deadly infection. https://www.wired.com/story/genetically-tweaked-viruses-just-saved-a-very-sick-teen/

May 7, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler China’s Scientists Are the New Kids on the Arctic Block Secretary of State Mike Pompeo berated China this week for using its growing Arctic research program as a Trojan horse for its military and commercial goals. https://www.wired.com/story/chinas-scientists-are-the-new-kids-on-the-arctic-block/

May 7, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Calculate the G’s of Using an Ejection Seat to Blast Out of a Jet Using a jet’s ejection seat to escape in an emergency means weathering some “hurt” level acceleration, as this video shows. https://www.wired.com/story/calculate-the-gs-of-using-an-ejection-seat-to-blast-out-of-a-jet/

May 6, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb Sunscreen in Your Bloodstream, Google’s Conference, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/sunscreen-bloodstream-fda-google-io-game-of-thrones/

May 6, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Sunscreen Chemicals Soak All the Way Into Your Bloodstream But whether that’s a health risk remains unclear, according to a new FDA-backed study. https://www.wired.com/story/sunscreen-chemicals-soak-all-the-way-into-your-bloodstream/

May 6, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Seafloor Maps Reveal Underwater Caves, Slopes—and Fault Lines Drone ships, deep-sea robots, and better sonar are finding unknown seafloor habitats as well as volcanoes, faults, and tsunami-triggering slopes. https://www.wired.com/story/seafloor-maps-reveal-underwater-caves-slopes-and-fault-lines/

May 6, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Legendary Haight Street Gets a New, Legal King of Weed Equity programs can help get those affected by the War on Drugs into the cannabis business. That’s helped Shawn Richard win approval for the first legal weed shop in the famed Upper Haight. https://www.wired.com/story/cannabis-equity/

May 5, 2019 | Author: K. Gretchen GreeneK. Gretchen Greene Spend Part of the $2 Trillion Infrastructure Plan on Robots Opinion: We need to invest in our crumbling infrastructure, and a good use of some of that money would be on robots, drones, and AI. https://www.wired.com/story/infrastructure-plan-robots/

May 5, 2019 | Author: David H. FreedmanDavid H. Freedman Physicists Are Bewitched by Twisted Graphene’s ‘Magic Angle’ If you give graphene a twist, you get superconductivity—and many giddy physicists, all clamoring to work in the new field of twistronics. https://www.wired.com/story/twisted-bilayer-graphene/

May 4, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Physics Analysis of Every Jedi Jump in All of Star Wars May the Fourth Be With You as you read this analysis of every time a Jedi used The Force to jump higher than a normal person could. https://www.wired.com/story/a-physics-analysis-of-every-jedi-jump-in-all-of-star-wars/

May 3, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus The Government Shutdown Killed an Artist’s Space Sculpture Trevor Paglen’s highly anticipated space sculpture made it to orbit, but a shutdown-induced lag at the FCC kept it from inflating as intended. https://www.wired.com/story/the-government-shutdown-killed-an-artists-space-sculpture/

May 3, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Is Launching ‘Organs on a Chip’ to the ISS Organs on a chip were created to expedite the process of drug discovery. Sending them to the International Space Station can speed things up even more. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-launches-organs-on-a-chip-to-the-iss/

May 3, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How to Build, and Keep Building, a Cathedral Like Notre-Dame Architects’ pitches for how to restore Notre-Dame are spurring a debate over when to hew to tradition and when to, say, put a beehive in the spire. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-build-and-keep-building-a-cathedral-like-notre-dame/

May 2, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How DNA Testing at the US-Mexico Border Will Actually Work A pilot project to test the DNA of migrant families raises concerns about the rise of a genetic surveillance state. https://www.wired.com/story/how-dna-testing-at-the-us-mexico-border-will-actually-work/

May 2, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Jakarta Is Sinking. Now Indonesia Has to Find a New Capital By 2050, 95 percent of North Jakarta could be submerged. Blame rising seas, but also the fact that the city is sinking 10 inches a year. https://www.wired.com/story/jakarta-is-sinking/

May 1, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Plan to Dodge a Killer Asteroid—Maybe Even Good Ol’ Bennu Meet the asteroid-impact planners who hope to protect humans from murderous space rocks and the fate of the dinosaurs. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-dodge-a-killer-asteroidmaybe-even-good-ol-bennu/

May 1, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The US Urgently Needs New Genetic Privacy Laws The laws governing DNA data in the US are patchy and incomplete. Yet people keep putting their DNA on the internet, compromising everyone’s genetic anonymity. https://www.wired.com/story/the-us-urgently-needs-new-genetic-privacy-laws/

May 1, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen These Super-Precise Clocks Help Weave Together Space And Time Insanely precise atomic clocks are letting astrophysicists image black holes, steer spacecraft, and maybe one day hunt for gravitational waves. https://www.wired.com/story/these-super-precise-clocks-help-weave-together-space-and-time/

April 30, 2019 | Author: Jon Brodkin, Ars TechnicaJon Brodkin, Ars Technica SpaceX Satellites Will Fly Low to Prevent Space Junk Halving the orbital altitude of its broadband satellites will ensure rapid re-entry and latency as low as 15ms. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-satellites-orbital-altitude/

April 30, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What if Air Conditioners Could Help Save the Planet Instead of Destroying It? Scientists propose a framework for modifying AC units to suck in carbon dioxide and spit out fuels for use in vehicles like cargo ships. https://www.wired.com/story/what-if-air-conditioners-could-help-save-the-planet/

April 30, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Grid Might Survive an Electromagnetic Pulse Just Fine A new report enters the debate over whether an EMP from a nuclear blast or a solar flare would cripple the power grid and concludes that actually, we’ll probably be OK. https://www.wired.com/story/the-grid-might-survive-an-electromagnetic-pulse-just-fine/

April 30, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Women May Soon Start Using AI to Tell Good Eggs From Bad Future Fertility, the first company to use artificial intelligence to grade the viability of women’s harvested eggs for use in IVF or for freezing, unveils its system. https://www.wired.com/story/women-may-soon-start-using-ai-to-tell-good-eggs-from-bad/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon R.I.P., Anki: Yet Another Home Robotics Company Powers Down A third major home robotics outfit shuts down in a year. Why is it so hard to build a companion droid that everyone wants? https://www.wired.com/story/rip-anki-yet-another-home-robotics-company-powers-down/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus A Programmer Solved a 20-Year-Old, Forgotten Crypto Puzzle A self-taught coder dedicated a CPU core to performing continuous computations for three years to crack the puzzle, beating a competing team by mere days. https://www.wired.com/story/a-programmer-solved-a-20-year-old-forgotten-crypto-puzzle/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Heating Up Water With a Battery You can make a simple water heater using a battery and a wire—here’s how. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-heating-up-water-with-a-battery/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Meet the Pro-Vaxxers Helping to Stave Off the Next Pandemic As vaccine hesitancy grows, some individuals are responding by volunteering to take part in experimental vaccine trials. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-pro-vaxxers-helping-to-stave-off-the-next-pandemic/

April 29, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Companies Can Predict Climate Catastrophes for You—as a Service One startup in the growing climate services industry lets you pull up a map and design your own disaster, to help put a price on climate change’s impacts. https://www.wired.com/story/companies-can-predict-climate-catastrophes-for-you-as-a-service/

April 28, 2019 | Author: Jonathan LambertJonathan Lambert Scientists Discover Nearly 200,000 Kinds of Ocean Viruses Far more viruses appear to populate the seas than was previously thought, a discovery that could help clarify viruses’ role in the global carbon cycle. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-discover-nearly-200000-kinds-of-ocean-viruses/

April 27, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Science Behind Nike’s New, Even Faster Marathon Shoe At Sunday’s London Marathon, Eliud Kipchoge will wear the ZoomX Vaporfly Next%, the latest installment in Nike’s performance-boosting Vaporfly line of shoes. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-behind-nikes-new-vaporfly-next-marathon-shoe/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Fighting Measles, LA Pulls a Classic Move: Quarantine With worries over outbreaks growing nationwide, health officials responded to reports of infected individuals by imposing quarantines at UCLA and Cal State LA. https://www.wired.com/story/fighting-measles-la-pulls-a-classic-move-quarantine/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Best Speed Climbers Dash up Walls With a Time-Saving Move Champion speed climbers chalk their hands, grab their holds, and do the Reza, a move that demands explosive power and tight coordination. https://www.wired.com/story/the-best-speed-climbers-dash-up-walls-with-a-time-saving-move/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss The Plan to Grab the World’s Carbon With Supercharged Plants Joanne Chory is tackling climate change as a biologist: by engineering plants to grab much more carbon from the air than they already do. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-grab-the-worlds-carbon-with-supercharged-plants/

April 26, 2019 | Author: Matt Simon, Arielle PardesMatt Simon and Arielle Pardes Bizarre New Materials Could Make Bendy Phones That Work Flexible phones are only now possible because of fancy materials, ones that likely don’t have all the kinks worked out yet. Enter the “metamaterial.” https://www.wired.com/story/metamaterials/

April 25, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Instagram’s Newest Star Is … a Tree? Tentree’s Instagram post about planting trees has gone viral. But as with any celebrity’s carefully orchestrated photo, the reality is much more complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/instagrams-newest-star-is-a-tree/

April 25, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Scientists Need to Talk More About Failure The most radical talk at TED 2019 wasn’t about a miracle cure or a moon shot. It was about a balloon that popped. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-need-more-failure-talk/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Machine That Reads Your Mind (Kinda) and Talks (Sorta) A new brain-computer interface takes the snap, crackle, pop from inside your motor cortex and translates it into digitally synthesized speech. https://www.wired.com/story/machine-reads-your-mind-talks/

April 24, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What the Golden State Killer Tells Us About Forensic Genetics In the year since the arrest of the Golden State Killer, investigative genetic genealogy has emerged as the most powerful crime-fighting tool since DNA itself. https://www.wired.com/story/the-meteoric-rise-of-family-tree-forensics-to-fight-crimes/

April 23, 2019 | Author: Eric Berger, Ars TechnicaEric Berger, Ars Technica What’s Known About the SpaceX Crew Dragon Accident During engine tests of SpaceX’s Dragon spacecraft this past Saturday, the vehicle experienced what the company has characterized as an “anomaly.” https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-crew-dragon-accident/

April 23, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of a Bolt Smashing a Watermelon (or Your Brain) It’s easier to follow rules when you know why they exist. In this case, you can calculate the force of an object hitting a melon to see why hard hats matter. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-a-bolt-smashing-a-watermelon-or-your-brain/

April 23, 2019 | Author: Matt BeaneMatt Beane In Automation, the ‘Last Motion’ Will Come Before the Last Mile Opinion: Robots seem to be the solution to the last-mile problem. But mechanization will likely come for a different part of the process first. https://www.wired.com/story/automation-last-motion-last-mile/

April 22, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Robots Want to Steal (the Boring Parts of) Your Job MIT’s Erik Brynjolfsson on why the Westworld dystopia is (hopefully) far off and why you should never use a telepresence robot to tell someone they’re dying. https://www.wired.com/story/erik-rynjolfsson-robots-steal-boring-parts-of-your-job/

April 21, 2019 | Author: Carrie ArnoldCarrie Arnold A Blazing Hot Coal Seam Shows How Microbes Can Spring to Life A decades-long fire in Pennsylvania revealed some unexpected twists in how microbes survive in harsh environments. https://www.wired.com/story/a-blazing-hot-coal-seam-shows-how-microbes-can-spring-to-life/

April 21, 2019 | Author: Amitha KalaichandranAmitha Kalaichandran AI Could Predict Death. But What If the Algorithm Is Biased? Opinion: Researchers are studying how artificial intelligence could predict risks of premature death. But the health care industry needs to consider another risk: unconscious bias in AI. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-bias-predict-death/

April 19, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Ancestry.com’s Racist Ad Tumbles Into a Cultural Minefield A slavery-themed ad for Ancestry.com exposes the awkward relationship between America’s darkest history and the current boom in family-tree building. https://www.wired.com/story/a-genealogy-sites-racist-ad-tumbles-into-a-cultural-minefield/

April 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Cook With Weed—and a Dash of Tasty, Tasty Science Mac and cheese. Peanut butter and jelly. Asparagus and … cannabis oil with a citrusy terpene profile? Welcome to the heady world of cannabis cuisine. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-cook-with-weed-and-a-dash-of-tasty-tasty-science/

April 19, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss You’re Not Getting Enough Sleep—and It’s Killing You At TED 2019, neuroscientist Matthew Walker argued that sleep deprivation is having a catastrophic effect on our health and safety—here are all the ways. https://www.wired.com/story/youre-not-getting-enough-sleep-and-its-killing-you/

April 18, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers New York’s Aggressive Climate Law Takes Aim at Skyscrapers The city’s new rules compel the owners of big buildings to dramatically reduce their carbon emissions as part of a broad package of climate reforms. https://www.wired.com/story/new-yorks-aggressive-climate-law-takes-aim-at-skyscrapers/

April 18, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles China Finds Phone-Wielding Tourists and Telescopes Don’t Mesh Part scientific instrument and part vacation destination, China’s FAST radio telescope welcomed visitors with their radio wave-emitting gadgets—until it didn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/china-finds-phone-wielding-tourists-and-telescopes-dont-mesh/

April 18, 2019 | Author: Geoff ManaughGeoff Manaugh Move Over, San Andreas: There’s an Ominous New Fault in Town An emerging fault system along the Nevada border is shaking up the tech industry’s latest frontier—and only a small group of scientists is paying attention. https://www.wired.com/story/walker-lane-move-over-san-andreas-fault/

April 17, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Estimate the Pulling Force of Boston Dynamics’ Robo-Dog Army In a new video, a team of robo-puppers pulls a truck as if it were a sled. Here’s how to estimate these SpotMinis’ pulling force and the friction involved. https://www.wired.com/story/estimate-the-pulling-force-of-boston-dynamics-robo-dog-army/

April 17, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr Gene Editing Is Coming for the Womb When an unborn baby is diagnosed with a life-threatening defect, it can be devastating. So some scientists hope to treat the fetus in the uterus using gene editing. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-gene-editing-is-coming-for-the-womb/

April 17, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Offshore Wind Farms Are Spinning Up in the US—At Last Bigger turbines, taller towers, and longer cables are making offshore wind farms more attractive than ever before. https://www.wired.com/story/offshore-wind-farms-are-spinning-up-in-the-us-at-last/

April 16, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Odd Physics of Rey’s Backflip in Star Wars: Episode IX The trailer for Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker didn’t disappoint: The universe’s physics remain as quirky as ever. https://www.wired.com/story/the-odd-physics-of-reys-backflip-in-star-wars-the-rise-of-skywalker/

April 16, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Colorado Tried a New Way to Vote: Make People Pay—Quadratically The state legislature used a method that’s designed to capture the intensity of a voter’s preference as a way to fix some of traditional voting’s big problems. https://www.wired.com/story/colorado-quadratic-voting-experiment/

April 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Notre Dame Fire and the Future of History The fire turned the thousand-year-old roof to ash. But a digital replica of the cathedral could help make its restoration all the more complete. https://www.wired.com/story/the-notre-dame-fire-and-the-future-of-history/

April 15, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni First Big Survey of Births Finds Millions of Missing Women A massive effort to catalog the number of male-female births shows that 23 million women were never born who should have been, according to the natural sex ratio. https://www.wired.com/story/first-big-survey-of-births-finds-millions-of-missing-women/

April 15, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Shocking Find Shows Just How Far Wind Can Carry Microplastics In the remote French Pyrenees, scientists are finding tiny bits of plastic—likely blown from big cities like Barcelona, 100 miles to the south. https://www.wired.com/story/wind-microplastics/

April 15, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why a (Very Bad and Unsafe!) Playground Stunt Sends Folks Flying If common sense hasn’t convinced you that using a moped to spin a merry-go-round is a bad idea, perhaps the physics of circular motion will. https://www.wired.com/story/why-a-very-bad-unsafe-playground-stunt-sends-folks-flying/

April 14, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Mathematicians Discover the Perfect Way to Multiply Most of us rely on the “carrying method” when we multiply. But there’s a much faster way to handle large numbers. https://www.wired.com/story/mathematicians-discover-the-perfect-way-to-multiply/

April 14, 2019 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson Prep for Your Toughest Races Like a Master Marathoner Mebrahtom Keflezighi, who retired from competitive racing at age 42, can convince almost anyone that they can run forever. https://www.wired.com/story/prep-for-your-toughest-races-like-a-master-marathoner/

April 12, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Researchers Want to Link Your Genes and Income—Should They? A push to calculate a ‘genetic income score’ using giant DNA databases raises a raft of ethical questions. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-want-to-link-your-genes-and-incomeshould-they/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus SpaceX Lands All 3 Boosters of the World’s Most Powerful Rocket The first commercial flight of SpaceX’s Falcon Heavy ended with two boosters touching down on land while a third alighted on its drone ship out at sea. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-lands-all-3-boosters-of-the-worlds-most-powerful-rocket/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Jason PontinJason Pontin Are Humans Fit for Space? A ‘Herculean’ Study Says Maybe Not Scientists around the world compared the genomes and health changes of twins Mark and Scott Kelly. One stayed on Earth, the other flew in the International Space Station for a year. https://www.wired.com/story/are-humans-fit-for-space-a-herculean-study-says-maybe-not/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Watch SpaceX Launch a Falcon Heavy on Its First Real Mission This is the second time SpaceX is flying the Falcon Heavy, the most powerful rocket by a factor of two, but it’s the first time it’s doing real work. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-spacex-launch-a-falcon-heavy-on-its-first-real-mission/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Lasers Highlight Ketamine’s Depression-Fighting Secrets Researchers implanted prisms in mouse brains to watch how ketamine affects neurons. The findings could lead to more effective antidepressant treatments. https://www.wired.com/story/lasers-highlight-ketamines-depression-fighting-secrets/

April 11, 2019 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson How the Boston Marathon Messes With Runners to Slow Them Down The course is mostly downhill and has few dramatic turns, yet it ranks among the slowest marathons in the world. Here’s why. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-boston-marathon-messes-with-runners-to-slow-them-down/

April 10, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb The First Black Hole Picture, Facebook Newsfeed Changes, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/black-hole-picture-facebook-newsfeed-changes/

April 10, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Perplexing Physics of Imaging a Black Hole Why is it so difficult to see a black hole? What is a radio wave image anyway? Here’s the science behind the first-ever “picture” of a black hole. https://www.wired.com/story/the-perplexing-physics-of-imaging-a-black-hole/

April 10, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Reveal the First Picture of a Black Hole The Event Horizon Telescope has captured a photo of a supermassive black hole at the center of M87, a galaxy 54 million light-years away. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-reveal-the-first-picture-of-a-black-hole/

April 10, 2019 | Author: Anton Toutov, Prineha NarangAnton Toutov and Prineha Narang Noisy Quantum Computers Could Be Good for Chemistry Problems Opinion: Noisy Intermediate-Scale Quantum devices produce errors. And in a field like chemistry, errors could be a feature, not a bug. https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-noisy-quantum-computers-chemistry-problems/

April 10, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni New York’s Vaccine Order Shows How Health Laws Are Failing Us The threat of bigger measles outbreaks is turning the political tides, making public health officials more willing to take draconian steps. https://www.wired.com/story/new-york-vaccine-order-shows-how-health-laws-are-failing-us/

April 9, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Loopy Secrets of How Charging Cables Work Your phone charger and USB cables look like they’re single cords, but don’t be fooled: Unwrap any cable and you’ll find multiple wires inside. https://www.wired.com/story/the-loopy-secrets-of-how-charging-cables-work/

April 9, 2019 | Author: Brian BarrettBrian Barrett The Weather Channel Flooded Charleston to Make You Give a Damn To show climate change’s devastating effects, the Weather Channel used its immersive mixed-reality studio to span centuries. https://www.wired.com/story/weather-channel-climate-change-immersive-mixed-reality/

April 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Meet Blue: The Cheap and Manipulative (in a Good Way) Robot The tiny price point could launch the robot into research stardom, forging a path to a future in which machines can do just about anything. https://www.wired.com/story/blue-the-robot/

April 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Plan to Save the Rhino With a Cervix-Navigating Robot To perform IVF on the white rhino, researchers are developing a special robot to navigate the females’ complex cervixes and deposit an embryo. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-save-the-rhino-with-a-cervix-navigating-robot/

April 7, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover The Math of How Crickets, Starlings, and Neurons Sync Up Scientists have discovered new patterns that help explain the synchronized behaviors of pendulum clocks, fireflies, and even the power grid. https://www.wired.com/story/the-math-of-how-crickets-starlings-and-neurons-sync-up/

April 6, 2019 | Author: Borja García de SotoBorja García de Soto The Construction Industry Needs a Robot Revolution Opinion: The average big construction project is overdue and over budget. A dose of automation could help. https://www.wired.com/story/the-construction-industry-needs-a-robot-revolution/

April 5, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Sea Levels Are Rising. Time to Build … Floating Cities? If climate change ends up coming for your home, you could move inland. Or you could decamp to tessellated platforms floating on the ocean. https://www.wired.com/story/sea-levels-are-rising-time-to-build-floating-cities/

April 5, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain 5 of the Best Demos of Projectile Motion and Its Quirks A dude jumping on a moving trampoline is a great excuse to dive into the unexpected properties of projectile motion. https://www.wired.com/story/5-of-the-best-demos-of-projectile-motion-and-its-quirks/

April 4, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Tiny Guillotine Decapitates Mosquitoes to Fight Malaria To produce a malaria vaccine, technicians have to decapitate and dissect individual mosquitoes. Now they’ve got help: the mass mosquito guillotine. https://www.wired.com/story/tiny-guillotine-decapitates-mosquitoes-to-fight-malaria/

April 4, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni AI Could Scan IVF Embryos to Help Make Babies More Quickly An algorithm that rates the quality of embryos better than specialists do is a first step toward making IVF easier for women. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-could-scan-ivf-embryos-to-help-make-babies-more-quickly/

April 3, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Two Unusual Galaxies Shake Up the Dark Matter Debate, Again No dark matter? No problem! Two galaxies that appear devoid of the mysterious substance could be strong—if ironic—evidence of its existence. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-have-found-two-galaxies-with-no-dark-matter/

April 3, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Is Lil Bub Such a Famous Cat? It’s in Her Blood. Literally Unusual DNA helped make Lil Bub a cat celebrity. Now that genetic data could improve medical care for cats without millions of Instagram followers. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-need-more-cat-dna-and-lil-bub-is-here-to-help/

April 3, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of the Doppler Effect, Represented as Tiny Balls Why do vehicles coming toward you (and moving away) make that characteristic sound? Let’s explore. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-doppler-effect-represented-tiny-balls/

April 2, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Boston Dynamics’ Rolling ‘Handle’ Robot Really Means It’s about the hardware, yes. But more and more it’s about the AI inside the scarycute dogs and humanoids. https://www.wired.com/story/what-boston-dynamics-rolling-handle-robot-really-means/

April 2, 2019 | Author: Eric HolthausEric Holthaus By 2080, Tropical Diseases Could Be Headed to Alaska Under one pessimistic climate change forecast, mosquitoes could expand their range all the way to the Arctic, redefining what we mean by ‘tropical’ diseases. https://www.wired.com/story/by-2080-tropical-diseases-could-be-headed-to-alaska/

April 1, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Time Would It Take to Dig an Underground Pool? The key is determining the volume of the pool and the time for a single scoop-toss. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-time-to-dig-an-underground-pool/

April 1, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Data Centers Gobble Energy. Could a ‘Fossil-Free’ Label Help? Though, to be honest, it’s probably a bit of a marketing ploy for a few green-powered Nordic countries. https://www.wired.com/story/data-centers-gobble-energy-could-fossil-free-label-help/

April 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Andrew Yang’s Presidential Bid Is So Very 21st Century In a Q&A with WIRED, the presidential hopeful talks about geoengineering the planet, the trickiness of defining a robot, and UBI for all. https://www.wired.com/story/andrew-yangs-presidential-bid-is-so-very-21st-century/

March 31, 2019 | Author: Raleigh McElveryRaleigh McElvery How the Brain Links Gestures, Perception, and Meaning Neuroscience has found that gestures are not merely important as tools of expression but as guides of cognition and perception. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-brain-links-gestures-perception-and-meaning/

March 31, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Building Jumps in The Matrix You could think about it in terms of speed, angle, or gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-of-building-jumps-the-matrix/

March 30, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Machine Learning for March Madness Is a Competition In Itself You’re more likely to win the Powerball jackpot than fill out the perfect bracket. So statisticians are using AI to improve these dismal odds as much as possible. https://www.wired.com/story/machine-learning-march-madness/

March 29, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr Gene Editing Could One Day Cut Away Human Pain But the technology could also, theoretically, be used to develop placid super-soldiers. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-gene-editing-could-one-day-cut-away-human-pain/

March 28, 2019 | Author: Alex Baker-WhitcombAlex Baker-Whitcomb A Human-Spread Fungus Is Killing Amphibians, and More News Catch up on the most important news today in 2 minutes or less. https://www.wired.com/story/chytrid-fungi-amphibian-twitter-dark-boston-dynamics/

March 28, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss The Failure of NASA’s Spacewalk Snafu? How Predictable It Was Years of ignoring the specific needs of women astronauts led up to this moment. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-spacewalk-spacesuit-snafu-predictable/

March 28, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Fungi Decimating Amphibians Are Worse Than We Thought More than 500 species have been ravaged by the chytrid fungi. And that number will probably rise. https://www.wired.com/story/chytrid-fungi-amphibian-decline/

March 28, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Free Throws Should Be Easy. Why Do Basketball Players Miss? The mechanics of a perfect foul shot are known … but it takes a LOT of practice to get them right each and every time—even for two-time MVP Steve Nash. https://www.wired.com/story/almost-impossible-free-throws/

March 27, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus India’s Anti-Satellite Test Wasn’t Really About Satellites It’s about politics, experts say. But it’s also about a chance to talk about the dangers of space debris. https://www.wired.com/story/india-anti-satellite-test-space-debris/

March 27, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Your Apples May Soon Be Picked By Laser-Shooting Robots It takes a deft touch to harvest fruit and veggies. Which is why roboticists are inventing hyper-specialized machines to pick crops. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-robot/

March 27, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Much Prenatal Genetic Information Do You Actually Want? Now that dozens of tests are on the market, patients can scan their unborn children for less serious diseases too. But what will we, as a society, do with that information? https://www.wired.com/story/how-we-reproduce-testing/

March 26, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Why America Wants to Send Astronauts to the Moon’s South Pole Vice President Mike Pence announced the first lunar destination for American astronauts: the south pole. But a lot of work needs to be done before that’s feasible. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-crewed-mission-moon-south-pole/

March 26, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Robot ‘Natural Selection’ Recombines Into Something Totally New If we let robots design themselves in simulations, they can come up with totally novel forms and materials—and some can reproduce to form lightly mutated offspring. https://www.wired.com/story/how-we-reproduce-robots/

March 26, 2019 | Author: Andrea ValdezAndrea Valdez It’s Either the Best Time or the Worst Time to Have a Baby Here’s everything you want or need to know about reproduction—from the best fertility apps to secret Facebook groups for egg donors. https://www.wired.com/story/how-we-reproduce-intro/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Simple Experiments Show How Motion Is Equivalent to Heat A big idea in thermodynamics is the mechanical equivalent of heat, a concept that spells out how moving objects and changing temperatures relate. https://www.wired.com/story/simple-experiments-show-how-motion-is-equivalent-to-heat/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Paul HockenosPaul Hockenos In Germany, Solar-Powered Homes Are Really Catching On The country is getting closer to the solar home revolution: a panel on every roof, an EV in every garage, and a battery in every basement. https://www.wired.com/story/in-germany-solar-powered-homes-are-catching-on/

March 25, 2019 | Author: David KushnerDavid Kushner Synthetic Biology Could Bring a Pox on Us All New methods are making it easier than ever to produce life-saving vaccines—and life-taking viruses that humanity is not prepared to fight. https://www.wired.com/story/synthetic-biology-vaccines-viruses-horsepox/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Roxanne KhamsiRoxanne Khamsi A Clever New Strategy for Treating Cancer, Thanks to Darwin Most advanced-stage cancers mutate, resisting drugs meant to kill them. Now doctors are harnessing the principles of evolution to thwart that lethal adaptation. https://www.wired.com/story/cancer-treatment-darwin-evolution/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Jessica WapnerJessica Wapner A Viral Crime, Genetic Evidence, and a Perplexed Jury Two decades ago, a new form of genetic testing helped send a man to prison. But the case exposed the limits of using complicated forensics in a criminal trial. https://www.wired.com/story/strands-of-evidence-genetic-testing-trial/

March 25, 2019 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson We Might Be Reaching ‘Peak Indifference’ on Climate Change Anyone who wants to deal with climate change may have only a brief window to sell the public on a plan. https://www.wired.com/story/we-might-be-reaching-peak-indifference-on-climate-change/

March 24, 2019 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz The Mysterious Math of How Cells Determine Their Own Fate During development, cells seem to use statistics to figure out what identities they should take on. https://www.wired.com/story/the-mysterious-math-of-how-cells-determine-their-own-fate/

March 22, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Play With Escape Velocity—Without Leaving the Planet Gravity is a real pain for aspiring space travelers. These equations explain how to defy it. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-play-with-escape-velocity-without-leaving-the-planet/

March 22, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Those Midwestern Floods Are Expected to Get Much, Much Worse The intense snow and rainfall of the past several weeks have saturated the ground and rivers, leaving little room for yet more upcoming rain. https://www.wired.com/story/those-midwestern-floods-are-expected-to-get-much-much-worse/

March 22, 2019 | Author: Sandra UpsonSandra Upson Costa Rica’s Zero-Carbon Plan Could Be a Model for the World President Carlos Alvarado Quesada explains Costa Rica’s plan to ditch fossil fuels and how it could inspire others to do the same. https://www.wired.com/story/costa-rica-zero-carbon-emissions-by-2050/

March 21, 2019 | Author: Daniel OberhausDaniel Oberhaus Finally! A DNA Computer That Can Actually Be Reprogrammed DNA computers have to date only been able to run one algorithm, but a new design shows how these machines can be made more flexible—and useful. https://www.wired.com/story/finally-a-dna-computer-that-can-actually-be-reprogrammed/

March 21, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Reveal Ancient Social Networks Using AI—and X-Rays Historians are using data science to unearth overlooked female power brokers, imperial influencers, and other figures hidden in ancient texts. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-reveal-ancient-social-networks-using-ai-and-x-rays/

March 20, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss The Youth Climate Strike as Seen by Teen Photographers Two young photographers covered last week’s global climate protests for WIRED: “There was this pride that we can do this by ourselves if we have to.” https://www.wired.com/story/youth-climate-strike-teen-photographers/

March 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The WIRED Guide to Cannabis Everything you need to know about THC, CBD, terpenes, and the entourage effect. https://www.wired.com/story/wired-guide-cannabis/

March 20, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The First Gene-Edited Food Is Now Being Served Calyxt is the first with its gene-edited oil, but several other companies also have edited foods in the works. https://www.wired.com/story/the-first-gene-edited-food-is-now-being-served/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber A More Humane Livestock Industry, Brought to You by Crispr Horn-free? Yup. Heat-tolerant? Sure. Flu-proof? Of course. Gene editing aims to make our food supply kinder and more efficient. But it’s struggling to leave the barn. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-gene-editing-humane-livestock/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Erika HayasakiErika Hayasaki Better Living Through Crispr: Growing Human Organs in Pigs Scientist Juan Carlos Izpisua Belmonte wants to use gene editing to create human-animal hybrids that we can harvest for parts. What could go wrong? https://www.wired.com/story/belmonte-crispr-human-animal-hybrid-organs/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Jennifer KahnJennifer Kahn Preparing to Unleash Crispr on an Unprepared World Researchers are poised to bring gene-editing tech out of the lab. But just how far do we want Crispr to go? https://www.wired.com/story/preparing-unleash-crispr-unprepared-world/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Anthony LydgateAnthony Lydgate Beyond Cas9: 4 Ways to Edit DNA As Crispr wends its way out of the petri dish and into our genes, scientists are searching for even sharper tools. https://www.wired.com/story/dna-editing-crispr-cas9-cas12e-cas12b-cas12a/

March 19, 2019 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill Women’s Pain Is Different From Men’s—the Drugs Could Be Too A new study shows clear differences in the biology of how men and women feel pain, a reminder that sex-specific pain medications might benefit us all. https://www.wired.com/story/womens-pain-is-different-from-mens-the-drugs-could-be-too/

March 18, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Need an Ohm’s Law Party Trick? Take a Light Bulb’s Temperature We can measure the temperature of an incandescent bulb’s filament while it’s connected to a variable DC power supply. https://www.wired.com/story/need-an-ohms-law-party-trick-take-a-lightbulbs-temperature/

March 18, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Uncanny Valley Nobody’s Talking About: Eerie Robot Voices We’ve all heard of the uncanny valley, in which realistic humanoid robots freak us out. But what might be even freakier is how those robots speak to us. https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-robot-voices/

March 17, 2019 | Author: Dan FalkDan Falk AI Algorithms Are Now Shockingly Good at Doing Science Whether probing the evolution of galaxies or discovering new chemical compounds, algorithms are detecting patterns no humans could have spotted. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-algorithms-are-now-shockingly-good-at-doing-science/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Emily Dreyfuss, Andrea ValdezEmily Dreyfuss and Andrea Valdez Kids and Teens Strike Against Adults’ Climate Screw-Ups Across the planet, children skipped school to protest inaction on climate change: “Just ’cause we’re kids doesn’t mean we have childish opinions.” https://www.wired.com/story/kids-and-teens-strike-against-adults-climate-screw-ups/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Ferocious Shrimp Inspires a Robot Claw That Shoots Plasma Researchers replicate the snapping shrimp’s plasma-firing claw, which is powerful enough to knock prey out cold. https://www.wired.com/story/shrimp-plasma/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Scott K. Johnson, Ars TechnicaScott K. Johnson, Ars Technica The Side Effects of Solar Geoengineering Could Be Minimal Results from a Harvard study don’t “support the common claims that [solar geoengineering] would inevitably lead to significant harms to some regions.” https://www.wired.com/story/the-side-effects-of-solar-geoengineering/

March 15, 2019 | Author: Kate YoderKate Yoder The Arctic’s ‘Carbon Bomb’ Could Screw the Climate Even More Arctic permafrost, a “sleeping giant” of greenhouse gases, is melting faster than expected and could release 1.5 trillion tons of carbon dioxide. https://www.wired.com/story/the-arctic-carbon-bomb-could-screw-the-climate-even-more/

March 14, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni DNA Crime-Solving Is Still New, Yet It May Have Gone Too Far Genetic databases are helping to solve cold crimes. But the arrest of a woman decades after she killed her baby raises questions of police overreach. https://www.wired.com/story/dna-crime-solving-is-still-new-yet-it-may-have-gone-too-far/

March 14, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson NASA’s Supersize Space Launch System Might Be Doomed The space agency’s ill-fated SLS was meant to be the biggest rocket in the world. Now the ‘rocket to nowhere’ may have lost its last reason for being. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-super-sized-space-launch-system-might-be-doomed/

March 14, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain For Pi Day, Calculate Pi Yourself Using Two Colliding Balls On this day of numerical glory, get to know pi in an unusual way: using the elastic collision of two different masses and a wall. https://www.wired.com/story/for-pi-day-calculate-pi-yourself-using-two-colliding-balls/

March 13, 2019 | Author: Andres Colubri, Todd Brown, Pardis C. SabetiAndres Colubri, Todd Brown, and Pardis C. Sabeti When It Comes to Disease, Why Wait for a Pandemic to Respond? Simulated real-world outbreaks are key to understanding how humans respond to outbreaks—and they provide valuable STEM education to boot. https://www.wired.com/story/opinion-disease-simulation/

March 13, 2019 | Author: Cheryl KatzCheryl Katz The World’s Recycling Is in Chaos. Here’s What Has to Happen China’s decision to no longer accept the world’s recycled waste has left countries scrambling to adapt. They have a long way to go. https://www.wired.com/story/the-worlds-recycling-is-in-chaos-heres-what-has-to-happen/

March 12, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Genetic Mutation Might Explain Why Birth Control Can Fail All hormonal contraceptives sometimes fail, for unknown reasons. As genetics trickles into women’s health, one study suggests a possible cause. https://www.wired.com/story/a-genetic-mutation-might-explain-why-birth-control-can-fail/

March 12, 2019 | Author: Jonathan WattsJonathan Watts A Teen Started a Global Climate Protest. What Are You Doing? One day last summer, Greta Thunberg skipped school, sat down outside the Swedish parliament—and launched a movement that’s still going strong. https://www.wired.com/story/a-teen-started-a-global-climate-protest-what-are-you-doing/

March 11, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Trump’s Budget Guts Science Agencies—But Favors the Moon As in years past, Congress is likely to restore many of the proposed cuts in Trump’s spending plan. But the deep cuts are still sowing confusion. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-budget-guts-science-agenciesbut-favors-the-moon/

March 11, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Genderless Digital Voice the World Needs Right Now The idea behind Q is to pressure the tech industry into acknowledging that gender isn’t necessarily binary, a matter of man or woman, masculine or feminine. https://www.wired.com/story/the-genderless-digital-voice-the-world-needs-right-now/

March 11, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Power a Calculator With Some LEDs LEDs generate light, which is why they’re in our screens. But if you instead shine a light on an LED, you can generate current to run a small device. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-power-a-calculator-with-some-leds/

March 10, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe’s New Diabetes Test Has Experts Asking Who It’s For The DNA company is releasing a genetic test to predict whether a person is likely to get diabetes, but it’s of limited use to many high-risk people. https://www.wired.com/story/23andmes-new-diabetes-test-has-experts-asking-who-its-for/

March 10, 2019 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Astronomers Think They Can Explain Mysterious Cosmic Bursts A new, testable theory proposes that fast radio bursts may draw their power from young neutron stars called magnetars. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-think-they-can-explain-mysterious-fast-radio-bursts/

March 8, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss 10 Women in Science and Tech Who Should Be Household Names From code breakers and proto-programmers to molecular biologists and AI leaders, their work has broken barriers and set the stage for the future. https://www.wired.com/story/10-women-science-tech-household-names/

March 8, 2019 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch Inside the High-Stakes Race to Make Quantum Computers Work Quantum computers could help explain some of the most fundamental mysteries in the universe and upend everything from finance to encryption—if only someone could get them to work. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-high-stakes-race-to-make-quantum-computers-work/

March 8, 2019 | Author: Chris D’AngeloChris D’Angelo The Fish on Your Plate May Not Be What You Ordered A fifth of the fish sold at restaurants and markets is mislabeled, according to a report that documents the extent of seafood fraud. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fish-on-your-plate-may-not-be-what-you-ordered/

March 7, 2019 | Author: Damian CarringtonDamian Carrington Oceans Are ‘Spiking a Fever’ With Record Heat Waves More frequent and more severe ocean heat waves are behaving like wildfires, wiping out sea life across large areas. https://www.wired.com/story/oceans-are-spiking-a-fever-with-record-heat-waves/

March 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Track a Tank Shell With a Mirror and Polar Coordinates Ultimately you get a differential equation that you can solve with a bit of code I wrote for you. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-tank-shell-polar-coordinates/

March 6, 2019 | Author: Ann Givens, The TraceAnn Givens, The Trace A New Method of DNA Testing Could Solve More Shootings Criminologists thought it was impossible to get DNA off of shell casings, but a technique pioneered in The Netherlands is having notable results. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-method-of-dna-testing-could-solve-more-shootings/

March 5, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Gene Mutation That Could Cure HIV Has a Checkered Past The same genetic defect used to cure two men of HIV was the target of unethical edits made by He Jiankui to produce the Crispr babies. New research on CCR5 suggests eliminating it in adults could be part of an ethical, practical cure. https://www.wired.com/story/gene-mutation-cure-hiv-london-patient/

March 5, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Save the Lemurs! Eat the Crickets! To take pressure off endangered lemurs, researchers are encouraging the people of Madagascar to embrace bugs as a source of protein. https://www.wired.com/story/save-the-lemurs-eat-the-crickets/

March 4, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Hackers Listen In on What Synthetic DNA Machines Are Printing Some of those sequences are worth millions of dollars, but fortunately the hack isn’t easy to deploy—yet. https://www.wired.com/story/hackers-listen-synthetic-dna-machines/

March 4, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Quantum Physics Could Protect the Grid From Hackers—Maybe If you measure the polarization of a photon, you instantly change it. Utility companies could use this fact to detect snoops trying to invade the system. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-physics-protect-grid/

March 3, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover As the World Warms, Clouds Could Disappear—Catastrophically Computer simulations are suggesting that as global temperatures rise, clouds become scarce, potentially causing warming to spiral out of control. https://www.wired.com/story/as-the-world-warms-clouds-could-disappear-catastrophically/

March 1, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How I Became a Robot in London—From 5,000 Miles Away Wearing a haptic feedback glove, I pilot a robotic hand from across the world, feeling what it feels. The sensation is almost too weird to be real. https://www.wired.com/story/how-i-became-a-robot-in-london/

March 1, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Is Sending Its First Crew-Ready Capsule to the ISS No humans will be onboard this time, but SpaceX hopes this trip will show it can be trusted with people’s lives. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-is-sending-its-first-crew-ready-capsule-to-the-iss/

February 28, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Gene Editing Is Trickier Than Expected—but Fixes Are in Sight A popular gene editing technique may produce lots of unintended changes to DNA, but the good news is we now have a better way of finding such errors. https://www.wired.com/story/precise-gene-editing-is-trickier-than-expected-but-fixes-are-in-sight/

February 28, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Many Times Do You Have to Slap a Chicken to Cook It? While you could technically cook a chicken by slapping it, as proposed by a recent meme, you might also cook your hand. We crunch the numbers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-times-do-you-have-to-slap-a-chicken-to-cook-it/

February 28, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Post-Apocalyptic Insurers Try Out a New ‘Make it Rain’ Strategy These disaster insurers don’t want to hear your story. They just want to drop a flat cash payout, no matter how much—or little—you suffered. https://www.wired.com/story/post-apocalyptic-insurers-are-trying-out-a-cash-bomb-strategy/

February 27, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What Is an Atmospheric River? The so-called Pineapple Express is dumping rain down all over California, for one thing. An explanation in the form of a song. (With apologies to Talking Heads.) https://www.wired.com/story/the-know-it-alls-what-is-atmospheric-river/

February 27, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Forget Growing Weed—Make Yeast Spit Out CBD and THC Instead Yeast gives us beer and bread. Now researchers have engineered it to do something more improbable: manufacturing the cannabis compounds CBD and THC. https://www.wired.com/story/yeast-cbd-and-thc/

February 27, 2019 | Author: Oliver MilmanOliver Milman Since China’s Ban, Recycling in the US Has Gone Up in Flames All that neatly sorted plastic, paper, and glass used to go to China. Now a lot of it is just getting burned instead. https://www.wired.com/story/since-chinas-ban-recycling-in-the-us-has-gone-up-in-flames/

February 27, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Chris Hadfield: Astronaut Life Is Much More Than a Spacewalk The astronaut shares the moments that changed his life, from his boyhood adventures to the rattling spacewalk during which he found himself going blind. https://www.wired.com/story/chris-hadfield-astronaut-life-is-much-more-than-a-spacewalk/

February 26, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Calculate How Fast Quicksilver Is Moving in X-Men Apocalypse To save two dozen people from an exploding building, Quicksilver must have moved at roughly 280 km/s—if you believe speed is in fact his superpower. https://www.wired.com/story/calculate-how-fast-quicksilver-is-moving-in-x-men-apocalypse/

February 26, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Viral Therapy Could Help Us Survive the Superbug Era When one man fell into a coma, his wife sought out a Soviet-era medical technique called phage therapy that ended up saving his life. https://www.wired.com/story/this-viral-therapy-could-help-us-survive-the-superbug-era/

February 26, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Polio Is Nearly Wiped Out—Unless Some Lab Tech Screws Up The world is close to declaring the total containment of polio, but several labs could still, accidentally, be storing samples of the deadly virus. https://www.wired.com/story/polio-is-nearly-wiped-out-unless-some-lab-tech-screws-up/

February 25, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Your Weather Tweets Are Showing Your Climate Amnesia A database of 2 billion tweets shows people get so used to weather extremes they might stop noticing them. That’s bad for action on climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/subtle-weather-shifts-might-make-climate-change-hard-to-see/

February 24, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Is the Universe a Hologram? Maybe! This Math Trick Shows How Physicists designed a holographic model for a universe similar to our own that could bring us closer to a quantum theory of gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/is-the-universe-a-hologram-maybe-this-math-trick-shows-how/

February 22, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Sunscreen Regulations Haven’t Aged Well So now, the FDA has announced proposals to update the process for regulating sun protection products. https://www.wired.com/story/sunscreen-regulations-havent-aged-well/

February 22, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Estimate the Friction Coefficient in That Massive Nascar Pile-Up A crash knocked 21 cars out of the Daytona 500. But good news: Everyone walked away, and the video makes for a cool physics problem. https://www.wired.com/story/estimate-the-friction-force-in-that-massive-nascar-pile-up/

February 22, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez One Woman Pushes Hula-Hooping to Its Absurd, Glittery Limits How many hoops can a person hula? Marawa Ibrahim holds the record at 200—but when she’s twirling a modest 100, her skill makes your head spin. https://www.wired.com/story/almost-impossible-hula-hooping-world-record/

February 22, 2019 | Author: Mark HarrisMark Harris NASA’s Space Shuttle Rises From the Dead to Power New Vehicles New documents show that Boeing wants to use Space Shuttle engines on a secret military project, the latest move to reuse parts of the famous vehicle. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-space-shuttle-rises-from-the-dead-to-power-new-vehicles/

February 21, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Watch SpaceX Launch the First Private Lunar Lander Tonight an Israeli company will dispatch its spacecraft to the moon aboard a Falcon 9 rocket. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-as-spacex-launches-the-first-private-lunar-lander/

February 21, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Doubling Our DNA Building Blocks Could Lead to New Life Forms But first, chemists hope to improve DNA data storage and churn out new medical compounds. https://www.wired.com/story/doubling-our-dna-building-blocks-could-lead-to-new-life-forms/

February 21, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Triumphant Rediscovery of the Biggest Bee on Earth Despite the astonishing size of Wallace’s giant bee, the species was lost to science for 40 years. This is the story of its dramatic rediscovery. https://www.wired.com/story/wallaces-giant-bee/

February 20, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Don’t Toss That Busted Toy Just Yet—Grab a Multimeter This essential tool lets you measure the electric current and voltage of a circuit. Here’s what you need to know to use it correctly. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-toss-that-busted-toy-just-yetgrab-a-multimeter/

February 20, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Get Ready For Gravitational Waves All Day, Every Day An infusion of cash is kicking off the next set of gravitational wave detectors, which will help physicists map the universe in richer detail. https://www.wired.com/story/get-ready-for-gravitational-waves-all-day-every-day/

February 20, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Boaty McBoatface Gears Up for Epic Swim Across the Arctic The probe with the famous name may soon have a new claim to fame, by crossing the Arctic Ocean on the longest underwater robot journey yet. https://www.wired.com/story/boaty-mcboatface-gears-up-for-an-epic-swim-across-the-arctic/

February 19, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Government’s New Weather Model Faces a Storm of Protest The National Weather Service will soon introduce a new forecasting model, but meteorologists are saying it’s worse than its predecessor. https://www.wired.com/story/the-governments-new-weather-model-faces-a-storm-of-protest/

February 19, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Confounding Climate Science of Lab-Grown Meat The assumption goes that lab-grown meat will drastically reduce emissions of beef production. But you know what they say about assumptions. https://www.wired.com/story/the-confounding-climate-science-of-lab-grown-meat/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Why a Grape Turns Into a Fireball in a Microwave Nuking a grape produces sparks of plasma, as plenty of YouTube videos document. Now physicists think they can explain how that energy builds up. https://www.wired.com/story/why-a-grape-turns-into-a-fireball-in-a-microwave/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Dun Dun. Duun Duuun! The Great White Shark Genome Is Here Sharks are renowned for their wound healing, lifespans of 70-odd years, and low rates of cancer. Their genes could reveal their superpowers. https://www.wired.com/story/dun-dun-duun-duuun-the-great-white-shark-genome-is-here/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil 3 Smart Things: What You Might Not Know About Attention We do actually become less attentive as we get older, but refocusing someone’s attention can have concrete physical effects. https://www.wired.com/story/3-smart-things-attention/

February 18, 2019 | Author: David DobbsDavid Dobbs The Devastating Allure of Medical Miracles After sepsis forced the amputation of Sheila Advento’s hands, an intricate transplant technique made her whole again. Then came the side effects. https://www.wired.com/story/devastating-allure-of-medical-miracles/

February 18, 2019 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson Our Ears Are Unlocking an Era of Aural Data While the eye is superior at perceiving sizes and ratios, the ear is better at detecting patterns that occur over time. Enter: sonification. https://www.wired.com/story/sonification-era-of-aural-data/

February 17, 2019 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz How the Brain Keeps Its Memories in the Right Order A long-standing mystery in neuroscience is how the brain attaches a timestamp to our memories. Researchers now may have identified a neural mechanism. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-brain-keeps-its-memories-in-the-right-order/

February 15, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Atmospheric Rivers Get an Intensity Scale—Like Hurricanes All that rain drenching California this week came from an atmospheric river. A new rating scale would tell you how much water is fueling the system. https://www.wired.com/story/atmospheric-rivers-get-an-intensity-scale-like-hurricanes/

February 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Darpa Wants to Solve Science’s Reproducibility Crisis With AI Social science has an image problem—too many findings don’t hold up. A new project will crank through 30,000 studies to try to identify red flags. https://www.wired.com/story/darpa-wants-to-solve-sciences-replication-crisis-with-robots/

February 14, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Launch an 80,000-Pound Sled off an Aircraft Carrier? Sure! This electromagnetic catapult flings airplanes into the sky (and giant sleds into the water). Here’s how to calculate the projectile motion involved. https://www.wired.com/story/launch-an-80000-pound-sled-off-an-aircraft-carrier-sure/

February 14, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Two Satellites Almost Crashed. Here’s How They Dodged It Close encounters of the orbiting kind are getting so common, the Air Force’s alerts are starting to look like junk mail. https://www.wired.com/story/two-satellites-almost-crashed-heres-how-they-dodged-it/

February 14, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Measles Hacks the Body—and Harms Its Victims for Years The virus is the most contagious in the world, exploiting the human body’s immune system to spread with extreme agility and harming its victims for years. https://www.wired.com/story/how-measles-hacks-the-body-and-harms-its-victims-for-years/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon R.I.P., Opportunity Rover: the Hardest-Working Robot in the Solar System NASA announced that, after 15 years and 5,000 charge cycles, the Mars rover Opportunity is officially dead. Here’s what killed the tenacious little robot. https://www.wired.com/story/rip-opportunity-rover/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A 6-Legged Robot Stares at the Sky to Navigate Like a Desert Ant AntBot looks for the polarized light from the sun in order to find its way. Your robot car could do the same one day. https://www.wired.com/story/a-6-legged-robot-stares-at-the-sky-to-navigate-like-a-desert-ant/

February 13, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers This Robot Debates and Cracks Jokes, but It’s Still a Toaster Domo arigato, debating roboto: An IBM project shows that a computer can carry on a sophisticated—if creepy—argument with a human. https://www.wired.com/story/this-robot-debates-and-cracks-jokes-but-its-still-a-toaster/

February 12, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Scary Map Shows How Climate Change Will Transform Your City Click on your city, and the map will pinpoint a modern analog city that matches what your climate may be in 2080. The results are startling. https://www.wired.com/story/this-scary-map-shows-how-climate-change-will-transform-your-city/

February 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Sorry, Sandra Bullock: A Fire Extinguisher Is a Lousy Thruster In the movie Gravity, Sandra Bullock uses a fire extinguisher to maneuver in space. Controlling it is much, much harder than it looks. https://www.wired.com/story/sorry-sandra-bullock-a-fire-extinguisher-is-a-lousy-thruster/

February 12, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A New Lab Is Brewing Microbes to Create Makeup and Medicines At Culture Biosciences, rows of bioreactors are brewing yeast and bacteria so synthetic biology startups can produce their foods, biofuels, and medicines faster. https://www.wired.com/story/culture-biosciences-is-fermenting-microbes-for-meat-makeup-and-fuel/

February 11, 2019 | Author: Alex BacaAlex Baca The Wretched, Climate-Killing Truth About American Sprawl Where we live plays an enormous role in our emissions. For the Green New Deal to work, it needs to grapple with that fact. https://www.wired.com/story/new-green-deal-american-sprawl/

February 11, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon There’s Still So Much We Need to Learn About Weed—and Fast A new research center will finally quantify cannabis’ toll on the environment, as well as how existing rules affect the growers themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/theres-still-so-much-we-need-to-learn-about-weed/

February 10, 2019 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz Clues to Our Unknown Ancestors Are Hiding in Our Genome Humans interbred with Neanderthals and Denisovans, but were there others? Paleontologists are using deep learning to find lost branches of our family tree. https://www.wired.com/story/clues-to-our-unknown-ancestors-are-hiding-in-our-genome/

February 10, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Monkeys With Superpower Eyes Could Help Cure Color Blindness Squirrel monkeys don’t see color like people. But inject their eyeballs with a genetically engineered virus, and they suddenly can perceive a new rainbow. The same trick could someday be used on color-blind people. https://www.wired.com/story/monkeys-with-superpower-eyes-could-help-cure-color-blindness/

February 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Gaze Upon the Black Magic of Electrical Discharge Machining Ever seen GIFs of metal parts fitting together so precisely that the boundaries between them seem to disappear? That’s the joy of EDM. (Um, the other EDM.) https://www.wired.com/story/gaze-upon-the-black-magic-of-electrical-discharge-machining/

February 8, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Green New Deal Shows How Grand Climate Politics Can Be Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and her allies’ sprawling plan leans heavily on what local governments are already doing to fend off climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/the-green-new-deal-climate-politics/

February 7, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Jagged Little Pill Could Make Diabetes Easier to Treat A tortoise-inspired, needle-carrying pill promises to let people swallow drugs that currently have to be injected. https://www.wired.com/story/needle-carrying-pill-to-replace-injections-for-diabetes/

February 7, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Now You Can Join the Search for Killer Asteroids A Hawaii observatory just put the largest astronomical data trove ever online, making it free and accessible so anyone can hunt for new cosmic phenomena. https://www.wired.com/story/now-you-can-join-the-search-for-killer-asteroids/

February 7, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Finally! Climate Science Returns to Capitol Hill It only took a decade, but climate change was front and center again in Washington as NOAA declared 2018 the fourth-hottest year on record. https://www.wired.com/story/finally-climate-science-returns-to-capitol-hill/

February 6, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX’s Starship, Meant for Mars, Prepares for a First Hop A new, extra-beefy SpaceX rocket is undergoing testing in Texas. Formerly called the BFR, Starship is designed to ferry up to 100 humans to Mars. https://www.wired.com/story/spacexs-starship-meant-for-mars-prepares-for-a-first-hop/

February 6, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Figure Out a Drone’s Angular Field of View If you have a drone, you can use this trick to figure out the size of an object captured on camera. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-figure-out-drone-angular-field-of-view/

February 6, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Birdlike Robot Uses Thrusters to Float on Two Legs Leonardo the lanky robot can sort of hover-walk on two legs—and that could land it on Mars one day. https://www.wired.com/story/this-bird-like-robot-uses-thrusters-to-float-on-two-legs/

February 6, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Should Cops Use Family Tree Forensics? Maryland Isn’t So Sure As genetic genealogy gains momentum, one state considers barring police departments from using public DNA databases in criminal cases. https://www.wired.com/story/maryland-considers-banning-genetic-genealogy-forensics/

February 5, 2019 | Author: Eric HolthausEric Holthaus January Was Unusually Warm—Yes, Warm!—Despite That Cold Snap Even places hit by the polar vortex had exceptionally toasty stretches last month, along with record-high temperatures worldwide. https://www.wired.com/story/january-record-warmth-despite-the-polar-vortex/

February 4, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Way Superman Picks Up a Building Is a Physics Travesty Superman is more than welcome to use his superpowers to pick up a building. But we really need to talk about his technique. https://www.wired.com/story/the-way-superman-picks-up-a-building-is-a-physics-travesty/

February 4, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The World Might Actually Run Out of People The United Nations predicts that the global population will soon explode. In Empty Planet, John Ibbitson and Darrell Bricker argue they’re dead wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/the-world-might-actually-run-out-of-people/

February 3, 2019 | Author: Sandra UpsonSandra Upson Ditch the Super Bowl for a Who’s Who of Superb Owls Great gray owls! Great horned owls! There are many great—nay, superb—owl livestreams to enjoy on Sunday … or whenever you’d like to see some head turners. https://www.wired.com/story/ditch-the-super-bowl-for-a-whos-who-of-superb-owls/

February 3, 2019 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Neural Networks Need a Cookbook. Here Are the Ingredients We know very little about how neural networks actually work. But mathematicians are developing a theory to help make them more predictable. https://www.wired.com/story/neural-networks-need-a-cookbook-here-are-the-ingredients/

February 3, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez When It Comes to Super Bowl Kickers, Who Will Choke First? The fate of this year’s big game could rest with the teams’ two formidable kickers—and whether they perform under pressure. https://www.wired.com/story/when-it-comes-to-super-bowl-kickers-who-will-choke-first/

February 1, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson China’s Moon Lander Wakes Up From Its Long, Ultra-Cold Night While slumbering, the spacecraft recorded the coldest temperature yet for our orbiting rock: a punishing -310°F. https://www.wired.com/story/china-lunar-lander-wakes-up-from-its-long-ultra-cold-night/

February 1, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Don’t Save the Planet for the Planet. Do It for the Beer If your Super Bowl Sunday includes cold brewskis, you’ll want to get that climate change thing fixed. Just ask Budweiser. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-save-the-planet-for-the-planet-do-it-for-the-beer/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Punishing Polar Vortex Is Ideal for Cassie the Robot While humans suffer, a trunkless pair of ostrich-like legs is braving the frozen grounds of the University of Michigan, for the good of science. https://www.wired.com/story/the-punishing-polar-vortex-is-ideal-for-cassie-the-robot/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The ‘Complete’ Cancer Cure Story Is Both Bogus and Tragic An Israeli company claimed it will cure cancer in a year, and the internet erupted. But in this latest viral incident, everyone loses. https://www.wired.com/story/the-complete-cancer-cure-story-is-both-bogus-and-tragic/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Very Vortex-y Science of Making Snow From Boiling Water Turning hot water into snow might as well be the official sport of the polar vortex. Here’s what’s those water molecules are up to. https://www.wired.com/story/the-very-vortex-y-science-of-making-snow-from-boiling-water/

January 31, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The WIRED Guide to Commercial Human Space Flight Everything you need to know about Blue Origin, SpaceX, Virgin Galactic, and what actually happens to your body if you go live in space. https://www.wired.com/story/wired-guide-commercial-space-flight/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Your Phone (and Other Gadgets) Fail You When It’s Cold Your phone won’t last more than about 5 minutes in weather below –35 degrees F—just long enough for you to also get nibbled by frostbite. https://www.wired.com/story/why-your-phone-and-other-gadgets-fail-you-when-its-cold/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Robot Teaches Itself to Play Jenga. But This Is No Game A machine is mastering the complex physics of Jenga. That’s a big step in the daunting quest to get robots to manipulate objects in the real world. https://www.wired.com/story/a-robot-teaches-itself-to-play-jenga/

January 30, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Fearsome Titan Games Event Reveals the Value of Torque An event called the Herculean Pull looks like it’s all about raw muscle power, but the real trick is to leverage torque. https://www.wired.com/story/this-fearsome-titan-games-event-reveals-the-value-of-torque/

January 29, 2019 | Author: C. Brandon OgbunuC. Brandon Ogbunu James Watson and the Insidiousness of Scientific Racism Opinion: Black scientists are in the best position to understand what is so broken about the ideas of Watson and his army. https://www.wired.com/story/james-watson-and-scientific-racism/

January 29, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers And Now, the Weather: Mars-like, With a Chance of Apocalypse Extreme cold from a broken polar vortex is hitting the US at the same time as extreme heat is scorching Australia. Not so good if a habitable planet is your jam. https://www.wired.com/story/and-now-the-weather-mars-like-with-a-chance-of-apocalypse/

January 28, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This App Lets Kenya’s Farmers Monitor Crops From Eyes in the Sky Using satellite data from the UN, PlantVillage monitors biomass on a plot of land, giving farmers insight into how their crops are growing. https://www.wired.com/story/app-lets-farmers-monitor-crops-from-the-sky/

January 28, 2019 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Revs Its Engines as It Gets Closer to Crewed Flight Next month SpaceX’s passenger capsule is expected to launch on an uncrewed mission—a big step toward bringing human spaceflight back to the US. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-revs-its-engines-as-it-gets-closer-to-crewed-flight/

January 28, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Controversial Fertility Treatment Gets Its First Big Test Although stalled in the US, a technique often called three-person IVF is gaining ground in Europe, where a pilot trial is now under way. https://www.wired.com/story/a-controversial-fertility-treatment-gets-its-first-big-test/

January 27, 2019 | Author: Marcus WooMarcus Woo A Child’s Puzzle Helped Uncover How Magnets Really Work The physics of ferromagnetism has long befuddled scientists, but a familiar puzzle is getting them closer to an answer. https://www.wired.com/story/a-childs-puzzle-helped-uncover-how-magnets-really-work/

January 27, 2019 | Author: Rose EvelethRose Eveleth It’s Time to Rethink Who’s Best Suited for Space Travel Being an astronaut is mentally and physically grueling—which is why people with disabilities, who adapt to challenges every day, are perfect fits. https://www.wired.com/story/its-time-to-rethink-whos-best-suited-for-space-travel/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Excruciating, Impossible Science of Airport Delays Network effects dictate how one flight delay ripples out, but our air traffic system is so complex that scientists still grapple with how it all works. https://www.wired.com/story/the-excruciating-impossible-science-of-airport-delays/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler An Underwater Skin Sensor Lets Swimmers Track Their Sweat Swimmers (and triathletes) can’t monitor their hydration as easily as other athletes do, but a new underwater sweat sensor offers a way. https://www.wired.com/story/an-underwater-skin-sensor-lets-swimmers-track-their-sweat/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Formidable Physics of Spider-Man’s Water Monster In the trailer for Spider-Man: Far From Home, the villain Mysterio appears to form a giant monster out of water. Let’s calculate how much power that would take. https://www.wired.com/story/the-formidable-physics-of-spider-mans-water-monster/

January 25, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez We Need a Radical New Way to Understand Screen Use To get to the bottom of how screens affect our mental health, we need to demand a lot more of the tech giants who possess our data. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-a-radical-new-way-to-understand-screen-use/

January 24, 2019 | Author: Liza GrossLiza Gross Pesticides Are Harming Bees in Literally Every Possible Way The weed killer dicamba is emerging as a big culprit in the mass die-off of bees. https://www.wired.com/story/pesticides-are-harming-bees-in-literally-every-possible-way/

January 24, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Drones Drop Poison Bombs to Fight One Island’s Rat Invasion On the Galapagos Island of Seymour Norte, conservationists scramble to destroy every last invasive rodent before the ecosystem descends into chaos. https://www.wired.com/story/drones-drop-poison-bombs-to-fight-one-islands-rat-invasion/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Stephanie MencimerStephanie Mencimer Google and Facebook Backed an Event Denying Climate Change Three tech giants, including Microsoft, sponsored a libertarian conference that included attacks on the science of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/google-and-facebook-backed-an-event-denying-climate-change/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Reconstruct an Object by Photographing Its Shadow Taking a page from film noir spycraft, a team of researchers found a way to photograph an object while pointing a camera in the opposite direction. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-reconstruct-an-object-by-photographing-its-shadow/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Sensible Math of Knocking Over Absurdly Large Dominoes Using a small domino to topple a taller one, you could in theory take down a domino the size of a skyscraper. Here’s how it would work. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sensible-math-of-knocking-over-absurdly-large-dominos/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Sandra UpsonSandra Upson Watch Blue Origin Launch a Rocket Stuffed With NASA Gear On Wednesday, Jeff Bezos’ space company will send its New Shepard rocket aloft carrying nine NASA payloads on a suborbital flight. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-blue-origin-launch-a-rocket-stuffed-with-nasa-gear/

January 23, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Water in Your Toilet Could Fight Climate Change One Day Researchers are beginning to explore how we might tweak wastewater treatment to capture CO2 instead of emitting it, slowing the ravages of climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/the-water-in-your-toilet-could-fight-climate-change-one-day/

January 22, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni We Can Still Avoid a Repeat of Last Year’s Deadly Flu Season It’s peak flu season, and almost 10 million people across the US have already been sickened by the virus. https://www.wired.com/story/we-can-still-avoid-a-repeat-of-last-years-deadly-flu-season/

January 21, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss For Women Job Seekers, Networking Like a Man Isn’t Enough A new study finds that male and female job seekers need different kinds of peer networks to get ahead. https://www.wired.com/story/women-leadership-job-networking/

January 21, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Thank the Old-Timey Telegraph For Your Garage Door Opener The electric relay makes all kinds of household devices possible, but they don’t get much love. Until now! https://www.wired.com/story/thank-the-old-timey-telegraph-for-your-garage-door-opener/

January 21, 2019 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil One Scientist Hopes to Engineer the Climate With Antacid In the first solar geoengineering experiment in the lower atmosphere, scientists will test a recipe that could provide some temperature control back on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/geoengineering-climate-with-antacid/

January 21, 2019 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil 3 Smart Things: The Hidden Lives of Liquids Did you know human salivary glands pump out about a quart—a Big Gulp!—a day? https://www.wired.com/story/3-smart-things-hidden-lives-liquids/

January 20, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Does a Lunar Eclipse Get Called a Blood Moon? Because people (cough … astrologers, not astronomers) give names to phenomena that don’t really need cute labels. https://www.wired.com/story/the-know-it-alls-weird-names-for-moon/

January 20, 2019 | Author: Rebecca BoyleRebecca Boyle Exploding Stars May Have Killed Off Prehistoric Predators Subatomic particles streaming through the atmosphere could have fatally irradiated ancient megafauna like the megalodon monster shark. https://www.wired.com/story/exploding-stars-may-have-killed-off-prehistoric-predators/

January 18, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Pharma Spending on Doctors Is Correlated With Opioid Deaths A new study shows that doctors wrote more prescriptions, and more people overdosed on opioids, in counties where drug companies spent more money. https://www.wired.com/story/pharma-spending-on-doctors-is-correlated-with-opioid-deaths/

January 18, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Space Billboards Are Just the Latest Orbital Stunt A company that wants to slap logos on the night sky is raising tricky questions about what belongs in space. https://www.wired.com/story/space-billboards-are-just-the-latest-orbital-stunt/

January 18, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers If Edible Insects Are the Future, We Should Talk About Poop Insects are touted as a major new source of protein, but scaling up Big Cricket could mean new problems—such as what to do with all their “frass.” https://www.wired.com/story/if-edible-insects-are-the-future-we-should-talk-about-poop/

January 17, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain In This Brutal Titan Games Event, Friction Is The Real Winner Sure, you need big muscles to win the Lunar Impact event in Dwayne Johnson’s new reality show. But you won’t get anywhere without friction. https://www.wired.com/story/in-titan-games-lunar-impact-friction-is-the-real-winner/

January 17, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon To Prevent Wildfires, Treat Utilities Like Railroad Barons Electrical equipment likely caused November’s massive Camp Fire. That’s particularly maddening because science knows full well how to stop that. https://www.wired.com/story/to-prevent-wildfires-treat-utilities-like-railroad-barons/

January 16, 2019 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Antibiotics Are Failing Us. Crispr Is Our Glimmer of Hope Antibiotics are still massively overprescribed, a new study shows. With no new drugs in sight, some scientists are turning to Crispr for a reboot. https://www.wired.com/story/antibiotics-are-failing-us-crispr-is-our-glimmer-of-hope/

January 16, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Crocodile-Like Robot Helps Solve a 300-Million-Year Mystery Researchers use a fossil, fancy computer work, and a complex robot to tease apart how an early land-walking animal moved. https://www.wired.com/story/a-crocodile-like-robot-helps-solve-a-300-million-year-mystery/

January 16, 2019 | Author: Nathanael JohnsonNathanael Johnson For Nervous Californians, Fire-Proofing Is a New Obsession In wildfire-prone cities and towns, increasingly worried residents are banding together to prevent future disasters. https://www.wired.com/story/for-nervous-californians-fire-proofing-is-a-new-obsession/

January 16, 2019 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen A Levitating Glass Bead Probes the Universe’s Mysteries New tabletop sensors could be sensitive enough to glimpse gravitational waves and even dark-matter particles. https://www.wired.com/story/a-levitating-glass-bead-probes-the-universes-mysteries/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain So You Want to Harness Evaporation From a Manmade Lake There are much better ways to generate electricity than this proposed scheme in Egypt, but here’s how it would theoretically work. https://www.wired.com/story/geoengineering-energy-from-evaporating-an-artificial-lake/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Is ’Oumuamua an Alien Spaceship? Sure! Except, No People love ‘Oumuamua because it’s an antidote to our cosmic loneliness. And that’s OK! https://www.wired.com/story/is-oumuamua-an-alien-spaceship-sure-except-no/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Cities Are Tucking Climate Change Fixes Into New Laws Across the country, cities are implementing new housing and transit laws that, oh by the way, lower their emissions of greenhouse gasses. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-are-tucking-climate-change-fixes-into-new-laws/

January 15, 2019 | Author: Kelly ClancyKelly Clancy One Couple’s Tireless Crusade to Stop a Genetic Killer When Sonia Vallabh lost her mother to a rare disease, she and her husband, Eric Minikel, set out to find a cure. https://www.wired.com/story/sleep-no-more-crusade-genetic-killer/

January 14, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Bio-Printers Are Churning out Living Fixes to Broken Spines A new study shows that 3D-printing a section of spinal cord, living cells and all, restored movement in injured rats. https://www.wired.com/story/bio-printers-are-churning-out-living-fixes-to-broken-spines/

January 14, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Bio-Printers Are Churning out Living Fixes to Broken Spines A new study shows that 3D-printing a section of spinal cord, living cells and all, restored movement in injured rats. https://www.wired.com/story/bio-printers-are-churning-out-living-fixes-to-broken-spines/

January 14, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Desalination Is Booming. But What About All That Toxic Brine? Desalination plants turn seawater into drinking water, but also pump hypersaline water back into the environment. That’s especially troubling because desal has become extremely popular. https://www.wired.com/story/desalination-is-booming-but-what-about-all-that-toxic-brine/

January 13, 2019 | Author: Rebecca BoyleRebecca Boyle Dark Matter Hunters Are Looking Inside Rocks for New Clues Dark matter may occasionally interact with minerals in the earth, leaving traces that physicists hope to decipher. https://www.wired.com/story/dark-matter-hunters-are-looking-inside-rocks-for-new-clues/

January 12, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Flying Tesla? Sure! We Calculate the Power Demands Elon says he’d use SpaceX propulsion tech to make a Roadster take flight, and we have thoughts. https://www.wired.com/story/a-flying-tesla-sure-we-calculate-the-power-demands/

January 11, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Insane Numbers Behind Cycling’s Most Masochistic Race The hour is one of cycling’s oldest and most prestigious records: How far can one person ride a bicycle in 60 minutes? https://www.wired.com/story/cycling-hour-record-almost-impossible/

January 11, 2019 | Author: Gary SmithGary Smith The Exaggerated Promise of So-Called Unbiased Data Mining Opinion: Why ransacking data for hidden patterns often results in misleading—or meaningless—conclusions. https://www.wired.com/story/the-exaggerated-promise-of-data-mining/

January 11, 2019 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles A Strange Kind of Data Tracks the Weather—and Pirate Ships Weather forecasters may soon use a technique called radio occultation, which infers the state of the atmosphere from various broadcasts. https://www.wired.com/story/a-strange-kind-of-data-tracks-the-weather-and-pirate-ships/

January 10, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Magic Wand? Nope, Just Good Ol’ Fashioned Physics What looks like magic is actually the electrostatic force in action, suspending objects in air by manipulating their electrons. https://www.wired.com/story/a-magic-wand-nope-just-good-ol-fashioned-physics/

January 10, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon To Prevent Fires, One California Town Says ‘Goat Fund Me’ Spooked by massive wildfires, a California city launches a crowdfunding campaign to hire goats to clear brush at the edges of town. https://www.wired.com/story/one-california-towns-plan-to-fight-wildfires-with-goats/

January 9, 2019 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Trump’s Immigration Speech Won’t Change Minds, Science Says Research shows that direct appeals from the president don’t sway people, and neither do fact-checks from the media. But they do keep us talking. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-immigration-speech-wont-change-minds-science-says/

January 9, 2019 | Author: Amanda Kolson HurleyAmanda Kolson Hurley Los Angeles Gets America’s First Earthquake Warning App ShakeAlertLA gives city residents a few seconds’ warning when an earthquake hits. It’s the first publicly available app to do so in the US. https://www.wired.com/story/los-angeles-gets-americas-first-earthquake-warning-app/

January 9, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Ocean Cleanup’s Plastic Catcher Is Busted. So What Now? First, the 600-meter-long plastic catcher didn’t catch plastic. Then it split in two. What is the right way, then, to cleanse our oceans of the plastic menace? https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-cleanups-plastic-catcher/

January 8, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Clever Clumsiness of a Robot Teaching Itself to Walk Researchers make robots teach themselves how to walk through trial and error, like babies, to navigate the real world. https://www.wired.com/story/the-clever-clumsiness-of-a-robot-teaching-itself-to-walk/

January 8, 2019 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Shutdown Shows Just How Vital Government Scientists Are As federal scientists sit at home, the many industries that rely on them are already beginning to feel their absence. https://www.wired.com/story/the-shutdown-shows-just-how-vital-government-scientists-are/

January 7, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Calculate the Physics in Super Smash Bros. Ultimate Using the videogame’s training mode, you can figure out the rules governing how the various characters jump and move. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-calculate-the-physics-in-super-smash-bros-ultimate/

January 6, 2019 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Space and Time Could Be a Quantum Error-Correcting Code The fabric of space-time may get its robustness from a network of quantum particles, according to a principle called quantum error correction. https://www.wired.com/story/space-and-time-could-be-a-quantum-error-correcting-code/

January 4, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez What Is the Dark Side of the Moon? Our in-house Know-It-Alls answer questions about your interactions with technology. https://www.wired.com/story/the-know-it-alls-what-is-the-dark-side-of-the-moon/

January 4, 2019 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We Need to Not Freak Out About the Robot Revolution A former Obama advisor says we’ll work alongside the machines—but we also need to be smarter about apprenticeships and job retraining. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-to-not-freak-out-about-the-robot-revolution/

January 3, 2019 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Finally, New Horizons’ First Photos of Ultima Thule On the first day of the year, NASA’s New Horizons Spacecraft captured an icy world 4 billion miles away. Here’s what the photos tell us about the fringes of our solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/new-horizons-first-photos-ultima-thule/

January 3, 2019 | Author: Kurt AmslerKurt Amsler Why Your Doctor Should Also Be a Scientist Opinion: Physician-scientists are an endangered species. Without them, patients could lose out on the next generation of life-saving treatments. https://www.wired.com/story/why-your-doctor-should-also-be-a-scientist/

January 3, 2019 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Does a Martian-Style Gravity Assist Actually Work? It’s basically a perfectly elastic collision, like two bouncy balls colliding. https://www.wired.com/story/how-does-a-gravity-assist-work/

January 2, 2019 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart One Species Loves Our Climate-Wrecking Ways: Fire Ants! These stinging insects love natural disasters, human landscaping, and the warming conditions brought by climate change. At least someone’s happy. https://www.wired.com/story/one-species-loves-our-climate-wrecking-ways-fire-ants/

December 31, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How to Follow New Horizons’ Historic Flyby of Ultima Thule On New Year’s Eve, NASA’s probe will reach Ultima Thule, an icy body at the edge of our solar system. Here’s its timeline. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-follow-new-horizons-historic-flyby-of-ultima-thule/

December 30, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson This Year SpaceX Made Us All Believe in Reusable Rockets A few small glitches marred an otherwise stellar year as SpaceX honed its reusable rocket technology. https://www.wired.com/story/this-year-spacex-made-us-all-believe-in-reusable-rockets/

December 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Year in Robots, From Boston Dynamics to (RIP) Baxter Look back on the biggest moments in robotics in 2018, from the continued ascendance of SpotMini to the rapid rise and fall of the home robot. https://www.wired.com/story/the-year-in-robots/

December 28, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez NASA’s New Horizons Probe Prepares To Make History—Again The intrepid spacecraft has traveled 13 years and 4 billion miles to glimpse Ultima Thule, a cold, dark world at the fringes of our solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-new-horizons-ultima-thule/

December 27, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Don’t Fear the Robot Overlords—Embrace Them as Coworkers In factories across the world, machines are beginning to work more intimately with humans without sending them to the unemployment line—or the grave. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-fear-the-robot-overlords-embrace-them-as-coworkers/

December 26, 2018 | Author: Andrea ValdezAndrea Valdez The Most-Read WIRED Science Stories of 2018 Feast your mind on stories about brain-eating amoebas, the science of wildfires, and a criminal twist to the genetics revolution. https://www.wired.com/gallery/the-most-read-science-stories-of-2018/

December 26, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Future of Crime-Fighting Is Family Tree Forensics Genealogy is about to send a lot more people to jail. https://www.wired.com/story/the-future-of-crime-fighting-is-family-tree-forensics/

December 25, 2018 | Author: WIRED StaffWIRED Staff 11 Fantastic Science Books to Binge Read Snuggle up with your favorite display technology and ignite your neurons with these recommended science books from 2018. https://www.wired.com/story/fantastic-science-books-to-binge-over-the-holidays/

December 24, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez 50 Years Ago, Earthrise Gave Us the View of a Lifetime Astronauts on NASA’s Apollo 8 mission snapped the first photos of Earth from space, forever changing how we see our place in the universe. https://www.wired.com/story/50-years-ago-earthrise-gave-us-the-view-of-a-lifetime/

December 23, 2018 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett It’s Not a Myth: Quantum Messages Really Can Travel Faster A new experiment showed for the first time that quantum communication can indeed be speedier than what’s seen in regular computing. https://www.wired.com/story/its-not-a-myth-quantum-messages-really-can-travel-faster/

December 21, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The DRC’s Ebola Outbreak Is an End-of-Year Nightmare A major election, holiday travel, and violent clashes in the Democratic Republic of Congo are confounding all attempts to contain Ebola’s spread. https://www.wired.com/story/the-drc-ebola-outbreak-is-an-end-of-year-nightmare/

December 20, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Physics Owes a Lot to a Little-Loved Math Class I’m talking about trigonometry, of course: that bastion of angles and triangles that is essential to calculating velocity, momentum, and much more. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-owes-a-lot-to-a-little-loved-math-class/

December 20, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez We’ve Got the Screen Time Debate All Wrong. Let’s Fix It The narrative around tech addiction has been driven more by fear than facts. But that’s finally starting to change. https://www.wired.com/story/year-in-review-tech-addiction-debate-all-wrong/

December 20, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson A SpaceX Booster Went for a Swim and Came Back as Scrap Metal The space company spent several days retrieving and inspecting a rocket booster that made an unplanned ocean landing. Now it appears to be toast. https://www.wired.com/story/a-spacex-booster-went-for-a-swim-and-came-back-as-scrap-metal/

December 19, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Bug-Like Robot Uses Electricity to Walk Upside Down The magic ingredient isn’t glue, or a material that mimics the pad of a gecko’s foot, but voltage. Specifically, electroadhesion. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bug-like-robot-uses-electricity-to-walk-upside-down/

December 19, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Dark Matter Hunters Pivot After Years of Failed Searches After a year of disappointing results, some physicists are now focusing on theorized particles called axions, rather than the more-famous WIMPs. https://www.wired.com/story/for-dark-matter-hunters-out-there-theories-are-catching-on/

December 18, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Use a Slo-Mo Video to Calculate How Fast Glass Shatters Using footage shot by The Slow Mo Guys, you can get a pretty good estimate of the speed at which cracks travel through a sheet of glass. https://www.wired.com/story/use-a-slo-mo-video-to-calculate-how-fast-glass-shatters/

December 18, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Scientists Journey Into the Dark Side of Cannabis Cannabis can treat inflammation, pain, and nausea, among other ills. But an estimated 9 percent of users will develop a dependence on the drug. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-journey-into-the-dark-side-of-cannabis/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Dense Does a Body Have to Be to Break a Concrete Floor? Solve this Captain America physics puzzle. https://www.wired.com/story/how-dense-does-a-body-have-to-be-to-break-a-concrete-floor/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Penguin Poop, Seen From Space, Tells Our Climate Story Satellite imagery of penguin poop is helping scientists see how climate change affects the birds’ diet and the food chain more broadly. https://www.wired.com/story/penguin-poop-antarctica-climate-change/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson Embrace a Fake-Meat Future for Its Lesser-Known Benefits You probably know that ditching meat from your diet is healthier and better for the planet. But what if it were better for your wallet? Or schedule? https://www.wired.com/story/embrace-fake-meat-future-benefits/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats The Next Mass Extinction Might Be About Survival of the Laziest The discovery that metabolic rate affects the longevity of not just organisms but also species is intriguing. Could this work for humans too? https://www.wired.com/story/survival-of-the-laziest/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Arielle PardesArielle Pardes Can’t Remember What You Read? Blame the Font, Not Forgetfulness Researchers in Australia have invented a new typeface with features designed to boost focus and learning. https://www.wired.com/story/new-font-sans-forgetica-for-learning/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A ‘Roadless Trip’ in a 3D-Printed, Solar-Powered Snow Rover A Dutch couple is traversing Antarctica at 5 miles per hour in their Solar Voyager, which they made from upcycled plastic and solar panels. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-printed-solar-powered-snow-rover/

December 17, 2018 | Author: Joshuah Bearman, Allison KeeleyJoshuah Bearman and Allison Keeley The Mad Scramble to Claim the World’s Most Coveted Meteorite In rural Peru, a chunk of rock made landfall with a tremendous blast. Meteorite hunters rushed to get a piece of the action. Then things got weird. https://www.wired.com/story/scramble-claim-worlds-most-coveted-meteorite/

December 16, 2018 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Confirmed! Scientists Did See Gravitational Waves (Probably) Two independent papers vanquish lingering doubts about LIGO’s historic discovery of gravitational waves. https://www.wired.com/story/confirmed-gravitational-waves-ligo/

December 14, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain No GPS? A DIY Radio Transmitter Can Help You Navigate The old-school way to navigate is with a clock and a sextant, but you can also hack together this alternative. https://www.wired.com/story/no-gps-a-diy-radio-transmitter-can-help-you-navigate/

December 14, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Sci-Fi Promised Us Home Robots. So Where Are They? It seemed like 2018 was going to be the year when robots made a big leap toward the fabled Rosie from the Jetsons. Consumers, though, had other ideas. https://www.wired.com/story/sci-fi-promised-us-home-robots-so-where-are-they/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Designer Seed Company Is Building a Farming Panopticon Indigo Ag, known for its microbe-coated seeds, is acquiring geospatial data startup TellusLabs to use satellites to learn every last thing about its farmers’ fields. https://www.wired.com/story/a-designer-seed-company-is-building-a-farming-panopticon/

December 13, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart Even Zoos Are Learning the Art of Doomsday Prepping With hurricanes and wildfires becoming more frequent and intense, zoos are facing the staggering task of protecting animals while the world runs amok. https://www.wired.com/story/even-zoos-are-learning-the-art-of-doomsday-prepping/

December 12, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler As Snow Disappears, the Sierras and Rockies Are Shrinking An analysis of 36 years of snowpack shows that the US’s peaks are shrinking, and that means more wildfires, less drinking water … and less skiing. https://www.wired.com/story/as-snow-disappears-the-sierras-and-rockies-are-shrinking/

December 12, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Quantum Computing Needs You to Help Solve Its Core Mystery Come get your qubits! The builders of quantum computers want more coders to use their machines and figure out what they’re actually good for. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-computing-needs-you-to-help-solve-its-core-mystery/

December 11, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles To Clean Up Space Junk, Some People Grabbed a Net and Harpoon The latest efforts to corral space debris employ a wide-ranging bag of tricks including orbital fishing gear, tiny thrusters, and “space feathers.” https://www.wired.com/story/to-clean-up-space-junk-some-people-grabbed-a-net-and-harpoon/

December 11, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Do You Publish the Work of a Scientific Villain? The scientific community is at a loss over how, and whether, to publish the controversial gene-editing work of He Jiankui. https://www.wired.com/story/how-do-you-publish-the-work-of-a-scientific-villain/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Jonathan WattsJonathan Watts Earth’s Depths Are Teeming With Otherworldly Microbes Scientists have discovered a vast subterranean ecosystem of microbial life deep underground, stretching our sense of life’s limits. https://www.wired.com/story/deep-carbon-observatory-subterranean-ecosystems/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Science of Growing a Perfect Christmas Tree Is your tree robust to cold? Do its needles cling to their branches? Christmas tree scientists ask these questions so we don’t have to. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-of-growing-a-perfect-christmas-tree/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain An Energy Evolution: From Delicious to Dirty to Almost Free A warp-speed history of our quest for cheap energy, from prehistoric hunters to climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/an-energy-evolution-from-delicious-to-dirty-to-almost-free/

December 10, 2018 | Author: Jon GertnerJon Gertner The Race to Understand Antarctica’s Most Terrifying Glacier The Thwaites Glacier is crumbling into the sea. Now scientists must answer two questions: When will it take the plunge? And can our coastal cities be saved? https://www.wired.com/story/antarctica-thwaites-glacier-breaking-point/

December 9, 2018 | Author: Anil AnanthaswamyAnil Ananthaswamy A New Quantum Paradox Flags Errors in Our View of Reality A weird thought experiment has shaken up the world of quantum physics by calling into question our assumptions about how the world works. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-quantum-paradox-flags-errors-in-our-view-of-reality/

December 7, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers What Causes Hangovers, and How Can I Avoid Them? No one really knows how drunkenness works, and hangovers are poorly understood, no matter what your friend tells you. Still, there are a few things you can try. https://www.wired.com/story/know-it-alls-what-causes-hangovers-how-can-i-avoid-them/

December 7, 2018 | Author: Eben KirkseyEben Kirksey Even China Roundly Condemns Editing the Genes of Babies Chinese scientists and regulators alike are censuring the rogue biophysicist who allowed two Crispr-edited babies to be born. https://www.wired.com/story/even-china-roundly-condemns-editing-the-genes-of-babies/

December 7, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The SpaceX ‘Clown Car’ Launch Actually Worked—Here’s How Go behind the scenes with Spaceflight Industries, the space travel agency of sorts that coordinated a jam-packed Falcon 9 flight earlier this week. https://www.wired.com/story/the-spacex-clown-car-launch-actually-workedheres-how/

December 6, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Apple’s Newest Watch Features Will Transform Heart Health For better or worse. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-watch-heart-monitoring-pros-and-cons/

December 6, 2018 | Author: Shannon OsakaShannon Osaka A Global Climate Summit Is Surrounded by All Things Coal This week’s COP24 climate talks in Katowice, Poland, are taking place in a region that is not at all prepared to quit its coal addiction. https://www.wired.com/story/a-global-climate-summit-is-surrounded-by-all-things-coal/

December 5, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX’s Failed Landing Still Ended With a Clean Plop On its 20th flight this year, SpaceX failed to set its booster down on a landing pad. But this rare mishap also showed how many things went well. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-first-failed-ground-landing-ended-in-ocean/

December 5, 2018 | Author: Eric J. WallaceEric J. Wallace America’s Cornfields Are Making the Weather Really Weird Large-scale corn production seems to be triggering more rain, increasing farmers’ yields. But hey, it’s climate change, so there’s also—always—a dark side. https://www.wired.com/story/corn-fields-are-making-it-rain-more/

December 5, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles A SpaceX Delivery Capsule May Be Contaminating the ISS Contamination sensors have spiked after several SpaceX arrivals at the International Space Station, suggesting that ISS instruments could be at risk. https://www.wired.com/story/a-spacex-delivery-capsule-may-be-contaminating-the-iss/

December 4, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Kyrie Irving’s Crazy Lean (Sort of) Explained by Physics In a video, the Boston Celtics player stands on a basketball court and leans… and leans. Here’s how to parse the mystery of why he doesn’t fall. https://www.wired.com/story/kyrie-irving-crazy-lean-sort-of-explained-by-physics/

December 4, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler China Is Both the Best and Worst Hope for Clean Energy China is the world’s biggest polluter but a leader in renewable energy, making it the country to watch at this week’s climate summit in Poland. https://www.wired.com/story/china-is-best-worst-hope-at-cop24-climate-summit/

December 3, 2018 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber Thousands of Unstudied Plants May Be at Risk of Extinction Plants often get short shrift in conservation circles, but machine learning could help botanists save tens of thousands of species. https://www.wired.com/story/thousands-of-unstudied-plants-may-be-at-risk-of-extinction/

December 3, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez NASA’s OSIRIS-REx Spacecraft Just Arrived at Asteroid Bennu The space rock could hold clues to the origins of our solar system, and maybe even life on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/osiris-rex-bennu-arrival/

December 3, 2018 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Here’s a Way to Fight Climate Change: Empower Women Women are disproportionately affected by climate change, says environmentalist Katharine Wilkinson, but she says there are three distinct ways to make a difference. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-a-way-to-fight-climate-change-empower-women/

December 2, 2018 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich The Collector Who Finds Startling Objects in Plain Sight Tadashi Tokieda discovers new physical phenomena by looking at the everyday world through the eyes of a child. https://www.wired.com/story/tadashi-tokieda-finds-startling-objects-in-plain-sight/

December 1, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Watch SpaceX Attempt Its Wickedly Complex Satellite Launch With more than 60 satellites jammed in for the ride, a Falcon 9 rocket will get used a third time, fulfilling one of Elon Musk’s standing promises. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-spacex-attempt-its-wickedly-complex-satellite-launch/

November 30, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni US Biotech Firms Made China’s Gene-Edited Babies Possible Even Crispr babies have a global supply chain. https://www.wired.com/story/us-biotech-firms-made-chinese-crispr-babies-possible/

November 30, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Would It Take to Shoot a Cannonball Into Orbit? We did the math on a famous thought experiment by Isaac Newton involving a very tall mountain, a wicked fast cannonball, and good old gravity. https://www.wired.com/story/what-would-it-take-to-shoot-a-cannonball-into-orbit/

November 29, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Aquaman’s Insane Leap out of Water Has One Foot in Reality In the new Aquaman trailer, the superhero bounds from the water and lands on a submarine. It’s a fantastical leap grounded in serious physics. https://www.wired.com/story/aquaman-trailer-physics/

November 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Supercomputers Can Help Fix Our Wildfire Problem Fires spread with a complexity that scientists can pick apart little by little, thanks to lasers, sensors, and some of the most powerful computers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-supercomputers-can-help-fix-our-wildfire-problem/

November 29, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Mercury Pollution Is Way Up. One Huge Culprit? Gold Mines The first big international effort to combat mercury pollution is zeroing in on small gold mines, which account for almost half of annual emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/mercury-poisoning-gold-mines/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Climate Apocalypse Is Now, and It’s Happening to You Goodbye, Arctic. Hello, heat stroke and asthma attacks. New climate reports connect the dots between predictions and your life—today. https://www.wired.com/story/the-climate-apocalypse-is-now-and-its-happening-to-you/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez What’s the Fastest 100 Meter Dash a Human Can Run? History’s best time, set by Usain Bolt, is 9.58 seconds. Depending on how you parse the data, he’s either rather close—or worlds away—from the theoretical limit. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-100-meter-dash/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Timothy SohnTimothy Sohn SpaceX Is Launching a Piece of Art Into Orbit Artist Trevor Paglen has built a balloon satellite intended to evoke awe and wonder back on Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-is-launching-a-piece-of-art-into-orbit/

November 28, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Rogue Scientist Says Another Crispr Pregnancy Is Underway Chinese researcher He Jiankui, who earlier claimed to have gene-edited twin baby girls, now says there’s another pregnancy with a Crispr’d embryo. https://www.wired.com/story/he-jiankui-gene-editing-crispr-second-pregnancy/

November 27, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Scientist Who Crispr’d Babies Bucked His Own Ethics Policy He Jiankiu, a Chinese researcher who claims to have edited the DNA of twin babies, now born, also published ethics guidelines directly contradicting his work. https://www.wired.com/story/he-jiankui-crispr-babies-bucked-own-ethics-policy/

November 27, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Try Landing InSight on Mars (Without Exploding) NASA just plopped a lander on the surface of Mars. This simple game lets you see if you can do the same. https://www.wired.com/story/try-landing-insight-on-mars-without-exploding/

November 27, 2018 | Author: Mark HarrisMark Harris SpaceX’s Next Launch Will Spark a Space Internet Showdown An unusual SpaceX launch will carry several startups’ satellites, some of which will jockey to provide dirt-cheap internet for earthbound IoT sensors. https://www.wired.com/story/spacexs-next-launch-will-spark-a-space-internet-showdown/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The View From the Control Room: How InSight Landed on Mars Inside Mission Support at Lockheed Martin, which led spacecraft operations for NASA’s InSight lander, tensions ran high as the robot prepared to touch down on martian soil. https://www.wired.com/story/the-view-from-the-control-room-how-insight-landed-on-mars/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Touchdown on Mars! NASA Lands Its InSight Spacecraft NASA’s Mars lander, called InSight, landed on the red planet and sent its first image of the Mars surface. https://www.wired.com/story/mars-nasa-insight-touchdown-landing/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Watch Live as NASA’s InSight Lander Descends to Mars These livestreams will let you follow along as the InSight spacecraft lowers itself to the surface of Mars. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-live-as-nasas-insight-lander-descends-to-mars/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Inside the Lab Training Genome Surgeons to Fight Disease At the Gladstone Institutes, Crispr pioneer Jennifer Doudna is trying to make genome editing a routine procedure. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-lab-training-crispr-genome-surgeons-to-fight-disease/

November 26, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Cities Have Turned Into Fire Bait—But We Can Fix Them We stopped American cities from burning once, and we can do it again. But it’ll take a massive shift in behavior statewide. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-have-turned-into-fire-bait-but-we-can-fix-them/

November 25, 2018 | Author: Adrienne Rose BitarAdrienne Rose Bitar The Government’s Role in the Rise of Lab-Grown Meat Opinion: What America’s history with whale casserole and “mush croquettes” tells us about the future of plant-based meat. https://www.wired.com/story/fda-labeling-on-lab-grown-meat/

November 25, 2018 | Author: Shannon HallShannon Hall Unexpectedly Vanishing Quasars Are Mystifying Scientists Some quasars, powered by supermassive black holes, have been shutting down ahead of schedule. A sort of “murder-suicide pact” could explain it. https://www.wired.com/story/unexpectedly-vanishing-quasars-are-mystifying-scientists/

November 23, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Government Climate Study Contradicts the President A massive new federal report describes a country in ecological collapse and infrastructural ruin by 2100. They released it on Black Friday. https://www.wired.com/story/a-government-climate-study-contradicts-the-president/

November 23, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez NASA Will Land InSight on Mars With Cunning—and Lots of Cork The latest robot to visit the red planet is built to withstand dust storms and temperatures that can melt steel during entry, descent, and landing. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-mars-insight-entry-descent-landing/

November 23, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How and Where to Watch NASA’s InSight Finally Land on Mars Here are the best livestreams and watch parties to keep tabs on the spacecraft as it completes its Mars landing Monday. https://www.wired.com/story/how-and-where-to-watch-nasas-insight-finally-land-on-mars/

November 22, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Deconstruct a Football Tackle With Physics Using video of a football collision, you can figure out the velocity and momentum of the players involved. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-deconstruct-a-football-tackle-with-physics/

November 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Should I Tell My Relative Who Wants to Try Cannabis? Make sure they know the difference between THC and CDB, and remember: Low and slow https://www.wired.com/story/the-know-it-alls-relative-wants-to-try-weed/

November 21, 2018 | Author: Maryn McKennaMaryn McKenna Did the CDC Really Just Ban … Romaine Lettuce? Not exactly, but you should definitely throw yours away. Plus: A brief history of E. coli outbreaks https://www.wired.com/story/cdc-romaine-lettuce-ecoli-thanksgiving/

November 21, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler When Did Fish Learn to Walk? Antarctica May Hold the Answer Fossil hunters are launching an Antarctic expedition to learn how fish developed into land animals. https://www.wired.com/story/fish-learn-to-walk-antarctica-evolution-tetrapods/

November 21, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Thanksgiving, Ditch the Food Psychology Cornell scientist Brian Wansink rocketed to fame by crafting easy, appealing rules on how to avoid overeating. Turns out, though, they’re probably not all true. https://www.wired.com/story/this-thanksgiving-ditch-the-food-psychology/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Cosmology Is in Crisis Over How to Measure the Universe A raging debate over the Hubble constant suggests that our standard model of cosmology might be wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/cosmology-is-in-crisis-over-how-to-measure-the-universe/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Andy Coravos Andy Coravos The Doctor Prescribes Video Games and Virtual Reality Rehab Opinion: Scientifically-backed software is slowly supplanting drugs. https://www.wired.com/story/prescription-video-games-and-vr-rehab/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon California Fire Survivors Brace for Debris-Filled Mudslides The rains are coming to California, and the fires have primed the soil for another disaster that can claim yet more lives. https://www.wired.com/story/california-fire-survivors-brace-for-debris-filled-mudslides/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil 3 Smart Things About Our Sixth, Inner Sense Beyond sight, hearing, smell, taste, and touch, we have a sixth sense that allows us to perceive ourselves. https://www.wired.com/story/3-smart-things-sixth-inner-sense/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee Giant Lasers Bring Distant Twinkling Stars Into Sharp Focus Earthbound beams of light help a telescope stabilize flickering from afar. https://www.wired.com/story/giant-lasers-distant-twinkling-stars-focus/

November 20, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil Eyes and Ears 3D-Printed From Flesh Could Boost Our Senses Michael McAlpine, a mechanical engineer at the University of Minnesota, has spent the past six years making a less synthetic kind of prosthetic. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-printed-flesh-body-parts/

November 19, 2018 | Author: Amelia UrryAmelia Urry Thin, Flexible New Solar Cells Could Soon Line Your Shirt A new kind of solar cell called a perovskite is improving rapidly, bringing the prospect of solar-powered vehicles, clothing, and windows closer to reality. https://www.wired.com/story/thin-flexible-new-solar-cells-could-soon-line-your-shirt/

November 19, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Now You Can Sequence Your Whole Genome for Just $200 Veritas is offering DNA reading, cheap, for two days. But most consumers don’t understand the difference between that and a 23andMe test. https://www.wired.com/story/whole-genome-sequencing-cost-200-dollars/

November 18, 2018 | Author: Viviane CallierViviane Callier The Evolutionary Importance of Neutral vs. Adaptive Genes For 50 years, evolutionary theory has emphasized the importance of neutral mutations over adaptive ones in DNA. Real genomic data challenge that assumption. https://www.wired.com/story/quanta-neutral-vs-adaptive-evolution/

November 16, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Kilogram Redefined. The Metric System Overhaul Is Complete The platinum-iridium cylinder has been scrapped, and the kilogram will now be determined by the Planck constant. https://www.wired.com/story/new-kilogram-definition-based-on-planck-constant/

November 16, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Your Drone Can Give Cops a Surprising Amount of Your Data Crime investigators are gleaning a host of personal information from a recovered drone, such as where its owner lives, credit card numbers, and email addresses. https://www.wired.com/story/your-drone-can-give-cops-a-surprising-amount-of-your-data/

November 16, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni These DNA Startups Want to Put All of You on the Blockchain Two different marketplaces for genetic data, Nebula and EncrypGen, recently launched with the promise of better protections for their users. https://www.wired.com/story/these-dna-startups-want-to-put-all-of-you-on-the-blockchain/

November 15, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Expanse Gets Artificial Gravity Right in This Neat Trick In a scene from season one, Jim Holden shows exquisite command of high school physics as he maneuvers himself onto a spaceship gangway. https://www.wired.com/story/the-expanse-gets-artificial-gravity-right-in-this-neat-trick/

November 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How California Needs to Adapt to Survive Future Fires The Golden State is burning for very good reasons, like climate change and population growth. But it doesn’t have to be this way. https://www.wired.com/story/how-california-needs-to-adapt-to-survive-future-fires/

November 15, 2018 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Construction Workers Toil Away in San Francisco’s Toxic Air Smoke from the raging Camp Fire continues to blanket the region, but outdoor workers are largely doing their jobs without protection—with increasing risks as these conditions become the norm. https://www.wired.com/story/construction-workers-toil-away-in-san-franciscos-toxic-air/

November 14, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Is California’s Smoke Getting Worse? It’s Complicated Wildfire smoke is more complex than most people realize. https://www.wired.com/story/is-californias-smoke-getting-worse-its-complicated/

November 14, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Cities Grab Onto Hurricanes; Buildings Make the Rain Worse Climate change makes hurricanes more intense, but new research on Hurricane Harvey says that the literal shape of the cities they land on makes their rainfall worse. https://www.wired.com/story/cities-cause-hurricanes-to-dump-extra-rain-on-them/

November 14, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Chemical Is So Hot It Destroys Nerve Endings—in a Good Way Resiniferatoxin is 10,000 times hotter than the hottest pepper, and has features that make it promising as a painkiller of last resort. https://www.wired.com/story/resiniferatoxin/

November 13, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You, Too, Can Have Superpowers—Just Hop in a Swimming Pool The buoyancy force gives you the boost that helps you float and do cool maneuvers in water. This experiment lets you see it in action. https://www.wired.com/story/you-too-can-have-superpowers-just-hop-in-a-swimming-pool/

November 13, 2018 | Author: Shaun RavivShaun Raviv The Genius Neuroscientist Who Might Hold the Key to True AI Karl Friston’s free energy principle might be the most all-encompassing idea since Charles Darwin’s theory of natural selection. But to understand it, you need to peer inside the mind of Friston himself. https://www.wired.com/story/karl-friston-free-energy-principle-artificial-intelligence/

November 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Take a Good Look, America. This Is What the Reckoning Looks Like Though we can point to a lack of rainfall to explain the devastation from the fires in California, they’re ultimately a product of a warming world. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-reckoning/

November 12, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Risk That Ebola Will Spread to Uganda Is Now ‘Very High’ With the Ebola outbreak in the Democratic Republic of Congo continuing to spread, neighboring Uganda deploys its health care defenses. https://www.wired.com/story/the-risk-that-ebola-will-spread-to-uganda-is-now-very-high/

November 11, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Wind Patterns Explain Why California’s Wildfires Are So Bad The Camp Fire, Hill Fire, and Woolsey Fire share an origin in the jet stream, which has produced extreme winds that are spreading the flames and hampering firefighting efforts. https://www.wired.com/story/these-wind-patterns-explain-why-californias-wildfires-are-so-bad/

November 11, 2018 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich How an Anonymous 4chan Post Helped Solve a 25-Year-Old Math Puzzle A debate over the most efficient way to watch a cult classic TV series’ episodes, in every possible order, lies at the heart of this mathematical breakthrough. https://www.wired.com/story/how-an-anonymous-4chan-post-helped-solve-a-25-year-old-math-puzzle/

November 9, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Terrifying Science Behind California’s Massive Camp Fire Lots of wind along with very dry vegetation turned the Northern California wildfire into a high-speed menace that tore through Butte County and the town of Paradise. https://www.wired.com/story/the-terrifying-science-behind-californias-massive-camp-fire/

November 9, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Stay Inside, Californians: Wildfire Smoke Is a Big Health Risk Here’s how smoke travels to your lungs and enters your bloodstream—and how you can protect yourself. https://www.wired.com/story/smoke-from-wildfires-is-a-growing-public-health-crisis-for-cities/

November 9, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Was a Star Wars Escape Pod Really Just a KFC Bucket? We can use video analysis to test whether an escape pod carrying R2-D2 and C-3PO in the first Star Wars movie was modeled using a KFC bucket, as one theory claims. https://www.wired.com/story/was-a-star-wars-escape-pod-really-just-a-kfc-bucket/

November 9, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Don’t Want to Fall for Fake News? Don’t Be Lazy An MIT professor argues that misinformation boils down to one simple thing: mental laziness, exacerbated by social media. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-want-to-fall-for-fake-news-dont-be-lazy/

November 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A New Robot Tracks Sick Bees Wearing Tiny Coded Backpacks A novel system monitors the dynamics of colonies exposed to imidacloprid, a neurotoxin that belongs to the infamous neonicotinoid group of pesticides. https://www.wired.com/story/bumblebee-tracking-robot/

November 8, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Aristotle Was Wrong—Very Wrong—But People Still Love Him Centuries-old ideas about force and motion have an intuitive appeal that is enduring but oh-so-incorrect, as these simple experiments show. https://www.wired.com/story/aristotle-was-wrong-very-wrong-but-people-still-love-him/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The House Science Committee May Soon Become… Pro-Science “Hopefully we will no longer see the science committee used as a messaging tool for the fossil fuel industry,” says Rep. Bill Foster, a science committee member. https://www.wired.com/story/the-house-science-committee-may-soon-become-pro-science/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Carbon Tax Is Pretty Much Inevitable, Even if Voters Said No Washington voters will likely shoot down a ballot initiative that would tax carbon emissions, but carbon pricing is still likely to reach the US. https://www.wired.com/story/a-carbon-tax-is-pretty-much-inevitable-even-if-voters-said-no/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Our Climate Is Headed for Disaster, But Voters Still Shrug In the midterm elections, major environmental ballot measures passed in Florida and Nevada, but not in Washington and Arizona. https://www.wired.com/story/our-climate-is-headed-for-disaster-but-voters-still-shrug/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Weed Wins on Election Day. So What Comes Next? A win for marijuana in Michigan, Utah, and Missouri may foreshadow a win for cannabis nationwide. https://www.wired.com/story/weed-wins-on-election-day-so-what-comes-next/

November 7, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles New Satellites Will Use Radio Waves to Spy on Ships and Planes This month, HawkEye 360 will send up satellites that monitor the radio transmissions of ships, planes and other things on Earth, allowing them to be tracked by their communications. https://www.wired.com/story/new-satellites-will-use-radio-waves-to-spy-on-ships-and-planes/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Key to a Long Life Has Little to Do With ‘Good Genes’ Alphabet’s longevity lab Calico trawled through Ancestry’s massive genealogy database to study human longevity—and found that DNA matters less than people have long believed. https://www.wired.com/story/the-key-to-a-long-life-has-little-to-do-with-good-genes/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Make Your Own Scale With a Rubber Band and a Ruler Take some simple measurements, add a dash of algebra, and you basically have a way to measure an unknown mass. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-make-your-own-scale-with-a-rubber-band-and-a-ruler/

November 6, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon THC! CBD! Terpenoids! Cannabis Science Is Getting Hairy Some call it the entourage effect: THC achieves its full effects only when it rolls with a crew of other compounds. https://www.wired.com/story/cannabis-science-entourage-effect/

November 5, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart The Breakthrough Prizes Have Money, but They Need Diversity Too Silicon Valley’s tech-funded science awards are attempting to bring glory to basic research, but so far they have done little to challenge the status quo. https://www.wired.com/story/to-shake-up-science-the-breakthrough-prizes-need-more-than-money/

November 5, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Bitcoin Will Burn the Planet Down. The Question: How Fast? A new paper concludes that it takes more than four times as much energy to mine $1 of bitcoin as mining $1 of copper. https://www.wired.com/story/bitcoin-will-burn-planet-down-how-fast/

November 5, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How Antivax PACs Helped Shape Midterm Ballots With political action committees, the modern antivaccine movement is taking its fight for medical freedoms to the campaign trail. And that has public health experts worried. https://www.wired.com/story/vaccine-choice-pacs-shaping-the-ballot/

November 4, 2018 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Astronomers Creep Up to the Edge of the Milky Way’s Black Hole Hot spots have been discovered orbiting just outside the supermassive black hole at the galaxy’s center. Their motions have given us the closest look at that violent environment. https://www.wired.com/story/quanta-astronomers-milky-way-black-hole/

November 2, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The ISS Has a Supercomputer! Never Mind the Fried Disks After a yearlong test, a supercomputer on the International Space Station has more or less survived and is ready to crunch data. https://www.wired.com/story/the-iss-has-a-supercomputer-never-mind-the-fried-disks/

November 2, 2018 | Author: Nicholas ThompsonNicholas Thompson An Aging Marathoner Tries to Run Fast After 40 Nicholas Thompson had been running marathons for years. At 42, he set out to reverse his slowing speeds with science, tech, and new dedication. https://www.wired.com/story/aging-marathoner-tries-to-run-fast-after-40/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Russia Blames a Bad Sensor for Its Failed Rocket Launch An investigation into the crewed Soyuz rocket that aborted mid-flight blamed the incident on a handling error. https://www.wired.com/story/russia-blames-a-bad-sensor-for-its-failed-rocket-launch/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Sea May Be Absorbing Way More Heat Than We Thought Scientists have developed a radical new method for measuring global warming-induced rising ocean temperatures: They aren’t sampling water, but air. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sea-may-be-absorbing-way-more-heat-than-we-thought/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Quantum Physicists Found a New, Safer Way to Navigate GPS can be hacked, so airplanes and ships need a backup system. These quantum physicists think they have an answer. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-physicists-found-a-new-safer-way-to-navigate/

November 1, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Apple’s Heart Study Is the Biggest Ever, But With a Catch The study enrolled a whopping 400,000 people, but it still won’t answer researchers’ biggest question: whether mass screening does more good than harm. https://www.wired.com/story/apples-heart-study-is-the-biggest-ever-but-with-a-catch/

October 31, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Water, Flour, Syrup, Dye: Mastering the Elements of Fake Blood To make realistic fake blood for Halloween, it helps to understand why actual blood looks and flows the way it does. https://www.wired.com/story/water-flour-syrup-dye-mastering-the-elements-of-fake-blood/

October 31, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Swift Stone Skippers Could in Theory Skip 100s of Skips Kurt Steiner holds the record for the most consecutive skips of a stone—but physics suggests the upper limit is actually much higher. https://www.wired.com/story/swift-stone-skippers-could-in-theory-skip-100s-of-skips/

October 31, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Just How Fast Is the Parker Solar Probe? Astonishingly Fast The probe just broke the record to become the fastest human-made object, relative to the sun. Here’s what that record really means. https://www.wired.com/story/just-how-fast-is-the-parker-solar-probe-astonishingly-fast/

October 31, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Los Angeles Must Pay Billions to Adapt—or Slip Into the Sea It’ll take LA as much as $6.4 billion to fortify itself against an impending increase in coastal flooding, with moves such as nourishing its beaches with extra sand and elevating its ports. https://www.wired.com/story/los-angeles-sea-level-rise/

October 31, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Calling the Caravan’s Migrants “Diseased” Is a Classic Xenophobic Move The migrants almost certainly do not have smallpox or leprosy, a claim that is just the latest attempt to dehumanize foreigners. https://www.wired.com/story/calling-the-caravans-migrants-diseased-is-a-classic-xenophobic-move/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Tiny Drone Uses Friction to Pull More Than Its Own Weight New flying robots can pull loads that appear far too heavy for their tiny size. Here’s the physics of how they cheat friction with their tiny claws and gecko-like grippers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-tiny-drone-can-pull-objects-way-heavier-than-itself/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Science of the Sniff: Why Dogs Are Great Disease Detectors Dogs have been trained to detect a dozen human diseases—most recently, malaria—but even these pups may ultimately find their jobs replaced by machines. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-of-the-sniff-why-dogs-are-great-disease-detectors/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Leor Hackel Gregg SparkmanLeor Hackel Gregg Sparkman Does Climate Change Mean You Should Fly Less? Yeah, Maybe Individual acts like eating less meat or adopting solar power won’t on their own save the planet, but they can inspire new social norms that lead to policy change. https://www.wired.com/story/does-climate-change-mean-you-should-fly-less-yeah-maybe/

October 30, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Boston Dynamics’ Robot Videos Became Internet Gold CEO Marc Raibert shares the backstory of his company’s viral videos and how the internet’s favorite robot dog, SpotMini, came to be. https://www.wired.com/story/how-boston-dynamics-robot-videos-became-internet-gold/

October 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Carbon Capture Is Messy and Fraught—But Might Be Essential A new report calls for more research into carbon capture tech. Problem, though: Who will pay to make it happen? https://www.wired.com/story/carbon-capture-is-messy-and-fraughtbut-might-be-essential/

October 28, 2018 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Huge Achievement in Math Shows the Limits of Symmetries A new proof resolves Zimmer’s conjecture, which has to do with what symmetries can exist in geometric spaces. https://www.wired.com/story/a-huge-achievement-in-math-shows-the-limits-of-symmetries/

October 26, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Trick-or-Treaters Can Stay Visible on a Dark and Spooooky Night Glow sticks and retroreflectors can help your kids be seen on Halloween night. Here’s how they work. https://www.wired.com/story/how-trick-or-treaters-can-stay-visible-on-a-dark-and-spooooky-night/

October 25, 2018 | Author: David HayesDavid Hayes Trump’s Attacks on the Environment Are Mostly Failing The administration’s attempts to remove environmental regulations have made very little headway—though that may soon change. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-attacks-on-the-environment-are-mostly-failing/

October 25, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Make Your Commute as Cheap and Fast as Possible Our calculator will help you figure out the most cost-effective driving speed, personalized to your own commute, wages, and fuel price. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-make-your-commute-as-cheap-and-fast-as-possible/

October 25, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni An Ebola Outbreak in a War Zone Is About as Bad as It Gets No amount of speedy Ebola testing and treatment can match the marauding militias currently tearing up the Democratic Republic of Congo. https://www.wired.com/story/an-ebola-outbreak-in-a-war-zone-is-about-as-bad-as-it-gets/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Oliver MilmanOliver Milman A New Climate Change Lawsuit Takes Aim at ExxonMobil The latest big lawsuit regarding climate change alleges the oil and gas giant defrauded investors by misrepresenting the climate-related risks to its business. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-climate-change-lawsuit-takes-aim-at-exxonmobil/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon These Wasp-Like Drones Lift Heavy Loads With Their Bellies A new class of robots, called FlyCroTugs, can lift objects 40 times their weight, using design ideas borrowed from wasps and geckos. https://www.wired.com/story/wasp-like-drones/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Ginkgo Bioworks Is Turning Human Cells Into On-Demand Factories The synthetic biology company has opened a new foundry to churn out mammal cells, first for drug development, and later to build potentially anything at all. https://www.wired.com/story/ginkgo-bioworks-is-turning-human-cells-into-on-demand-factories/

October 24, 2018 | Author: Adam Rogers, Megan MolteniAdam Rogers and Megan Molteni Trump’s Plan to Redefine Gender Makes No Scientific Sense A leaked memo that proposes to eliminate protections for transgender individuals, in part by relying on genetic testing, is deeply problematic. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-plan-to-redefine-gender-makes-no-scientific-sense/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez New Puffy Coats Are Being Designed to Fall Apart Faster People generate about 70 pounds of textile trash a year, which then sits in landfills for centuries. A new fiber would decompose much, much faster. https://www.wired.com/story/new-puffy-coats-are-being-designed-to-fall-apart-faster/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Science Isn’t About ‘the Truth’—It’s About Building Models These are the three key things that any person should know about the nature of science. https://www.wired.com/story/science-isnt-about-the-truth-its-about-building-models/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Pia CeresPia Ceres 3 Smart Things About Animal-Inspired Robotics From the energy-efficient way turkeys walk to the “invincibility” of a cockroach, critters serve as models for tech. https://www.wired.com/story/3-smart-things-animal-inspired-robotics/

October 23, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil What a Mouse Teaches Us About the Future of 3D Color X-Rays The MARS scanner, armed with particle-detecting tech used in CERN’s Large Hadron Collider, lets us see so much more beyond the bone. https://www.wired.com/story/3d-color-x-rays-mars-cern-mouse/

October 22, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Your Poop Is Probably Full of Plastic A new study suggests that microplastics routinely show up in our food—and our digestive tracts. https://www.wired.com/story/your-poop-is-probably-full-of-plastic/

October 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Scientists Help Robots ‘Evolve.’ Weirdness Ensues Algorithms design robot legs tailored to walk on specific surfaces. The results are at once logical, counterintuitive, and bizarre. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-help-robots-evolve-weirdness-ensues/

October 22, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni DNA Tests Could Help Docs Detect Infectious Diseases Faster It’s still too expensive and unproven, but it has the potential to prevent antibiotic overuse and keep people healthy. https://www.wired.com/story/dna-sequencing-detect-infectious-disease/

October 22, 2018 | Author: Charles GraeberCharles Graeber Meet the Carousing, Harmonica-Playing Texan Who Won a Nobel for his Cancer Breakthrough Jim Allison is an iconoclastic scientist who toiled in obscurity for years. Then he helped crack a mystery that may save millions of lives: Why doesn’t the immune system attack cancer? https://www.wired.com/story/meet-jim-allison-the-texan-who-just-won-a-nobel-cancer-breakthrough/

October 21, 2018 | Author: Ramin SkibbaRamin Skibba ’Oumuamua Was Neither Comet nor Asteroid…So What Was It? Last year’s brief interstellar visit from a cigar-shaped thing named ’Oumuamua is confounding astronomers in new ways. https://www.wired.com/story/oumuamua-was-neither-comet-nor-asteroid-so-what-was-it/

October 19, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Fusty Ol’ Scientific Texts Get a Gorgeous, Pricey Makeover Arty reprints of Newton and Euclid are mostly a gift for your midcentury modern coffee table—but crack them open, and you might learn a thing or two about science too. https://www.wired.com/story/fusty-ol-scientific-texts-get-a-gorgeous-pricey-makeover/

October 19, 2018 | Author: Jason KeheJason Kehe Why the Search for Aliens Could Unite Us Here on Earth Jill Tarter and Maggie Turnbull discuss Trappist-1, the Fermi paradox, and Fast Radio Bursts at Wired25 https://www.wired.com/story/wired-25-search-for-aliens/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni An App Built for Hurricane Harvey Is Now Saving Lives in Florida Crowdsource Rescue, a kind of “Uber for emergencies,” has become the leading tool to coordinate volunteer rescuers, helping them check on hundreds of vulnerable individuals. https://www.wired.com/story/an-app-built-for-hurricane-harvey-is-now-saving-lives-in-florida/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Funky Materials Give the Mantis Shrimp Its Powerful Punch The legendary crustacean uses a hammer-like appendage made of ceramic and polymer to deliver its punishing blow. https://www.wired.com/story/funky-materials-give-the-mantis-shrimp-its-powerful-punch/

October 18, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain For the Last Time: The Difference Between Weight and Mass If we ever move off-planet, we’ll have to get more serious about the difference between ‘mass’ and ‘weight.’ https://www.wired.com/story/think-weight-and-mass-are-the-same-nope-and-heres-why-it-matters/

October 17, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles These New Tricks Can Outsmart Deepfake Videos—for Now We’ll soon find it hard to know with our own eyes if a video is real or generated by AI, but new algorithms are staying one or two steps ahead of the fakers. https://www.wired.com/story/these-new-tricks-can-outsmart-deepfake-videosfor-now/

October 16, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Here’s What Astronauts See When a Rocket Aborts Mid-Flight Nick Hague, the NASA astronaut onboard the Soyuz rocket that failed after takeoff last week, recounts his experience inside the capsule. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-what-astronauts-see-when-a-rocket-aborts-mid-flight/

October 16, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Your Facebook Posts Can Reveal If You’re Depressed Researchers used people’s Facebook data and their medical records to detect early symptoms of a mental health problem. https://www.wired.com/story/your-facebook-posts-can-reveal-if-youre-depressed/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Jack StewartJack Stewart Lifesaving Deliveries Will Get Drones Flying the Skies It’s a lot easier for regulators to understand the need for new frameworks that allow innovations like drones, when every flight could potentially save a life. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-keller-rinaudo/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Big Data and the End of Painful, Invasive Medical Procedures Onstage at WIRED25, 23andMe CEO Anne Wojcicki and bioengineer Stephen Quake focused on unlocking the secrets hidden in blood and spit. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-stephen-quake-anne-wojcicki/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Silicon Valley’s Tech Elite Zoom in on Crispr “Where we are now with biotech feels quite a bit like where we were with information technology in the late 1990s,” said Napster co-founder Sean Parker on stage at WIRED25 https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-sean-parker-alex-marson-jiwoo-lee/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Climate Change Might Double the Cost of a Beer More extreme droughts and heat waves will hit barley especially hard, so growers are trying to hack the grain to make it more resistant. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-might-double-the-cost-of-a-beer/

October 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon You’re Expecting Too Much Out of Boston Dynamics’ Robots Boston Dynamics CEO Marc Raibert doesn’t know exactly how people will use robots like the SpotMini. But at least it can do the running man. https://www.wired.com/story/boston-dynamics-spotmini-running-man/

October 14, 2018 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich A Grad Student Solved a Fundamental Quantum Computing Problem Urmila Mahadev became obsessed with a basic question in quantum computing: how do you know when the computer is cheating? https://www.wired.com/story/a-grad-student-solved-a-fundamental-quantum-computing-problem/

October 12, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Boston Dynamics Is Prepping Its Robot Dog to Get a Job A new video of SpotMini, a quadruped robot, shows the mechanical pup looking more businesslike than usual. https://www.wired.com/story/boston-dynamics-is-prepping-its-robot-dog-to-get-a-job/

October 12, 2018 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Dietary Supplements Can Contain Viagra, Steroids, or Worse When the FDA discovers that a supplement is contaminated, it might issue a voluntary recall—and that’s about where the action stops. https://www.wired.com/story/dietary-supplements-can-contain-viagra-steroids-or-worse/

October 12, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Get Better at ‘Back of the Envelope’ Calculations Estimating answers to everyday physics problems is an art form. Here’s one tip: learn to ignore what you don’t know. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-get-better-at-back-of-the-envelope-calculations/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch Boston Dynamics’ Humanoid Robot Do Parkour A new video of Atlas, the company’s two-legged robot, shows off its agility as it bounds up a platform. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-boston-dynamics-humanoid-robot-do-parkour/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Genome Hackers Show No One’s DNA Is Anonymous Anymore Consumer genomics is making it easier than ever to identify individuals from anonymous DNA databases. Even if you’ve never spit in a tube. https://www.wired.com/story/genome-hackers-show-no-ones-dna-is-anonymous-anymore/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson A Faulty Booster Might Have Sabotaged a Soyuz Rocket Launch The spacecraft’s failure minutes after launch—the second mishap in recent months—raises questions about how people will travel to and from the space station. https://www.wired.com/story/soyuz-rocket-failure-jeopardizes-future-iss-missions/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How Hurricane Michael Got Super Big, Super Fast The phenomenon known as ‘rapid intensification’ used to be rare. With climate change, this most deadly type of hurricane is becoming more common. https://www.wired.com/story/how-hurricane-michael-got-super-big-super-fast/

October 11, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Watch Mouse Embryos Develop Under This 4-D Microscope An unusual new instrument can peer inside a living mammalian embryo and watch its cells grow. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-mouse-embryos-develop-under-this-4-d-microscope/

October 10, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why Hurricane Michael’s Storm Surge Is So High Storm surge depends on wind speed, shoreline shape, and timing. On two out of three, Florida got slammed. https://www.wired.com/story/why-hurricane-michaels-storm-surge-is-so-high/

October 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Quest to Make California’s Weed the Champagne of Cannabis Growers in California want to do for their legendary marijuana what the champagne appellation has done for French bubbly. https://www.wired.com/story/the-quest-to-make-californias-weed-the-champagne-of-cannabis/

October 10, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni So Much Genetic Testing. So Few People to Explain It to You Personal genomics is booming, but there’s a nationwide shortage of genetic counselors who can make sense of that DNA data. https://www.wired.com/story/so-much-genetic-testing-so-few-people-to-explain-it-to-you/

October 9, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Spider-Man Defies Physics When He Falls Backward Off a Plane If you care about the momentum principle, this should bother you. https://www.wired.com/story/spider-man-defies-physics-when-he-falls-backwards-off-a-plane/

October 9, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Bionic Limbs ‘Learn’ to Open a Beer Deep learning is helping to make prosthetic arms behave more naturally. https://www.wired.com/story/bionic-limbs-learn-to-open-a-beer/

October 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We Need Massive Change to Avoid Climate Hell A new IPCC report says we can still hit the target of limiting global warming to 1.5 degree Celsius, as agreed on in Paris, but we have to act immediately and drastically. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-massive-change-to-avoid-climate-hell/

October 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Long Goodbye to Baxter, a Gentle Giant Among Robots Baxter is a legend in these early days of advanced robotics. But now its maker, Rethink Robotics, is folding. https://www.wired.com/story/a-long-goodbye-to-baxter-a-gentle-giant-among-robots/

October 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What One Devastated Community Can Teach the World About Mental Health As the anniversary of the massive wildfires in Northern California arrives, researchers are trying to pinpoint the best ways to treat the anxiety, depression, and trauma left in the disaster’s wake. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfires-mental-health/

October 8, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler STEM Candidates Try to Ride a Pro-Science Wave to Congress At the March for Science, protesters spoke about the importance of getting more scientists in office. Actually winning elections takes a lot more. https://www.wired.com/story/2018-midterms-stem-candidates-pro-science-wave/

October 8, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Sticks Its Landing After a Showy California Launch SpaceX’s latest Falcon rocket launch tore across a perfectly clear night sky as it delivered a satellite into space and returned its booster to a new West Coast landing pad. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-sticks-its-landing-after-a-showy-california-launch/

October 7, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Tonight: Watch SpaceX Try to Land Its First Rocket on California Soil SpaceX intends to launch a Falcon 9, with a souped-up block 5 booster, from Vandenberg Air Force Base. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-plans-to-land-its-first-rocket-on-california-soil/

October 7, 2018 | Author: Rebecca BoyleRebecca Boyle How Are Planets Made? With Very Little Stuff, It Seems Exoplanets are far more massive than the material they’re made of. New evidence suggests our planet-building theories are incomplete. https://www.wired.com/story/how-are-planets-made-with-very-little-stuff-it-seems/

October 6, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Insane Physics of Airbags In a collision, a car’s airbag has a tiny fraction of a second in which to inflate—which is why airbags use explosives. https://www.wired.com/story/the-insane-physics-of-airbags/

October 5, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Condemn Sexism Through ‘Particles for Justice’ About 1,600 signatures have been submitted to a letter protesting a sexist talk given by physicist Alessandro Strumia at CERN last week. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-condemn-sexism-through-particles-for-justice/

October 5, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We’re Destroying the Sea—But It Could Save Us From Ourselves A new review looks at more than 1,000 studies of potential oceanic solutions to climate change. A good idea? Wind energy. Maybe not so good? Loading the sea with iron. https://www.wired.com/story/the-sea-could-save-us-from-ourselves/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez A Mushroom Extract Might Save Bees From a Killer Virus Two types of mushroom seem to help bees fight a major virus contributing to colony collapse disorder. https://www.wired.com/story/a-mushroom-extract-might-save-bees-from-a-killer-virus/

October 4, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Swarms of Supersize Mosquitoes Besiege North Carolina These mosquitoes are monstrous in size, hyperaggressive, and hatching by the millions in the wake of Hurricane Florence. https://www.wired.com/story/north-carolina-fends-off-swarms-of-super-sized-mosquitoes/

October 3, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Chewbacca Falling Out of a Moving Train Chewbacca is tumbling out of a moving train! Han rushes to save him! Turns out, ordinary physics would have saved him, too. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-chewbacca-falling-out-of-a-moving-train/

October 3, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil America’s Clergy Are Teaming Up With Scientists Scientists and religious leaders joined forces to create programs on neuroscience, cosmology—and even some evolutionary science. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-clergy-are-teaming-up-with-scientists/

October 3, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon It’s Time to Talk About Robot Gender Stereotypes How gender biases manifest in the design of voice assistants is well-worn territory. But scientists are just beginning to consider how these gender biases materialize in physical robots. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-gender-stereotypes/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Physicists Win Nobel Prize for Lasers That Stretch, Bend and Blow Up Molecules A trio of laser physicists—Arthur Ashkin, Donna Strickland, and Gérard Mourou—nab the prize for their work on optical tweezers and chirped pulse amplification. https://www.wired.com/story/physicists-win-nobel-prize-for-lasers-that-stretch-bend-and-blow-up-molecules/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez A Brain-Eating Amoeba Just Claimed Another Victim Naegleria fowleri lays waste to cells in the brain, leading to a grisly demise in the very rare cases when it manages to lodge itself in a victim’s nasal cavity. https://www.wired.com/story/naegleria-fowleri-investigation/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Farmers Can Now Buy Designer Microbes to Replace Fertilizer Pivot Bio is the first company to offer US corn farmers a new ‘probiotic for plants’ as a replacement for expensive, greenhouse-gassy fertilizer. https://www.wired.com/story/farmers-can-now-buy-designer-microbes-to-replace-fertilizer/

October 2, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Crawling Dead: How Ants Turn Into Zombies Allow us to explain the gruesome process by which ordinary ants become the pawns of an insidious and spectacularly clever fungus. https://www.wired.com/story/plight-of-the-living-dead/

October 1, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Human Cell Atlas Is Biologists’ Latest Grand Project The goal is to create a massive map of everything we know about all the cells in the human body, like the human genome did with DNA. https://www.wired.com/story/the-human-cell-atlas-is-biologists-latest-grand-project/

October 1, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Launching a Lunar Lander From the Moon’s Surface How fast was the acceleration of NASA’s lunar lander when it took off from the Moon in the Apollo 17 mission? Using video analysis, we can figure that out. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-launching-a-lunar-lander-from-the-moons-surface/

September 30, 2018 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich Math Titans Clash Over Epic Proof of the ABC Conjecture Two mathematicians say they found a glaring hole in a proof that has convulsed the math community for years. https://www.wired.com/story/math-titans-clash-over-epic-proof-of-the-abc-conjecture/

September 28, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Trump’s Auto Emissions Plan Is Full of Faulty Logic A federal proposal to freeze cars’ emissions standards argues that climate change isn’t worth fighting at the tailpipe, but scientific research suggests otherwise. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-auto-emissions-plan-is-full-of-faulty-logic/

September 28, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why a Tennis Ball Goes Flying When Bounced on a Basketball When you bounce a tennis ball off a moving basketball, the tennis ball goes careening off at high speed. Here’s why that happens. https://www.wired.com/story/why-a-tennis-ball-goes-flying-when-bounced-on-a-basketball/

September 28, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart San Francisco’s Dream of ‘Zero Waste’ Lands in the Dumpster The city has reduced its trash more than any other American metropolis. But eliminating all garbage, it turns out, is an impractical goal. https://www.wired.com/story/san-franciscos-dream-of-zero-waste-lands-in-the-dumpster/

September 28, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Darpa Goes Underground for Its Most Daring Robot Extravaganza Yet Darpa is calling it the Subterranean Challenge, but you may as well call it the Death to All Robots Challenge. https://www.wired.com/story/darpa-goes-underground-for-its-most-daring-robot-extravaganza-yet/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Elizabeth Shogren, Susie NeilsonElizabeth Shogren and Susie Neilson The Science Is Clear: Dirty Farm Water Is Making Us Sick Lettuce contaminated with pathogens have sickened and killed people. But the FDA has shelved Obama-era plans to test the culprit: farms’ irrigation water. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-is-clear-dirty-farm-water-is-making-us-sick/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Laser-Carrying Airplanes Uncover Massive, Sprawling Maya Cities Using lidar, archaeologists have mapped the previously unseen ruins of entire Maya cities, revealing new details of their complex civilizations. https://www.wired.com/story/laser-carrying-airplanes-uncover-massive-sprawling-maya-cities/

September 27, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Cats Bad at Nabbing Rats But Feast on Other Beasts Researchers wanted to know what cats would do with a large colony of rats in Brooklyn. The answer: Not much. But cats could still pose a huge threat to more vulnerable urban wildlife. https://www.wired.com/story/rats-vs-cats/

September 26, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Everyone Wants to Go to the Moon Again—Logic Be Damned Space companies and national agencies are all gunning to visit the moon and kick off a bustling lunar economy, but the business case is shaky. https://www.wired.com/story/everyone-wants-to-go-to-the-moon-again-logic-be-damned/

September 26, 2018 | Author: Maria GallucciMaria Gallucci As the Arctic Melts, the Northern Sea Route Opens for Business More container ships on Arctic sea routes will also mean more black soot… and more melting. https://www.wired.com/story/as-the-arctic-melts-the-fabled-northwest-passage-opens-for-cargo-ships/

September 26, 2018 | Author: Stephanie ParkerStephanie Parker Robot Lawnmowers Are Killing Hedgehogs With grass-cutting robots growing increasingly popular in Europe, hedgehogs are more often getting trapped under their blades. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-lawnmowers-are-killing-hedgehogs/

September 25, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Flummoxed by Force and Motion? Try This Physics Experiment Physics class can get painfully abstract. But you can collect your own data to see Newton’s second law in action. https://www.wired.com/story/flummoxed-by-force-and-motion-try-this-physics-experiment/

September 25, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Learn From These Bugs. Don’t Let Social Media Zombify You The idea of “zombie scrolling syndrome” has legs, really. From worms to wasps, nature has figured out mind control—in ways that bring to mind social media. https://www.wired.com/story/learn-from-these-bugs-dont-let-social-media-zombify-you/

September 25, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Creepy-Cute Robot that Picks Peppers With its Face Researchers have developed a robot that roams a greenhouse, eyeballing peppers to determine if they’re mature enough before sawing them off the plant. https://www.wired.com/story/the-creepy-cute-robot-that-picks-peppers/

September 24, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Here’s the Plan to End Malaria With Crispr-Edited Mosquitoes Target Malaria hopes to eradicate Africa’s malaria-carrying mosquitoes. But when manipulating the fate of a species, moving slowly is a virtue. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-the-plan-to-end-malaria-with-crispr-edited-mosquitoes/

September 24, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How The Best Jumpers in the World Fly So Damn High In 2016, Evan Ungar set the box jump world record at 63.5 inches. Here’s how he does it—and how he could go higher. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-vertical-leap/

September 24, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Strange, Sad Case of Sunspot, the Empty Astronomy Town New Mexico’s Sunspot Observatory was evacuated over a child porn investigation. But that’s just one of the forces clearing the place out. https://www.wired.com/story/the-strange-sad-case-of-sunspot-the-empty-astronomy-town/

September 23, 2018 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz Artificial Intelligence Has a Strange New Muse: Our Sense of Smell The brain’s way of processing smells is inspiring scientists to rethink how we design machine learning algorithms. https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-has-a-strange-new-muse-our-sense-of-smell/

September 22, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Shooting Stars and Dwarf Galaxies The universe’s origin story lies in fast-moving and faraway objects. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-dwarf-galaxy/

September 22, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers First It Was a Hurricane. Then Pig Poop. Now It’s Coal Ash North Carolina is being slammed by a succession of disasters triggered by Hurricane Florence. The latest scare is from coal plants, where pools of ash are at risk of spilling into already toxic waters. https://www.wired.com/story/first-it-was-hurricane-florence-then-pig-poop-now-its-coal-ash/

September 21, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Measure Things That Are Astronomically Far Away Light-years, parsecs and more: these are the units for describing distances between planets and other astronomical objects. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-measure-things-that-are-astronomically-far-away/

September 21, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson The Rocket That Gave Us GPS and the Mars Rovers Retires The Delta II rocket was a workhorse, with 153 successful launches and a bevy of wild scientific missions to its credit. https://www.wired.com/story/the-delta-ii-rocket-that-gave-us-gps-and-the-mars-rovers-retires/

September 21, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen This Microscope Shows the Quantum World in Crazy Detail The transmission electron microscope has a new bag of tricks, revealing the properties of materials at a much higher resolution than ever before. https://www.wired.com/story/new-microscope-shows-the-quantum-world-in-crazy-detail/

September 20, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Science Behind Home Disaster Preparedness Kits Is a Disaster Officials are pushing for extreme self-sufficiency when the next hurricane, earthquake, or other catastrophe hits, but the advice can be unclear and impractical. https://www.wired.com/story/the-science-behind-home-disaster-preparedness-kits-is-a-disaster/

September 20, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Invisible Swarms of Particles Envelop Us All. Come Have a Look Scientists have demonstrated a promising technique for measuring and mapping your exposome—the flecks of animate and inanimate stuff that surround you at all times. https://www.wired.com/story/exposome-maps/

September 20, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want a Robot to Really Get a Grip? Make It Like Baymax Inflatable graspers don’t have to be taught how to hold something, the way robo-hands do. https://www.wired.com/story/soft-robots-air-driven-grippers/

September 19, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Wildlife Detective Uses DNA to Link Stolen Ivory to Big Cartels A new method looks at the DNA of elephant tusks to pinpoint the crime networks behind disparate stashes of poached ivory. https://www.wired.com/story/wildlife-detective-uses-dna-to-link-stolen-ivory-to-big-cartels/

September 19, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of a Star Wars Bomber Dropping Bombs in Space The Empire Strikes Back brought us the TIE bomber—and new physics questions to try to solve. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-a-star-wars-bomber-dropping-bombs-in-space/

September 19, 2018 | Author: Saket Navlakha Saket Navlakha Why Animal Extinction Is Crippling Computer Science Opinion: As the work of biologists and computer scientists converge, algorithmic secrets are increasingly found in nature https://www.wired.com/story/why-animal-extinction-is-crippling-computer-science/

September 19, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler This Supple, Squishy Robo-Jellyfish Can Explore Ocean Reefs A new robotic jellyfish can squeeze through holes smaller than its body size. https://www.wired.com/story/supple-squishy-robot-jellyfish-can-explore-ocean-reefs/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Lauren MurrowLauren Murrow 6 Terrific Books for Getting Girls Into Tech Room to Read CEO Geetha Murali on her favorite page-turners for future scientists and engineers. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-susan-wojcicki-geetha-murali-girls-tech-books/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Anthony LydgateAnthony Lydgate Jeff Bezos and the Clock That Will Outlast Civilization This past winter, inside a mountain on the Amazon founder’s West Texas ranch, the Long Now Foundation began assembling its 10,000-year clock. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-jeff-bezos-10000-year-clock-civilization/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Why DNA Is the Most Exciting Programming Language Today Napster cofounder Sean Parker and biologist Alex Marson on the coming power of Crispr. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-sean-parker-alex-marson-crispr-dna-programming/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles E.T. Hunters Join Forces to Probe the Heavens SETI Institute cofounder Jill Tarter doesn’t want her former intern to forget about intelligent aliens. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-jill-tarter-margaret-turnbull-space-aliens-technology/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Katie M. PalmerKatie M. Palmer Why the Gene Editors of Tomorrow Need to Study Ethics Today Jennifer Doudna says the next generation of biologists will be our first line of defense against Crispr gone wild. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-jennifer-doudna-jiwoo-lee-crispr-gene-editing-ethics/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Jennifer KahnJennifer Kahn Marc Benioff Bets on Cleanup Tech for Ocean Trash Boyan Slat’s tubular new contraption is designed to take on the oceans’ garbage gyres. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-marc-benioff-boyan-slat-ocean-cleanup-plastic/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats Jargon Watch: Silicages Could Make Gene Therapy Less Risky Silicage: A nanostructure made of silica that may provide a safer carrier for gene therapy. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-silicage-gene-therapy-jargon-watch/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Anthony LydgateAnthony Lydgate To an AI, Every Eye Tells a Story Algorithms can reveal when patients are going blind—but that’s just the beginning. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-sundar-pichai-r-kim-artificial-intelligence-vision/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Bill GatesBill Gates Bill Gates on How Blood Will Soon Tell Us Everything Cheap, easy tests will replace expensive medical screenings and make health care more accessible for people everywhere. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-bill-gates-stephen-quake-blood-tests/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Janelle AyresJanelle Ayres Enlisting Our Own Germs to Help Us Battle Infections Biologist Janelle Ayres on how the body’s own bugs may be our best defense. https://www.wired.com/story/wired25-elizabeth-blackburn-janelle-ayres-new-infection-treatment/

September 18, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Will Send Yusaku Maezawa (and Artists!) to the Moon Elon Musk introduced the Japanese billionaire as the mystery passenger who booked a trip to the moon aboard SpaceX’s BFR rocket, along with a half-dozen artists he plans to invite. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-will-send-yusaku-maezawa-and-artists-to-the-moon/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Who You Calling a Blood Moon? What do all of these “rare” moon terms really mean? https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/blood-moon-supermoon-explainer/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Tonight: Watch SpaceX Announce Its First Passenger to the Moon Here’s how to watch live as CEO Elon Musk reveals the first customer it will take to the moon aboard its BFR rocket, among other details. https://www.wired.com/story/tonight-watch-spacex-announce-its-first-passenger-to-the-moon/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Google AI Tool Identifies a Tumor’s Mutations From an Image The algorithm can distinguish between different kinds of lung cancer, and could speed up a patient’s diagnosis by weeks. https://www.wired.com/story/google-ai-tool-identifies-a-tumors-mutations-from-an-image/

September 17, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon At the Edge of the World, Facing the End of the World Want to feel better about climate change? Last week’s climate summit showed that the most ambitious action isn’t happening on the national scale—it’s cities and states that are leading the way. https://www.wired.com/story/at-the-edge-of-the-world-facing-the-end-of-the-world/

September 16, 2018 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch Astronomers Have Found the Universe’s Missing Matter For decades, some of the atomic matter in the universe had not been located. Recent papers reveal where it’s been hiding. https://www.wired.com/story/astronomers-have-found-the-universes-missing-matter/

September 15, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Easily Locate the Accelerometer in an iPhone Don’t take apart your phone! Circular motion, an app to record sensor data, and some physics is all you need. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-easily-locate-the-accelerometer-in-an-iphone/

September 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Los Angeles Is Helping Lead the Fight Against Climate Change Los Angeles mayor Eric Garcetti sits down with WIRED to talk about how to turn LA into a greentech testbed, why cities have to compete in order to save the world, and what the city can learn from its infamous water wars. https://www.wired.com/story/how-los-angeles-is-helping-lead-the-fight-against-climate-change/

September 14, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart Hurricane Florence Threatens to Spread Hog Poop Over North Carolina Big pools of pig excrement, a byproduct of the state’s many hog farms, sit in the path of Hurricane Florence. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-florence-threatens-to-spread-hog-poop-over-north-carolina/

September 14, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler New Satellite’s Lasers Will Track Tiny Changes in Polar Ice NASA’s ICESat-2 will watch over the planet’s polar ice to improve forecasts of sea level rise. https://www.wired.com/story/new-nasa-satellites-lasers-will-track-tiny-changes-in-polar-ice/

September 14, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers An Equator Full of Hurricanes Shows a Preview of End Times The climate has changed, and our planet is growing less habitable. https://www.wired.com/story/an-equator-full-of-hurricanes-shows-a-preview-of-end-times/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Trump’s Disregard of Puerto Rico’s Death Toll Is Putting Lives at Risk President Trump’s tweet about the death toll in Puerto Rico is worse than a lie. It means we’ll never learn from past disasters, repeating devastating mistakes. https://www.wired.com/story/trumps-disregard-of-puerto-ricos-death-toll-is-putting-lives-at-risk/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Nuclear Plant Braces for Impact With Hurricane Florence In North Carolina, a nuclear power plant sits right in the hurricane’s path, creating a high-stakes test of its post-Fukushima safety measures. https://www.wired.com/story/a-nuclear-plant-braces-for-impact-with-hurricane-florence/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A New Robotic Fly Dips and Dives Like the Real Thing Inspired by a fruit fly, this robot insect manages to twist and bank with astonishing speed. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-robotic-fly-dips-and-dives-like-the-real-thing/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Emissions Have Already Peaked in 27 Cities—And Keep Falling At the Global Climate Action Summit, a coalition of cities says it’s made big progress in combating climate change. https://www.wired.com/story/emissions-have-already-peaked-in-27-cities-and-keep-falling/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The New ECG Apple Watch Could Do More Harm Than Good For folks with atrial fibrillation, Apple’s new wearable could actually be useful. For everyone else, evidence suggests otherwise. https://www.wired.com/story/ecg-apple-watch/

September 13, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Underwater Drones Track Hurricane Florence’s Trajectory A new tool called a Slocum glider measures the ocean heat that fuels super-storms like Florence, filling in data gaps to help make forecasting more accurate. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-florence-underwater-drone-slocum-glider/

September 12, 2018 | Author: Jenavieve HatchJenavieve Hatch North Carolina Chose to Ignore Its Dangerous Sea Levels Years Before Hurricane Florence Hit Six years ago, North Carolina’s politicians shot down a report on its rising sea levels. Now it prepares for disaster. https://www.wired.com/story/north-carolina-chose-to-ignore-its-dangerous-sea-levels-years-before-hurricane-florence-hit/

September 12, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How Our Biological Clock Could Dictate Medical Treatments Two new studies bring us closer to finding the optimal time, according to our internal clocks, to pop a pill—or maybe even schedule surgery. https://www.wired.com/story/how-our-biological-clock-could-dictate-medical-treatments/

September 12, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler You Can Drink Champagne in Space—Yes, Really Champagne maker Mumm is testing a piston-activated bottle on zero-G flights. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-drink-champagne-in-space/

September 12, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Yes, You Can Boil Water at Room Temperature. Here’s How Everything you ever wanted to know about boiling water, vapor pressure, and cooking at altitude. https://www.wired.com/story/yes-you-can-boil-water-at-room-temperature-heres-how/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr’s Epic Patent Fight Changed the Course of Biology The Crispr-Cas9 intellectual property battle forced scientists to innovate quickly, rendering the expensive, drawn-out legal process nearly irrelevant. https://www.wired.com/story/crisprs-epic-patent-fight-changed-the-course-of-biology/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Law Alone Won’t Get California to 100 Percent Green Power The state’s already ambitious efforts to fight climate change may get more juice—but tech and policy will have to play catch-up. https://www.wired.com/story/a-law-alone-wont-get-california-to-100-percent-green-power/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers We Know Exactly How to Stop Wildfires—With Money Wildfires would be much less destructive if forests were managed actively, with controlled burns and by culling trees and undergrowth. But someone has to pay for that. https://www.wired.com/story/we-know-exactly-how-to-stop-wildfires-with-money/

September 11, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez When Your Phone Sucks You Into the Void, This App Notices Flipd is designed to build awareness of all the ways you subconsciously waste time on your phone. https://www.wired.com/story/psychology-of-flipd-digital-detox-app/

September 10, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles New Space Robots Will Fix Satellites, or Maybe Destroy Them Upcoming “service” satellites will be like doctors for older, ailing satellites. Should they take the Hippocratic oath? https://www.wired.com/story/new-space-robots-will-fix-satellites-or-maybe-destroy-them/

September 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This One-Armed Robot Is Super Manipulative (in a Good Way) Researchers have taught a robot to fish for boots, like in the cartoons. That could be big news for robots still struggling to get a grip on our complicated world. https://www.wired.com/story/this-one-armed-robot-is-super-manipulative-in-a-good-way/

September 9, 2018 | Author: Charlie WoodCharlie Wood Meet The Four-Dimensional Numbers That Led to Modern Algebra Strange, long-forgotten numbers called quaternions are undergoing a revival in computer graphics, math, and physics. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-four-dimensional-numbers-that-led-to-modern-algebra/

September 8, 2018 | Author: Eric HolthausEric Holthaus Wisconsin’s Floods Are Catastrophic—and Only Getting Worse Record rainfall and flooding have been “absolutely unbelievable to witness,” says a local climate scientist. https://www.wired.com/story/wisconsins-floods-are-catastrophic-and-only-getting-worse/

September 7, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe Cuts Off the DNA App Ecosystem It Created Fearing pseudoscience and privacy breaches, 23andMe is shutting down access to the third-party diet, fitness and other apps that relied on its data. https://www.wired.com/story/23andme-cuts-off-the-dna-app-ecosystem-it-created/

September 7, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A 600-Meter-Long Plastic Catcher Heads to Sea, but Scientists Are Skeptical Ocean Cleanup has raised $40 million to deploy a massive device to capture plastic pollution. But many scientists don’t think the plan holds water. https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-cleanup-skeptical-scientists/

September 6, 2018 | Author: Jane C. HuJane C. Hu Mission Unstoppable: Inside the All-Female Trek to the North Pole A dozen women brave polar bears and frostbite to walk, ski, and trudge to the top of the world. It’s a bonding exercise, yes, but also a unique chance to study the female body in extremis. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-all-female-trek-to-north-pole/

September 6, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Fall Is Here! Time to Learn the Physics of … Falling Stuff is constantly falling—off tables, out of bags, from the sky. Let’s explore the science of all things tumbling downward. https://www.wired.com/story/fall-is-here-time-to-learn-the-physics-of-falling/

September 6, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Hyper-Real Robot Will Cry and Bleed on Med Students A new robot named Hal is sending medical training straight into the uncanny valley. https://www.wired.com/story/hal-robot/

September 5, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Startups Flock to Turn Young Blood Into an Elixir of Youth A new startup, Elevian, is joining a host of other companies trying to disrupt death. https://www.wired.com/story/startups-flock-to-turn-young-blood-into-an-elixir-of-youth/

September 5, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles America’s Spaceport Boom Is Outpacing the Need to Go to Space Cities are building spaceports to try to attract aerospace companies, even if no one’s launching much these days. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-spaceport-boom-is-outpacing-the-need-to-go-to-space/

September 5, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Why Scientists Are Using Frog Eggs to Power Tiny Electronics Medical microbots might power themselves off our own cells, if this research pans out. https://www.wired.com/story/why-scientists-are-using-frog-eggs-to-power-tiny-electronics/

September 4, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Clever and Simple Robot Hand Researchers have developed a simple, yet capable hand that promises to help robots get a grip at a fraction of the price. https://www.wired.com/story/a-clever-and-simple-robot-hand/

September 3, 2018 | Author: Marcia BjornerudMarcia Bjornerud Geology Is Like Augmented Reality for the Planet Rock slabs may seem boring, but a geologic lens can immerse you in Earth’s deep past and future. https://www.wired.com/story/geology-is-like-augmented-reality-for-the-planet/

September 2, 2018 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz To Heal Wounds, Cells Time-Travel Back to a Fetal State Cells can reprogram themselves after an injury much more radically than people thought. https://www.wired.com/story/to-heal-wounds-cells-time-travel-back-to-a-fetal-state/

September 1, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Inside the Nebulae Where Stars Are Born Far-off clouds of gas and dust are the eye-popping birthplaces of new stars. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-inside-the-nebulae-where-stars-are-born/

August 31, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Far Out! Worms May Dose Mice With Cannabinoids to Kill the Pain One parasitic worm’s devilish strategy may reduce inflammation and discomfort in its mouse host. Trippy, man… https://www.wired.com/story/worms-cannabinoids/

August 31, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Here’s How Fast That Jumping Tesla Was Traveling A Tesla was caught on video going airborne after blasting over railroad tracks. Here’s how to estimate its speed. https://www.wired.com/story/heres-how-fast-that-jumping-tesla-was-traveling/

August 30, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr Halted Muscular Dystrophy in Dogs. Are Humans Next? Gene editing halted the progression of Duchenne’s muscular dystrophy in dogs https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-halted-muscular-dystrophy-in-dogs-someday-it-might-cure-humans/

August 30, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Big Can a Solar-Powered Drone Be? Students in Singapore built a quadcopter that runs on solar power. Here’s how to build your own. https://www.wired.com/story/how-big-can-a-solar-powered-drone-be/

August 29, 2018 | Author: Michele Cohen MarillMichele Cohen Marill 98.6 Degrees Is a Normal Body Temperature, Right? Not Quite Fever is a more flexible concept than previously thought, as new crowdsourced data show. https://www.wired.com/story/98-degrees-is-a-normal-body-temperature-right-not-quite/

August 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What if Ketamine Actually Works Like an Opioid? Researchers report that ketamine may be working on the brain’s opioid system. The study is small, but if replicated, the findings could have big implications for the treatment of depression. https://www.wired.com/story/ketamine-opioid/

August 28, 2018 | Author: Jennifer ChausseeJennifer Chaussee Starbucks’ Pumpkin Spice Latte Is Back to Mess With Your Brain The real reasons why these frothy, fatty drinks are so devilishly addictive. https://www.wired.com/story/starbucks-pumpkin-spice-latte-is-back-to-mess-with-your-brain/

August 28, 2018 | Author: Kate YoderKate Yoder Your Next Weather Apocalypse: The Smokestorm Atmospheric scientist Cliff Mass coined the word “smokestorm” to describe city-choking air conditions. Here’s what he says we need to do to prevent another one. https://www.wired.com/story/smokestorm/

August 27, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Science Behind Social Science Gets Shaken Up—Again An attempt to replicate some of the decade’s best research shows some of it … doesn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/social-science-reproducibility/

August 27, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Meet the Rose Hip Cell, a New Kind of Neuron Transcriptome sequencing technologies are opening the doors to a new era of cellular discovery, and not just in the brain. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-rosehip-cell-a-new-kind-of-neuron/

August 27, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Falling Into a Black Hole This week, newspapers reported that a man had fallen into an art installation consisting of an 8-foot-deep circular hole painted black. It’s kinda not his fault. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-falling-into-a-black-hole/

August 26, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles China Built the World’s Largest Telescope. Then Came the Tourists Thousands of people moved to let China build and protect the world’s largest telescope. And then the government drew in orders of magnitude more tourists, potentially undercutting its own science in an attempt to promote it. https://www.wired.com/story/china-fast-worlds-largest-telescope-tourists/

August 25, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Hubble Sees Things a Long Time Ago …They Are Galaxies Far, Far Away https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-hubble-photos/

August 25, 2018 | Author: Veronique GreenwoodVeronique Greenwood You Are Getting Sleepy—Tagged Proteins May Point to Why The identification of SNIPPs, a set of proteins found primarily at the brain’s synapses, brings science closer to understanding why we need to sleep. https://www.wired.com/story/why-you-get-sleepy/

August 24, 2018 | Author: Laura MalloneeLaura Mallonee The Spiky Simulator That Will Help Find Oceans in Space The Hybrid European Radio Frequency and Antenna Test Zone, or HERTZ, can mimic signals hurtling at light speed through 500 million miles of space. https://www.wired.com/story/the-spiky-simulator-that-will-help-find-oceans-in-space/

August 24, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Gear That Could Solve the Next Big Wildfire Whodunit Wildfire investigators retrace a fire’s path, sifting through the ashes—sometimes literally—in search of its cause. Here’s how. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-investigation-kit/

August 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Serious Security Problem Looming Over Robotics Herb2 the robot is not in its right mind, because clear across the country at Brown University, researchers have compromised it. Robotics, in other words, has itself a security issue. https://www.wired.com/story/security-robotics/

August 23, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Energy Can You Store in a Stack of Cement Blocks? It’s not a trick question: You can make a battery out of concrete by storing gravitational potential energy. https://www.wired.com/story/battery-built-from-concrete/

August 23, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How NASA Built a Shark Tank for Space Inventions At an event in Denver, companies faced off in a battle to win NASA mentorship—and maybe the chance to put their tech in space. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-shark-tank-for-space-inventions/

August 23, 2018 | Author: Daniel AlarcÓnDaniel AlarcÓn What Happened in the Dark: Puerto Rico’s Year of Fighting for Power More Americans rely on Puerto Rico’s grid than on any other public electric utility. How one renegade plant worker led them through the shadows. https://www.wired.com/story/puerto-rico-hurricane-maria-recovery/

August 23, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton What Tech Has—and Hasn’t—Done for Puerto Rico Balloons, batteries, and the crypto invasion. A progress report on the industry’s aid to the island. https://www.wired.com/story/puerto-rico-hurricane-maria-tech/

August 22, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Rebirth of Radio Astronomy The National Science Foundation has backed away from three of its headlining radio telescopes in the last decade. What comes next? https://www.wired.com/story/radio-astronomy-rebirth/

August 22, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Trump’s New Power Plan Comes With a Deadly Price The Environmental Protection Agency says the new plan will result in more air pollution deaths. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-new-power-plan-air-pollution-deaths/

August 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Prepare to Be Hypnotized By These Delicate Paper Robots Researchers at Carnegie Mellon University use conductive 3-D-printed material and paper to build actuators for use in delicate little robots. https://www.wired.com/story/prepare-to-be-hypnotized-by-these-delicate-paper-robots/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni With Embryo Base Editing, China Gets Another Crispr First Scientists in China have used a cutting-edge Crispr technique to repair a disease-causing mutation in viable human embryos. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-base-editing-first-china/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How to Show That the Earth Orbits the Sun With simple tools, there are three things you can observe to support the heliocentric model of the solar system. https://www.wired.com/story/earth-orbits-the-sun-physics/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Emily AtkinEmily Atkin Germany Has Proven the Modern Automobile Must Die If we want to solve climate change, there’s no other option. https://www.wired.com/story/germany-proves-cars-must-die/

August 21, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon An Adorable Rodent Gives a Glimpse Into Earth’s Climate Chaos Scientists track in incredible detail how the giant kangaroo rat and over 400 other species struggled and triumphed amid a punishing drought. https://www.wired.com/story/giant-kangaroo-rat-climate-change/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Before Using Birth Control Apps, Consider Your Privacy All your industrious tracking of periods, sex, and basal body temperature is also valuable as a database. https://www.wired.com/story/natural-cycles-birth-control-app-privacy/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Think Rivers Are Dangerous Now? Just Wait Climate change could increase river flooding damage by as much as 1,000 percent, an ambitious new study finds. https://www.wired.com/story/think-rivers-are-dangerous-now-just-wait/

August 20, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan The Globe-Trotting Show Bringing Science and Tech to Arab TV In a given thirty minute episode, 4Tech’s hosts might test for counterfeit medicines at a pharmacy in Ghana, try out a wetsuit in cold Russian waters, or peek into a zebrafish lab in Iceland. https://www.wired.com/story/4tech/

August 18, 2018 | Author: Raleigh McElveryRaleigh McElvery Scientists Are Developing a Unique Identifier for Your Brain A neurological “functional fingerprint” allows scientists to explore the influence of genetics, environment and aging on brain connectivity. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-are-developing-a-unique-identifier-for-your-brain/

August 17, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen The Curious Case of a Revolutionary (But Imaginary?) Superconductor If the unconfirmed claims of a room temperature superconductor are real, this is bonkers. https://www.wired.com/story/the-curious-case-of-a-revolutionary-but-imaginary-superconductor/

August 17, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Get an Inside Look at SpaceX’s Astronaut Training Sims SpaceX’s first crew is starting training on cockpit simulators and replicas of the spacecraft that will take them to the ISS. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-astronaut-training-sims/

August 16, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Three Science Experiments You Can Do With Your Phone Your phone can measure acceleration, magnetic field, sound, location, and maybe more—which turns it into a portable data collector for science projects. https://www.wired.com/story/phone-science-experiments/

August 16, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni After 13 Years, Scientists Finally Map the Massive Wheat Genome The first high-quality, complete sequence of the bread wheat genome could support the creation of the first genetically modified wheat. https://www.wired.com/story/after-13-years-scientists-finally-map-the-massive-wheat-genome/

August 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Rude Humanoid Robots Can Mess With Your Head A pair of clever studies show how the development of advanced social robots is far outpacing our understanding of how they’re going to make us feel. https://www.wired.com/story/how-rude-humanoid-robots-can-mess-with-your-head/

August 15, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Catching a Gnarly 80-Foot-Tall Wave Surf’s up, dude. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-catching-a-gnarly-80-foot-tall-wave/

August 15, 2018 | Author: Elena Saavedra Buckley Elena Saavedra Buckley Your Tweets Can Help Map the Spread of Wildfire Smoke Social media could help monitor air pollution that physical monitors miss. https://www.wired.com/story/twitter-wildfire-model/

August 14, 2018 | Author: Jason KeheJason Kehe Drone Swarms as You Know Them Are Just an Illusion—for Now Networking isn’t inherently evil. It’s how teams of drones will one day be able to survey natural disasters, rescue survivors, and deliver your burritos. https://www.wired.com/story/drone-swarms-are-an-illusion-for-now/

August 14, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Wildfire Smoke Is Smothering the US—Even Where You Don’t Expect It “Minnesota actually gets just about the most smoke days of any state in the US, you just don’t notice it.” https://www.wired.com/story/wildfire-smoke-kills-where-you-dont-expect-it/

August 14, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Lab Where Spiders Put on Face Paint and Fake Eyelashes (and Termites Wear Capes) Researchers are using eyeliner and fake eyelashes to tease apart the complexities of the jumping spider mating ritual. Welcome to Extreme Makeover: Arachnid Edition. https://www.wired.com/story/spiders-put-on-face-paint-and-fake-eyelashes/

August 13, 2018 | Author: Tom PhilpottTom Philpott Your Chicken’s Salmonella Problem Is Worse Than You Think And cooking it to kingdom come won’t necessarily protect you. https://www.wired.com/story/your-chickens-salmonella-problem-is-worse-than-you-think/

August 13, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Watch a Harlem Globetrotter Sink a Shot from a Plane Really, this is a classic projectile motion physics problem. https://www.wired.com/story/harlem-globetrotters-basketball-shot-plane/

August 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Mind-Bending Avalanche Animation That Could Save Your Life Thanks in part to groundwork laid by the animators of Disney’s Frozen, this simulation may help develop better avalanche warning systems. https://www.wired.com/story/a-mind-bending-avalanche-animation/

August 11, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Dead Stars and a Cute L’il Comet 67p is known as the rubber ducky comet because of its funky shape—the result of two smaller bodies colliding. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-dead-stars-and-a-cute-comet/

August 11, 2018 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Star-Swallowing Black Holes Reveal Secrets in Exotic Light Shows Black holes occasionally reveal themselves when passing stars get ripped apart by their gravity. These tidal disruption events have created a new way for astronomers to map the hidden cosmos. https://www.wired.com/story/star-swallowing-black-holes-reveal-secrets/

August 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Sporty AI Teach Itself to Dribble Better Than You A simulated basketball player can teach itself through trial and error how to finely manipulate the ball, both while stationary and while running. https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-intelligence-basketball-dribbling/

August 10, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan How NASA Will Watch the 2018 Perseid Meteor Shower Every night, 17 video cameras scan the skies for meteors. https://www.wired.com/story/2018-perseid-meteor-shower-how-nasa-watches/

August 10, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Solar Probe Is Built to Survive a Brush With the Sun Here’s how the Parker probe was engineered to withstand temperatures spiking to over a million degrees Fahrenheit. https://www.wired.com/story/parker-solar-probe-brush-with-the-sun/

August 9, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The President Wants a Space Force. He Might Get One. Vice President Mike Pence’s speech at the Pentagon laid out what a new US Space Force would do. It’ll cost $8 billion to start. https://www.wired.com/story/space-force-mike-pence-pentagon/

August 9, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan Native Tribes Are Taking Fire Control Into Their Own Hands On July 27, the US Forest Service signed a new plan for managing public forest lands that lets tribes like the Karuk continue their tradition of controlled burns. https://www.wired.com/story/wildfires-native-tribes-controlled-burns/

August 9, 2018 | Author: Lisa MargonelliLisa Margonelli What Termites Teach Us About Robot Cooperation We imagine that the future of autonomous swarms is machinelike perfection, but moments of unpredictable, Three Stooges–like chaos are also likely to emerge. https://www.wired.com/story/what-termites-teach-us-about-robot-cooperation/

August 9, 2018 | Author: Leslie NemoLeslie Nemo Chicago’s ‘Wild Mile’ Is a Habitat Made Almost Entirely From Scratch The city’s manmade North Branch Canal is polluted and lacks natural habitat. Enter 80 coconut-fiber “islands” that host wildlife and filter the water. https://www.wired.com/story/chicago-wild-mile-habitat-made-from-scratch/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Scientists Take a Harder Look at Genetic Engineering of Human Embryos A year ago, a cell biologist announced that he had successfully used Crispr to edit human embryos for the first time in the US—but plenty of scientists didn’t buy it. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-take-a-harder-look-at-genetic-engineering-of-human-embryos/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Engineering the Climate Could Mess With Our Food Scientists look at the eruptions of Mount Pinatubo and El Chichón to give us a glimpse at how geoengineering might affect a critical global system: agriculture. https://www.wired.com/story/how-engineering-the-climate-could-mess-with-our-food/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Anki’s New Home Robot Sure Is Cute. But Can It Survive? It’s charming, it’s (relatively) smart, and it’s mobile. The question is: Can Vector succeed where other home robots have failed? https://www.wired.com/story/ankis-new-home-robot-sure-is-cute-but-can-it-survive/

August 8, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Learn Everything Online Except for the Things You Can’t College is like a chocolate chip cookie, and courses—online or not—are the chocolate chips. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-learn-everything-online-except-for-the-things-you-cant/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Garnet HendersonGarnet Henderson Telemedicine Could Help Fill the Gaps in America’s Abortion Care A growing body of research suggests that medication abortion could be offered without any in-person interaction at all. https://www.wired.com/story/telemedicine-could-help-fill-the-gaps-in-americas-abortion-care/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats The Unknowability of the Next Global Epidemic What may strike next, the World Health Organization fears, is something no doctor has ever heard of or knows how to treat. It’s come to be known as Disease X. https://www.wired.com/story/the-unknowability-of-the-next-global-epidemic/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Power Does It Take to Fly in a Real-Life Jet Suit? To hover a human over the ground, you need some serious engineering—and the momentum principle. https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-power-does-it-take-to-fly-in-a-real-life-jet-suit/

August 7, 2018 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser The Ultra-Pure, Super-Secret Sand That Makes Your Phone Possible The processor that makes your laptop or cell phone work was fabricated using quartz from this obscure Appalachian backwater. https://www.wired.com/story/book-excerpt-science-of-ultra-pure-silicon/

August 6, 2018 | Author: Jake MalooleyJake Malooley My Two-Week Edible-Insect Feast If we’re willing to sink our teeth into lab-grown meat and plant-based burgers that magically bleed, maybe old-fashioned bugs aren’t such a stretch. https://www.wired.com/story/my-two-week-edible-insect-feast/

August 6, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Quantum Computing Will Create Jobs. But Which Ones? A new bill aims to support a growing quantum industry by training a new cross-disciplinary workforce. https://www.wired.com/story/national-quantum-initiative-quantum-computing-jobs/

August 6, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Who’s Responsible for Your Bad Tech Habits? It’s Complicated As the conversation around tech is increasingly framed in terms of its impact on public health, the question of responsibility for our lopsided relationship with digital devices becomes more fraught. https://www.wired.com/story/whos-responsible-for-your-bad-tech-habits-its-complicated/

August 5, 2018 | Author: Anil AnanthaswamyAnil Ananthaswamy Loopholes and the ‘Anti-Realism’ of the Quantum World After researchers found a loophole in a famous experiment designed to prove that quantum objects don’t have intrinsic properties, three experimental groups quickly sewed the loophole shut. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-world-anti-realism/

August 3, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe’s Pharma Deals Have Been the Plan All Along A new partnership with GlaxoSmithKline drew intense scrutiny from customers, reflecting eroding public trust in companies’ ability to protect private information. https://www.wired.com/story/23andme-glaxosmithkline-pharma-deal/

August 3, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Meet the Astronauts Who Will Fly the First Private ‘Space Taxis’ SpaceX and Boeing are vying to take the first US crew members to the ISS. Now they know who’ll be on board. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-boeing-commercial-astronauts-first-private-space-taxis-/

August 3, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Robots Are Renting Airbnbs to Get a Better Grip Airbnb: great for travelers, and even better for putting a robot’s new manipulation skills to the test. https://www.wired.com/story/robots-are-renting-airbnbs-to-get-a-better-grip/

August 2, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan This Community Is Advocating for Air Quality—With Science With the help of local scientists, the unincorporated community of Brandywine plans to collect its own air quality data to test the impacts of new power plants. https://www.wired.com/story/this-community-is-advocating-for-air-qualitywith-science/

August 2, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Change’s Looming Mental Health Crisis “As we have more natural disasters, one would expect to also have increases in those kinds of mental health consequences.” https://www.wired.com/story/climate-changes-looming-mental-health-crisis/

August 1, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Bioengineers Are Closer Than Ever To Lab-Grown Lungs The first research team to bioengineer human lungs in a lab have now performed multiple successful transplants in pigs. https://www.wired.com/story/four-successful-bel-transplants/

August 1, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why Big Stuff Cools Off Slower Than Small Stuff Take a batch of cookies out of the oven, and the big ones cool down slower than the small ones. Why’s that? https://www.wired.com/story/why-big-stuff-cools-off-slower-than-small-stuff/

August 1, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Only Thing Fire Scientists Are Sure of: This Will Get Worse It’s a new world for global warming-powered wildfires. Unless things change, they’re just going to get bigger. https://www.wired.com/story/the-only-thing-fire-scientists-are-sure-of-this-will-get-worse/

July 31, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Does It Take to Put a Waterfall on a Skyscraper? The Liebian Building in Guiyang, China has a 350-foot-tall artificial waterfall built into its face. https://www.wired.com/story/what-does-it-take-to-put-a-waterfall-on-a-skyscraper/

July 31, 2018 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester Climate Change Is Coming for Underwater Archaeological Sites The second death of long-submerged shipwrecks. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-is-coming-for-underwater-archaeological-sites/

July 31, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Are Diplomas in Your DNA? Last week researchers announced more than 1,000 genetic variants associated with how far a person gets through school—along with warnings for how not to use that data. But earlier results from the same group are already available in a consumer product. https://www.wired.com/story/are-diplomas-in-your-dna/

July 30, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Robot Hand Taught Itself How to Grab Stuff Like a Human The system, developed by OpenAI, ends up “inventing” characteristic grasps that we humans already commonly use to handle objects. https://www.wired.com/story/this-robot-hand-taught-itself-how-to-grab-stuff-like-a-human/

July 30, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Sorry, Nerds: Terraforming Might Not Work on Mars If a new analysis is correct, conditions on Mars make it impossible for existing technology to turn it into a garden of Earth-like delights. https://www.wired.com/story/co2-terraforming-mars/

July 30, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler If Germany Can’t Quit Coal, Can Anyone Else? Germany’s last black-coal mine will close next month. But that doesn’t mean the country has weaned itself off the emissions-spewing stuff. https://www.wired.com/story/if-germany-cant-quit-coal-can-anyone-else/

July 28, 2018 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover The Peculiar Math That Could Underlie the Laws of Nature New findings are fueling an old suspicion that fundamental particles and forces spring from strange eight-part numbers called “octonions.” https://www.wired.com/story/the-peculiar-math-that-could-underlie-the-laws-of-nature/

July 27, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Guano in 60 Seconds A quick introduction to the surprising ecological benefits of bird droppings. https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/bird-guano-coral-reefs/

July 27, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HeilweilRebecca Heilweil How to Watch Friday’s Super-Long Lunar Eclipse This so-called blood moon will be visible from every continent on Earth except North America. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-watch-fridays-super-long-lunar-eclipse-online/

July 27, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Congress Has a $95 Million Proposal to Study Tech’s Effect on Kids “Congress has a vital role to play on matters of public health, but we must act based on sound evidence.” https://www.wired.com/story/congress-has-a-dollar65-million-proposal-to-study-techs-effect-on-kids/

July 26, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Just Some Other Totally Legit Microbes That Will Definitely (Not) Make Your Tech Startup a Unicorn A study this week got people thinking that infection by Toxoplasma gondii, a parasite found in cat poop, could be used to prime people for entrepreneurship. We’ve got some better equally terrible ideas. https://www.wired.com/story/just-some-other-totally-legit-microbes-that-will-definitely-not-make-your-tech-startup-a-unicorn/

July 26, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Why Do You Feel Lighter at the Top of a Ferris Wheel? It’s because of something called apparent weight, and you can calculate it for yourself. https://www.wired.com/story/why-do-you-feel-lighter-at-the-top-of-a-ferris-wheel/

July 26, 2018 | Author: Nick StocktonNick Stockton How Plastic Straws Slip Through the Cracks of Waste Management Straws may not be the worst type of litter. But they are remarkably good at escaping from the waste stream and into the wild. https://www.wired.com/story/how-plastic-straws-slip-through-the-cracks-of-waste-management/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler European Ruling Could Slow Africa’s Push for Crispr Crops Court says crops using new gene-editing tools should be regulated just like older GMOs. https://www.wired.com/story/european-ruling-could-slow-africas-push-for-crispr-crops/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Scientists Discover Evidence of the First Large Body of Liquid Water on Mars “Going from zero bodies of water to one is a big change, for sure, but the full extent of this discovery depends on what we find next.” https://www.wired.com/story/large-body-of-liquid-water-on-mars/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Inside the 23-Dimensional World of Your Car’s Paint Job Hue. Saturation. Luminance. Sparkle. Fixing a door ding is about way more than color. (Also: Why the sky is blue and clouds are white.) https://www.wired.com/story/car-paint-colors/

July 25, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Making Personalized Cancer Vaccines Takes an Army—of Robots Take a look inside the new manufacturing plant for Moderna Therapeutics, the Boston area-based biotech valued at $7 billion. https://www.wired.com/story/making-personalized-cancer-vaccines-takes-an-armyof-robots/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Was It Ethical for Dropbox to Share Customer Data with Scientists? The data was anonymized, but academics are still concerned about the ethics of the analysis. https://www.wired.com/story/dropbox-sharing-data-study-ethics/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Major Victory for the Impossible Burger, the Veggie ‘Meat’ That Bleeds The highly engineered food with GM yeast finally makes its way through an FDA maze. Not everyone is jazzed, though. https://www.wired.com/story/a-major-victory-for-the-impossible-burger/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Preps for Three Block 5 Launches in Just Two Weeks The company is slated to loft three payloads in just 12 days with its new and improved Falcon 9 rocket. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-preps-for-three-block-5-launches-in-just-two-weeks/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Nathanael JohnsonNathanael Johnson Next-Gen Nuclear Is Coming—If Society Wants It Scores of nuclear startups are aiming to solve the problems that plague nuclear power. https://www.wired.com/story/next-gen-nuclear/

July 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon That Purple Kush You’re Toking Might Be a Genetic Imposter ACDC and Lamb’s Bread and Ghost OG, oh my: Researchers compare the genetics of cannabis strains and find … irregularities. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-in-a-cannabis-strain-name/

July 23, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Drafting in the Tour de France Drafting decreases the overall power needed to ride at a constant speed or allows a rider to go slightly faster with the same power. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-drafting-in-the-tour-de-france/

July 23, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles This Bomb-Simulating US Supercomputer Broke a World Record A trillion-particle simulation? No sweat for the Trinity supercomputer at Los Alamos National Lab. https://www.wired.com/story/this-bomb-simulating-us-supercomputer-broke-a-world-record/

July 22, 2018 | Author: Joshua RoebkeJoshua Roebke Meet the Woman Who Rocked Particle Physics—Three Times Sau Lan Wu spent decades working to establish the Standard Model of particle physics. Now she’s searching for what lies beyond it. https://www.wired.com/story/meet-the-woman-who-rocked-particle-physicsthree-times/

July 21, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Sweeping the Clouds Away on Titan With infrared eyes, astronomers are more than scratching the surface of Saturn’s hazy moon. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-sweeping-the-clouds-away-on-titan/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Turns Out Cities Can’t Sue Oil Companies for Climate Change Municipalities all over the US are taking oil companies to court for damages related to global warming. They’re losing. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-lawsuits-dismissed/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How a Team of Experts Quelled Colorado’s Enormous Spring Fire The state’s third-largest wildfire ever burned more than 100,000 acres and destroyed more than 200 homes. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-team-of-experts-quelled-colorados-enormous-spring-fire/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats Welcome to the Era of Orbital Publicity Stunts Are science and commerce the only legitimate pursuits off-planet—and who gets to decide? https://www.wired.com/story/welcome-to-the-era-of-orbital-publicity-stunts/

July 20, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Some Scientists Work With China, but NASA Won’t NASA’s ban on scientific contacts doesn’t apply to all academics. https://www.wired.com/story/some-scientists-work-with-china-but-nasa-wont/

July 19, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain A Comprehensive Guide to the Physics of Running on the Moon Humans are going to live on the moon eventually. So how are we going to move around there? https://www.wired.com/story/a-comprehensive-guide-to-the-physics-of-running-on-the-moon/

July 19, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Dive Under the Ice With the Brave Robots of Antarctica Sending a robot into the icy depths and getting it back alive can be more challenging than communicating with a Mars rover millions of miles away. https://www.wired.com/story/dive-under-the-ice-with-the-brave-robots-of-antarctica/

July 18, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How a Flock of Drones Developed Collective Intelligence Just like groups of birds or insects, these drones organize themselves into cohesive groups—a so-called “emergent” property of their individual actions. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-flock-of-drones-developed-collective-intelligence/

July 18, 2018 | Author: Greta JochemGreta Jochem Rising Seas Could Cause Your Next Internet Outage In just 15 years, roughly 4,000 miles of fiber-optic cables in US coastal cities could go underwater. https://www.wired.com/story/rising-seas-could-cause-your-next-internet-outage/

July 18, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Why You Can’t Trust More Cryptocurrency White Papers Crypto-developers—ironically, a community devoted to eliminating centralized authority—could use more traditional vetting structures. https://www.wired.com/story/why-you-cant-trust-most-cryptocurrency-white-papers/

July 17, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan A Giant Iceberg Grounded Itself Near a Greenland Town It has retreated, but the risk of what happens with a grounded iceberg is almost luck of the draw. https://www.wired.com/story/in-greenland-iceberg-shedding-is-a-tourist-attraction-and-a-threat/

July 17, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Astronomers Discovered 12 New Moons Around Jupiter. Here’s How Eleven of them behave a lot like Jupiter’s other moons, but the twelfth one is weird (in a good way). https://www.wired.com/story/twelve-new-jovian-moons/

July 17, 2018 | Author: Stephen S. HallStephen S. Hall Crispr Can Speed Up Nature—and Change How We Grow Food It took thousands of years for humans to breed a pea-sized fruit into a beautiful beefsteak tomato. Now, with gene editing, scientists can change everything. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-tomato-mutant-future-of-food/

July 16, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Is a Runner Like a Bouncing Ball? You can make a physics model that teaches you tons about running. https://www.wired.com/story/how-is-a-runner-like-a-bouncing-ball/

July 16, 2018 | Author: Justine CalmaJustine Calma How New York City Is Tackling Extreme Heat in a Warming World Extreme heat already kills more than 100 New Yorkers yearly. That could rise to thousands a year by 2080. https://www.wired.com/story/how-new-york-city-is-tackling-extreme-heat-in-a-warming-world/

July 16, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon What Is Meat, Anyway? Lab-Grown Food Sets Off a Debate You don’t typically find philosophical bickering at an FDA public meeting. But then again, lab-grown meat is no ordinary topic. https://www.wired.com/story/what-is-meat-anyway/

July 14, 2018 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch Slime Molds Remember—But Do They Learn? Evidence mounts that organisms without nervous systems can in some sense learn and solve problems, but researchers disagree about whether this is “primitive cognition.” https://www.wired.com/story/slime-molds-rememberbut-do-they-learn/

July 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Robots Can’t Hold Stuff Very Well, But You Can Help A new online sim computes how and where a robot should grip objects like vases and turbine housings. You can even upload designs of your own objects. https://www.wired.com/story/robots-cant-hold-stuff-very-well-but-you-can-help/

July 13, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Company Wants Your Fertility Data Celmatix sells a genetic test for reproductive health, and it’s looking to expand. https://www.wired.com/story/this-company-wants-your-fertility-data/

July 13, 2018 | Author: Richard FloridaRichard Florida Climate Change Will Force the Poor From Their Homes A new study investigates the intersection of climate change and real estate, and finds that higher elevations bring higher values. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-will-force-the-poor-from-their-homes/

July 12, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan The Ultimate Carbon-Saving Tip? Travel by Cargo Ship Container ships sometimes have a handful of passenger cabins—the peak of carbon emissions frugality. https://www.wired.com/story/the-ultimate-carbon-saving-tip-travel-by-cargo-ship/

July 12, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen What’s a Blazar? A Galactic Bakery for Cosmic Rays Astrophysicists have traced the origin of some of Earth’s cosmic rays to a blazar 4 billion light years away. https://www.wired.com/story/whats-a-blazar-a-galactic-bakery-for-cosmic-rays/

July 12, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How Does NASA Test For Spacecraft Safety? Brutalize a Replica In Denver, engineers have built an architecturally identical twin for Orion, NASA’s next launch vehicle—and they’re putting it through its paces. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-test-chamber-for-nasas-astronaut-vehicle-double/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Why Nevada’s Execution Drug Cocktail Is So Controversial A sedative, an opioid, and a paralytic sit at the core of legal and ethical debates over the state-sanctioned killing of death row prisoner Scott Dozier. https://www.wired.com/story/the-untested-drugs-at-the-heart-of-nevadas-execution-controversy/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Rats! Coral Reefs Aren’t Getting the Bird Poop They Need Rat invasions ripple across an island ecosystem into places you’d never expect—including all the way into surrounding coral reefs. https://www.wired.com/story/coral-reefs-arent-getting-the-bird-poop-they-need/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Facebook Opens Its Private Servers to Scientists Studying Fake News Social Science One, an independent research commission, will give social scientists unprecedented access to Facebook’s data. https://www.wired.com/story/social-science-one-facebook-fake-news/

July 11, 2018 | Author: Jason PlautzJason Plautz Cheap, Portable Sensors Are Democratizing Air-Quality Data A new generation of air-quality sensors is making it easier for citizen groups and residents to monitor the air around them. https://www.wired.com/story/cheap-portable-sensors-are-democratizing-air-quality-data/

July 10, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Can Your Electronic Gadgets Interfere With Your Compass? Electric currents have magnetic fields, so the right kind could mess with your navigation. https://www.wired.com/story/can-your-electronic-gadgets-interfere-with-your-compass/

July 10, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson The Race to Get Tourists to Suborbital Space Is Heating Up Blue Origin and Virgin Galactic are quietly competing to see who will be the first to ferry tourists into space. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-get-tourists-to-suborbital-space-is-heating-up/

July 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Did the Human Cross the Road? To Confuse the Self-Driving Car Human drivers struggle to figure out something as simple as whether someone will cross the road. Just imagine how robocars feel. https://www.wired.com/story/why-did-the-human-cross-the-road-to-confuse-the-self-driving-car/

July 9, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez A Time-Lapsed Glacier Collapse Is the Saddest Science Lesson Time-lapse footage of a calving glacier in Greenland could help researchers anticipate catastrophic sea-level rise. https://www.wired.com/story/a-time-lapsed-glacier-collapse-is-the-saddest-science-lesson/

July 9, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Don’t Just Lecture Robots—Make Them Learn By drawing on prior experience, a humanoid-ish robot can watch a human pick up an apple and drop it in a bowl, then do the same itself, even if it’s never seen an apple before. https://www.wired.com/story/dont-just-lecture-robotsmake-them-learn/

July 9, 2018 | Author: Nathanael JohnsonNathanael Johnson Where Can Climate Activists Find Common Ground? Fights over renewable standards and nuclear power can be vicious. Here’s a list of views that climate hawks share. https://www.wired.com/story/where-can-climate-activists-find-common-ground/

July 8, 2018 | Author: Ramin SkibbaRamin Skibba This Galactic Collision Shaped the History of the Milky Way Astronomers have found stars dating from a long-ago collision between the Milky Way and another galaxy. The crash helps to explain why the Milky Way looks the way it does. https://www.wired.com/story/this-galactic-collision-shaped-the-history-of-the-milky-way/

July 7, 2018 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol Flattened Fluids Help Scientists Understand Oceans and Atmospheres By squeezing fluids into flat sheets, researchers can get a handle on the strange ways that turbulence feeds energy into a system instead of eating it away. https://www.wired.com/story/flattened-fluids-help-scientists-understand-oceans-and-atmospheres/

July 6, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Future of Former EPA Chief Scott Pruitt’s Anti-Science Legacy Pruitt’s replacement might be more effective at gutting environmental protection than Pruitt himself. https://www.wired.com/story/the-future-of-former-epa-chief-scott-pruitts-anti-science-legacy/

July 6, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Try Out This Physics Problem With a Baseball and a Neighbor The best questions are always the ones that don’t have a single clear answer. https://www.wired.com/story/try-out-this-physics-problem-with-a-baseball-and-a-neighbor/

July 6, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Never Prebook Your Return Flight From a Rocket Launch Rocket Lab has scrubbed or delayed each of its first three launch attempts. That’s standard. https://www.wired.com/story/never-prebook-your-return-flight-from-a-rocket-launch/

July 5, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez An Astronomer Explains Black Holes at 5 Levels of Difficulty His specialty: The structure of the universe. (That’s the official name of his research group at NASA.) https://www.wired.com/story/an-astronomer-explains-black-holes-at-5-levels-of-difficulty/

July 5, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson The Air Force Is Already Betting on SpaceX’s Brand-New Falcon Heavy The Falcon Heavy has only flown once, but the Air Force is already buying in. https://www.wired.com/story/the-air-force-is-already-betting-on-spacexs-brand-new-falcon-heavy/

July 4, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni We Have No Idea How Bad the US Tick Problem Is And new tick-borne pathogens are emerging at a troubling clip. https://www.wired.com/story/we-have-no-idea-how-bad-the-us-tick-problem-is/

July 4, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Launching Fireworks From a Drone Not that you’d ever do such a thing. Please keep drones and fireworks far away from each other. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-launching-fireworks-from-a-drone/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Emily DreyfussEmily Dreyfuss Do Thundershirts Really Calm Dogs During Fireworks or What? The anxiety vests were inspired by research into humans with severe anxiety or autism, but the veterinary science isn’t quite up to par. https://www.wired.com/story/do-thundershirts-really-calm-dogs-during-fireworks-or-what/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan New University Rules Encourage Scientists to Avoid Air Travel For some researchers it’s a personal choice; other academic departments have to pay carbon offset fees. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-scientists-take-the-train/

July 3, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Is Hogweed? This Invasive Flower Gives You Third-Degree Burns The giant hogweed is set to bloom just around the Fourth of July every year—and every year, it spreads a little further. https://www.wired.com/story/this-giant-invasive-flower-can-give-you-third-degree-burns/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers In Search of New Rules to Protect Other Worlds From Earth’s Cooties NASA’s Office of Planetary Protection has tried to protect other worlds from us and us from other worlds since the Cold War. But the future wants a better way. https://www.wired.com/story/planetary-protection-report/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Can the Koala Genome Save the Species From Deforestation and Chlamydia? Understanding the animal’s genes could help combat shrinking habitats and an epidemic of chlamydia. https://www.wired.com/story/koala-genome/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez DNA-Repairing Sunscreen: Legit or Not? Several products claim to repair DNA damage inflicted by UVB rays. What’s the science behind them? https://www.wired.com/story/dna-repairing-sunscreen-legit-or-nah/

July 2, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why (and How) California Is Destroying Mountains of Weed How exactly do you obliterate potentially tens of thousands of pounds of cannabis across the state? Not unlike how you get rid of yard trimmings. https://www.wired.com/story/why-and-how-california-is-destroying-mountains-of-weed/

July 1, 2018 | Author: John RennieJohn Rennie This Mutation Math Shows How Life Keeps on Evolving New results emerging from graph theory prove that the way a population is organized can guarantee the eventual triumph of natural selection—or permanently thwart it. https://www.wired.com/story/this-mutation-math-shows-how-life-keeps-on-evolving/

June 29, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of a Spinning Spacecraft in The Expanse For the most part, this show gets a lot right. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-a-spinning-spacecraft-in-the-expanse/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Floating Robot With an IBM Brain Is Headed to Space The IBM robot bound for the International Space Station doesn’t have a body, but it has cameras for eyes, microphones for ears, and a speaker for a mouth. https://www.wired.com/story/the-floating-robot-with-an-ibm-brain-is-headed-to-space/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni NASA’s Astro-Mice Will Test What Space Does to Your Gut A new study will help the space agency understand how to keep its astronauts—and their resident microbes—healthy on future missions to Mars. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-astro-mice-will-test-what-space-does-to-your-gut/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez One Sentence With 7 Meanings Unlocks a Mystery of Human Speech Neuroscientists turned to an internet-famous phrase to identify the region of the brain that controls pitch and emphasis in human speech. https://www.wired.com/story/one-sentence-with-7-meanings-unlocks-a-mystery-of-human-speech/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Roboticists Are Copying Nature to Make Fantastical Machines Nature knows what it’s doing, and roboticists are more than happy to steal evolution’s ideas to make a plethora of curious and clever machines. https://www.wired.com/story/how-roboticists-are-copying-nature-to-make-fantastical-machines/

June 28, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson SpaceX Is About to Launch Its Final Block 4 Falcon RIP to the moderately reusable Falcon 9. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-is-about-to-launch-its-final-block-4-falcon/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Fred VogelsteinFred Vogelstein The FDA Approved its First Cannabis Drug. What Next? The approval of epilepsy drug Epidiolex is poised to permanently change the way we talk about cannabis in the US. https://www.wired.com/story/the-fda-approved-its-first-cannabis-drug-what-next/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope Plagued by Delays, Rising Costs The project will come in at least an extra 18 months behind schedule and $800 million over budget. https://www.wired.com/story/delays-rising-costs-plague-nasas-james-webb-space-telescope/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Jackie Flynn MogensenJackie Flynn Mogensen San Francisco vs. Big Oil: Climate Case Dismissed “Our litigation forced a public court proceeding on climate science, and now these companies can no longer deny it is real and valid.” https://www.wired.com/story/san-francisco-vs-big-oil-climate-case-dismissed/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Drones Just Learned to Fly Solo, Which Means Pro Racers May Soon Meet Their Match A new system lets robot drones to navigate an obstacle course with 100 percent accuracy—that is, the robots almost never crash and explode. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-out-pro-racers-these-drones-just-learned-to-fly-solo/

June 27, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni These Beating Mini-Hearts Could Save Big Bucks—And Maybe Lives The pharma industry is increasingly using miniature hearts as part of its drug screening and discovery process. https://www.wired.com/story/these-beating-mini-hearts-could-save-big-bucksand-maybe-lives/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Blanca MyersBlanca Myers A Microguide to Microdosing Psychedelic Drugs How much is a microdose, exactly? Here’s our semi-scientific guide to taking acid, mushrooms, DMT, and more. Hint: If you feel the trees breathing, you’re doing it wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/a-microguide-to-microdosing-psychedelic-drugs/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Feargus O’SullivanFeargus O’Sullivan Denmark’s Carbon Footprint Is Set to Balloon—Blame Big Tech The sustainability-focused country will host six new data centers within 12 years, leading to rising carbon emissions. https://www.wired.com/story/denmarks-carbon-footprint-is-set-to-balloonblame-big-tech/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Rise of DNA Data Storage Could DNA as an archival medium be the solution to our information overload? https://www.wired.com/story/the-rise-of-dna-data-storage/

June 26, 2018 | Author: Garrett M. GraffGarrett M. Graff The New Arms Race Threatening to Explode in Space Trump’s call for a “Space Force” escalates a quiet, dangerous contest between the US, China, and Russia—one whose consequences no one really understands. https://www.wired.com/story/new-arms-race-threatening-to-explode-in-space/

June 25, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen The Quest to Make Super-cold Quantum Blobs in Space Physicists launched a custom-made freezer and then let it plummet back to Earth—for science! https://www.wired.com/story/the-quest-to-make-super-cold-quantum-blobs-in-space/

June 25, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Troubled End of an Ethically Compromised Booze Study NIH pulled the plug on what would have been a grand experiment in “healthy” drinking. Where can the field go now? https://www.wired.com/story/the-troubled-end-of-an-ethically-compromised-booze-study/

June 24, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Let’s Use Physics to Model a Curving Soccer Ball You could practice out on the pitch, or you could use a numerical calculation. https://www.wired.com/story/lets-use-physics-to-model-a-curving-soccer-ball/

June 24, 2018 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Finally, a Problem Only Quantum Computers Will Ever Be Able to Solve Computer scientists have been searching for years for a type of problem that a quantum computer can solve but that any possible future classical computer cannot. Now they’ve found one. https://www.wired.com/story/finally-a-problem-only-quantum-computers-will-ever-be-able-to-solve/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Family DNA Testing at the Border Would Be an Ethical Quagmire New offers from consumer genetic testing companies raise more questions than they answer. https://www.wired.com/story/family-dna-testing-at-the-border-would-be-an-ethical-quagmire/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Pain Is Weird. Making Bionic Arms Feel Pain Is Even Weirder Researchers get a robotic prosthesis to feel pain. But is that something amputees would even want? https://www.wired.com/story/pain-is-weird-making-bionic-arms-feel-pain-is-even-weirder/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles It’s Business Time for Rocket Lab, Launcher of Small Satellites The question now is: Can it loft its rockets inside the newly opened launch window, or will it stay on the launch pad for ever and ever and ever? https://www.wired.com/story/its-business-time-for-rocket-lab-launcher-of-small-satellites/

June 22, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Twitter Users Are Analytical in the Morning, Angsty at Night What an analysis of 800 million tweets and 7 billion words published to Twitter between 2010 and 2014, across the 54 largest cities in the UK, reveals (and doesn’t) about the British state of mind. https://www.wired.com/story/twitter-diurnal-trends/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles NASA’s New Plan: Do More Science With Small Satellites A new NASA program aims to turn the gaze of small, traditionally Earth-monitoring satellites outward toward the cosmos. https://www.wired.com/story/nasa-smallsats-look-at-spaaaaace/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Amphiphilic Liquid Coating That Keeps Your Avocados Fresh A coating doubles the ripeness window of avocados. How? By supercharging the defenses that evolution crafted on its own. https://www.wired.com/story/apeel/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Big Tech Isn’t the Problem With Homelessness. It’s All of Us Amid all the digital wealth, the big cities of the West are racked with the destitute. We know how to solve this problem, so what’s stopping us? https://www.wired.com/story/big-tech-isnt-the-problem-with-homelessness-its-all-of-us/

June 21, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How ‘Self-Limiting’ Mosquitos Can Help Eradicate Malaria With help from the Gates Foundation, Oxitec aims to release genetically engineered mosquitoes in the Western Hemisphere by 2020. https://www.wired.com/story/oxitec-gates-self-limiting-mosquitoes/

June 20, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart China Won’t Solve the World’s Plastics Problem Any More China has stopped taking in most of the world’s recycling. Where does it go now? https://www.wired.com/story/china-wont-solve-the-worlds-plastics-problem-any-more/

June 19, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez WHO Calls Gaming Disorder an Illness. Experts Say Not So Fast Some mental health experts have reservations about the change in the WHO’s International Classification of Diseases. https://www.wired.com/story/who-calls-gaming-disorder-an-illness-experts-say-not-so-fast/

June 19, 2018 | Author: Oliver MilmanOliver Milman Analysis: Data Shows Rising Seas Threaten Over 300,000 Homes Climate change study predicts ‘staggering impact’ of swelling oceans on coastal communities within next 30 years. https://www.wired.com/story/flooding-from-sea-level-rise-threatens-over-300000-us-coastal-homes/

June 19, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Space Really Does Need Traffic Cops Trump’s new space directive spreads out the responsibility for Earth’s congested orbital thoroughfares. https://www.wired.com/story/space-really-does-need-traffic-cops/

June 18, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Trump Hasn’t Signed a Space Force Into Being—Yet A brand-new sixth military branch lacks political support. https://www.wired.com/story/trump-hasnt-signed-a-space-force-into-beingyet/

June 18, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Tug of War With a Lion Isn’t About Strength—It’s About Friction If you want a fair fight between a lion and a human playing tug of war, you should give the lion a pair of tennis shoes. https://www.wired.com/story/this-tug-of-war-with-a-lion-isnt-about-strengthits-about-friction/

June 18, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Struggles of a $40 Million Nutrition Science Crusade The Nutrition Science Initiative promised to study obesity and diabetes the right way. Now it’s nearly broke and all but gone. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-dollar40-million-nutrition-science-crusade-fell-apart/

June 17, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Crazy Slide Is Either Evil or Funny It’s like the designer wanted people to crash in excellent viral videos. https://www.wired.com/story/this-crazy-slide-is-either-evil-or-funny/

June 17, 2018 | Author: Emily AtkinEmily Atkin The Powerful Groups Stonewalling a Greener Way to Die “Aquamation,” a greener form of body disposal, is gaining acceptance in America. But some groups are fighting to stop it. https://www.wired.com/story/the-powerful-groups-stonewalling-the-greener-way-to-die/

June 16, 2018 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover The Universe Is Not a Simulation, but We Can Now Simulate It Computer simulations have become so accurate that cosmologists can now use them to study dark matter, supermassive black holes, and other mysteries of the real evolving cosmos. https://www.wired.com/story/the-universe-is-not-a-simulation-but-we-can-now-simulate-it/

June 15, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Protect My Head? Soccer Pros Shrug and Carry On New tests find that certain headbands cut risk of head injuries, but officials are reluctant to mandate their use. https://www.wired.com/story/protect-my-head-soccer-pros-shrug-and-carry-on/

June 15, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Physics of the One Goal You Won’t See at the World Cup A soccer player rarely scores directly off a corner kick. It’s called an Olympic goal, and when it does happen, it’s usually an accident. Here’s why. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-the-one-goal-you-wont-see-at-the-world-cup/

June 15, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Puerto Rico’s Observatory Is Still Recovering From Hurricane Maria Arecibo Observatory’s 1,000-foot telescope was damaged in last year’s storm, and the recovery money is only just beginning to flow in. https://www.wired.com/story/puerto-ricos-observatory-is-still-recovering-from-hurricane-maria/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon ‘Ninjabot’ Reveals the Mantis Shrimp’s Wily Snail-Hunting Scheme The mantis shrimp wields one of the fiercest strikes on Earth. With the help of a robot, researchers show that the predator is a master strategist, too. https://www.wired.com/story/ninjabot-reveals-the-mantis-shrimps-wily-snail-hunting-scheme/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Matt BeaneMatt Beane Robots Might Not Take Your Job—But They Will Probably Make It Boring Opinion: “Good” automation assigns tasks that are dirty, dangerous, or dull to robots. But shifting responsibility often makes the surrounding jobs less fulfilling. https://www.wired.com/story/robots-wont-take-your-jobbut-they-might-make-it-boring/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Mad Lab That’s Getting Robots to Walk and Jump Like Us Truly useful robots will have to be able to tackle everything humans can, so they’ve gotta have legs. Easier said than done, though. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-mad-lab-thats-getting-robots-to-walk-and-jump-like-us/

June 14, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Can PJs and Sound Sleep Lead to a World Cup Victory? Under Armour equipped a Swiss star with ceramic bedsheets and sleep monitors to boost his performance. https://www.wired.com/story/can-pjs-and-sound-sleep-lead-to-a-world-cup-victory/

June 13, 2018 | Author: Mejs HasanMejs Hasan How Scientists Tracked Antarctica’s Stunning Ice Loss The combined results of 24 different surveys of Antarctic ice loss suggest that the rate of melting has tripled in the last five years. https://www.wired.com/story/how-scientists-tracked-antarcticas-stunning-ice-loss/

June 13, 2018 | Author: Wonbo WooWonbo Woo Why Are CDC Disease Detectives in a Cave Crawling With Snakes? The scientists aren’t there for the pythons: They’re there for the pythons’ food. https://www.wired.com/story/why-are-cdc-disease-detectives-in-a-cave-crawling-with-snakes/

June 13, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Potential Pitfalls of Sucking Carbon From the Atmosphere A new method makes negative emissions more of a reality than ever before. https://www.wired.com/story/the-potential-pitfalls-of-sucking-carbon-from-the-atmosphere/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Forget X-Ray Vision. You Can See Through Walls With Radio Researchers at MIT, actualizers of all things science fiction, have taken a different tack to seeing through walls: radio waves. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-x-ray-vision-you-can-see-through-walls-with-radio/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of a Puzzling Perpetual Motion Machine Nope, this YouTube video hasn’t just changed everything we know about energy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-a-puzzling-perpetual-motion-machine/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon LA Is Doing Water Better Than Your City. Yes, That LA With climate change on the horizon, Los Angeles is rushing to pull water from surprising sources. The goal: aqueous independence. https://www.wired.com/story/la-is-doing-water-better-than-your-city-yes-that-la/

June 12, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Inside a Chemist’s Quest to Hack Evolution and Cure Genetic Disease David Liu is a scientific superhero on a mission to knock out genetic mutants. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-a-chemists-quest-to-hack-evolution-and-cure-genetic-disease/

June 11, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Surprisingly Cool Physics of Pushing a Block Against a Wall You might think this is just a boring physics problem—but you’d be wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/the-surprisingly-cool-physics-of-pushing-a-block-against-a-wall/

June 11, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How a Uranium Hunter Sniffs Out Nuclear Weapons Every bit of uranium ore has a chemical fingerprint specific to its source on Earth. Track the metal, and you can track the ne’er-do-well who took it. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-uranium-hunter-sniffs-out-nuclear-weapons/

June 10, 2018 | Author: Ursula K. HeiseUrsula K. Heise Endangered Species and the Case for ‘Sanctuary Cities’ Non-native animals and plants often arrive in cities by happenstance and carve out ecological niches for themselves. But if cities were more deliberate about biodiversity, they’d take in well-suited species that are struggling elsewhere. https://www.wired.com/story/endangered-species-and-the-case-for-sanctuary-cities/

June 10, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Life, Death, and Dream of a Research Diversity Crusader The billion-dollar, 10-year All of Us initiative promises to sequence and study the health of 1 million Americans. But will they represent the diversity of the country’s population? https://www.wired.com/story/all-of-us-the-life-death-and-dream-of-a-research-diversity-crusader/

June 9, 2018 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz When Overtaxed Working Memory Knocks Your Brain Out of Sync Researchers find that when working memory gets overburdened, dialog between three brain regions breaks down. The discovery provides new support for a broader theory about how the brain operates. https://www.wired.com/story/when-overtaxed-working-memory-knocks-your-brain-out-of-sync/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wanna Pull Water Out of Air? Grab Some Ions or a Weird Sponge These techniques won’t quench humanity’s thirst, but they’ve got serious potential to help augment water supplies in particularly dry places. https://www.wired.com/story/pull-water-out-of-air/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Ray Dalio, Marc BenioffRay Dalio and Marc Benioff It’s Time for the Next Wave of Ocean Exploration and Protection Opinion: Reigniting exploration of the world’s oceans is essential to protecting our natural resources and promoting scientific advancement. https://www.wired.com/story/forget-space-oceans-need-exploring/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Many Shades of Bad Physics There are different categories of incorrect physics—and each deserves its own strategy. https://www.wired.com/story/the-many-shades-of-bad-physics/

June 8, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez How Science Helps the Warriors Sleep Their Way to Success Not like that. https://www.wired.com/story/how-science-helps-the-warriors-sleep-their-way-to-success/

June 7, 2018 | Author: Kate YoderKate Yoder Can This State Finally Put a Price on Carbon? After a decade of failed carbon taxes, Washington state is pushing to pass the country’s first “carbon fee.” Will this time be different? https://www.wired.com/story/can-this-state-finally-put-a-price-on-carbon/

June 7, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart Alternatives to Cobalt, the Blood Diamond of Batteries Can scientists find a way to power our phones, robots, and electric cars without cobalt? https://www.wired.com/story/alternatives-to-cobalt-the-blood-diamond-of-batteries/

June 7, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon We Need to Talk About Robots Trying to Pass as Humans Robots that mimic humans are getting so entrancing, it’s easy to forget how ethically problematic they could be one day if we’re not careful. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-to-talk-about-robots-trying-to-pass-as-humans/

June 6, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Elections Don’t Work at All. You Can Blame the Math San Francisco still doesn’t have a new mayor. But that’s democracy for you. https://www.wired.com/story/elections-dont-work-at-all-you-can-blame-the-math/

June 6, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr Fans Fight for Egalitarian Access to Gene Editing The applications of gene editing tech will be shaped by the values of the societies that wield it. https://www.wired.com/story/crispr-fans-fight-for-egalitarian-access-to-gene-editing/

June 6, 2018 | Author: Chris BerdikChris Berdik Solar Panels Power New Schools—and New Ways of Learning Nationwide, K-12 schools are leading an oh-so-green zero-energy building boom. https://www.wired.com/story/solar-panels-power-new-schools-and-new-ways-of-learning/

June 5, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Why Apple Can’t Tackle Digital Wellness in a Vacuum The company has unveiled a suite of time-management tools to help balance your digital and real lives—without consulting researchers. https://www.wired.com/story/apple-screen-time/

June 5, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Physics Face-off: The Momentum Principle vs. Newton’s 2nd Law Which method is better? It’s complicated. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-face-off-the-momentum-principle-vs-newtons-2nd-law/

June 5, 2018 | Author: Gloria DickieGloria Dickie Humans Tracked Iceland’s Glaciers For Ages. Now, Tech Does Citizen scientists have served as glacier trackers in Iceland—and witnesses to the ravages of climate change—for generations. Will they continue? https://www.wired.com/story/tech-forces-a-reckoning-for-icelands-glacier-keepers/

June 4, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The Race to Send Robots to Mine the Ocean Floor As worldwide development rises for electric vehicle batteries and wind turbines, the demand for metals from the bottom of the sea has spiked. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-send-robots-to-mine-the-ocean-floor/

June 4, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Can a New Kind of Consumerism Help Fight Climate Change? In a global scenario called Low Energy Demand, a revolution in consumer energy efficiency could help us meet our climate goals. Could. https://www.wired.com/story/is-a-new-kind-of-consumerism-the-fix-to-climate-change/

June 4, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen These Physicists Watched a Clock Tick for 14 Years Straight It was to test Einstein’s theory of general relativity. https://www.wired.com/story/these-physicists-watched-a-clock-tick-for-14-years-straight/

June 4, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Cosmic Ray Showers Crash Supercomputers. Here’s What to Do About It What happens when a national laboratory’s supercomputers start glitching? https://www.wired.com/story/cosmic-ray-showers-crash-supercomputers-heres-what-to-do-about-it/

June 3, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Blood-Based Cancer Test Gets Its First Results The biotech unicorn Grail just gave its first look at how its sequencing-based cancer test prototypes are performing. https://www.wired.com/story/a-blood-based-cancer-test-gets-its-first-results/

June 2, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: A Cruise Around Mars’ Hale Crater Once upon a time, an asteroid or comet got a bit too close to Mars, leaving a deep, permanent reminder of the encounter on the surface of the planet. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-mars-hale-and-hearty-hale-crater/

June 2, 2018 | Author: Philip BallPhilip Ball Questioning Truth, Reality, and the Role of Scientific Progress In an era when untestable ideas such as the multiverse hold sway, Michela Massimi defends science from those who think it hopelessly unmoored from physical reality. https://www.wired.com/story/questioning-truth-reality-and-scientific-progress/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Wild Physics of a Firefighter’s Window Catch This catch looks close to being impossible—but it’s real. https://www.wired.com/story/the-wild-physics-of-a-firefighters-window-catch/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Hurricane Season 2018 Has a Lot to Learn From Last Year The storms of 2017 were the costliest and deadliest ever. And they taught the world some important lessons about science, readiness, and risk. https://www.wired.com/story/hurricane-season-2018-has-a-lot-to-learn-from-last-year/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Scientists Turned This Taxidermy Bird Into a Robot Spoiler: It’s a sage grouse sexbot. https://www.wired.com/story/why-scientists-turned-this-taxidermy-bird-into-a-robot/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Key to Cracking Cold Cases Might Be Genealogy Sites A forensic DNA firm that works with law enforcement says it has uploaded 100 files to GEDmatch, the site that helped identify the alleged Golden State Killer. https://www.wired.com/story/police-will-crack-a-lot-more-cold-cases-with-dna/

June 1, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Did Science Miss Its Best Shot at an AIDS Vaccine? For 35 years, researchers have been trying to beat the virus that causes AIDS. For just as long, Burt Dorman has been advocating another way. https://www.wired.com/story/search-for-aids-vaccine/

May 31, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The ‘Thanksgiving Effect’ and the Creepy Power of Phone Data Researchers used smartphone-location data and polling results to peer into millions of people’s personal lives. Could bad actors do the same? https://www.wired.com/story/the-thanksgiving-effect-and-the-power-of-phone-data/

May 31, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Fast Do Spacecraft Travel in The Expanse? You should never show a physicist a spaceship’s control panel. https://www.wired.com/story/how-fast-do-spacecraft-travel-in-the-expanse/

May 31, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Are So Many Dead Whales Washing Up in the Bay Area? The messy, malodorous mystery of a dead 60-foot whale—just one of three to wash up in a week. https://www.wired.com/story/the-messy-malodorous-mystery-of-the-dead-60-foot-whale/

May 30, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Why Darpa Wants Everyone to Launch Tiny Satellites A flock of little guys is less vulnerable to attack than one big bird. Also, you could maybe send them up with space balloons. https://www.wired.com/story/darpas-little-launch-challenge/

May 30, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe Is Suing Ancestry Over Some Pretty Ancient IP And the outcome of the case could reshape the genetic genealogy testing industry. https://www.wired.com/story/23andme-sues-ancestry/

May 30, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Get a Robot to (One Day) Do Your Chores If we are going to have home assistants that set our tables and fold our clothes, we’re going to have to train them in simulations first. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-get-a-robot-to-one-day-do-your-chores/

May 29, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Wild Logistical Ride of the Ebola Vaccine’s High-Tech Thermos The hardest part of deploying a new Ebola vaccine is teaching people what it’s for. The second hardest part is getting it to them. https://www.wired.com/story/the-wild-logistical-ride-of-the-ebola-vaccines-high-tech-thermos/

May 29, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Facebook Is Giving Scientists Its Data to Fight Misinformation For the first time, researchers will be able to access Facebook’s data and publish their findings without pre-approval from the company. https://www.wired.com/story/facebook-is-giving-scientists-its-data-to-fight-misinformation/

May 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Climate Change Made Zombie Ants Even More Cunning The parasitic fungus that drives ants to sabotage their own colonies has adapted to zombify their quarry better in different climates. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-made-zombie-ants-even-more-cunning/

May 28, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Maybe DNA Can’t Answer All Our Questions About Heredity Carl Zimmer’s new book She Has Her Mother’s Laugh is a book about the question genetics was invented to answer—and perhaps can’t. https://www.wired.com/story/maybe-dna-cant-answer-all-our-questions-about-heredity/

May 28, 2018 | Author: Joshua SokolJoshua Sokol These Spinning Disks of Gas and Dust Reveal How Planets Get Made Detailed images of disks swirling around young stars show the details of how solar systems come to be. https://www.wired.com/story/these-spinning-disks-of-gas-and-dust-reveal-how-planets-get-made/

May 27, 2018 | Author: Brian KeatingBrian Keating There’s Nothing Noble about Science’s Nobel Prize Gender Gap Opinion: Given the dearth of women receiving the top science prizes, it’s time for the Nobel Committee to revamp how it awards great work. https://www.wired.com/story/theres-nothing-noble-about-sciences-nobel-prize-gender-gap/

May 27, 2018 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett A Classical Math Problem Gets Pulled Into Self-Driving Cars A century ago, the great mathematician David Hilbert posed a probing question in pure mathematics. A recent advance in optimization theory is bringing Hilbert’s work into the modern world. https://www.wired.com/story/a-classical-math-problem-gets-pulled-into-self-driving-cars/

May 25, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Accelerating Spacecraft in The Expanse There are no pew-pew lasers or faster-than-light space travel here—just serious science. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-accelerating-spacecraft-in-the-expanse/

May 25, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inconvenient Minifauna and the Invasion of the Hammerhead Flatworms Based on the amount of media attention they’re getting, the worms might work to bring attention to the upending of ecosystems by invasive species. https://www.wired.com/story/inconvenient-minifauna-and-the-invasion-of-the-hammerhead-flatworms/

May 25, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Can a City Really Sue an Oil Company for Climate Change? In a federal court in San Francisco, a judge heard a motion to dismiss from five fossil fuel companies, the defendants in the suit brought by San Francisco and Oakland. https://www.wired.com/story/can-a-city-really-sue-an-oil-company-for-climate-change/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Ingestible Sensors Electronically Monitor Your Guts Researchers are cooking up pill-sized sensors to detect medical molecules and possibly diagnose other gastrointestinal ailments. https://www.wired.com/story/this-digital-pill-prototype-uses-bacteria-to-sense-stomach-bleeding/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Nathanael JohnsonNathanael Johnson Are Avocados Toast? What will we eat in 2050? California farmers are placing bets. https://www.wired.com/story/are-avocados-toast/

May 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Give the Robots Electronic Tongues Roboticists have to not only in create artificial senses of touch and taste, but figure out what robots should ignore in a human world. https://www.wired.com/story/give-the-robots-electronic-tongues/

May 23, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon This Robotic Pollinator Is Like a Huge Bee With Wheels and an Arm In a world with too many humans and not enough pollinators, robots like the BrambleBee could help. https://www.wired.com/story/robotic-pollinator/

May 23, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Scientists Are Using AI to Painstakingly Assemble Single Atoms A machine’s atom-wide tip could help usher in an era of microscopic circuits. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-are-using-ai-to-painstakingly-assemble-single-atoms/

May 23, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Congress Is About to Learn Just How Little Science Knows About Tech Addiction But political interest—and political capital—could drive the research needed for evidence-based policies. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-is-about-to-learn-just-how-little-science-knows-about-tech-addiction/

May 22, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of How a Mirror Creates a Virtual World Human eyes are sort of dumb—but you can trick them into being smart. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-how-a-mirror-creates-a-virtual-world/

May 22, 2018 | Author: Jake BullingerJake Bullinger America’s Fastest-Growing Urban Area Has a Water Problem As St. George, Utah grows, it will have to cut down on its high water consumption or pay handsomely for it—or both. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-fastest-growing-urban-area-has-a-water-problem/

May 22, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Watch SpaceX Launch NASA’s Next Earth-Observing Satellites And five communications satellites from Iridium are piggybacking on the ride. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-spacex-launch-nasas-next-earth-observing-satellites/

May 21, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers An Ebola Vaccine Gets Its First Real-World Test Scientists have known about Ebola since 1976, and the Democratic Republic of Congo has had nine outbreaks since then. But now one shot might beat it. https://www.wired.com/story/an-ebola-vaccine-gets-its-first-real-world-test/

May 21, 2018 | Author: John CarreyrouJohn Carreyrou A Look Inside Theranos’ Dysfunctional Corporate Culture When a chemist raised concerns about the blood testing machines’ high error rates, she was ignored. So she resigned. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-look-inside-theranos-dysfunctional-corporate-culture/

May 21, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The 6-Foot Chinese Giant Salamander Is in Serious Trouble Scientists figured out one species is actually at least five. Which means conservationists have been going about trying to save the creature all wrong. https://www.wired.com/story/the-6-foot-chinese-giant-salamander/

May 20, 2018 | Author: Shannon HallShannon Hall A New World’s Extraordinary Orbit Points to Planet Nine Astronomers argue that there’s an undiscovered giant planet far beyond the orbit of Neptune. A newly discovered rocky body has added evidence to the circumstantial case for it. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-worlds-extraordinary-orbit-points-to-planet-nine/

May 19, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Mars Gets Pac-Man Fever NASA just released an image of a crater-dune combination it is calling Bachan Pac-Man. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-mars-pacman/

May 18, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe Goes Global In Its Data-Mining Efforts The consumer genetics company is opening its data set to some researchers—and recruiting others to make that data set more robust in the first place. https://www.wired.com/story/23andme-outside-researchers/

May 18, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Shape-Shifting Robot That Evolves by Falling Down Evolutionary robotics is a potentially powerful way to get machines to master novel terrain on their own, no hand-holding required. https://www.wired.com/story/the-shape-shifting-robot-that-evolves-by-falling-down/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How Volcanologists Predicted Kilauea’s Explosive Eruption Scientists are now warning that the next phase of eruptions could send very large boulders as far as a mile from the crater. https://www.wired.com/story/how-volcanologists-predicted-kilaueas-explosive-eruption/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of a Tesla Model X Towing a Boeing 787 This Dreamliner weighs 130,000 kg—but actually, even a human could pull a full-sized aircraft. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-a-tesla-model-x-pulling-a-boeing-787/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA’s Jim Bridenstine Agrees Humans Are Responsible for Climate Change “We are putting [carbon dioxide] into the atmosphere in volumes we haven’t seen before,” said NASA’s new administrator. “We are responsible for it.” https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-jim-bridenstine-agrees-humans-are-responsible-for-climate-change/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Spermbots Offer a Promising New Way to Target Cancer After discovering that sperm could be coaxed into carrying chemotherapy drugs, researchers shifted their focus from inducing life to slaying reproductive cancer. https://www.wired.com/story/spermbots-offer-a-promising-new-way-to-target-cancer/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Physics—and Physicality—of Extreme Juggling The world’s best numbers juggler can throw and catch 14 balls. Once. Has he reached juggling’s limit? https://www.wired.com/story/the-physicsand-physicalityof-extreme-juggling/

May 17, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Fun Ideas That Keep Kids Learning Even After School’s Out Boredom is just the start of an adventure. https://www.wired.com/story/fun-ideas-to-keep-learning-even-after-schools-out/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Fundamental Nihilism of Yanny vs. Laurel When everyone’s brain makes a little world out of sensory input, and everyone’s world is just a little bit different, can you really know anyone? https://www.wired.com/story/the-fundamental-nihilism-of-yanny-vs-laurel/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Scientists Are Subverting Formal Publishing. Well, Some of Them A survey shows which scientists are more likely to share their results before “official” publication. https://www.wired.com/story/scientists-are-subverting-formal-publication-well-some-of-them/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of NASA’s New Mars Helicopter Needless to say, this coaxial, self-powered chopper is not your traditional helicopter. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-nasas-new-mars-helicopter/

May 16, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Is This Stem-Cell Clinic Really Making Cancer Vaccines? In a Facebook Live video, the CSO of one of the largest networks of stem-cell clinics in the country touted a new, unregulated treatment. https://www.wired.com/story/is-this-stem-cell-clinic-really-making-cancer-vaccines/

May 15, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart This Insect-Sized Flying Robot Is Powered by Lasers It’s the first robo-fly that doesn’t need to be tethered to a power supply. https://www.wired.com/story/this-insect-sized-flying-robot-is-powered-by-lasers/

May 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Darpa’s Next Challenge? A Grueling Underground Journey Darpa calls on researchers to autonomously explore the innards of Earth. Get ready for high drama and some fantastical-looking robots. https://www.wired.com/story/darpas-next-challenge-a-grueling-underground-journey/

May 14, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler How NASA Will Look for Geysers (and Life) on Europa Future spacecraft will scan for biomarkers of life in the ocean of Jupiter’s moon. https://www.wired.com/story/how-nasa-will-look-for-geysers-and-life-on-europa/

May 14, 2018 | Author: Sean W. FlemingSean W. Fleming Lessons from Montecito: Science’s Credibility Is At Stake Opinion: Residents’ failure to follow expert advice during mudslides signal a loss of faith in science. https://www.wired.com/story/lessons-from-montecito/

May 14, 2018 | Author: Melody SchreiberMelody Schreiber The Race to Save Arctic Cities As Permafrost Melts As the ground shifts beneath their feet, officials in Canada’s Nunavut turn to creative engineering to save scarce homes—and plan for a future built on bedrock. https://www.wired.com/story/the-race-to-save-arctic-cities-as-permafrost-melts/

May 14, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Japanese Space Bots That Could Build ‘Moon Valley’ The Lunar X Prize may be dead, but this startup still wants to go to the moon. https://www.wired.com/story/the-japanese-space-bots-that-could-build-moon-valley/

May 13, 2018 | Author: John RennieJohn Rennie Artificial Neural Nets Grow Brainlike Cells to Find Their Way Faced with a navigational challenge, neural networks spontaneously evolved units resembling the brain cells that help living animals track their location. https://www.wired.com/story/artificial-neural-nets-grow-brainlike-cells-to-find-their-way/

May 12, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Mini-Moons Make Saturn’s Rings Extra Groovy Pan, the “ravioli moon,” carves a path through the pretty debris ringing this most photogenic of planets. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-saturns-rings-are-groovy/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Hey Alexa, What Are You Doing to My Kid’s Brain? The new Echo Dot Kids edition encourages kids to be polite, but psychologists and ethicists want parents to ask deeper questions than will Alexa make my kid a jerk? https://www.wired.com/story/hey-alexa-what-are-you-doing-to-my-kids-brain/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Boston Dynamics’ Robot Dog Will Be Available Next Year The secretive company has long been research-focused, but that doesn’t mean it hasn’t been thinking about what consumers want out of SpotMini. https://www.wired.com/story/boston-dynamics-robot-dog-spotmini-will-be-available-next-year/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Something’s Off With the Turbolaser Shots in The Last Jedi I’m OK with movies fudging science a bit—except when the rules of “physics” change within their universe. https://www.wired.com/story/somethings-off-with-the-turbolaser-shots-in-the-last-jedi/

May 11, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Can This AI-Powered Baby Translator Help Diagnose Autism? With enough data from the Chatterbaby app, researchers could mine irregularities in cry patterns for signals about hunger, pain—and maybe one day, autism. https://www.wired.com/story/can-this-ai-powered-baby-translator-help-diagnose-autism/

May 10, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Implacable Power of Volcanic Lava The Army Air Corps once even tried to stop an active volcano with bombs. No dice. https://www.wired.com/story/the-implacable-power-of-volcanic-lava/

May 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Lots of Doctors Recommend Weed Without Understanding It Half of oncologists who recommended marijuana did so without feeling they had sufficient knowledge of the drug. https://www.wired.com/story/lots-of-doctors-recommend-weed-without-understanding-it/

May 10, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Arena Where Drones Battle a Wall of 1,300 Computer Fans In Caltech’s fancy new drone arena, the machines face terrifying atmospheric disturbances, all to help shape the future of flight. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-arena-where-drones-battle-computer-fans/

May 10, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Watch the New SpaceX Reusable Rocket Make Its Debut The Block 5 version of the Falcon 9 is designed to re-fly as soon as 48 hours after landing. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-the-new-spacex-reusable-rocket-make-its-debut/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Research Behind Google’s New Tools for Digital Well-Being Google wants to foster JOMO—the joy of missing out—by helping users understand their habits and unplug from their phones. https://www.wired.com/story/the-research-behind-googles-new-tools-for-digital-well-being/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen This Random Videogame Powers Quantum Entanglement Experiments How a simplistic keyboard-mashing game recruited thousands of players—for physics! https://www.wired.com/story/this-random-video-game-powers-quantum-entanglement-experiments/

May 9, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Swinging a Mass on a String for Fun With a specific setup, you can control the tension in the string. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-swinging-a-mass-on-a-string-for-fun/

May 8, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Tornado’s Secret Sounds Could Reveal Where It’ll Strike Tornadoes seem to emit sounds the human ear can’t hear. That could help scientists develop better early detection systems. https://www.wired.com/story/a-tornados-secret-sounds/

May 8, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni This Startup Wants to Be Airbnb for Gene Sequencers Gene sequencers are pricey, so many researchers rent time on the machines. Now a startup called Meenta is simplifying the reservation process. https://www.wired.com/story/meenta-gene-sequencing/

May 7, 2018 | Author: Jessica Leigh HesterJessica Leigh Hester What Ecologists Can Learn From Memes Some scientists are studying YouTube comments and trying to do their part for the world—by going viral. https://www.wired.com/story/what-ecologists-can-learn-from-memes/

May 6, 2018 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch Troubled Times for Alternatives to Einstein’s Theory of Gravity New observations of extreme astrophysical systems have “brutally and pitilessly murdered” attempts to replace Einstein’s general theory of relativity. https://www.wired.com/story/troubled-times-for-alternatives-to-einsteins-theory-of-gravity/

May 6, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The NIH Launches Its Ambitious Million-Person Genetic Survey The All of Us precision health initiative could lead to medical breakthroughs—but the agency has to lock the doors tight to make sure sensitive data doesn’t get hacked or leaked. https://www.wired.com/story/all-of-us-launches/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why Is NASA’s InSight Mars Mission Launching from California? This month, NASA will fire its first interplanetary mission from Vandenberg Air Force Base north of Los Angeles. Why the snub for Cape Canaveral in Florida? https://www.wired.com/story/why-is-nasas-insight-mars-mission-launching-from-california/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers How to Fight Climate Change: Figure Out Who’s to Blame, and Sue Them It’s only possible with the new science of extreme weather attribution. https://www.wired.com/story/climate-attribution-sue/

May 4, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of Leia Using the Force Happy Star Wars Day! Celebrate by determining how much force is applied by the Force. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-leia-using-the-force/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Figure Out Where You Are With Nothing But a Watch and Protractor Teach yourself the basics of celestial navigation. https://www.wired.com/story/figure-out-where-you-are-with-nothing-but-a-watch-and-protractor/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How to Interact With Robots Without Embarrassing Yourself Researchers are crashing tiny drones into PhD students to make humans and machines get along better. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-interact-with-robots/

May 3, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Biology Will Be the Next Great Computing Platform New companies are popping up to become the Amazons, Apples, and Intels of genome engineering. https://www.wired.com/story/biology-will-be-the-next-great-computing-platform/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Want to Prune Trees More Easily? Use Physics A blade will slice into a limb at some particular minimum pressure—but there are different ways to reach that value. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-prune-trees-more-easily-use-physics/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles This Trucking Company Keeps Spacecraft Safe on the Interstate McCollister’s hauls a lot of oversized things, from astronaut capsules to weather-monitoring satellites to military aircraft. And it goes fine—usually. https://www.wired.com/story/this-trucking-company-keeps-spacecraft-safe-on-the-interstate/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez NASA’s InSight Lander Will Probe Mars, Measure Its Quakes Brace yourself, Mars. NASA’s sending a 5-meter probe to take your temperature. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-insight-lander-will-probe-mars-measure-its-quakes/

May 2, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Insect-Borne Diseases Have Tripled. Here’s Why. More people get sick from mosquito, tick, and flea bites than ever before. Climate change is a culprit, yes. But there are other factors at play. https://www.wired.com/story/insect-borne-diseases-have-tripled-heres-why/

May 1, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Robotics Startup Perishes, and It’s Got Tales to Tell With the demise of TickTock comes valuable insights into what the robotic home of the future may look like, and which company will end up conquering it. https://www.wired.com/story/a-robotics-startup-perishes-and-its-got-tales-to-tell/

May 1, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Testosterone Ruling for Athletes Fuels Debate Over ‘Natural’ Ability Women with high levels of testosterone—like Olympic gold medalist Caster Semenya—must either compete against men or take medication. https://www.wired.com/story/testosterone-ruling-for-athletes-fuels-debate-over-natural-ability/

May 1, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Does Your Doctor Need a Voice Assistant? By helping them spend more time listening to patients and less time typing into electronic health records, voice assistants aim to keep physicians from getting burned out. https://www.wired.com/story/does-your-doctor-need-a-voice-assistant/

May 1, 2018 | Author: Amanda SchafferAmanda Schaffer The Dying Scientist and His Rogue Vaccine Trial Bill Halford was convinced he’d found a miracle cure, but he was running out of time to prove it. So he teamed up with a Hollywood executive and recruited a band of desperate patients. https://www.wired.com/story/infectious-rogue-vaccine-trial/

April 30, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Too High, Drunk, or Sleepy to Drive? One Day Your Phone Could Know Eventually, phone-based sobriety tests could tell you if you’re too drunk, stoned, or sleepy to drive. https://www.wired.com/story/portable-field-sobriety-tests/

April 30, 2018 | Author: Evelyn LambEvelyn Lamb An Anti-Aging Pundit Solves a Decades-Old Math Problem By making the first progress on the “chromatic number of the plane” problem in over 60 years, biologist Aubrey de Grey has achieved mathematical immortality. https://www.wired.com/story/an-anti-aging-pundit-solves-a-decades-old-math-problem/

April 30, 2018 | Author: Sharon WeinbergerSharon Weinberger How a Soviet A-Bomb Test Launched US Climate Science The untold story of a failed Russian geoengineering scheme, panic in the Pentagon, and a Nixon-era effort to study global cooling. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-soviet-a-bomb-test-launched-us-climate-science/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni The Creepy Genetics Behind the Golden State Killer Case In the end, it wasn’t stakeouts or fingerprints or cell phone records that got him. It was a genealogy website. https://www.wired.com/story/detectives-cracked-the-golden-state-killer-case-using-genetics/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Terrifying Technological Tactics Behind BattleBots Here’s the fundamental physics behind every class of robots in the showdown. https://www.wired.com/story/the-terrifying-technological-tactics-behind-battlebots/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Chemists Orchestrate the Molecular Union of Two Single Atoms It’s a molecular Parent Trap: Stick two atoms in a vacuum chamber, and steer them together with lasers. https://www.wired.com/story/chemists-orchestrate-the-molecular-union-of-two-single-atoms/

April 27, 2018 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser Fukushima’s Other Big Problem: A Million Tons of Radioactive Water More than 1 million tons of radiation-laced water is already being kept on-site in an ever-expanding forest of hundreds of hulking steel tanks. https://www.wired.com/story/fukushimas-other-big-problem-a-million-tons-of-radioactive-water/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Nature’s Mechanical Secrets Could Help Build Faster Robots Some small animals can produce bullet-like accelerations—could robots do it, too? https://www.wired.com/story/natures-mechanical-secrets-could-help-build-faster-robots/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A New Startup Wants to Use Crispr to Diagnose Disease Genetics pioneer Jennifer Doudna has launched the first commercial Crispr platform for detecting disease-causing DNA. https://www.wired.com/story/a-new-startup-wants-to-use-crispr-to-diagnose-disease/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler If Scott Pruitt Leaves, Will EPA Science Change Course? Advocates say attacks on science and deregulation would continue under the agency’s number two. https://www.wired.com/story/if-scott-pruitt-leaves-will-epa-science-change-course/

April 26, 2018 | Author: Vince BeiserVince Beiser The Robot Assault On Fukushima The 2011 earthquake and tsunami in Japan triggered a devastating catastrophe in one of the country’s largest nuclear power plants. The cleanup will take decades, and it’s no job for humans. https://www.wired.com/story/fukushima-robot-cleanup/

April 25, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Lab Making Robots Walk Through Fire and Ride Segways Benefits of robots: 1. They never get tired. 2. They can lift very heavy things. 3. They can walk through (controlled) conflagrations at the University of Michigan. https://www.wired.com/story/the-lab-making-robots-walk-through-fire-and-ride-segways/

April 25, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain USC Wide Receiver Josh Imatorbhebhe’s Crazy Floating Jump Is this normal physics, some type of optical illusion, or just plain magic? https://www.wired.com/story/usc-wide-receiver-josh-imatorbhebhes-crazy-floating-jump/

April 25, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles What Happens When Science Just Disappears? When one of the first online science journals went under, its papers all disappeared. Here’s how a crack team got them (mostly) back. https://www.wired.com/story/what-happens-when-science-just-disappears/

April 24, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Delivery Bots Have Awkward Sidewalk Interactions, Too Marble wants to make these things proficient enough to find their own way around the people and the buskers and the intersections. https://www.wired.com/story/delivery-bots-have-awkward-sidewalk-interactions-too/

April 24, 2018 | Author: Laura BlissLaura Bliss Lyft Delivers Carbon-Neutral Rides The ride-hailing company announced last week that it plans to become one of the largest voluntary purchasers of carbon offsets in the world. https://www.wired.com/story/lyft-delivers-carbon-neutral-rides/

April 23, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni California’s Water Whiplash Is Only Going to Get Worse Get ready for more dramatic shifts between severe drought and record-breaking rainfall. https://www.wired.com/story/californias-water-whiplash-is-only-going-to-get-worse/

April 23, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Corals Are in Serious Trouble. This Lab Could Help Save Them Scientists reach a milestone in establishing a captive coral population that could reproduce year after year, allowing researchers to perform crucial studies. https://www.wired.com/story/corals-are-in-serious-trouble-this-lab-could-help-save-them/

April 21, 2018 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Machine Learning’s ‘Amazing’ Ability to Predict Chaos In new computer experiments, artificial-intelligence algorithms can tell the future of chaotic systems. https://www.wired.com/story/machine-learnings-amazing-ability-to-predict-chaos/

April 21, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Just How Random Are Two Factor Authentication Codes? Have you noticed patterns in those ephemeral, six-digit tokens? There’s a reason for that. https://www.wired.com/story/2fa-randomness/

April 20, 2018 | Author: Fred VogelsteinFred Vogelstein My Son Pioneered an Epilepsy Drug Derived From Marijuana. An FDA Panel Just Approved It The treatment was fast-tracked for approval, and the first person to use the drug in the US was our writer’s son. https://www.wired.com/story/my-son-pioneered-an-epilepsy-drug-derived-from-marijuana-an-fda-panel-just-approved-it/

April 20, 2018 | Author: Michael SchulsonMichael Schulson Science’s “Reproducibility Crisis” Is Being Used as Political Ammunition A report from the National Association of Scholars takes on the reproducibility crisis in science. Not everyone views the group’s motives as pure. https://www.wired.com/story/sciences-reproducibility-crisis-is-being-used-as-political-ammunition/

April 20, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni 23andMe Wants You to Share Even More Health Data On a new health portal, 23andMe encourages customers to share how they manage common health conditions. It’s not hard to see who gets the better side of the deal. https://www.wired.com/story/23andme-wants-you-to-share-even-more-health-data/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Physics Explains Why No One Can Beat the Freeze A spandex-clad superhero keeps beating Atlanta Braves fans…even when they have a huge head start. https://www.wired.com/story/physics-explains-why-no-one-can-beat-the-freeze/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Clever Vine-Like Robot That Grows and Steers With Air Vinebot is part of the first generation of advanced “soft robots,” which promise to go where no traditional robot can tread—literally. https://www.wired.com/story/vinebot/

April 19, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Biotech Gets Some Silicon Valley Shine at Illumina’s New Campus With tons of amenities, the DNA sequencing giant hopes to attract the Bay Area’s top life science talent. https://www.wired.com/story/biotech-gets-some-silicon-valley-shine-at-illuminas-new-campus/

April 18, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Why Can’t We Fix Puerto Rico’s Power Grid? The only upside to Puerto Rico’s island-wide blackout is that engineers and aid groups could rethink it from the ground up. They may have to. https://www.wired.com/story/why-cant-we-fix-puerto-ricos-power-grid/

April 18, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Let’s Use Star Wars to Explain the Concept of Angular Size Could you actually see invading Star Destroyers from the surface of a planet? https://www.wired.com/story/lets-use-star-wars-to-explain-the-concept-of-angular-size/

April 18, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon A Robot Does the Impossible: Assembling an Ikea Chair Without Having a Meltdown Researchers use off-the-shelf robot parts to piece together one of those Stefan Ikea chairs. https://www.wired.com/story/a-robot-does-the-impossible-assembling-an-ikea-chair-without-having-a-meltdown/

April 18, 2018 | Author: Natalie WolchoverNatalie Wolchover Trouble Detected in Infamous Dark Matter Signal New results from a decades-old experiment were initially touted as further evidence for dark matter. But independent scientists have cast serious doubt on that claim. https://www.wired.com/story/trouble-detected-in-infamous-dark-matter-signal/

April 17, 2018 | Author: Maria GallucciMaria Gallucci The Shipping Industry Sets Sail Toward a Carbon-Free Future Cargo-shipping regulators have struck a historic deal to set their dirty fuel-burning industry on a low-carbon course. https://www.wired.com/story/the-shipping-industry-sets-sail-toward-a-carbon-free-future/

April 17, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Plan to Save California’s Legendary Weed From ‘Big Cannabis’ Inside the sprawling new facility that wants to help small cannabis farmers survive the invasion of Big Cannabis. https://www.wired.com/story/the-plan-to-save-californias-legendary-weed-from-big-cannabis/

April 17, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez NASA’s New Exoplanet Satellite Has a Better Shot of Finding Life Close to Home TESS is designed to find and study the exoplanets closest to Earth. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-new-exoplanet-satellite-has-a-better-shot-of-finding-life-close-to-home/

April 16, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Incredibles 2 Asks: What’s the Right Way to Solve a Math Problem? The new Pixar movie has a trailer that makes you think about how teaching math really works. https://www.wired.com/story/incredibles-2-asks-whats-the-right-way-to-solve-a-math-problem/

April 16, 2018 | Author: Amy ThompsonAmy Thompson Watch SpaceX Loft NASA’s New Planet-Hunting Mission Into Orbit The TESS satellite will hitch a ride atop a Falcon 9 rocket to search out new worlds. https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-tess-nasa/

April 15, 2018 | Author: Kevin HartnettKevin Hartnett Exploring the Mirror Link Between Two Geometric Worlds Decades after stumbling upon a stunning coincidence, researchers are close to understanding the link between two seemingly unrelated geometric universes. https://www.wired.com/story/math-mirror/

April 14, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Morning Light Hits the Southern Lights Unearthly celestial events, Martian craters, and Jovian storms. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-martian-craters-jovian-storms/

April 14, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler As Scientists March, Federal Researchers Weather Trump Storm Many anti-Trump protesters have turned their attention toward recruiting scientists to run for office in local, state, and congressional offices. https://www.wired.com/story/mfs-scientists-weather-trump/

April 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Catching up With Pepper, the Surprisingly Helpful Humanoid Robot Pepper is part of the first wave of intelligent machines that promise to not only make our lives easier, but to bring a strange new form of interaction into being. https://www.wired.com/story/pepper-the-humanoid-robot/

April 13, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni How the March for Science Became a Movement “In 2017 we marched for science. In 2018, we vote for science.” https://www.wired.com/story/mos-movement/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez AI Learns a New Trick: Measuring Brain Cells New techniques could help researchers outsource the grunt work of neuroscience. https://www.wired.com/story/ai-learns-a-new-trick-measuring-brain-cells/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Why It’s Almost Impossible for Fastballs to Get Any Faster Advances have fueled a dramatic upward trend in world-record athletic performances, but the baseball pitch is stuck. The reason is physics. https://www.wired.com/story/why-its-almost-impossible-for-fastballs-to-get-any-faster/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Amy WebbAmy Webb Space Oddities: We Need a Plan to Stop Polluting Space Before It’s Too Late Opinion: Before we start colonizing other planets, we have to deal with all the junk we’ve hurtled into the atmosphere. https://www.wired.com/story/we-need-a-plan-to-stop-polluting-space-before-its-too-late/

April 12, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Case of the Evaporating Exoplanets What if some of the Earth-like planets discovered by Kepler aren’t there at all? https://www.wired.com/story/the-case-of-the-evaporating-exoplanets/

April 11, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Want to Fight Sea Level Rise? Look to San Francisco’s Ocean Beach During a big storm, the bluffs along Ocean Beach can lose 25 to 40 feet. Here’s how San Francisco is hedging against sea level rise. https://www.wired.com/story/want-to-fight-sea-level-rise-look-to-san-franciscos-ocean-beach/

April 11, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Quantum Mechanics Could Solve Cryptography’s Random Number Problem A perfectly provable random number generator is the bedrock of good cryptography. This scientist wants to make one. https://www.wired.com/story/quantum-mechanics-could-solve-cryptographys-random-number-problem/

April 10, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Many G’s Will the Hyperloop Pull in Its Next Test? Elon Musk tweeted that a hyperloop test will accelerate to half the speed of sound and brake in just 1.2 kilometers. https://www.wired.com/story/how-many-gs-will-the-hyperloop-pull-in-its-next-test/

April 10, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain What Random Walks in Multiple Dimensions Teach You About Life There are real world applications of the stochastic mathematical process known as a random walk—really. https://www.wired.com/story/what-random-walks-in-multiple-dimensions-teach-you-about-life/

April 10, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Helix Takes Clinical Genetic Testing Straight to Consumers Soon, anyone curious about their health will be able to request a clinical DNA test—not just doctors. https://www.wired.com/story/helix-takes-clinical-genetic-testing-straight-to-consumers/

April 9, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Cleanroom Where NASA’s New Mars Lander Waits to Launch The InSight lander will probe beneath the surface of Mars to understand its geology—unless humans contaminate it first. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-cleanroom-where-nasas-new-mars-lander-waits-to-launch/

April 8, 2018 | Author: Monique BrouilletteMonique Brouillette New Brain Maps With Unmatched Detail May Change Neuroscience A technique based on genetic bar codes can easily map the connections of individual brain cells in unprecedented numbers. Unexpected complexity in the visual system is only the first secret it has revealed. https://www.wired.com/story/new-brain-maps-with-unmatched-detail-may-change-neuroscience/

April 7, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: The Case of the Missing Dark Matter Galaxy NGC 1052-DF2 doesn’t seem to contain any dark matter, and scientists have no idea why. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-case-of-the-missing-dark-matter/

April 7, 2018 | Author: Patrick HonnerPatrick Honner Why Winning in Rock-Paper-Scissors Isn’t Everything What does John Nash’s game theory equilibrium concept look like in Rock-Paper-Scissors? https://www.wired.com/story/why-winning-in-rock-paper-scissors-isnt-everything/

April 6, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers A Month’s Worth of Rain Will Hit California This Weekend An atmospheric river means this weekend is going to be as wet as an entire typical April. https://www.wired.com/story/a-months-worth-of-rain-will-hit-california-this-weekend/

April 6, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez A Brain-Boosting Prosthesis Moves From Rats to Humans An algorithm tailored to individual brain activity shows it can boost memory with electrical zaps. https://www.wired.com/story/hippocampal-neural-prosthetic/

April 5, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler From AI to Russia, Here’s How Estonia’s President Is Planning for the Future Kersti Kaljulaid, Estonia’s youngest and first female president, lays out her plans for moving the country from a traditional state to a digital society. https://www.wired.com/story/from-ai-to-russia-heres-how-estonias-president-is-planning-for-the-future/

April 5, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Do You Weigh More at the Equator or at the North Pole? In which a physics professor severely overthinks his daughter’s science homework. https://www.wired.com/story/do-you-weigh-more-at-the-equator-or-at-the-north-pole/

April 5, 2018 | Author: Marcello RossiMarcello Rossi Will a Huge New Flood Barrier Save Venice? Finally, construction is finishing on the delayed barrier to protect the city from high tides. But how well will MOSE actually work? https://www.wired.com/story/will-a-huge-new-flood-barrier-save-venice/

April 4, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni With Some Structure, Stem Cells Might Still Stop Vision Loss Poorly regulated stem cell treatments have blinded some macular degeneration patients. But a new technique is showing therapeutic promise. https://www.wired.com/story/with-some-structure-stem-cells-might-still-stop-vision-loss/

April 4, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Too Much Engineering Has Made Mississippi River Floods Worse New research confirms that the river’s worst floods aren’t just the result of bad weather—they’re the result of bad engineering. https://www.wired.com/story/too-much-engineering-has-made-mississippi-river-floods-worse/

April 4, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles The Woman Who Knows Everything About the Universe For 16 years, Virginia Trimble read every astronomy paper in 23 journals. Now, her review papers are part of the canon. https://www.wired.com/story/the-woman-who-knows-everything-about-the-universe/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Stephen WolframStephen Wolfram 2001: A Space Odyssey Predicted the Future—50 Years Ago Stanley Kubrick’s iconic film gave us Hal and other sci-fi elements. Here’s how they stack up against reality. https://www.wired.com/story/2001-a-space-odyssey-predicted-the-future50-years-ago/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why These Bumblebees Are Wearing Itty-Bitty QR Codes Researchers have been super-gluing little barcodes to bumblebees in order to track their movements in unprecedented detail. https://www.wired.com/story/why-these-bumblebees-are-wearing-itty-bitty-qr-codes/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics Behind a Fake Flying Samurai Battle Quality is one sign of a video hoax, but physics gives you indisputable evidence. https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-behind-a-fake-flying-samurai-battle/

April 3, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Mini Brains Just Got Creepier—They’re Growing Their Own Veins The more like real brains they become, the more useful these organoids are for studying complex behaviors and neurological diseases. https://www.wired.com/story/mini-brains-just-got-creepiertheyre-growing-their-own-veins/

April 2, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Flawed Study Shows How Little We Understand Crispr’s Effects Flaws in a study about unintended gene editing snips have led to its retraction. But that’s not the end of the story. https://www.wired.com/story/a-flawed-study-shows-how-little-we-understand-crisprs-effects/

April 2, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Watch SpaceX Launch Its Resupply Mission to the ISS The most significant thing about Monday’s cargo run may be that there is little novelty to it whatsoever https://www.wired.com/story/spacex-14-iss-cargo-mission/

April 1, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart The Hairy Problem With Drug Testing For some African American police officers, a false positive can leave their careers dangling on a thin strand. https://www.wired.com/story/the-hairy-problem-with-drug-testing/

March 31, 2018 | Author: Carolyn CristCarolyn Crist Use Science (Not Surgery) to Create Your Best Selfie 42 percent of plastic surgeons have seen patients specifically looking to up their selfie game. You don’t need surgery; you need math. https://www.wired.com/story/use-science-not-surgery-to-create-your-best-selfie/

March 31, 2018 | Author: Liz KruesiLiz Kruesi Whisper From the First Stars Sets Off Loud Dark Matter Debate A surprise discovery announced a month ago suggested that the early universe looked very different than previously believed. Initial theories that the discrepancy was due to dark matter have come under fire. https://www.wired.com/story/whisper-from-the-first-stars-sets-off-loud-dark-matter-debate/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez All the Places Tiangong-1 Won’t Land (and Where It Still Might) Large swaths of Earth are already safe from falling space debris. https://www.wired.com/story/all-the-places-tiangong-1-wont-land-and-where-it-still-might/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Ocean Acidification Could Be a Net Positive for Some Fish Baby herring adapt to extra carbon dioxide in the water; cod and clams, not so much. https://www.wired.com/story/ocean-acidification-might-not-be-bad-for-every-fish/

March 30, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Crispr’d Food, Coming Soon to a Supermarket Near You This week the USDA announced it has no plans to regulate gene-editing technologies like Crispr, opening the door to a boom in designer foods. https://www.wired.com/story/crisprd-food-coming-soon-to-a-supermarket-near-you/

March 29, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Model China’s Tiangong-1 Space Station Crash When and where will the Chinese space station land? We can’t know for sure—but we can examine some variables. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-model-chinas-tiangong-1-space-station-crash/

March 29, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Some Frogs May Be Developing a Resistance to the Disastrous Chytrid Fungus Certain frog species are rebounding after a fungal invasion, probably not because the fungus got any less deadly—the frogs may be evolving to resist the pathogen. https://www.wired.com/story/some-frogs-may-be-developing-a-resistance-to-the-disastrous-chytrid-fungus/

March 29, 2018 | Author: Ian McMahanIan McMahan The Tricky Ethics of the NFL’s New Open Data Policy The NFL will start sharing RFID data on its players with every team—opening up questions about the ethics of analytics in the game. https://www.wired.com/story/the-tricky-ethics-of-the-nfls-new-open-data-policy/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler NASA’s New Parker Probe Will Skim the Sun’s Surface Engineers hope a special heat shield will keep the craft cool while it collects space weather info. https://www.wired.com/story/nasas-new-parker-probe-will-skim-the-suns-surface/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen The Case of the Missing Dark Matter Physicists have discovered a galaxy 65 million light years away with so little dark matter that it may contain none at all. https://www.wired.com/story/the-case-of-the-missing-dark-matter/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Model How Light Reflects Off a Mirror With Python Anything you can do with a pencil and paper is worth doing in code. https://www.wired.com/story/model-how-light-reflects-off-a-mirror-with-python/

March 28, 2018 | Author: Katherine EllisonKatherine Ellison Why Climate Change Skeptics Are Backing Geoengineering Under the Trump administration, untested, privately funded projects to manipulate the climate have been gaining unprecedented momentum. https://www.wired.com/story/why-climate-change-skeptics-are-backing-geoengineering/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Kate ConnolloyKate Connolloy How a Store of Rhino Semen Could Save the Species Thomas Hildebrandt has been collecting samples from the white rhinoceros with colleagues for about 15 years. https://www.wired.com/story/how-a-store-of-rhino-semen-could-save-the-species/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Cannabis Tech Can Help Build a Better Cup of Coffee Clean, tasty coffee that begins life in a lab takes a cue from the cultivation of marijuana. https://www.wired.com/story/how-cannabis-tech-can-help-build-a-better-cup-of-coffee/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Robin Marantz HenigRobin Marantz Henig Women May Have an Alternative to Freezing Their Eggs To stave off what’s called “anticipated gamete exhaustion,” would-be moms could freeze their ovarian tissue and have it reimplanted it later. https://www.wired.com/story/reboot-reproduction-modern-fertility/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Gregory BarberGregory Barber The Science Behind the Pursuit of Youth As researchers begin to understand how aging works at a molecular level, there’s a glint of promise—and oodles of hype—in new life-extension treatments. https://www.wired.com/story/antiaging-methods/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Phuc PhamPhuc Pham Sophisticated Tools Lead to Breakthroughs in Prenatal Surgery Modified instruments have led to fewer preterm deliveries and C-sections for mothers, and these surgeries have helped improve survival rates for infants. https://www.wired.com/story/nicu-tools-fetal-surgery/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Sarah FallonSarah Fallon How Kids Can Use ‘Screen Time’ to Their Advantage Developmental psychologist Alison Gopnik wants us to take a deep breath—and focus on the quality, not quantity, of the time kids use tech. https://www.wired.com/story/kids-screen-time-allison-gopnik/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Hayley CampbellHayley Campbell A New Way to Dispose of Corpses—With Chemistry! Alkaline hydrolysis is a clean, green method for dissolving a body into its chemical building blocks; the runny remains just wash down the drain. https://www.wired.com/story/alkaline-hydrolysis-liquid-biocremation/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Eva HollandEva Holland Saving Baby Boy Green Born at a barely viable 24 weeks, his life began as a battle for survival. His future is a test for how far neonatal medicine has come. https://www.wired.com/story/preemies-neonatal-medicine/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Virginia HeffernanVirginia Heffernan What Are Screens Doing to Our Eyes—and Our Ability to See? Our eyes are hardening; we can barely see our phones anymore. We must learn to look at the wider world. https://www.wired.com/story/failing-vision-screens-blindness/

March 27, 2018 | Author: David Ewing DuncanDavid Ewing Duncan The Next Best Version of Me: How to Live Forever Researchers want to synthesize an optimized human genome that can be stored indefinitely and grown decades from now. So I volunteered mine. https://www.wired.com/story/live-forever-synthetic-human-genome/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Chelsea LeuChelsea Leu How Science Is Solving Health Issues at All Stages of Life From allergies to Alzheimer’s, here are some big ones science and tech are helping to solve. https://www.wired.com/story/science-solving-health-issues/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Jason PontinJason Pontin Science Is Getting Us Closer to the End of Infertility In an era of artificial eggs and Crispr, anyone could become a biological parent to the healthiest baby. https://www.wired.com/story/reverse-infertility/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Gerald MarzoratiGerald Marzorati Telomeres Are the New Cholesterol. Now What? Parts of our chromosomes called telomeres are seen a sort of aging biomarker. Long, you’ve got a while. Short, don’t buy any green bananas. But what do we do with that information? https://www.wired.com/story/biomarkers-age-management/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Clive ThompsonClive Thompson You Know Who’s Really Addicted to Their Phones? The Olds. Millennials have gotten a bad rap. Graying Gen Xers are the ones who can’t get their faces out of their screens. https://www.wired.com/story/gen-x-adhd-screen-addiction/

March 27, 2018 | Author: Katrina KarkazisKatrina Karkazis The Testosterone Myth Big T conquered the imagination of millions of men looking for renewed vigor. libido, and cognition. But there’s scant evidence that the hormone can actually conquer the ravages of age. https://www.wired.com/story/testosterone-treatment-myth/

March 26, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch Astronauts Answer Your Burning Questions About Space We’ve assembled seven astronauts to prove just how smart and cool they are by answering the top 50 Googled questions about space. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-astronauts-answer-your-burning-questions-about-space/

March 26, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Ski Resorts Fight Climate Change With Snow Guns and Buses “We are going to have to be appreciative of what we get.” https://www.wired.com/story/ski-resorts-fight-climate-change-with-snow-blowers-and-buses/

March 25, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Cambridge Analytica Data Apocalypse Was Predicted in 2007 The scientists warned us about big data and corporate surveillance. They tried to warn themselves. https://www.wired.com/story/the-cambridge-analytica-data-apocalypse-was-predicted-in-2007/

March 24, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: You Can’t Clean Up Space, It’s Too Messier These strange collection of stars aren’t galaxies, but random groups of hundreds of millions of stars. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-you-cant-clean-up-space-its-too-messier/

March 24, 2018 | Author: Erica KlarreichErica Klarreich In Search of God’s Mathematical Perfect Proofs The mathematicians Günter Ziegler and Martin Aigner have spent the past 20 years collecting some of the most beautiful proofs in mathematics. https://www.wired.com/story/in-search-of-gods-mathematical-perfect-proofs/

March 23, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart Spending Bill Gives Green Energy Its R&D Budget—But That’s Not All It Needs Trump stands for coal. Congress doesn’t. https://www.wired.com/story/spending-bill-gives-green-energy-its-randd-budgetbut-thats-not-all-it-needs/

March 23, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Much Energy Can You Store in a Rubber Band? On a scale from “light thwack” to “geez, watch it with that thing!” https://www.wired.com/story/how-much-energy-can-you-store-in-a-rubber-band/

March 23, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni See Everything Bad About Climate Change in a Single California Town In four months, the southern California town has seen mudslides, the largest wildfire in state history, and now flash floods. https://www.wired.com/story/montecito-is-everything-bad-about-climate-change-in-a-single-california-town/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Facebook’s New Data Restrictions Will Handcuff Even Honest Researchers It was already hard for researchers to use Facebook’s data. It looks like it’s about to get harder. https://www.wired.com/story/fb-data-restrictions-hobble-researchers/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Will Cutting Calories Make You Live Longer? The biggest human study of calorie restriction tries to answer that question. https://www.wired.com/story/will-cutting-calories-make-you-live-longer/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Robot Microscopes Demystify Plankton, the Sea’s Most Vital Residents Researchers are developing clever robots that use AI to examine and classify plankton, the pivotal organisms at the base of our oceanic food chain. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-microscopes-demystify-plankton-the-seas-most-vital-residents/

March 22, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Shatter, Batter, Wax: How Cannabis Extracts Come to Be It’s sticky, it’s icky, it’s cannabis-derived oleoresin! https://www.wired.com/story/shatter-batter-wax-how-cannabis-extracts-come-to-be/

March 21, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers In the Courtroom, Climate Science Needs Substance—and Style San Francisco and Oakland are suing oil companies for money to protect against sea level rise. https://www.wired.com/story/courtroom-climate-science/

March 21, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon MIT Unleashes a Hypnotic Robot Fish to Help Save the Oceans Researchers detail the evolution of the world’s strangest fish, and describe how it could be a potentially powerful tool for scientists to study ocean life. https://www.wired.com/story/mit-robot-fish/

March 20, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Big Ag Wants Farmers to Buy Into Satellite Imagery DowDuPont just signed a big deal with a company that keeps close tabs on the Earth’s surface. https://www.wired.com/story/big-ag-wants-farmers-to-buy-into-satellite-imagery/

March 20, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How the Jaegers in Pacific Rim Uprising Violate Physics Sometimes real science isn’t nearly as exciting as pretend science. https://www.wired.com/story/how-the-jaegers-in-pacific-rim-uprising-violate-physics/

March 20, 2018 | Author: Amanda Kolson HurleyAmanda Kolson Hurley Climate Change Will Not Make Us Nicer A recent study found that people who grow up in places with mild weather are more agreeable and outgoing. What does that mean in a world of climate extremes? https://www.wired.com/story/climate-change-will-not-make-us-nicer/

March 20, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni With Medicare Support, Genetic Cancer Testing Goes Mainstream Medicare will now cover FDA-approved gene sequencing tests to match patients with cancer treatments. https://www.wired.com/story/with-medicare-support-genetic-cancer-testing-goes-mainstream/

March 19, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez To Stay Healthy On Your Next Flight, Avoid Aisles and Stay Put Just grab a window seat and don’t move. https://www.wired.com/story/to-stay-healthy-on-your-next-flight-avoid-aisles-and-stay-put/

March 19, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Robot ‘Hen’ Adopt a Flock of Chicks The PoulBot is teaching researchers about flocking behavior and about the cues animals need to fall in love with their robot overlords. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-chicken-mom/

March 18, 2018 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch Brainless Embryos Suggest Bioelectricity Guides Growth Researchers are building a case that long before the nervous system works, the brain sends crucial bioelectric signals to guide the growth of embryonic tissues. https://www.wired.com/story/brainless-embryos-suggest-bioelectricity-guides-growth/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Michael Isaac SteinMichael Isaac Stein The Uneven Gains of Energy Efficiency Low-income Americans are more likely to live in housing that wastes energy, which saddles them with disproportionately high energy costs. https://www.wired.com/story/the-uneven-gains-of-energy-efficiency/

March 16, 2018 | Author: Katia MoskvitchKatia Moskvitch To Understand the Universe, Physicists Are Building Their Own Silke Weinfurtner isn’t an evil genius hell-bent on creating a new world of her own to rule. She just wants to understand the origins of the one we already have. https://www.wired.com/story/to-understand-the-universe-physicists-are-building-their-own/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Theranos Didn’t Nuke the Diagnostics Business Dozens of other companies were working on point-of-care blood testing before Theranos, and dozens still are. https://www.wired.com/story/theranos-diagnostics-business/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Far Can a Car Go Using Different Fuel Sources? A typical car can travel 30 miles on just one gallon of gasoline. How do electric vehicles stack up? https://www.wired.com/story/how-far-can-a-car-go-using-different-fuel-sources/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Med Students Are Getting Terrible Training in Robotic Surgery A researcher reckons that at most, one out of five residents at top-tier institutions are succeeding at robotic surgery. https://www.wired.com/story/med-students-are-getting-terrible-training-in-robotic-surgery/

March 15, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Maybe Nobody Wants Your Space Internet A growing group of companies believes satellites, balloons, and drones can help bring internet access to everyone on Earth. But what if not everybody wants it? https://www.wired.com/story/maybe-nobody-wants-your-space-internet/

March 14, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Researchers Restore Elusive Sixth Sense to Lost Limbs They’ve restored the patients’ kinesthetic sense—an awareness of movement and space most people don’t even realize they have. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-restore-feeling-to-lost-limbskinda/

March 14, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Google’s Quantum Computing Party Is as Fancy as Physics Gets Physicists aren’t known for their fancy shindigs—but quantum computer researchers break the mold. https://www.wired.com/story/googles-quantum-computing-party-is-as-fancy-as-physics-gets/

March 14, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Stephen Hawking, a Physicist Transcending Space and Time, Passes Away at 76 Hawking may have been the most famous physicist in the world—not only because he saw the face of the universe, but also because he could describe it to the rest of us. https://www.wired.com/story/stephen-hawking-a-physicist-transcending-space-and-time-passes-away-at-76/

March 14, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain This Pi Day, Calculate the Value of Pi for Yourself You just have to add up all the rectangles. https://www.wired.com/story/this-pi-day-calculate-the-value-of-pi-for-yourself/

March 13, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni What Keeps Egg-Freezing Operations From Failing? This week, cryogenic storage at two fertility clinics malfunctioned, putting their clients’ family planning in jeopardy. Will it happen again? https://www.wired.com/story/what-keeps-egg-freezing-operations-from-failing/

March 13, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Controversial Link Between Epic Storms and a Warming Arctic A controversial theory argues that weirdly enough, it’s a warming arctic that’s causing extreme winter weather in the eastern US. https://www.wired.com/story/the-controversial-link-between-epic-storms-and-a-warming-arctic/

March 13, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Please Stop Building Houses Exactly Where Wildfires Start Every fire scientist knows the place where houses meet the wild is dangerous. But people keep putting more houses there. https://www.wired.com/story/please-stop-building-houses-exactly-where-wildfires-start/

March 13, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart These Conservationists Are Desperate to Defrost Snake Sperm Freezing and defrosting snake sperm could be a key to conserving endangered species—but artificial insemination isn’t always easy. https://www.wired.com/story/these-conservationists-are-desperate-to-defrost-snake-sperm/

March 12, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain The Physics of the Speeder Chase in Solo: A Star Wars Story How do you pull off a banking turn if there’s no road to bank off? https://www.wired.com/story/the-physics-of-the-speeder-chase-in-solo-a-star-wars-story/

March 12, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Thank Colleges for Imminent Carbon Taxes (No Seriously, Thank Them) It turns out universities provide a fantastic model for how politicians should start thinking about this on a state or even national level. https://www.wired.com/story/thank-colleges-for-imminent-carbon-taxes-no-seriously-thank-them/

March 11, 2018 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz Can Machine Learning Find Medical Meaning in a Mess of Genes? The computer scientist Barbara Engelhardt develops machine-learning models and methods to scour human genomes for the elusive causes and mechanisms of disease. https://www.wired.com/story/can-machine-learning-find-medical-meaning-in-a-mess-of-genes/

March 10, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Jupiter’s Wild, Wispy Weather Anomalies Juno has documented clusters of cyclones, including eight around the north pole. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-jupiters-wild-wispy-weather-anomalies/

March 10, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart How Wikipedia Portrayed Humanity in a Single Photo There is no ideal Homo sapiens specimen. But the internet had to decide on something. https://www.wired.com/story/how-wikipedia-portrayed-humanity-in-a-single-photo/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni When WhatsApp’s Fake News Problem Threatens Public Health As Brazil’s health authorities scramble to contain the worst yellow fever outbreak in decades, WhatsApp’s misinformation trade threatens to go from destabilizing to deadly. https://www.wired.com/story/when-whatsapps-fake-news-problem-threatens-public-health/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Matt JancerMatt Jancer The Transformer of Autonomous Farmbots Can Do 100 Jobs on Its Own The multitalented Dot Power Platform could raise crop yields 70 percent by 2050. https://www.wired.com/story/dot-power-autonomous-farming/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon The Quest to Make a Robotic Cat Walk With Artificial Neurons Want to create machines that move more naturally? Maybe start by replicating the spinal cord. https://www.wired.com/story/the-quest-to-make-a-robot-cat-walk-with-artificial-neurons/

March 9, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles How Fast Can Gravitational Wave Detection Get? With machine learning and other algorithmic approaches, researchers are increasing the speed at which they detect the undulations of spacetime. https://www.wired.com/story/ligo-data-sifting/

March 8, 2018 | Author: Ryan BradleyRyan Bradley Can Humans Survive on Water Vapor Alone? Technologies like hydropanels could keep us hydrated in a hotter, drier future. https://www.wired.com/story/hydropanels-suck-water-out-of-thin-air/

March 8, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Apparently We Can Let the Stock Market Fight Climate Change A new working paper considers whether environmental factors can actually increase returns on investment. https://www.wired.com/story/market-climate-change/

March 7, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Sea Level Rise in the SF Bay Area Just Got a Lot More Dire Sea levels are rising. But the San Francisco Bay Area has another problem: It’s sinking. By 2100, it could lose 165 square miles to the sea. https://www.wired.com/story/sea-level-rise-in-the-sf-bay-area/

March 7, 2018 | Author: Rebecca HuvalRebecca Huval No Refrigeration Necessary: New Tech for Everlasting Shelf-Life Scientists are experimenting with everything from microwave sterilization to blasts of plasma to ensure food stays appetizing longer. https://www.wired.com/story/food-preservation/

March 7, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler The CDC Can’t Fund Gun Research. What if that Changed? Scientists want to know more about risk factors, gun epidemiology, and whether laws work. https://www.wired.com/story/what-if-the-cdc-could-fund-gun-research/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Jonathon KeatsJonathon Keats What Sea Slugs Can Teach Us About Saving the Environment It turns out that kleptopredation is an environmentally friendly strategy. Perhaps there really is honor among thieves. https://www.wired.com/story/kleptopredation-jargon-watch/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Demonstrations of Bernoulli’s Principle You Can Try at Home To understand Bernoulli’s principle, it helps to think of air as a bunch of tiny balls. https://www.wired.com/story/bernoulli-demonstrations/

March 6, 2018 | Author: Ellen AirhartEllen Airhart An Illustrated Guide to Matching Foods’ Flavor Molecules The Flavor Matrix teaches readers about the volatile compounds in food (VCF), and how to combine them in their cooking. https://www.wired.com/story/the-flavor-matrix/

March 5, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Martian Moons and Jovian Jaunts A close-up look at the universe’s many wonders, from nearby planets to faraway galaxies. https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/space-photos-martian-moons/

March 5, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Wanna See Around Corners? Better Get Yourself a Laser A clever system uses lasers and algorithms to map out-of-sight objects in 3-D. That could be great news for self-driving cars. https://www.wired.com/story/wanna-see-around-corners-better-get-yourself-a-laser/

March 5, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Inside the Company Delivering the Next Generation of Cancer Therapies When you’re sending a $500,000 vial of genetically engineered, cancer-fighting cells, a safe delivery can mean the difference between life and death. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-company-delivering-the-next-generation-of-cancer-therapies/

March 4, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen Elusive Higgs-Like State Created in Exotic Materials Two teams of physicists have figured out how to create a “mini universe,” which could help researchers understand the strange behavior of deeply quantum systems. https://www.wired.com/story/elusive-higgs-like-state-created-in-exotic-materials/

March 3, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: 410 Light-Years Away, a Proto-Saturn Comes to Life After a star forms, a leftover ring of dust and gas eventually forms into planets. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-410-lights-years-away-a-proto-saturn-comes-to-life/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni A Bomb Cyclone Brings Massive Flooding to New England—Again Add three to five feet of storm surge on top of a very high tide, and you’ve got a recipe for flooding. https://www.wired.com/story/a-bomb-cyclone-brings-massive-flooding-to-new-englandagain/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon If You Want a Robot to Stop Screwing Up, Hold Its Hand We can’t trust robots to learn everything on their own. For one startup, the solution is a very human touch. https://www.wired.com/story/if-you-want-a-robot-to-stop-screwing-up-hold-its-hand/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Spoof, Jam, Destroy: Why We Need a Backup for GPS The 24 satellites that keep GPS running in the US aren’t especially secure. So private and federal groups are working on alternatives. https://www.wired.com/story/spoof-jam-destroy-why-we-need-a-backup-for-gps/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez The Subtle Nudges That Could Unhook Us From Our Phones People need help deciding where to place their attention. Tech companies could help ease our time-inconsistency. https://www.wired.com/story/nudge-unhook-phone/

March 2, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Secret to a High Tech Concierge Medical Office? Data Managing electronic medical records is still a pain, but if a start-up can figure it out, better records could lead to new cures https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-to-a-high-tech-concierge-medical-office-data/

March 1, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez Watch NOAA’s New GOES-S Weather Satellite Launch Live Assuming the 11,500-pound spacecraft makes it into geostationary orbit safely, it’ll go by GOES-17. https://www.wired.com/story/noaas-goes-s-satellite-is-a-game-changer-for-severe-weather-forecasts/

March 1, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni Researchers Used This Genealogy Site to Build a 13 Million-Person Family Tree One of the members is Kevin Bacon. https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-used-this-genealogy-site-to-build-a-13-million-person-family-tree/

March 1, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon How Flight Simulation Tech Can Help Turn Robots Into Surgeons A heaving robotic platform adapted from the tech that powers flight simulators could help train other robots to do surgery. https://www.wired.com/story/robot-surgeons/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain You Can Find the Gravitational Constant with String and a Mountain Calculating fundamental constants used to be a much harder job. https://www.wired.com/story/you-can-find-the-gravitational-constant-with-string-and-a-mountain/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Charley LockeCharley Locke Objects in the Camera May Be Smaller Than They Appear Alex Wild wants to teach you—and everyone else—how to be a bug photographer. https://www.wired.com/amp-stories/giving-bugs-their-close-up/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Megan MolteniMegan Molteni With This DNA Dating App, You Swab, Then Swipe For Love But the science of genetic compatibility is dubious at best. https://www.wired.com/story/with-this-dna-dating-app-you-swab-then-swipe-for-love/

February 28, 2018 | Author: Eric NiilerEric Niiler Congress Takes On Sexual Harassment in the Sciences New rules could make it easier to remove faculty members who harass or assault grad students and postdocs. https://www.wired.com/story/congress-addresses-harassment-in-the-sciences/

February 27, 2018 | Author: Emma Grey EllisEmma Grey Ellis If There’s Life on Saturn’s Moon Enceladus, It Might Look Like This Attention alien hunters: Scientists have identified a deep sea microbe that could possibly survive the ocean floor of Saturn’s moon Enceladus. https://www.wired.com/story/if-theres-life-on-saturns-moon-enceladus-it-might-look-like-this/

February 27, 2018 | Author: Sarah LaskowSarah Laskow America’s Secret Ice Base Won’t Stay Frozen Forever Climate change is turning a Cold War project into an environmental hazard. https://www.wired.com/story/americas-secret-ice-base-wont-stay-frozen-forever/

February 27, 2018 | Author: Sophia ChenSophia Chen How to Build a Space Communication System Out of Lasers Get ready for terabytes of laser data to rain from the sky. https://www.wired.com/story/how-to-build-a-space-communication-system-out-of-lasers/

February 26, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Why It’s So Hard to Dose Weed Too much weed = a very bad time. But companies making cannabis devices are figuring out ways to tackle the dosing problem. https://www.wired.com/story/why-its-so-hard-to-dose-weed/

February 25, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain How Fast Can a Tiny Van Go in Ant-Man and the Wasp? Yup, this whole trailer is just an excuse to do physics. https://www.wired.com/story/how-fast-can-a-tiny-van-go-in-ant-man-and-the-wasp/

February 25, 2018 | Author: Jordana CepelewiczJordana Cepelewicz How Cells Pack Tangled DNA Into Neat Chromosomes For the first time, researchers can see how proteins grab loops of DNA and bundle them for cell division. The discovery also hints at how the genome folds to regulate gene expression. https://www.wired.com/story/how-cells-pack-tangled-dna-into-neat-chromosomes/

February 24, 2018 | Author: Shannon StironeShannon Stirone Space Photos of the Week: Juno Helps Jupiter Show Off Its Stripes Juno completed its eleventh orbit of the planet on February 7, capturing some spectacular images in the process. https://www.wired.com/story/space-photos-of-the-week-juno-helps-jupiter-shows-off-its-stripes/

February 24, 2018 | Author: Sarah ScolesSarah Scoles Inside Robert Bigelow’s Decades-Long Obsession With UFOs The budget hotel magnate and inflatable space habitat maker has a unique side project. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-robert-bigelows-decades-long-obsession-with-ufos/

February 23, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers The Struggle to Predict—and Prevent—Toxic Masculinity Sociological research shows that some delinquent boys—but not all—turn into men with no regard for other people’s rights. https://www.wired.com/story/the-struggle-to-predictand-preventtoxic-masculinity/

February 22, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain There’s No One Way to Explain How Flying Works You can use Bernoulli’s principle to explain how planes fly—but that isn’t the only way. https://www.wired.com/story/theres-no-one-way-to-explain-how-flying-works/

February 22, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Inside the Panoptic Studio, the Dome That Could Give Robots Super-Senses In a chilly basement room sits a giant dome that looks like part physics experiment and part like that chamber Darth Vader kicks back in. https://www.wired.com/story/inside-the-panoptic-studio/

February 22, 2018 | Author: J. Madeleine NashJ. Madeleine Nash Permafrost Experiments Mimic Alaska’s Climate-Changed Future In the permafrost zone near Denali, an expanse of tundra bristles with so many sensors and cables that it resembles an outdoor ICU ward. https://www.wired.com/story/permafrost-experiments-mimic-alaskas-climate-changed-future/

February 21, 2018 | Author: Robbie GonzalezRobbie Gonzalez You Don’t Need a Personal Genetics Test to Take Charge of Your Health That in-home DNA test won’t tell you much about how to eat or exercise. Fortunately, you don’t need it to. https://www.wired.com/story/you-dont-need-a-personal-genetics-test-to-take-charge-of-your-health/

February 21, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Snakelike Skin Gives a Robot the Power to Crawl Researchers report today that they’ve designed an inflatable robot with its own scales that automatically pop out to get a grip. https://www.wired.com/story/snakelike-skin-gives-a-robot-the-power-to-crawl/

February 21, 2018 | Author: Adam RogersAdam Rogers Solve Genomics with the Blockchain? Why the Hell Not Start-ups are clamoring to use cryptocurrency software to get and trade genome sequences for research and profit. https://www.wired.com/story/solve-genomics-with-blockchain/

February 20, 2018 | Author: Matt SimonMatt Simon Watch a Human Try to Fight Off That Door-Opening Robot Dog A human with a hockey stick does everything in his power to stop a robot from opening a door. https://www.wired.com/story/watch-a-human-try-to-fight-off-that-door-opening-robot-dog/

February 20, 2018 | Author: Rhett AllainRhett Allain Winter Olympics 2018: The Physics of Blazing Fast Bobsled Runs Four-person bobsled teams go faster than two-person teams—but why? https://www.wired.com/story/winter-olympics-2018-the-physics-of-blazing-fast-bobsled-runs/

February 20, 2018 | Author: Amy CrawfordAmy Crawford Big Data Suggests Big Potential for Urban Farming A global analysis finds that urban agriculture could yield up to 10 percent of many food crops—good news for its future as a force for sustainability. https://www.wired.com/story/big-data-suggests-big-potential-for-urban-farming/